<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Blog</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Blog.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Building a Healthcare Robot from Simulation to Deployment with NVIDIA Isaac</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/lerobotxnvidia-healthcare</link><description>Back to Articles Building a Healthcare Robot from Simulation to Deployment with NVIDIA Isaac Published October 29, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 11 +5 Steven Palma imstevenpmwork Follow Andres Diaz-Pinto diazandr3s Follow TL;DR Table-of-Contents Introduction SO-ARM Starter Workflow; Building an Embodied Surgical Assistant Technical Implementation Sim2Real Mixed Training Approach Hardware Requirements Data Collection Implementation Simulation Teleoperation Controls Model Training Pipeline End-to-End Sim Collect–Train–Eval Pipelines Generate Synthetic Data in Simulation Train and Evaluate Policies Convert Models to TensorRT Getting Started Resources TL;DR A hands-on guide to collecting data, training policies, and deploying autonomous medical robotics workflows on real hardware Table-of-Contents Building a Healthcare Robot from Simulation to Deployment with NVIDIA Isaac TL;DR Table-of-Contents Introduction SO-ARM Starter Workflow; Building an Embodied Surgical Assistant Technical...</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/lerobotxnvidia-healthcare</guid></item><item><title>Voice Cloning with Consent</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/voice-consent-gate</link><description>Back to Articles Voice Cloning with Consent Published October 28, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 14 +8 Margaret Mitchell meg Follow Lucie-Aimée Kaffee frimelle Follow Ethics in Practice: Consent as System Infrastructure The Technical Details Approach Unlocking the Voice Consent Gate In this blog post, we introduce the idea of a 'voice consent gate' to support voice cloning with consent. We provide an example Space and accompanying code to start the ball rolling on the idea. Realistic voice generation technology has gotten uncannily good in the past few years. In some situations, it’s possible to generate a synthetic voice that sounds almost exactly like the voice of a real person. And today, what once felt like science fiction is reality: Voice cloning. With just a few seconds of recorded speech, anyone’s voice can be made to say almost anything. Voice generation, and in particular the subtask of voice cloning, has notable risks and benefits. The risks of “deepfakes”, such as the...</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/voice-consent-gate</guid></item><item><title>Streaming datasets: 100x More Efficient</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/streaming-datasets</link><description>Back to Articles Streaming datasets: 100x More Efficient Published October 27, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 38 +32 Andres Marafioti andito Follow Quentin Lhoest lhoestq Follow ben burtenshaw burtenshaw Follow Pedro Cuenca pcuenq Follow merve merve Follow TLDR Streaming: The Same Easy API The Challenge: Streaming at Scale Under the Hood: What We Improved How are we faster than plain S3: Xet Need a custom streaming pipeline ? Push streaming to the limit Get Started and See the Difference TLDR We boosted load_dataset('dataset', streaming=True) , streaming datasets without downloading them with one line of code! Start training on multi-TB datasets immediately, without complex setups, downloading, no "disk out of space", or 429 “stop requesting!” errors. It's super fast! Outrunning our local SSDs when training on 64xH100 with 256 workers downloading data. We've improved streaming to have 100x fewer requests, → 10× faster data resolution → 2x sample/sec, → 0 worker crashes at 256...</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/streaming-datasets</guid></item><item><title>huggingface_hub v1.0: Five Years of Building the Foundation of Open Machine Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/huggingface-hub-v1</link><description>Back to Articles huggingface_hub v1.0: Five Years of Building the Foundation of Open Machine Learning Published October 27, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 51 +45 Lucain Pouget Wauplin Follow Célina Hanouti celinah Follow Lysandre lysandre Follow Julien Chaumond julien-c Follow The Story Behind the Library The Foundation Years (2020-2021) The Great Shift: Git to HTTP (2022) An Expanding API Surface (2022–2024) Ready. Xet. Go! (2024-2025) Measuring Growth and Impact Building for the Next Decade Modern HTTP Infrastructure with httpx and hf_xet Agents Made Simple with MCP and Tiny-Agents A Fully-Featured CLI for Modern Workflows Cleaning House for the Future The Migration Guide Acknowledgments TL;DR: After five years of development, huggingface_hub has reached v1.0 - a milestone that marks the library's maturity as the Python package powering 200,000 dependent libraries and providing core functionality for accessing over 2 million public models, 0.5 million public datasets, and 1 million...</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/huggingface-hub-v1</guid></item><item><title>LeRobot v0.4.0: Supercharging OSS Robot Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/lerobot-release-v040</link><description>Back to Articles LeRobot v0.4.0: Supercharging OSS Robot Learning Published October 24, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 31 +25 Steven Palma imstevenpmwork Follow Michel Aractingi aractingi Follow Pepijn Kooijmans pepijn223 Follow Caroline Pascal CarolinePascal Follow Jade Choghari jadechoghari Follow Francesco Capuano fracapuano Follow Adil Zouitine AdilZtn Follow Martino Russi nepyope Follow Thomas Wolf thomwolf Follow TL;DR Table-of-Contents Datasets: Ready for the Next Wave of Large-Scale Robot Learning What's New in Datasets v3.0? New Feature: Dataset Editing Tools! Simulation Environments: Expanding Your Training Grounds LIBERO Support Meta-World Integration Codebase: Powerful Tools For Everyone The New Pipeline for Data Processing Multi-GPU Training Made Easy Policies: Unleashing Open-World Generalization PI0 and PI0.5 GR00T N1.5 Robots: A New Era of Hardware Integration with the Plugin System Key Benefits Reachy 2 Integration Phone Integration The Hugging Face Robot Learning...</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/lerobot-release-v040</guid></item><item><title>Building the Open Agent Ecosystem Together: Introducing OpenEnv</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/openenv</link><description>Back to Articles Building the Open Agent Ecosystem Together: Introducing OpenEnv Published October 23, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 108 +102 Joseph Spisak spisakjo Follow openenv Davide Testuggine darktex Follow guest Zach Wentz zkwentz Follow openenv Pierre Andrews mortimerp9 Follow openenv Sanyam Bhutani Sanyam Follow openenv Hamid Shojanazeri Hamid-Nazeri Follow openenv Pankit Thapar Pankit01 Follow openenv Emre Guven emre0 Follow openenv Lewis Tunstall lewtun Follow Vaibhav Srivastav reach-vb Follow The Problem The Solution The RFCs Use cases What’s Next With tools like TRL , TorchForge and verl , the open-source community has shown how to scale AI across complex compute infrastructure. But compute is only one side of the coin. The other side is the developer community; the people and tools that make agentic systems possible. That’s why Meta and Hugging Face are partnering to launch the OpenEnv Hub : a shared and open community hub for agentic environments. Agentic environments...</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/openenv</guid></item><item><title>Hugging Face and VirusTotal collaborate to strengthen AI security</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/virustotal</link><description>Back to Articles Hugging Face and VirusTotal collaborate to strengthen AI security Published October 22, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 35 +29 Adrien Carreira XciD Follow Bernardo Quintero bquintero Follow VirusTotal Why this matters How the collaboration works Benefits for the community Join us We’re excited to announce a new collaboration between Hugging Face and VirusTotal , the world’s leading threat-intelligence and malware analysis platform. This collaboration enhances the security of files shared across the Hugging Face Hub, helping protect the machine learning community from malicious or compromised assets. TL;DR - Starting today, every one of the 2.2M+ public model and datasets repositories on the Hugging Face Hub is being continuously scanned with VirusTotal. Why this matters AI models are powerful but they’re also complex digital artifacts that can include large binary files, serialized data, and dependencies that sometimes carry hidden risks. As of today HF Hub hosts 2.2...</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/virustotal</guid></item><item><title>Sentence Transformers is joining Hugging Face!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/sentence-transformers-joins-hf</link><description>Back to Articles Sentence Transformers is joining Hugging Face! Published October 22, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 72 +66 Tom Aarsen tomaarsen Follow Project History Acknowledgements Getting Started Today, we are announcing that Sentence Transformers is transitioning from Iryna Gurevych’s Ubiquitous Knowledge Processing (UKP) Lab at the TU Darmstadt to Hugging Face. Hugging Face's Tom Aarsen has already been maintaining the library since late 2023 and will continue to lead the project. At its new home, Sentence Transformers will benefit from Hugging Face's robust infrastructure, including continuous integration and testing, ensuring that it stays up-to-date with the latest advancements in Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing. Sentence Transformers (a.k.a. SentenceBERT or SBERT) is a popular open-source library for generating high-quality embeddings that capture semantic meaning. Since its inception by Nils Reimers in 2019, Sentence Transformers has been widely...</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/sentence-transformers-joins-hf</guid></item><item><title>Supercharge your OCR Pipelines with Open Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/ocr-open-models</link><description>Back to Articles Supercharge your OCR Pipelines with Open Models Published October 21, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 218 +212 merve merve Follow Aritra Roy Gosthipaty ariG23498 Follow Daniel van Strien davanstrien Follow Hynek Kydlicek hynky Follow Andres Marafioti andito Follow Vaibhav Srivastav reach-vb Follow Pedro Cuenca pcuenq Follow Table-of-Contents Brief Introduction to Modern OCR Model Capabilities Cutting-edge Open OCR Models Comparing Latest Models Evaluating Models Tools to Run Models Locally Remotely Going Beyond OCR Wrapping up We have added Chandra and OlmOCR-2 to this blog, as well as OlmOCR Scores of the models 🫡 TL;DR: The rise of powerful vision-language models has transformed document AI. Each model comes with unique strengths, making it tricky to choose the right one. Open-weight models offer better cost efficiency and privacy. To help you get started with them, we’ve put together this guide. In this guide, you’ll learn: The landscape of current models and their...</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/ocr-open-models</guid></item><item><title>Unlock the power of images with AI Sheets</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/aisheets-unlock-images</link><description>Back to Articles Unlock the power of images with AI Sheets Published October 21, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 23 +17 Ame Vi Ameeeee Follow Daniel Vila dvilasuero Follow Francisco Aranda frascuchon Follow Damián Pumar damianpumar Follow Leandro von Werra lvwerra Follow Thomas Wolf thomwolf Follow Your images have stories to tell Generate and transform text and images in the same flow Step-by-step guide Upload your data Understanding AI actions Extract text from images. Clean, transform, and enrich text Edit and transform images. Export your dataset What's next? 🧭 TL;DR : Hugging Face AI Sheets is an open-source tool for supercharging datasets with AI models , no code required. Now with vision support : extract data from images (receipts, documents), generate visuals from text, and edit images—all in a spreadsheet. Powered by thousands of open models via Inference Providers. Analyzing your images with AI Sheets We are excited to release a massive update to Hugging Face AI Sheets , the...</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/aisheets-unlock-images</guid></item><item><title>Google Cloud C4 Brings a 70% TCO improvement on GPT OSS with Intel and Hugging Face</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/gpt-oss-on-intel-xeon</link><description>Back to Articles Google Cloud C4 Brings a 70% TCO improvement on GPT OSS with Intel and Hugging Face Published October 16, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 14 +8 Jiqing.Feng Jiqing Follow Intel Matrix Yao MatrixYao Follow Intel Ke Ding kding1 Follow Intel Ilyas Moutawwakil IlyasMoutawwakil Follow Introduction Benchmark Scope &amp; Hardware Configuration Summary Hardware Under Test Create instance C3 C4 Set up the environment Benchmark Procedure Results Normalized Throughput per vCPU Cost &amp; TCO Conclusion Intel and Hugging Face collaborated to demonstrate the real-world value of upgrading to Google’s latest C4 Virtual Machine (VM) running on Intel® Xeon® 6 processors (codenamed Granite Rapids (GNR)). We specifically wanted to benchmark improvements in the text generation performance of OpenAI GPT OSS Large Language Model(LLM). The results are in, and they are impressive, demonstrating a 1.7x improvement in Total Cost of Ownership(TCO) over the previous-generation Google C3 VM instances. The...</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/gpt-oss-on-intel-xeon</guid></item><item><title>Get your VLM running in 3 simple steps on Intel CPUs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/openvino-vlm</link><description>Back to Articles Get your VLM running in 3 simple steps on Intel CPUs Published October 15, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 15 +9 Ezequiel Lanza ezelanza Follow Intel Helena helenai Follow Intel Nikita nikita-savelyev-intel Follow Intel Ella Charlaix echarlaix Follow Ilyas Moutawwakil IlyasMoutawwakil Follow Deploy your model with Optimum Step 1: Convert your model Step 2: Quantization Option 1: Weight Only Quantization Option 2: Static Quantization Step 3: Run inference Evaluation and Conclusion Useful Links &amp; Resources With the growing capability of large language models (LLMs), a new class of models has emerged: Vision Language Models (VLMs) . These models can analyze images and videos to describe scenes, create captions, and answer questions about visual content. While running AI models on your own device can be difficult as these models are often computationally demanding, it also offers significant benefits: including improved privacy since your data stays on your machine, and...</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/openvino-vlm</guid></item><item><title>SOTA OCR on-device with Core ML and dots.ocr</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/dots-ocr-ne</link><description>Back to Articles SOTA OCR on-device with Core ML and dots.ocr Published October 2, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 56 +50 Christopher Fleetwood FL33TW00D-HF Follow Pedro Cuenca pcuenq Follow Conversion Dots.OCR Step 0: Understand and simplify the model Step 1: A simple harness Step 2: Bug hunting Step 3: Benchmarking Every year our hardware is a little more powerful, our models a little smarter for each parameter. In 2025, it is more feasible than ever to run truly competitive models on-device. dots.ocr , a 3B parameter OCR model from RedNote, surpasses Gemini 2.5 Pro in OmniDocBench , making OCR a truly no compromises on-device use case. Running models on-device is certainly appealing to developers: no smuggling API keys, zero cost, and no network required. However, if we want these models to run on-device, we need to be mindful of the limited compute and power budgets. Enter the Neural Engine, Apple's custom AI accelerator that has shipped with every Apple device since 2017. This...</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/dots-ocr-ne</guid></item><item><title>Introducing RTEB: A New Standard for Retrieval Evaluation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/blog/rteb</link><description>Back to Articles Introducing RTEB: A New Standard for Retrieval Evaluation Published October 1, 2025 Update on GitHub Upvote 120 +114 Frank Liu fzliu Follow guest Kenneth C. Enevoldsen KennethEnevoldsen Follow mteb Solomatin Roman Samoed Follow mteb Isaac Chung isaacchung Follow mteb Tom Aarsen tomaarsen Follow mteb Fődi, Zoltán fzoll Follow guest Why Existing Benchmarks Fall Short Introducing RTEB A Hybrid Strategy for True Generalization Built for Real-World Domains Launching RTEB: A Community Effort Limitations and Future Work TL;DR – We’re excited to introduce the beta version of the Retrieval Embedding Benchmark (RTEB) , a new benchmark designed to reliably evaluate the retrieval accuracy of embedding models for real-world applications. Existing benchmarks struggle to measure true generalization, while RTEB addresses this with a hybrid strategy of open and private datasets. Its goal is simple: to create a fair, transparent, and application-focused standard for measuring how...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/blog/rteb</guid></item></channel></rss>