<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Why Language Models Hallucinate</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.04664</link><description>Language models produce incorrect statements due to training and evaluation procedures that reward guessing over acknowledging uncertainty, leading to a need for socio-technical changes in benchmark scoring.  					AI-generated summary 				 Like students facing hard exam questions, large language models sometimes guess when uncertain, producing plausible yet incorrect statements instead of admitting uncertainty. Such "hallucinations" persist even in state-of-the-art systems and undermine trust. We argue that language models hallucinate because the training and evaluation procedures reward guessing over acknowledging uncertainty, and we analyze the statistical causes of hallucinations in the modern training pipeline. Hallucinations need not be mysterious -- they originate simply as errors in binary classification. If incorrect statements cannot be distinguished from facts, then hallucinations in pretrained language models will arise through natural statistical pressures. We then argue that hallucinations persist due to the way most evaluations are graded -- language models are optimized to be good test-takers, and guessing when uncertain improves test performance. This "epidemic" of penalizing uncertain responses can only be addressed through a socio-technical mitigation: modifying the scoring of existing benchmarks that are misaligned but dominate leaderboards, rather than introducing additional hallucination evaluations. This change may steer the field toward more trustworthy AI systems.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 04:14:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.04664</guid></item><item><title>WildScore: Benchmarking MLLMs in-the-Wild Symbolic Music Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.04744</link><description>WildScore evaluates MLLMs' symbolic music reasoning through a benchmark of real-world music scores and user-generated queries, revealing both strengths and challenges.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have demonstrated impressive capabilities across various vision-language tasks. However, their reasoning abilities in the multimodal symbolic music domain remain largely unexplored. We introduce WildScore, the first in-the-wild multimodal symbolic music reasoning and analysis benchmark, designed to evaluate MLLMs' capacity to interpret real-world music scores and answer complex musicological queries. Each instance in WildScore is sourced from genuine musical compositions and accompanied by authentic user-generated questions and discussions, capturing the intricacies of practical music analysis. To facilitate systematic evaluation, we propose a systematic taxonomy, comprising both high-level and fine-grained musicological ontologies. Furthermore, we frame complex music reasoning as multiple-choice question answering, enabling controlled and scalable assessment of MLLMs' symbolic music understanding. Empirical benchmarking of state-of-the-art MLLMs on WildScore reveals intriguing patterns in their visual-symbolic reasoning, uncovering both promising directions and persistent challenges for MLLMs in symbolic music reasoning and analysis. We release the dataset and code.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 02:29:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.04744</guid></item><item><title>LatticeWorld: A Multimodal Large Language Model-Empowered Framework for
  Interactive Complex World Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.05263</link><description>LatticeWorld, a 3D world generation framework using lightweight LLMs and Unreal Engine 5, creates dynamic, interactive environments from textual and visual inputs, achieving high accuracy and efficiency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent research has been increasingly focusing on developing 3D world models that simulate complex real-world scenarios. World models have found broad applications across various domains, including embodied AI, autonomous driving, entertainment, etc. A more realistic simulation with accurate physics will effectively narrow the sim-to-real gap and allow us to gather rich information about the real world conveniently. While traditional manual modeling has enabled the creation of virtual 3D scenes, modern approaches have leveraged advanced machine learning algorithms for 3D world generation, with most recent advances focusing on generative methods that can create virtual worlds based on user instructions. This work explores such a research direction by proposing LatticeWorld, a simple yet effective 3D world generation framework that streamlines the industrial production pipeline of 3D environments. LatticeWorld leverages lightweight LLMs (LLaMA-2-7B) alongside the industry-grade rendering engine (e.g., Unreal Engine 5) to generate a dynamic environment. Our proposed framework accepts textual descriptions and visual instructions as multimodal inputs and creates large-scale 3D interactive worlds with dynamic agents, featuring competitive multi-agent interaction, high-fidelity physics simulation, and real-time rendering. We conduct comprehensive experiments to evaluate LatticeWorld, showing that it achieves superior accuracy in scene layout generation and visual fidelity. Moreover, LatticeWorld achieves over a 90times increase in industrial production efficiency while maintaining high creative quality compared with traditional manual production methods. Our demo video is available at https://youtu.be/8VWZXpERR18</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 03:16:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.05263</guid></item><item><title>MedVista3D: Vision-Language Modeling for Reducing Diagnostic Errors in
  3D CT Disease Detection, Understanding and Reporting</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.03800</link><description>MedVista3D is a multi-scale semantic-enriched vision-language pretraining framework for 3D CT analysis that addresses local-global understanding, report variability, and achieves state-of-the-art performance in disease classification, report retrieval, and medical visual question answering.  					AI-generated summary 				 Radiologic diagnostic errors-under-reading errors, inattentional blindness, and communication failures-remain prevalent in clinical practice. These issues often stem from missed localized abnormalities, limited global context, and variability in report language. These challenges are amplified in 3D imaging, where clinicians must examine hundreds of slices per scan. Addressing them requires systems with precise localized detection, global volume-level reasoning, and semantically consistent natural language reporting. However, existing 3D vision-language models are unable to meet all three needs jointly, lacking local-global understanding for spatial reasoning and struggling with the variability and noise of uncurated radiology reports. We present MedVista3D, a multi-scale semantic-enriched vision-language pretraining framework for 3D CT analysis. To enable joint disease detection and holistic interpretation, MedVista3D performs local and global image-text alignment for fine-grained representation learning within full-volume context. To address report variability, we apply language model rewrites and introduce a Radiology Semantic Matching Bank for semantics-aware alignment. MedVista3D achieves state-of-the-art performance on zero-shot disease classification, report retrieval, and medical visual question answering, while transferring well to organ segmentation and prognosis prediction. Code and datasets will be released.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 03:49:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.03800</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral Fingerprinting of Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.04504</link><description>A Behavioral Fingerprinting framework evaluates Large Language Models using a Diagnostic Prompt Suite and automated pipeline, revealing divergent alignment behaviors and clustering patterns.  					AI-generated summary 				 Current benchmarks for Large Language Models (LLMs) primarily focus on performance metrics, often failing to capture the nuanced behavioral characteristics that differentiate them. This paper introduces a novel ``Behavioral Fingerprinting'' framework designed to move beyond traditional evaluation by creating a multi-faceted profile of a model's intrinsic cognitive and interactive styles. Using a curated Diagnostic Prompt Suite and an innovative, automated evaluation pipeline where a powerful LLM acts as an impartial judge, we analyze eighteen models across capability tiers. Our results reveal a critical divergence in the LLM landscape: while core capabilities like abstract and causal reasoning are converging among top models, alignment-related behaviors such as sycophancy and semantic robustness vary dramatically. We further document a cross-model default persona clustering (ISTJ/ESTJ) that likely reflects common alignment incentives. Taken together, this suggests that a model's interactive nature is not an emergent property of its scale or reasoning power, but a direct consequence of specific, and highly variable, developer alignment strategies. Our framework provides a reproducible and scalable methodology for uncovering these deep behavioral differences. Project: https://github.com/JarvisPei/Behavioral-Fingerprinting</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 04:28:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.04504</guid></item></channel></rss>