<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>ColorBench: Can VLMs See and Understand the Colorful World? A
  Comprehensive Benchmark for Color Perception, Reasoning, and Robustness</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10514</link><description>Color plays an important role in human perception and usually provides critical clues in visual reasoning. However, it is unclear whether and how vision-language models (VLMs) can perceive, understand, and leverage color as humans. This paper introduces ColorBench, an innovative benchmark meticulously crafted to assess the capabilities of VLMs in color understanding, including color perception, reasoning, and robustness. By curating a suite of diverse test scenarios, with grounding in real applications, ColorBench evaluates how these models perceive colors, infer meanings from color-based cues, and maintain consistent performance under varying color transformations. Through an extensive evaluation of 32 VLMs with varying language models and vision encoders, our paper reveals some undiscovered findings: (i) The scaling law (larger models are better) still holds on ColorBench, while the language model plays a more important role than the vision encoder. (ii) However, the performance gaps across models are relatively small, indicating that color understanding has been largely neglected by existing VLMs. (iii) CoT reasoning improves color understanding accuracies and robustness, though they are vision-centric tasks. (iv) Color clues are indeed leveraged by VLMs on ColorBench but they can also mislead models in some tasks. These findings highlight the critical limitations of current VLMs and underscore the need to enhance color comprehension. Our ColorBenchcan serve as a foundational tool for advancing the study of human-level color understanding of multimodal AI.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 02:28:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10514</guid></item><item><title>Cobra: Efficient Line Art COlorization with BRoAder References</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12240</link><description>The comic production industry requires reference-based line art colorization with high accuracy, efficiency, contextual consistency, and flexible control. A comic page often involves diverse characters, objects, and backgrounds, which complicates the coloring process. Despite advancements in diffusion models for image generation, their application in line art colorization remains limited, facing challenges related to handling extensive reference images, time-consuming inference, and flexible control. We investigate the necessity of extensive contextual image guidance on the quality of line art colorization. To address these challenges, we introduce Cobra, an efficient and versatile method that supports color hints and utilizes over 200 reference images while maintaining low latency. Central to Cobra is a Causal Sparse DiT architecture, which leverages specially designed positional encodings, causal sparse attention, and Key-Value Cache to effectively manage long-context references and ensure color identity consistency. Results demonstrate that Cobra achieves accurate line art colorization through extensive contextual reference, significantly enhancing inference speed and interactivity, thereby meeting critical industrial demands. We release our codes and models on our project page: https://zhuang2002.github.io/Cobra/.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 02:02:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12240</guid></item><item><title>BitNet b1.58 2B4T Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12285</link><description>We introduce BitNet b1.58 2B4T, the first open-source, native 1-bit Large Language Model (LLM) at the 2-billion parameter scale. Trained on a corpus of 4 trillion tokens, the model has been rigorously evaluated across benchmarks covering language understanding, mathematical reasoning, coding proficiency, and conversational ability. Our results demonstrate that BitNet b1.58 2B4T achieves performance on par with leading open-weight, full-precision LLMs of similar size, while offering significant advantages in computational efficiency, including substantially reduced memory footprint, energy consumption, and decoding latency. To facilitate further research and adoption, the model weights are released via Hugging Face along with open-source inference implementations for both GPU and CPU architectures.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 02:59:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12285</guid></item><item><title>AlayaDB: The Data Foundation for Efficient and Effective Long-context
  LLM Inference</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10326</link><description>AlayaDB is a cutting-edge vector database system natively architected for efficient and effective long-context inference for Large Language Models (LLMs) at AlayaDB AI. Specifically, it decouples the KV cache and attention computation from the LLM inference systems, and encapsulates them into a novel vector database system. For the Model as a Service providers (MaaS), AlayaDB consumes fewer hardware resources and offers higher generation quality for various workloads with different kinds of Service Level Objectives (SLOs), when comparing with the existing alternative solutions (e.g., KV cache disaggregation, retrieval-based sparse attention). The crux of AlayaDB is that it abstracts the attention computation and cache management for LLM inference into a query processing procedure, and optimizes the performance via a native query optimizer. In this work, we demonstrate the effectiveness of AlayaDB via (i) three use cases from our industry partners, and (ii) extensive experimental results on LLM inference benchmarks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 07:30:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10326</guid></item><item><title>SIFT-50M: A Large-Scale Multilingual Dataset for Speech Instruction
  Fine-Tuning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.09081</link><description>We introduce SIFT (Speech Instruction Fine-Tuning), a 50M-example dataset designed for instruction fine-tuning and pre-training of speech-text large language models (LLMs). SIFT-50M is built from publicly available speech corpora, which collectively contain 14K hours of speech, and leverages LLMs along with off-the-shelf expert models. The dataset spans five languages, encompassing a diverse range of speech understanding as well as controllable speech generation instructions. Using SIFT-50M, we train SIFT-LLM, which outperforms existing speech-text LLMs on instruction-following benchmarks while achieving competitive performance on foundational speech tasks. To support further research, we also introduce EvalSIFT, a benchmark dataset specifically designed to evaluate the instruction-following capabilities of speech-text LLMs.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 09:02:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.09081</guid></item><item><title>Robust and Fine-Grained Detection of AI Generated Texts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11952</link><description>An ideal detection system for machine generated content is supposed to work well on any generator as many more advanced LLMs come into existence day by day. Existing systems often struggle with accurately identifying AI-generated content over shorter texts. Further, not all texts might be entirely authored by a human or LLM, hence we focused more over partial cases i.e human-LLM co-authored texts. Our paper introduces a set of models built for the task of token classification which are trained on an extensive collection of human-machine co-authored texts, which performed well over texts of unseen domains, unseen generators, texts by non-native speakers and those with adversarial inputs. We also introduce a new dataset of over 2.4M such texts mostly co-authored by several popular proprietary LLMs over 23 languages. We also present findings of our models' performance over each texts of each domain and generator. Additional findings include comparison of performance against each adversarial method, length of input texts and characteristics of generated texts compared to the original human authored texts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 02:17:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11952</guid></item><item><title>REPA-E: Unlocking VAE for End-to-End Tuning with Latent Diffusion
  Transformers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10483</link><description>In this paper we tackle a fundamental question: "Can we train latent diffusion models together with the variational auto-encoder (VAE) tokenizer in an end-to-end manner?" Traditional deep-learning wisdom dictates that end-to-end training is often preferable when possible. However, for latent diffusion transformers, it is observed that end-to-end training both VAE and diffusion-model using standard diffusion-loss is ineffective, even causing a degradation in final performance. We show that while diffusion loss is ineffective, end-to-end training can be unlocked through the representation-alignment (REPA) loss -- allowing both VAE and diffusion model to be jointly tuned during the training process. Despite its simplicity, the proposed training recipe (REPA-E) shows remarkable performance; speeding up diffusion model training by over 17x and 45x over REPA and vanilla training recipes, respectively. Interestingly, we observe that end-to-end tuning with REPA-E also improves the VAE itself; leading to improved latent space structure and downstream generation performance. In terms of final performance, our approach sets a new state-of-the-art; achieving FID of 1.26 and 1.83 with and without classifier-free guidance on ImageNet 256 x 256. Code is available at https://end2end-diffusion.github.io.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 06:38:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10483</guid></item><item><title>Vivid4D: Improving 4D Reconstruction from Monocular Video by Video
  Inpainting</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11092</link><description>Reconstructing 4D dynamic scenes from casually captured monocular videos is valuable but highly challenging, as each timestamp is observed from a single viewpoint. We introduce Vivid4D, a novel approach that enhances 4D monocular video synthesis by augmenting observation views - synthesizing multi-view videos from a monocular input. Unlike existing methods that either solely leverage geometric priors for supervision or use generative priors while overlooking geometry, we integrate both. This reformulates view augmentation as a video inpainting task, where observed views are warped into new viewpoints based on monocular depth priors. To achieve this, we train a video inpainting model on unposed web videos with synthetically generated masks that mimic warping occlusions, ensuring spatially and temporally consistent completion of missing regions. To further mitigate inaccuracies in monocular depth priors, we introduce an iterative view augmentation strategy and a robust reconstruction loss. Experiments demonstrate that our method effectively improves monocular 4D scene reconstruction and completion.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 09:02:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11092</guid></item></channel></rss>