<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>🤗 Just released Rain-100M, an experimental ~97M-parameter Qwen3-style language model trained from random initialization.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/raincandy-u/660562661454335</link><description>🤗 Just released Rain-100M, an experimental ~97M-parameter Qwen3-style language model trained from random initialization. Repo: raincandy-u/Rain-100M Data: HuggingFaceFW/fineweb-edu , ~3B tokens, English only Tokenizer: custom 16k BPE, context length 4096 Architecture: 12 Transformer layers, hidden size 768, 12 heads, MLP 2048, SiLU, bf16 Rain-100M is a raw base model (not instruction-tuned or safety-aligned), aimed at small-scale research, debugging training pipelines, and CPU/edge experiments. If you run evaluations, finetunes, or visualizations with it, I would be very interested in your results! See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/raincandy-u/660562661454335</guid></item><item><title>We’ve released two conversational speech datasets from oto on Hugging Face 🤗</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/consome2/284818675921006</link><description>We’ve released two conversational speech datasets from oto on Hugging Face 🤗 Both are based on real, casual, full-duplex conversations, but with slightly different focuses. Dataset 1: Processed / curated subset otoearth/otoSpeech-full-duplex-processed-141h * Full-duplex, spontaneous multi-speaker conversations * Participants filtered for high audio quality * PII removal and audio enhancement applied * Designed for training and benchmarking S2S or dialogue models Dataset 2: Larger raw(er) release otoearth/otoSpeech-full-duplex-280h * Same collection pipeline, with broader coverage * More diversity in speakers, accents, and conversation styles * Useful for analysis, filtering, or custom preprocessing experiments We intentionally split the release to support different research workflows: clean and ready-to-use vs. more exploratory and research-oriented use. The datasets are currently private, but we’re happy to approve access requests — feel free to request access if you’re interested....</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/consome2/284818675921006</guid></item><item><title>Tencent HunyuanImage 3.0-Instruct is seriously impressive</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Benedictat/483321622062325</link><description>Tencent HunyuanImage 3.0-Instruct is seriously impressive skyrocketed to 2nd place globally on the LMArena leaderboard, only trailing Google Nano-banana Pro. What excites me most is its newly launched image editing and multi-image fusion capabilities its semantic understanding is rock-solid this Instruct-following capability basically enables one-sentence end-to-end workflows, delivering a dimensionality-reducing boost in efficiency. Frankly, it nails the pain points of frontline creators: old photo restoration, text modification, even extracting people from multiple images to create group shots. Previously, tweaking the fusion quality took tons of effort, but now the out-of-the-box realism and emotional expression are top-tier zero cheap AI artifacts 👉 Repo: https://hunyuan.tencent.com/chat/HunyuanDefault?from=modelSquare&amp;modelId=Hunyuan-Image-3.0-Instruct technical report：https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.23951 See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Benedictat/483321622062325</guid></item><item><title>Reverse Engineering a $500M Mystery: From HashHop to Memory-Augmented Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/260857666290873</link><description>Reverse Engineering a $500M Mystery: From HashHop to Memory-Augmented Language Models I wrote a deep dive into how Magic AI's 100M token context window might work, starting from their HashHop benchmark and building up to MALM - a Memory-Augmented Language Model. Key insight: treating each key as a single token enables perfect retrieval at unlimited context lengths. The article covers: - How HashHop works and why its perfect accuracy is suspicious - Building a tokenized solver that achieves 100% accuracy - Scaling to MALM for real code search tasks - Why this approach could handle 100M+ tokens Read the full article: https://huggingface.co/blog/codelion/reverse-engineering-magic-hashhop Try the model: codelion/malm-165m Code: https://github.com/codelion/hash-hop See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/260857666290873</guid></item><item><title>HunyuanImage 3.0-Instruct just dropped</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/wangbuer999/572194851679348</link><description>HunyuanImage 3.0-Instruct just dropped fresh -sourceImage 3.0model! Spent 20 mins testing it on a Messi + retro scrambler fusion case Ran on diffusers v0.26.3 + CUDA 12.1 | 8B MoE params (1.3B activated) | zero VRAM issues strength=0.9 Messi #10 kit/tattoo sharp, moto’s rusted metal texture blurred (classic open-source pain) strength=0.7 Moto/cobblestone background crisp, Messi’s jersey details faded completely strength=0.75 + prompt "Blend seamlessly, keep all original details": both subject &amp; background sharp No ControlNet, no manual masking the model’s chain-of-thought reasoning parses image+prompt first Already outperforms Qwen-Image-Edit 2511 (GSB eval +25.7% on single-image edits) | 100% open-source 👉 Repo: https://hunyuan.tencent.com/chat/HunyuanDefault?from=modelSquare&amp;modelId=Hunyuan-Image-3.0-Instruct technical report：https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.23951 Anyone else struggled with strength tweaks for fusion? This fixed it for my Messi+moto case did it work as well for yours?...</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/wangbuer999/572194851679348</guid></item><item><title>I'm absolutely stunned by the aesthetics of HunyuanImage-3.0</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/kelsend/790764867019535</link><description>I'm absolutely stunned by the aesthetics of HunyuanImage-3.0 The visual effects of this model are simply beyond imagination it’s every bit as good as NanoBanana, no compromise at all. I fine-tuned my micro-scene prompts by adding text overlays and background effects, and its adaptability is truly breathtaking. With just one prompt, you can generate scene posters for any movie or novel. Every detail, from scene design to text style and atmospheric effects, perfectly aligns with the tone of the original material. No forced elements, just seamless, film-grade visual effects that exactly match what I envisioned. 👉 Repo: https://hunyuan.tencent.com/chat/HunyuanDefault?from=modelSquare&amp;modelId=Hunyuan-Image-3.0-Instruct See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/kelsend/790764867019535</guid></item><item><title>Uncensored, Heretic GGUF quants of GLM 4.7 (30B-A3B) with correct Llamacpp and all updates ; NEO-CODE Imatrix W 16 bit OTs.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DavidAU/879154559678091</link><description>Uncensored, Heretic GGUF quants of GLM 4.7 (30B-A3B) with correct Llamacpp and all updates ; NEO-CODE Imatrix W 16 bit OTs. Also specialized quants (balanced for this model), and all quants are NEO-CODE Imatrix W 16 bit output tensor. DavidAU/GLM-4.7-Flash-Uncensored-Heretic-NEO-CODE-Imatrix-MAX-GGUF "Reg quants, non-heretic" : Also 16 bit ot, NEO-CODE Imatrix and specialized: DavidAU/GLM-4.7-Flash-NEO-CODE-Imatrix-MAX-GGUF See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DavidAU/879154559678091</guid></item><item><title>After 2 months of refinement, I'm happy to announce that a lot of Transformers' modeling code is now significantly more torch-compile &amp; export-friendly 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/IlyasMoutawwakil/703555138750194</link><description>After 2 months of refinement, I'm happy to announce that a lot of Transformers' modeling code is now significantly more torch-compile &amp; export-friendly 🔥 Why it had to be done 👇 PyTorch's Dynamo compiler is increasingly becoming the default interoperability layer for ML systems. Anything that relies on torch.export or torch.compile, from model optimization to cross-framework integrations, benefits directly when models can be captured as a single dynamo-traced graph ! Transformers models are now easier to: ⚙️ Compile end-to-end with torch.compile backends 📦 Export reliably via torch.export and torch.onnx.export 🚀 Deploy to ONNX / ONNX Runtime, Intel Corporation's OpenVINO, NVIDIA AutoDeploy (TRT-LLM), AMD's Quark, Meta's Executorch and more hardware-specific runtimes. This work aims at unblocking entire TorchDynamo-based toolchains that rely on exporting Transformers across runtimes and accelerators. We are doubling down on Transformers commitment to be a first-class citizen of the...</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/IlyasMoutawwakil/703555138750194</guid></item><item><title>🔥 SWE-Pruner can save up to 40% of your Claude Code cost without sacrificing performance. Try it out!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/YerbaPage/493697712808947</link><description>🔥 SWE-Pruner can save up to 40% of your Claude Code cost without sacrificing performance. Try it out! 📚 SWE-Pruner: Self-Adaptive Context Pruning for Coding Agents (2601.16746) 💻 https://github.com/Ayanami1314/swe-pruner Drawing inspiration from how human programmers “selectively skim” source code during development and debugging, SWE-Pruner performs task-aware adaptive pruning for long contexts. See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/YerbaPage/493697712808947</guid></item><item><title>👀Just published a first-look at Tencent HY-Image-v3.0-I2I!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/imnotkitty/991984513173348</link><description>👀Just published a first-look at Tencent HY-Image-v3.0-I2I! Tested its multi-image fusion and single-reference consistency. The results on complex prompts are quite impressive. What’s the most creative image task you’d give it? 👉 Read the full analysis: https://huggingface.co/blog/imnotkitty/tencent-hy-image-v30-i2i See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/imnotkitty/991984513173348</guid></item></channel></rss>