<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>LiquidAI</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mlabonne/882001725108546</link><description>LiquidAI open-sources a new generation of edge LLMs! 🥳 Based on a new hybrid architecture, these 350M, 700M, and 1.2B models are both fast and performant, ideal for on-device deployment. I recommend fine-tuning them to power your next edge application. We already provide Colab notebooks to guide you. More to come soon! 📝 Blog post: https://www.liquid.ai/blog/liquid-foundation-models-v2-our-second-series-of-generative-ai-models 🤗 Models: LiquidAI/lfm2-686d721927015b2ad73eaa38 See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mlabonne/882001725108546</guid></item><item><title>Since when are H200s on ZeroGPU?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/nroggendorff/580094805938772</link><description>Since when are H200s on ZeroGPU? See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/nroggendorff/580094805938772</guid></item><item><title>I am happy to announce that Ark now supports the following robots:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/hba123/547491071894207</link><description>I am happy to announce that Ark now supports the following robots: 1. Franka Panda 2. Kuka LWR 3. UFactory XArm 4. Husky Robot Everything is done in Python. You can even control your robot from a Jupiter notebook. Check out the tutorials: https://arkrobotics.notion.site/ARK-Home-22be053d9c6f8096bcdbefd6276aba61 Check out the code: https://github.com/orgs/Robotics-Ark/repositories Check out the documentation: https://robotics-ark.github.io/ark_robotics.github.io/docs/html/index.html Check out the paper: https://robotics-ark.github.io/ark_robotics.github.io/static/images/ark_framework_2025.pdf Hope you find it useful. Let us know if you want a specific feature! We would love to support you 😄 See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/hba123/547491071894207</guid></item><item><title>Kimi-K2 is now available on the hub🔥🚀</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/423045666935241</link><description>Kimi-K2 is now available on the hub🔥🚀 This is a trillion-parameter MoE model focused on long context, code, reasoning, and agentic behavior. moonshotai/kimi-k2-6871243b990f2af5ba60617d ✨ Base &amp; Instruct ✨ 1T total / 32B active - Modified MIT License ✨ 128K context length ✨ Muon optimizer for stable trillion-scale training See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/423045666935241</guid></item><item><title>✅ New Article on Hugging Face: Teaching AI to Think Like a System — Not a Toolkit</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/kanaria007/210554569109150</link><description>✅ New Article on Hugging Face: Teaching AI to Think Like a System — Not a Toolkit Title: 🏗️ Understanding Structured Cognitive Architecture: A Unified Framework for AI Reasoning Systems 🔗 Read it here: https://huggingface.co/blog/kanaria007/understanding-structured-cognitive-architecture Summary: After exploring how AI can select reasoning modes or learn from failure, this new article zooms out: *How do all these capabilities form a single mind, not just a menu of functions?* The **Structured Cognitive Architecture** defines a unified framework where protocols interact coherently — forming a self-organizing, reflective, and ethically grounded reasoning system. This architecture enables agents to: • Integrate memory, ethics, reasoning, and identity across layers • Select and execute reasoning jumps with traceable structure • Coordinate failure recovery and adaptive learning • Maintain cross-session identity and self-editing capability It’s not modular stacking. It’s **structured...</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/kanaria007/210554569109150</guid></item><item><title>MultiTalk (from MeiGen) Full Tutorial With 1-Click Installer - Make Talking and Singing Videos From Static Images - Moreover shows how to setup and use on RunPod and Massed Compute private cheap cloud services as well</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/753734380960763</link><description>MultiTalk (from MeiGen) Full Tutorial With 1-Click Installer - Make Talking and Singing Videos From Static Images - Moreover shows how to setup and use on RunPod and Massed Compute private cheap cloud services as well Tutorial video link &gt; https://youtu.be/8cMIwS9qo4M Video Chapters 0:00 Intro &amp; MultiTalk Showcase 0:28 Singing Animation Showcase 0:57 Tutorial Structure Overview (Windows, Massed Compute, RunPod) 1:10 Windows - Step 1: Download &amp; Extract the Main ZIP File 1:43 Windows - Prerequisites (Python, Git, CUDA, FFmpeg) 2:12 Windows - How to Perform a Fresh Installation (Deleting venv &amp; custom_nodes) 2:42 Windows - Step 2: Running the Main ComfyUI Installer Script 4:24 Windows - Step 3: Installing MultiTalk Nodes &amp; Dependencies 5:05 Windows - Step 4: Downloading Models with the Unified Downloader 6:18 Windows - Tip: Setting Custom Model Paths in ComfyUI 7:18 Windows - Step 5: Updating ComfyUI to the Latest Version 7:39 Windows - Step 6: Launching ComfyUI 7:53 Workflow Usage -...</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/753734380960763</guid></item><item><title>New Space: Generate Knowledge Graphs from input data using LLM's (OpenRouter). It's a trial project but seems to be working alright so far!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/CultriX/969512018114620</link><description>New Space: Generate Knowledge Graphs from input data using LLM's (OpenRouter). It's a trial project but seems to be working alright so far! CultriX/Generate-Knowledge-Graphs Below is an example after feeding it the wikipedia page about Elon Musk: See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/CultriX/969512018114620</guid></item><item><title>Test SmolLM3, the newest fully open model released by</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/321784447889589</link><description>Test SmolLM3, the newest fully open model released by @ HuggingFaceTB ! It's smol (3B), multilingual (6 languages), comes with dual mode reasoning (think/no_think modes) and supports long-context (128k). Try it now in the notebook below!! ⬇️ Colab notebook: https://colab.research.google.com/github/sergiopaniego/samples/blob/main/smollm3_3b_inference.ipynb notebook: https://github.com/sergiopaniego/samples/blob/main/smollm3_3b_inference.ipynb blog: https://huggingface.co/blog/smollm3 See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/321784447889589</guid></item><item><title>🚀 Announcing the Synthetic-to-Real Multi-Class Object Detection Challenge!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/3LC/827651059369427</link><description>🚀 Announcing the Synthetic-to-Real Multi-Class Object Detection Challenge! We’re excited to announce the launch of the Synthetic-to-Real Multi-Class Object Detection Challenge—now live on Kaggle! This exciting competition is brought to you by 3LC in partnership with Duality AI, creators of the powerful FalconCloud tool for generating targeted synthetic data. Together, we're offering a unique opportunity to push the boundaries of object detection through high-fidelity, simulation-to-real workflows. 🧪 What Makes This Challenge Special? 💻 Create customized training data with Duality’s cloud-based scenario 🧠 Analyze data weaknesses and take precise, data-driven actions using 3LC's robust tooling ⚙️ Optimize data for peak model training 🏆 Why Join? • Win cash prizes, certificates, and global recognition • Gain exposure to real-world simulation workflows used in top AI companies • Collaborate and compete with leading minds in computer vision, ML, and AI Whether you're a student,...</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/3LC/827651059369427</guid></item><item><title>📢 The Kaggle Synthetic-to-Real Object Detection Challenge is back, and it's a multi-class challenge 😎 !</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/395314150122330</link><description>📢 The Kaggle Synthetic-to-Real Object Detection Challenge is back, and it's a multi-class challenge 😎 ! 💵This time we made a harder, multi-class challenge and are offering a larger prize pool. Sign up here: https://www.kaggle.com/competitions/multi-class-object-detection-challenge 🤝 Duality AI is partnering in this competition with 3LC.AI, a cutting-edge platform which enables users to capture per sample metrics and take meaningful action leading to better, faster, and smaller AI models. Competitors will be challenged to: ✨ Create customized training data with Duality’s cloud-based scenario ✨Analyze data weaknesses and make calculated changes using 3LC’s robust software ✨Optimize data for peak model training Compete for prizes, certificates, and recognition from peer competitors around the world. Whether you’re a student, researcher, or industry pro, this challenge offers hands-on experience customizing high-fidelity synthetic data for robust models. Ready to bridge the Sim2Real...</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/395314150122330</guid></item></channel></rss>