<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Wan-Move: Motion-controllable Video Generation via Latent Trajectory Guidance</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08765</link><description>Wan-Move enhances motion control in video generative models by integrating motion-aware features into latent space, enabling high-quality and scalable video synthesis.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present Wan-Move, a simple and scalable framework that brings motion control to video generative models. Existing motion-controllable methods typically suffer from coarse control granularity and limited scalability, leaving their outputs insufficient for practical use. We narrow this gap by achieving precise and high-quality motion control. Our core idea is to directly make the original condition features motion-aware for guiding video synthesis. To this end, we first represent object motions with dense point trajectories, allowing fine-grained control over the scene. We then project these trajectories into latent space and propagate the first frame's features along each trajectory, producing an aligned spatiotemporal feature map that tells how each scene element should move. This feature map serves as the updated latent condition, which is naturally integrated into the off-the-shelf image-to-video model, e.g., Wan-I2V-14B, as motion guidance without any architecture change. It removes the need for auxiliary motion encoders and makes fine-tuning base models easily scalable. Through scaled training, Wan-Move generates 5-second, 480p videos whose motion controllability rivals Kling 1.5 Pro's commercial Motion Brush, as indicated by user studies. To support comprehensive evaluation, we further design MoveBench, a rigorously curated benchmark featuring diverse content categories and hybrid-verified annotations. It is distinguished by larger data volume, longer video durations, and high-quality motion annotations. Extensive experiments on MoveBench and the public dataset consistently show Wan-Move's superior motion quality. Code, models, and benchmark data are made publicly available.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:50:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08765</guid></item><item><title>Preserving Source Video Realism: High-Fidelity Face Swapping for Cinematic Quality</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07951</link><description>LivingSwap enhances video face swapping by using keyframes and reference guidance to maintain identity and fidelity over long sequences, reducing manual effort and achieving state-of-the-art results.  					AI-generated summary 				 Video face swapping is crucial in film and entertainment production, where achieving high fidelity and temporal consistency over long and complex video sequences remains a significant challenge. Inspired by recent advances in reference-guided image editing, we explore whether rich visual attributes from source videos can be similarly leveraged to enhance both fidelity and temporal coherence in video face swapping. Building on this insight, this work presents LivingSwap, the first video reference guided face swapping model. Our approach employs keyframes as conditioning signals to inject the target identity, enabling flexible and controllable editing. By combining keyframe conditioning with video reference guidance, the model performs temporal stitching to ensure stable identity preservation and high-fidelity reconstruction across long video sequences. To address the scarcity of data for reference-guided training, we construct a paired face-swapping dataset, Face2Face, and further reverse the data pairs to ensure reliable ground-truth supervision. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method achieves state-of-the-art results, seamlessly integrating the target identity with the source video's expressions, lighting, and motion, while significantly reducing manual effort in production workflows. Project webpage: https://aim-uofa.github.io/LivingSwap</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:29:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07951</guid></item><item><title>ThreadWeaver: Adaptive Threading for Efficient Parallel Reasoning in Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07843</link><description>ThreadWeaver, a framework for adaptive parallel reasoning, achieves accuracy comparable to sequential models while reducing inference latency through parallel trajectory generation, trie-based training-inference co-design, and parallelization-aware reinforcement learning.  					AI-generated summary 				 Scaling inference-time computation has enabled Large Language Models (LLMs) to achieve strong reasoning performance, but inherently sequential decoding leads to substantial latency, especially on complex tasks. Recent work on adaptive parallel reasoning aims to improve inference efficiency by decomposing the problem-solving process into concurrent reasoning threads when beneficial. However, existing methods on realistic tasks are either limited to supervised behavior cloning or exhibit significant accuracy drops compared to widely-used sequential long chain-of-thought (CoT) baselines. Moreover, many require customized inference engines, complicating deployment. We introduce ThreadWeaver, a framework for adaptive parallel reasoning that achieves accuracy on par with popular sequential reasoning models of comparable size while significantly reducing inference latency. ThreadWeaver's performance stems from three key innovations: 1) a two-stage parallel trajectory generator that produces large-scale, high-quality CoT data with parallel annotations for supervised fine-tuning; 2) a trie-based training-inference co-design that enables parallel reasoning on any off-the-shelf autoregressive inference engine without modifying position embeddings or KV caches; and 3) a parallelization-aware reinforcement learning framework that teaches the model to balance accuracy with effective parallelization. Across six challenging mathematical reasoning benchmarks, ThreadWeaver trained atop Qwen3-8B achieves accuracy comparable to cutting-edge sequential reasoning models (71.9% on average and 79.9% on AIME24) while delivering up to 1.53x average speedup in token latency, establishing a new Pareto frontier between accuracy and efficiency.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:44:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07843</guid></item><item><title>MIND-V: Hierarchical Video Generation for Long-Horizon Robotic Manipulation with RL-based Physical Alignment</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.06628</link><description>MIND-V generates long-horizon robotic manipulation videos by integrating semantic reasoning, domain-invariant representations, and physical plausibility through a hierarchical framework.  					AI-generated summary 				 Embodied imitation learning is constrained by the scarcity of diverse, long-horizon robotic manipulation data. Existing video generation models for this domain are limited to synthesizing short clips of simple actions and often rely on manually defined trajectories. To this end, we introduce MIND-V, a hierarchical framework designed to synthesize physically plausible and logically coherent videos of long-horizon robotic manipulation. Inspired by cognitive science, MIND-V bridges high-level reasoning with pixel-level synthesis through three core components: a Semantic Reasoning Hub (SRH) that leverages a pre-trained vision-language model for task planning; a Behavioral Semantic Bridge (BSB) that translates abstract instructions into domain-invariant representations; and a Motor Video Generator (MVG) for conditional video rendering. MIND-V employs Staged Visual Future Rollouts, a test-time optimization strategy to enhance long-horizon robustness. To align the generated videos with physical laws, we introduce a GRPO reinforcement learning post-training phase guided by a novel Physical Foresight Coherence (PFC) reward. PFC leverages the V-JEPA world model to enforce physical plausibility by aligning the predicted and actual dynamic evolutions in the feature space. MIND-V demonstrates state-of-the-art performance in long-horizon robotic manipulation video generation, establishing a scalable and controllable paradigm for embodied data synthesis.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:16:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.06628</guid></item><item><title>OneStory: Coherent Multi-Shot Video Generation with Adaptive Memory</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07802</link><description>OneStory generates coherent multi-shot videos by modeling global cross-shot context through a Frame Selection module and an Adaptive Conditioner, leveraging pretrained image-to-video models and a curated dataset.  					AI-generated summary 				 Storytelling in real-world videos often unfolds through multiple shots -- discontinuous yet semantically connected clips that together convey a coherent narrative. However, existing multi-shot video generation (MSV) methods struggle to effectively model long-range cross-shot context, as they rely on limited temporal windows or single keyframe conditioning, leading to degraded performance under complex narratives. In this work, we propose OneStory, enabling global yet compact cross-shot context modeling for consistent and scalable narrative generation. OneStory reformulates MSV as a next-shot generation task, enabling autoregressive shot synthesis while leveraging pretrained image-to-video (I2V) models for strong visual conditioning. We introduce two key modules: a Frame Selection module that constructs a semantically-relevant global memory based on informative frames from prior shots, and an Adaptive Conditioner that performs importance-guided patchification to generate compact context for direct conditioning. We further curate a high-quality multi-shot dataset with referential captions to mirror real-world storytelling patterns, and design effective training strategies under the next-shot paradigm. Finetuned from a pretrained I2V model on our curated 60K dataset, OneStory achieves state-of-the-art narrative coherence across diverse and complex scenes in both text- and image-conditioned settings, enabling controllable and immersive long-form video storytelling.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:36:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07802</guid></item><item><title>TreeGRPO: Tree-Advantage GRPO for Online RL Post-Training of Diffusion Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08153</link><description>TreeGRPO, a novel RL framework, enhances training efficiency for generative models by using a tree-structured denoising process, leading to faster training and better performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement learning (RL) post-training is crucial for aligning generative models with human preferences, but its prohibitive computational cost remains a major barrier to widespread adoption. We introduce TreeGRPO, a novel RL framework that dramatically improves training efficiency by recasting the denoising process as a search tree. From shared initial noise samples, TreeGRPO strategically branches to generate multiple candidate trajectories while efficiently reusing their common prefixes. This tree-structured approach delivers three key advantages: (1) High sample efficiency, achieving better performance under same training samples (2) Fine-grained credit assignment via reward backpropagation that computes step-specific advantages, overcoming the uniform credit assignment limitation of trajectory-based methods, and (3) Amortized computation where multi-child branching enables multiple policy updates per forward pass. Extensive experiments on both diffusion and flow-based models demonstrate that TreeGRPO achieves 2.4times faster training while establishing a superior Pareto frontier in the efficiency-reward trade-off space. Our method consistently outperforms GRPO baselines across multiple benchmarks and reward models, providing a scalable and effective pathway for RL-based visual generative model alignment. The project website is available at treegrpo.github.io.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:44:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08153</guid></item><item><title>From Next-Token to Next-Block: A Principled Adaptation Path for Diffusion LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.06776</link><description>Adapting autoregressive models to block-wise diffusion enables parallel generation and retains pretrained knowledge, achieving state-of-the-art performance among 7B-class diffusion language models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) excel at generation but dominant autoregressive (AR) decoding is inherently sequential, creating a throughput bottleneck. Diffusion Language Models (DLMs)--especially block-wise variants--enable parallel generation and intra-block bidirectional reasoning, yet training large DLMs from scratch is costly and wastes the knowledge in mature AR checkpoints. Prior "adaptation" attempts either modify logits or randomly grow attention masks to full-sequence diffusion, or simply transplant AR weights into a block-diffusion recipe, leaving a fundamental mismatch between AR causality and block-wise bidirectionality unaddressed. We reframe adaptation as a intra-paradigm path from AR to Block-Diffusion by viewing AR as Block-Diffusion with blocksize=1. Concretely, we design the pathway of adaptation as follows: we use a context-causal attention mask (causal in context, bidirectional only within the active block), an efficient parallel adaptation procedure, an auxiliary AR loss to maximize data utilization and retain pretrained knowledge, and gradual increment of the generation block size. The recipe integrates cleanly with masked block-diffusion and maintains train-inference consistency. Built on these components, NBDiff-7B (Base and Instruct) could inherit the long-context modeling and reasoning capabilities, and achieve state-of-the-art performance among the 7B-class DLMs, delivering strong gains on general-knowledge, math, and code benchmarks over strong baselines. These results demonstrate that principled AR-to-block-diffusion adaptation is an effective and compute-efficient alternative to training DLMs from scratch. Codes: https://github.com/YuchuanTian/NBDiff.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:50:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.06776</guid></item><item><title>EcomBench: Towards Holistic Evaluation of Foundation Agents in E-commerce</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08868</link><description>EcomBench is a benchmark that evaluates agent performance in real-world e-commerce environments through deep information retrieval, multi-step reasoning, and cross-source knowledge integration.  					AI-generated summary 				 Foundation agents have rapidly advanced in their ability to reason and interact with real environments, making the evaluation of their core capabilities increasingly important. While many benchmarks have been developed to assess agent performance, most concentrate on academic settings or artificially designed scenarios while overlooking the challenges that arise in real applications. To address this issue, we focus on a highly practical real-world setting, the e-commerce domain, which involves a large volume of diverse user interactions, dynamic market conditions, and tasks directly tied to real decision-making processes. To this end, we introduce EcomBench, a holistic E-commerce Benchmark designed to evaluate agent performance in realistic e-commerce environments. EcomBench is built from genuine user demands embedded in leading global e-commerce ecosystems and is carefully curated and annotated through human experts to ensure clarity, accuracy, and domain relevance. It covers multiple task categories within e-commerce scenarios and defines three difficulty levels that evaluate agents on key capabilities such as deep information retrieval, multi-step reasoning, and cross-source knowledge integration. By grounding evaluation in real e-commerce contexts, EcomBench provides a rigorous and dynamic testbed for measuring the practical capabilities of agents in modern e-commerce.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:10:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08868</guid></item><item><title>Modular Neural Image Signal Processing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08564</link><description>A modular neural ISP framework provides high rendering accuracy, scalability, and flexibility for diverse photo-editing operations with competitive results.  					AI-generated summary 				 This paper presents a modular neural image signal processing (ISP) framework that processes raw inputs and renders high-quality display-referred images. Unlike prior neural ISP designs, our method introduces a high degree of modularity, providing full control over multiple intermediate stages of the rendering process.~This modular design not only achieves high rendering accuracy but also improves scalability, debuggability, generalization to unseen cameras, and flexibility to match different user-preference styles. To demonstrate the advantages of this design, we built a user-interactive photo-editing tool that leverages our neural ISP to support diverse editing operations and picture styles. The tool is carefully engineered to take advantage of the high-quality rendering of our neural ISP and to enable unlimited post-editable re-rendering. Our method is a fully learning-based framework with variants of different capacities, all of moderate size (ranging from ~0.5 M to ~3.9 M parameters for the entire pipeline), and consistently delivers competitive qualitative and quantitative results across multiple test sets. Watch the supplemental video at: https://youtu.be/ByhQjQSjxVM</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:59:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08564</guid></item><item><title>Ground Slow, Move Fast: A Dual-System Foundation Model for Generalizable Vision-and-Language Navigation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08186</link><description>DualVLN integrates high-level reasoning and low-level action execution to improve vision-language navigation in dynamic environments, achieving robust real-time control and long-horizon planning.  					AI-generated summary 				 While recent large vision-language models (VLMs) have improved generalization in vision-language navigation (VLN), existing methods typically rely on end-to-end pipelines that map vision-language inputs directly to short-horizon discrete actions. Such designs often produce fragmented motions, incur high latency, and struggle with real-world challenges like dynamic obstacle avoidance. We propose DualVLN, the first dual-system VLN foundation model that synergistically integrates high-level reasoning with low-level action execution. System 2, a VLM-based global planner, "grounds slowly" by predicting mid-term waypoint goals via image-grounded reasoning. System 1, a lightweight, multi-modal conditioning Diffusion Transformer policy, "moves fast" by leveraging both explicit pixel goals and latent features from System 2 to generate smooth and accurate trajectories. The dual-system design enables robust real-time control and adaptive local decision-making in complex, dynamic environments. By decoupling training, the VLM retains its generalization, while System 1 achieves interpretable and effective local navigation. DualVLN outperforms prior methods across all VLN benchmarks and real-world experiments demonstrate robust long-horizon planning and real-time adaptability in dynamic environments.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:21:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08186</guid></item><item><title>DeepCode: Open Agentic Coding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07921</link><description>DeepCode, a fully autonomous framework, addresses the challenges of document-to-codebase synthesis by optimizing information flow through source compression, structured indexing, knowledge injection, and error correction, achieving state-of-the-art performance and surpassing human experts.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have given rise to powerful coding agents, making it possible for code assistants to evolve into code engineers. However, existing methods still face significant challenges in achieving high-fidelity document-to-codebase synthesis--such as scientific papers to code--primarily due to a fundamental conflict between information overload and the context bottlenecks of LLMs. In this work, we introduce DeepCode, a fully autonomous framework that fundamentally addresses this challenge through principled information-flow management. By treating repository synthesis as a channel optimization problem, DeepCode seamlessly orchestrates four information operations to maximize task-relevant signals under finite context budgets: source compression via blueprint distillation, structured indexing using stateful code memory, conditional knowledge injection via retrieval-augmented generation, and closed-loop error correction. Extensive evaluations on the PaperBench benchmark demonstrate that DeepCode achieves state-of-the-art performance, decisively outperforming leading commercial agents such as Cursor and Claude Code, and crucially, surpassing PhD-level human experts from top institutes on key reproduction metrics. By systematically transforming paper specifications into production-grade implementations comparable to human expert quality, this work establishes new foundations for autonomous scientific reproduction that can accelerate research evaluation and discovery.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:18:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07921</guid></item><item><title>TrackingWorld: World-centric Monocular 3D Tracking of Almost All Pixels</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08358</link><description>TrackingWorld provides dense 3D tracking of pixels in a world-centric coordinate system by upsampling sparse 2D tracks and optimizing camera poses and 3D coordinates.  					AI-generated summary 				 Monocular 3D tracking aims to capture the long-term motion of pixels in 3D space from a single monocular video and has witnessed rapid progress in recent years. However, we argue that the existing monocular 3D tracking methods still fall short in separating the camera motion from foreground dynamic motion and cannot densely track newly emerging dynamic subjects in the videos. To address these two limitations, we propose TrackingWorld, a novel pipeline for dense 3D tracking of almost all pixels within a world-centric 3D coordinate system. First, we introduce a tracking upsampler that efficiently lifts the arbitrary sparse 2D tracks into dense 2D tracks. Then, to generalize the current tracking methods to newly emerging objects, we apply the upsampler to all frames and reduce the redundancy of 2D tracks by eliminating the tracks in overlapped regions. Finally, we present an efficient optimization-based framework to back-project dense 2D tracks into world-centric 3D trajectories by estimating the camera poses and the 3D coordinates of these 2D tracks. Extensive evaluations on both synthetic and real-world datasets demonstrate that our system achieves accurate and dense 3D tracking in a world-centric coordinate frame.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:55:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08358</guid></item><item><title>Same Content, Different Answers: Cross-Modal Inconsistency in MLLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08923</link><description>Two new benchmarks assess cross-modal inconsistency in multimodal large language models, showing significant variability and impact of visual characteristics on performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce two new benchmarks REST and REST+(Render-Equivalence Stress Tests) to enable systematic evaluation of cross-modal inconsistency in multimodal large language models (MLLMs). MLLMs are trained to represent vision and language in the same embedding space, yet they cannot perform the same tasks in both modalities. Our benchmarks contain samples with the same semantic information in three modalities (image, text, mixed) and we show that state-of-the-art MLLMs cannot consistently reason over these different modalities. We evaluate 15 MLLMs and find that the degree of modality inconsistency varies substantially, even when accounting for problems with text recognition (OCR). Neither rendering text as image nor rendering an image as text solves the inconsistency. Even if OCR is correct, we find that visual characteristics (text colour and resolution, but not font) and the number of vision tokens have an impact on model performance. Finally, we find that our consistency score correlates with the modality gap between text and images, highlighting a mechanistic interpretation of cross-modal inconsistent MLLMs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:51:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.08923</guid></item><item><title>Predicting Time-Dependent Flow Over Complex Geometries Using Operator Networks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.04434</link><description>A geometry-aware Deep Operator Network encodes shape and flow history to predict velocity fields for unsteady flows, achieving significant speedup over CFD simulations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Fast, geometry-generalizing surrogates for unsteady flow remain challenging. We present a time-dependent, geometry-aware Deep Operator Network that predicts velocity fields for moderate-Re flows around parametric and non-parametric shapes. The model encodes geometry via a signed distance field (SDF) trunk and flow history via a CNN branch, trained on 841 high-fidelity simulations. On held-out shapes, it attains sim 5% relative L2 single-step error and up to 1000X speedups over CFD. We provide physics-centric rollout diagnostics, including phase error at probes and divergence norms, to quantify long-horizon fidelity. These reveal accurate near-term transients but error accumulation in fine-scale wakes, most pronounced for sharp-cornered geometries. We analyze failure modes and outline practical mitigations. Code, splits, and scripts are openly released at: https://github.com/baskargroup/TimeDependent-DeepONet to support reproducibility and benchmarking.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:57:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.04434</guid></item></channel></rss>