<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Say hello to my little friends! I just unboxed this trio of HP Z2 G1a!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mitkox/390180686171042</link><description>Say hello to my little friends! I just unboxed this trio of HP Z2 G1a! Three is always better than one! 3x AMD Ryzen AI Max+ Pro 395 384GB RAM 24TB of RAID storage Ubuntu 24.04 ROCm 7.0.2 llama cpp, vLLM and Aibrix Small, cheap GPUs are about to become the Raspberry Pi of edge AI inference. Sprinkle some kubectl fairy dust on top, and suddenly it's a high-availability, self-healing, cloud-native, enterprise-grade AI cluster camping in a closet. Make sure you own your AI. AI in the cloud is not aligned with you; it’s aligned with the company that owns it. See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mitkox/390180686171042</guid></item><item><title>🤗 Sentence Transformers is joining Hugging Face! 🤗 This formalizes the existing maintenance structure, as I've personally led the project for the past two years on behalf of Hugging Face! Details:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/tomaarsen/527498981313495</link><description>🤗 Sentence Transformers is joining Hugging Face! 🤗 This formalizes the existing maintenance structure, as I've personally led the project for the past two years on behalf of Hugging Face! Details: Today, the Ubiquitous Knowledge Processing (UKP) Lab is transferring the project to Hugging Face. Sentence Transformers will remain a community-driven, open-source project, with the same open-source license (Apache 2.0) as before. Contributions from researchers, developers, and enthusiasts are welcome and encouraged. The project will continue to prioritize transparency, collaboration, and broad accessibility. Read our full announcement for more details and quotes from UKP and Hugging Face leadership: https://huggingface.co/blog/sentence-transformers-joins-hf We see an increasing wish from companies to move from large LLM APIs to local models for better control and privacy, reflected in the library's growth: in just the last 30 days, Sentence Transformer models have been downloaded &gt;270...</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/tomaarsen/527498981313495</guid></item><item><title>We've built over 10K containerized reproductions of papers from arXiv!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/salma-remyx/787120125285076</link><description>We've built over 10K containerized reproductions of papers from arXiv! Instead of spending all day trying to build an environment to test that new idea, just pull the Docker container from the Remyx registry. And with Remyx, you can start experimenting faster by generating a test PR in your codebase based on the ideas found in your paper of choice. Hub: https://hub.docker.com/u/remyxai Remyx docs: https://docs.remyx.ai/resources/ideate Coming soon, explore reproduced papers with AG2 + Remyx: https://github.com/ag2ai/ag2/pull/2141 See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/salma-remyx/787120125285076</guid></item><item><title>Is it hot in here, or is it just me?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/nroggendorff/194600363127405</link><description>Is it hot in here, or is it just me? See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/nroggendorff/194600363127405</guid></item><item><title>Meet OpenEnv 👋, an open ecosystem of environments for intelligent agents. Build, share, and test agents safely and consistently.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/527159223589050</link><description>Meet OpenEnv 👋, an open ecosystem of environments for intelligent agents. Build, share, and test agents safely and consistently. Ideal for training with TRL (we include examples🤓), deployment, and community collaboration via the HF Hub Blog: https://huggingface.co/blog/openenv Hub for Environments: openenv OpenEnv repo: https://github.com/meta-pytorch/OpenEnv Try it out using TRL: https://huggingface.co/docs/trl/main/en/openenv See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/527159223589050</guid></item><item><title>Which is the best model to use as a signal for investment?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/SelmaNajih001/829546518885653</link><description>Which is the best model to use as a signal for investment? Here who is gaining the most: SelmaNajih001/InvestmentStrategyBasedOnSentiment The Space uses titles from this dataset: 📊 SelmaNajih001/Cnbc_MultiCompany Given a news title, it calculates a sentiment score : if the score crosses a certain threshold, the strategy decides to buy or sell. Each trade lasts one day, and the strategy then computes the daily return. For Tesla the best model seems to be the regression 👀 Just a quick note: the model uses the closing price as the buy price, meaning it already reflects the impact of the news. See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/SelmaNajih001/829546518885653</guid></item><item><title>Hello from PyTorch Conference 2025! 👋</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sondhiArm/743734106671454</link><description>Hello from PyTorch Conference 2025! 👋 The energy is high, and we’re excited to connect with the community to showcase how developers can build high-performance GenAI applications across cloud, mobile, and edge using PyTorch and ExecuTorch. Visit us at Booth #P1 to explore hands-on demos, join a one-on-one workshop, or catch one of our insightful sessions throughout the day. https://developer.arm.com/developer-partners/pytorch See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sondhiArm/743734106671454</guid></item><item><title>I’m just reading that Ryzen AI 395 has to be 30% slower than DGX Spark in LLM inferencing… and only 96GB GPU RAM… good I haven’t RTFM upfront, so I made the AMD faster with 128GB unified RAM 🫡</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mitkox/949505421454376</link><description>I’m just reading that Ryzen AI 395 has to be 30% slower than DGX Spark in LLM inferencing… and only 96GB GPU RAM… good I haven’t RTFM upfront, so I made the AMD faster with 128GB unified RAM 🫡 Z2 mini G1a can run Qwen3 Coder 30B BF16 at 26.8 tok/sec in ~60GB GPU RAM See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mitkox/949505421454376</guid></item><item><title>How Financial News Can Be Used to Train Good Financial Models 📰</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/SelmaNajih001/973945902491280</link><description>How Financial News Can Be Used to Train Good Financial Models 📰 Numbers tell you what happened, but news tells you why. I’ve written an article explaining how news can be used to train AI models for sentiment analysis and better forecasting. Hope you find it interesting! Read it here: https://huggingface.co/blog/SelmaNajih001/llms-applied-to-finance I would love to read your opinions! I’m open to suggestions on how to improve the methodology and the training See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/SelmaNajih001/973945902491280</guid></item><item><title>We’re preparing an in-depth review of the Feetech STS-3250 servo motor — exploring its performance, features. One of the top serial bus servo for hobby robotics compatible with SO-ARM 100 manipulator.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/branikita/215658672762252</link><description>We’re preparing an in-depth review of the Feetech STS-3250 servo motor — exploring its performance, features. One of the top serial bus servo for hobby robotics compatible with SO-ARM 100 manipulator. See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:18:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/branikita/215658672762252</guid></item></channel></rss>