<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Bielik v3 Small: Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.02550</link><description>We introduce Bielik v3, a series of parameter-efficient generative text models (1.5B and 4.5B) optimized for Polish language processing. These models demonstrate that smaller, well-optimized architectures can achieve performance comparable to much larger counterparts while requiring substantially fewer computational resources. Our approach incorporates several key innovations: a custom Polish tokenizer (APT4) that significantly improves token efficiency, Weighted Instruction Cross-Entropy Loss to balance learning across instruction types, and Adaptive Learning Rate that dynamically adjusts based on training progress. Trained on a meticulously curated corpus of 292 billion tokens spanning 303 million documents, these models excel across multiple benchmarks, including the Open PL LLM Leaderboard, Complex Polish Text Understanding Benchmark, Polish EQ-Bench, and Polish Medical Leaderboard. The 4.5B parameter model achieves results competitive with models 2-3 times its size, while the 1.5B model delivers strong performance despite its extremely compact profile. These advances establish new benchmarks for parameter-efficient language modeling in less-represented languages, making high-quality Polish language AI more accessible for resource-constrained applications.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 08:56:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.02550</guid></item><item><title>Bielik 11B v2 Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.02410</link><description>We present Bielik 11B v2, a state-of-the-art language model optimized for Polish text processing. Built on the Mistral 7B v0.2 architecture and scaled to 11B parameters using depth up-scaling, this model demonstrates exceptional performance across Polish language benchmarks while maintaining strong cross-lingual capabilities. We introduce two key technical innovations: Weighted Instruction Cross-Entropy Loss, which optimizes learning across diverse instruction types by assigning quality-based weights to training examples, and Adaptive Learning Rate, which dynamically adjusts based on context length. Comprehensive evaluation across multiple benchmarks demonstrates that Bielik 11B v2 outperforms many larger models, including those with 2-6 times more parameters, and significantly surpasses other specialized Polish language models on tasks ranging from linguistic understanding to complex reasoning. The model's parameter efficiency and extensive quantization options enable deployment across various hardware configurations, advancing Polish language AI capabilities and establishing new benchmarks for resource-efficient language modeling in less-represented languages.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 08:55:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.02410</guid></item><item><title>UniVLA: Learning to Act Anywhere with Task-centric Latent Actions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.06111</link><description>A generalist robot should perform effectively across various environments. However, most existing approaches heavily rely on scaling action-annotated data to enhance their capabilities. Consequently, they are often limited to single physical specification and struggle to learn transferable knowledge across different embodiments and environments. To confront these limitations, we propose UniVLA, a new framework for learning cross-embodiment vision-language-action (VLA) policies. Our key innovation is to derive task-centric action representations from videos with a latent action model. This enables us to exploit extensive data across a wide spectrum of embodiments and perspectives. To mitigate the effect of task-irrelevant dynamics, we incorporate language instructions and establish a latent action model within the DINO feature space. Learned from internet-scale videos, the generalist policy can be deployed to various robots through efficient latent action decoding. We obtain state-of-the-art results across multiple manipulation and navigation benchmarks, as well as real-robot deployments. UniVLA achieves superior performance over OpenVLA with less than 1/20 of pretraining compute and 1/10 of downstream data. Continuous performance improvements are observed as heterogeneous data, even including human videos, are incorporated into the training pipeline. The results underscore UniVLA's potential to facilitate scalable and efficient robot policy learning.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 06:00:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.06111</guid></item><item><title>G-FOCUS: Towards a Robust Method for Assessing UI Design Persuasiveness</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.05026</link><description>Evaluating user interface (UI) design effectiveness extends beyond aesthetics to influencing user behavior, a principle central to Design Persuasiveness. A/B testing is the predominant method for determining which UI variations drive higher user engagement, but it is costly and time-consuming. While recent Vision-Language Models (VLMs) can process automated UI analysis, current approaches focus on isolated design attributes rather than comparative persuasiveness-the key factor in optimizing user interactions. To address this, we introduce WiserUI-Bench, a benchmark designed for Pairwise UI Design Persuasiveness Assessment task, featuring 300 real-world UI image pairs labeled with A/B test results and expert rationales. Additionally, we propose G-FOCUS, a novel inference-time reasoning strategy that enhances VLM-based persuasiveness assessment by reducing position bias and improving evaluation accuracy. Experimental results show that G-FOCUS surpasses existing inference strategies in consistency and accuracy for pairwise UI evaluation. Through promoting VLM-driven evaluation of UI persuasiveness, our work offers an approach to complement A/B testing, propelling progress in scalable UI preference modeling and design optimization. Code and data will be released publicly.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 07:03:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.05026</guid></item><item><title>Sailing AI by the Stars: A Survey of Learning from Rewards in
  Post-Training and Test-Time Scaling of Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.02686</link><description>Recent developments in Large Language Models (LLMs) have shifted from pre-training scaling to post-training and test-time scaling. Across these developments, a key unified paradigm has arisen: Learning from Rewards, where reward signals act as the guiding stars to steer LLM behavior. It has underpinned a wide range of prevalent techniques, such as reinforcement learning (in RLHF, DPO, and GRPO), reward-guided decoding, and post-hoc correction. Crucially, this paradigm enables the transition from passive learning from static data to active learning from dynamic feedback. This endows LLMs with aligned preferences and deep reasoning capabilities. In this survey, we present a comprehensive overview of the paradigm of learning from rewards. We categorize and analyze the strategies under this paradigm across training, inference, and post-inference stages. We further discuss the benchmarks for reward models and the primary applications. Finally we highlight the challenges and future directions. We maintain a paper collection at https://github.com/bobxwu/learning-from-rewards-llm-papers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 08:11:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.02686</guid></item><item><title>Healthy LLMs? Benchmarking LLM Knowledge of UK Government Public Health
  Information</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.06046</link><description>As Large Language Models (LLMs) become widely accessible, a detailed understanding of their knowledge within specific domains becomes necessary for successful real world use. This is particularly critical in public health, where failure to retrieve relevant, accurate, and current information could significantly impact UK residents. However, currently little is known about LLM knowledge of UK Government public health information. To address this issue, this paper introduces a new benchmark, PubHealthBench, with over 8000 questions for evaluating LLMs' Multiple Choice Question Answering (MCQA) and free form responses to public health queries, created via an automated pipeline. We also release a new dataset of the extracted UK Government public health guidance documents used as source text for PubHealthBench. Assessing 24 LLMs on PubHealthBench we find the latest private LLMs (GPT-4.5, GPT-4.1 and o1) have a high degree of knowledge, achieving &gt;90% in the MCQA setup, and outperform humans with cursory search engine use. However, in the free form setup we see lower performance with no model scoring &gt;75%. Therefore, whilst there are promising signs that state of the art (SOTA) LLMs are an increasingly accurate source of public health information, additional safeguards or tools may still be needed when providing free form responses on public health topics.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 08:55:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.06046</guid></item><item><title>A Preliminary Study for GPT-4o on Image Restoration</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.05621</link><description>OpenAI's GPT-4o model, integrating multi-modal inputs and outputs within an autoregressive architecture, has demonstrated unprecedented performance in image generation. In this work, we investigate its potential impact on the image restoration community. We present the first systematic evaluation of GPT-4o across diverse restoration tasks. Our experiments reveal that, although restoration outputs from GPT-4o are visually appealing, they often suffer from pixel-level structural fidelity when compared to ground-truth images. Common issues are variations in image proportions, shifts in object positions and quantities, and changes in viewpoint.To address it, taking image dehazing, derainning, and low-light enhancement as representative case studies, we show that GPT-4o's outputs can serve as powerful visual priors, substantially enhancing the performance of existing dehazing networks. It offers practical guidelines and a baseline framework to facilitate the integration of GPT-4o into future image restoration pipelines. We hope the study on GPT-4o image restoration will accelerate innovation in the broader field of image generation areas. To support further research, we will release GPT-4o-restored images from over 10 widely used image restoration datasets.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 11:23:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.05621</guid></item></channel></rss>