<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>DDT: Decoupled Diffusion Transformer</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.05741</link><description>Diffusion transformers have demonstrated remarkable generation quality, albeit requiring longer training iterations and numerous inference steps. In each denoising step, diffusion transformers encode the noisy inputs to extract the lower-frequency semantic component and then decode the higher frequency with identical modules. This scheme creates an inherent optimization dilemma: encoding low-frequency semantics necessitates reducing high-frequency components, creating tension between semantic encoding and high-frequency decoding. To resolve this challenge, we propose a new \color{ddtD}ecoupled \color{ddtD}iffusion \color{ddtT}ransformer~(\color{ddtDDT}), with a decoupled design of a dedicated condition encoder for semantic extraction alongside a specialized velocity decoder. Our experiments reveal that a more substantial encoder yields performance improvements as model size increases. For ImageNet 256times256, Our DDT-XL/2 achieves a new state-of-the-art performance of {1.31 FID}~(nearly 4times faster training convergence compared to previous diffusion transformers). For ImageNet 512times512, Our DDT-XL/2 achieves a new state-of-the-art FID of 1.28. Additionally, as a beneficial by-product, our decoupled architecture enhances inference speed by enabling the sharing self-condition between adjacent denoising steps. To minimize performance degradation, we propose a novel statistical dynamic programming approach to identify optimal sharing strategies.</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 02:10:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.05741</guid></item><item><title>GenDoP: Auto-regressive Camera Trajectory Generation as a Director of
  Photography</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.07083</link><description>Camera trajectory design plays a crucial role in video production, serving as a fundamental tool for conveying directorial intent and enhancing visual storytelling. In cinematography, Directors of Photography meticulously craft camera movements to achieve expressive and intentional framing. However, existing methods for camera trajectory generation remain limited: Traditional approaches rely on geometric optimization or handcrafted procedural systems, while recent learning-based methods often inherit structural biases or lack textual alignment, constraining creative synthesis. In this work, we introduce an auto-regressive model inspired by the expertise of Directors of Photography to generate artistic and expressive camera trajectories. We first introduce DataDoP, a large-scale multi-modal dataset containing 29K real-world shots with free-moving camera trajectories, depth maps, and detailed captions in specific movements, interaction with the scene, and directorial intent. Thanks to the comprehensive and diverse database, we further train an auto-regressive, decoder-only Transformer for high-quality, context-aware camera movement generation based on text guidance and RGBD inputs, named GenDoP. Extensive experiments demonstrate that compared to existing methods, GenDoP offers better controllability, finer-grained trajectory adjustments, and higher motion stability. We believe our approach establishes a new standard for learning-based cinematography, paving the way for future advancements in camera control and filmmaking. Our project website: https://kszpxxzmc.github.io/GenDoP/.</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 02:43:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.07083</guid></item><item><title>Missing Premise exacerbates Overthinking: Are Reasoning Models losing
  Critical Thinking Skill?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.06514</link><description>We find that the response length of reasoning LLMs, whether trained by reinforcement learning or supervised learning, drastically increases for ill-posed questions with missing premises (MiP), ending up with redundant and ineffective thinking. This newly introduced scenario exacerbates the general overthinking issue to a large extent, which we name as the MiP-Overthinking. Such failures are against the ``test-time scaling law'' but have been widely observed on multiple datasets we curated with MiP, indicating the harm of cheap overthinking and a lack of critical thinking. Surprisingly, LLMs not specifically trained for reasoning exhibit much better performance on the MiP scenario, producing much shorter responses that quickly identify ill-posed queries. This implies a critical flaw of the current training recipe for reasoning LLMs, which does not encourage efficient thinking adequately, leading to the abuse of thinking patterns. To further investigate the reasons behind such failures, we conduct fine-grained analyses of the reasoning length, overthinking patterns, and location of critical thinking on different types of LLMs. Moreover, our extended ablation study reveals that the overthinking is contagious through the distillation of reasoning models' responses. These results improve the understanding of overthinking and shed novel insights into mitigating the problem.</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 02:37:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.06514</guid></item><item><title>OLMoTrace: Tracing Language Model Outputs Back to Trillions of Training
  Tokens</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.07096</link><description>We present OLMoTrace, the first system that traces the outputs of language models back to their full, multi-trillion-token training data in real time. OLMoTrace finds and shows verbatim matches between segments of language model output and documents in the training text corpora. Powered by an extended version of infini-gram (Liu et al., 2024), our system returns tracing results within a few seconds. OLMoTrace can help users understand the behavior of language models through the lens of their training data. We showcase how it can be used to explore fact checking, hallucination, and the creativity of language models. OLMoTrace is publicly available and fully open-source.</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 02:24:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.07096</guid></item><item><title>FantasyTalking: Realistic Talking Portrait Generation via Coherent
  Motion Synthesis</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.04842</link><description>Creating a realistic animatable avatar from a single static portrait remains challenging. Existing approaches often struggle to capture subtle facial expressions, the associated global body movements, and the dynamic background. To address these limitations, we propose a novel framework that leverages a pretrained video diffusion transformer model to generate high-fidelity, coherent talking portraits with controllable motion dynamics. At the core of our work is a dual-stage audio-visual alignment strategy. In the first stage, we employ a clip-level training scheme to establish coherent global motion by aligning audio-driven dynamics across the entire scene, including the reference portrait, contextual objects, and background. In the second stage, we refine lip movements at the frame level using a lip-tracing mask, ensuring precise synchronization with audio signals. To preserve identity without compromising motion flexibility, we replace the commonly used reference network with a facial-focused cross-attention module that effectively maintains facial consistency throughout the video. Furthermore, we integrate a motion intensity modulation module that explicitly controls expression and body motion intensity, enabling controllable manipulation of portrait movements beyond mere lip motion. Extensive experimental results show that our proposed approach achieves higher quality with better realism, coherence, motion intensity, and identity preservation. Ours project page: https://fantasy-amap.github.io/fantasy-talking/.</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 02:28:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.04842</guid></item></channel></rss>