<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Shifting AI Efficiency From Model-Centric to Data-Centric Compression</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19147</link><description>The focus in AI research is shifting from model-centric to data-centric compression, with token compression identified as key to improving efficiency in handling long-context scenarios.  					AI-generated summary 				 The rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) and multi-modal LLMs (MLLMs) has historically relied on model-centric scaling through increasing parameter counts from millions to hundreds of billions to drive performance gains. However, as we approach hardware limits on model size, the dominant computational bottleneck has fundamentally shifted to the quadratic cost of self-attention over long token sequences, now driven by ultra-long text contexts, high-resolution images, and extended videos. In this position paper, we argue that the focus of research for efficient AI is shifting from model-centric compression to data-centric compression. We position token compression as the new frontier, which improves AI efficiency via reducing the number of tokens during model training or inference. Through comprehensive analysis, we first examine recent developments in long-context AI across various domains and establish a unified mathematical framework for existing model efficiency strategies, demonstrating why token compression represents a crucial paradigm shift in addressing long-context overhead. Subsequently, we systematically review the research landscape of token compression, analyzing its fundamental benefits and identifying its compelling advantages across diverse scenarios. Furthermore, we provide an in-depth analysis of current challenges in token compression research and outline promising future directions. Ultimately, our work aims to offer a fresh perspective on AI efficiency, synthesize existing research, and catalyze innovative developments to address the challenges that increasing context lengths pose to the AI community's advancement.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:36:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19147</guid></item><item><title>ARM: Adaptive Reasoning Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20258</link><description>Adaptive Reasoning Model (ARM) uses Ada-GRPO to reduce token usage and improve efficiency across different reasoning modes.  					AI-generated summary 				 While large reasoning models demonstrate strong performance on complex tasks, they lack the ability to adjust reasoning token usage based on task difficulty. This often leads to the "overthinking" problem -- excessive and unnecessary reasoning -- which, although potentially mitigated by human intervention to control the token budget, still fundamentally contradicts the goal of achieving fully autonomous AI. In this work, we propose Adaptive Reasoning Model (ARM), a reasoning model capable of adaptively selecting appropriate reasoning formats based on the task at hand. These formats include three efficient ones -- Direct Answer, Short CoT, and Code -- as well as a more elaborate format, Long CoT. To train ARM, we introduce Ada-GRPO, an adaptation of Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO), which addresses the format collapse issue in traditional GRPO. Ada-GRPO enables ARM to achieve high token efficiency, reducing tokens by an average of 30%, and up to 70%, while maintaining performance comparable to the model that relies solely on Long CoT. Furthermore, not only does it improve inference efficiency through reduced token generation, but it also brings a 2x speedup in training. In addition to the default Adaptive Mode, ARM supports two additional reasoning modes: 1) Instruction-Guided Mode, which allows users to explicitly specify the reasoning format via special tokens -- ideal when the appropriate format is known for a batch of tasks. 2) Consensus-Guided Mode, which aggregates the outputs of the three efficient formats and resorts to Long CoT in case of disagreement, prioritizing performance with higher token usage.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:14:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20258</guid></item><item><title>Embodied Agents Meet Personalization: Exploring Memory Utilization for
  Personalized Assistance</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.16348</link><description>MEMENTO evaluates personalized memory utilization in embodied agents, revealing limitations in understanding user semantics and routines.  					AI-generated summary 				 Embodied agents empowered by large language models (LLMs) have shown strong performance in household object rearrangement tasks. However, these tasks primarily focus on single-turn interactions with simplified instructions, which do not truly reflect the challenges of providing meaningful assistance to users. To provide personalized assistance, embodied agents must understand the unique semantics that users assign to the physical world (e.g., favorite cup, breakfast routine) by leveraging prior interaction history to interpret dynamic, real-world instructions. Yet, the effectiveness of embodied agents in utilizing memory for personalized assistance remains largely underexplored. To address this gap, we present MEMENTO, a personalized embodied agent evaluation framework designed to comprehensively assess memory utilization capabilities to provide personalized assistance. Our framework consists of a two-stage memory evaluation process design that enables quantifying the impact of memory utilization on task performance. This process enables the evaluation of agents' understanding of personalized knowledge in object rearrangement tasks by focusing on its role in goal interpretation: (1) the ability to identify target objects based on personal meaning (object semantics), and (2) the ability to infer object-location configurations from consistent user patterns, such as routines (user patterns). Our experiments across various LLMs reveal significant limitations in memory utilization, with even frontier models like GPT-4o experiencing a 30.5% performance drop when required to reference multiple memories, particularly in tasks involving user patterns. These findings, along with our detailed analyses and case studies, provide valuable insights for future research in developing more effective personalized embodied agents. Project website: https://connoriginal.github.io/MEMENTO</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:50:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.16348</guid></item><item><title>Lifelong Safety Alignment for Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20259</link><description>A lifecycle safety alignment framework employs a Meta-Attacker and Defender to adapt LLMs to novel jailbreaking strategies, improving robustness in deployment.  					AI-generated summary 				 LLMs have made impressive progress, but their growing capabilities also expose them to highly flexible jailbreaking attacks designed to bypass safety alignment. While many existing defenses focus on known types of attacks, it is more critical to prepare LLMs for unseen attacks that may arise during deployment. To address this, we propose a lifelong safety alignment framework that enables LLMs to continuously adapt to new and evolving jailbreaking strategies. Our framework introduces a competitive setup between two components: a Meta-Attacker, trained to actively discover novel jailbreaking strategies, and a Defender, trained to resist them. To effectively warm up the Meta-Attacker, we first leverage the GPT-4o API to extract key insights from a large collection of jailbreak-related research papers. Through iterative training, the first iteration Meta-Attacker achieves a 73% attack success rate (ASR) on RR and a 57% transfer ASR on LAT using only single-turn attacks. Meanwhile, the Defender progressively improves its robustness and ultimately reduces the Meta-Attacker's success rate to just 7%, enabling safer and more reliable deployment of LLMs in open-ended environments. The code is available at https://github.com/sail-sg/LifelongSafetyAlignment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:43:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20259</guid></item><item><title>Enigmata: Scaling Logical Reasoning in Large Language Models with
  Synthetic Verifiable Puzzles</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19914</link><description>Enigmata is a comprehensive suite for improving LLMs in puzzle reasoning through scalable multi-task RL training, leading to better performance on benchmarks and advanced math tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Models (LLMs), such as OpenAI's o1 and DeepSeek's R1, excel at advanced reasoning tasks like math and coding via Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR), but still struggle with puzzles solvable by humans without domain knowledge. We introduce Enigmata, the first comprehensive suite tailored for improving LLMs with puzzle reasoning skills. It includes 36 tasks across seven categories, each with 1) a generator that produces unlimited examples with controllable difficulty and 2) a rule-based verifier for automatic evaluation. This generator-verifier design supports scalable, multi-task RL training, fine-grained analysis, and seamless RLVR integration. We further propose Enigmata-Eval, a rigorous benchmark, and develop optimized multi-task RLVR strategies. Our trained model, Qwen2.5-32B-Enigmata, consistently surpasses o3-mini-high and o1 on the puzzle reasoning benchmarks like Enigmata-Eval, ARC-AGI (32.8%), and ARC-AGI 2 (0.6%). It also generalizes well to out-of-domain puzzle benchmarks and mathematical reasoning, with little multi-tasking trade-off. When trained on larger models like Seed1.5-Thinking (20B activated parameters and 200B total parameters), puzzle data from Enigmata further boosts SoTA performance on advanced math and STEM reasoning tasks such as AIME (2024-2025), BeyondAIME and GPQA (Diamond), showing nice generalization benefits of Enigmata. This work offers a unified, controllable framework for advancing logical reasoning in LLMs. Resources of this work can be found at https://seed-enigmata.github.io.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 04:27:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19914</guid></item><item><title>Can MLLMs Guide Me Home? A Benchmark Study on Fine-Grained Visual
  Reasoning from Transit Maps</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18675</link><description>ReasonMap evaluates the fine-grained visual understanding and spatial reasoning abilities of multimodal large language models, revealing that base models often outperform reasoning variants and highlighting the importance of genuine visual perception for complex tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have recently achieved significant progress in visual tasks, including semantic scene understanding and text-image alignment, with reasoning variants enhancing performance on complex tasks involving mathematics and logic. However, their capacity for reasoning tasks involving fine-grained visual understanding remains insufficiently evaluated. To address this gap, we introduce ReasonMap, a benchmark designed to assess the fine-grained visual understanding and spatial reasoning abilities of MLLMs. ReasonMap encompasses high-resolution transit maps from 30 cities across 13 countries and includes 1,008 question-answer pairs spanning two question types and three templates. Furthermore, we design a two-level evaluation pipeline that properly assesses answer correctness and quality. Comprehensive evaluations of 15 popular MLLMs, including both base and reasoning variants, reveal a counterintuitive pattern: among open-source models, base models outperform reasoning ones, while the opposite trend is observed in closed-source models. Additionally, performance generally degrades when visual inputs are masked, indicating that while MLLMs can leverage prior knowledge to answer some questions, fine-grained visual reasoning tasks still require genuine visual perception for strong performance. Our benchmark study offers new insights into visual reasoning and contributes to investigating the gap between open-source and closed-source models.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:05:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18675</guid></item><item><title>Reinforcement Fine-Tuning Powers Reasoning Capability of Multimodal
  Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18536</link><description>Reinforcement fine-tuning significantly enhances the reasoning capabilities of multimodal large language models through diverse modalities, tasks, algorithms, benchmarks, and frameworks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Standing in 2025, at a critical juncture in the pursuit of Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), reinforcement fine-tuning (RFT) has demonstrated significant potential in enhancing the reasoning capability of large language models (LLMs) and has led to the development of cutting-edge AI models such as OpenAI-o1 and DeepSeek-R1. Moreover, the efficient application of RFT to enhance the reasoning capability of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) has attracted widespread attention from the community. In this position paper, we argue that reinforcement fine-tuning powers the reasoning capability of multimodal large language models. To begin with, we provide a detailed introduction to the fundamental background knowledge that researchers interested in this field should be familiar with. Furthermore, we meticulously summarize the improvements of RFT in powering reasoning capability of MLLMs into five key points: diverse modalities, diverse tasks and domains, better training algorithms, abundant benchmarks and thriving engineering frameworks. Finally, we propose five promising directions for future research that the community might consider. We hope that this position paper will provide valuable insights to the community at this pivotal stage in the advancement toward AGI. Summary of works done on RFT for MLLMs is available at https://github.com/Sun-Haoyuan23/Awesome-RL-based-Reasoning-MLLMs.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:13:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18536</guid></item><item><title>Deciphering Trajectory-Aided LLM Reasoning: An Optimization Perspective</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19815</link><description>LLM reasoning is understood through a meta-learning framework, treating reasoning as pseudo-gradient descent and questions as individual tasks, which enhances generalization and provides practical insights for improvement.  					AI-generated summary 				 We propose a novel framework for comprehending the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs) through the perspective of meta-learning. By conceptualizing reasoning trajectories as pseudo-gradient descent updates to the LLM's parameters, we identify parallels between LLM reasoning and various meta-learning paradigms. We formalize the training process for reasoning tasks as a meta-learning setup, with each question treated as an individual task, and reasoning trajectories serving as the inner loop optimization for adapting model parameters. Once trained on a diverse set of questions, the LLM develops fundamental reasoning capabilities that can generalize to previously unseen questions. Extensive empirical evaluations substantiate the strong connection between LLM reasoning and meta-learning, exploring several issues of significant interest from a meta-learning standpoint. Our work not only enhances the understanding of LLM reasoning but also provides practical insights for improving these models through established meta-learning techniques.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:30:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19815</guid></item><item><title>Flex-Judge: Think Once, Judge Anywhere</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18601</link><description>Flex-Judge uses minimal textual reasoning data to generalize across multiple modalities and evaluation formats, outperforming state-of-the-art models in multimodal evaluations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Human-generated reward signals are critical for aligning generative models with human preferences, guiding both training and inference-time evaluations. While large language models (LLMs) employed as proxy evaluators, i.e., LLM-as-a-Judge, significantly reduce the costs associated with manual annotations, they typically require extensive modality-specific training data and fail to generalize well across diverse multimodal tasks. In this paper, we propose Flex-Judge, a reasoning-guided multimodal judge model that leverages minimal textual reasoning data to robustly generalize across multiple modalities and evaluation formats. Our core intuition is that structured textual reasoning explanations inherently encode generalizable decision-making patterns, enabling an effective transfer to multimodal judgments, e.g., with images or videos. Empirical results demonstrate that Flex-Judge, despite being trained on significantly fewer text data, achieves competitive or superior performance compared to state-of-the-art commercial APIs and extensively trained multimodal evaluators. Notably, Flex-Judge presents broad impact in modalities like molecule, where comprehensive evaluation benchmarks are scarce, underscoring its practical value in resource-constrained domains. Our framework highlights reasoning-based text supervision as a powerful, cost-effective alternative to traditional annotation-intensive approaches, substantially advancing scalable multimodal model-as-a-judge.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:44:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18601</guid></item><item><title>B-score: Detecting biases in large language models using response
  history</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18545</link><description>LLMs can reduce biases in multi-turn conversations for certain types of questions, and a novel B-score metric improves the accuracy of verifying LLM answers.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) often exhibit strong biases, e.g, against women or in favor of the number 7. We investigate whether LLMs would be able to output less biased answers when allowed to observe their prior answers to the same question in a multi-turn conversation. To understand which types of questions invite more biased answers, we test LLMs on our proposed set of questions that span 9 topics and belong to three types: (1) Subjective; (2) Random; and (3) Objective. Interestingly, LLMs are able to "de-bias" themselves in a multi-turn conversation in response to questions that seek an Random, unbiased answer. Furthermore, we propose B-score, a novel metric that is effective in detecting biases to Subjective, Random, Easy, and Hard questions. On MMLU, HLE, and CSQA, leveraging B-score substantially improves the verification accuracy of LLM answers (i.e, accepting LLM correct answers and rejecting incorrect ones) compared to using verbalized confidence scores or the frequency of single-turn answers alone. Code and data are available at: https://b-score.github.io.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:20:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18545</guid></item><item><title>Omni-R1: Reinforcement Learning for Omnimodal Reasoning via Two-System
  Collaboration</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20256</link><description>An end-to-end reinforcement learning framework, Omni-R1, achieves superior performance in long-horizon video-audio reasoning and fine-grained pixel understanding tasks by combining global reasoning and detail understanding systems.  					AI-generated summary 				 Long-horizon video-audio reasoning and fine-grained pixel understanding impose conflicting requirements on omnimodal models: dense temporal coverage demands many low-resolution frames, whereas precise grounding calls for high-resolution inputs. We tackle this trade-off with a two-system architecture: a Global Reasoning System selects informative keyframes and rewrites the task at low spatial cost, while a Detail Understanding System performs pixel-level grounding on the selected high-resolution snippets. Because ``optimal'' keyframe selection and reformulation are ambiguous and hard to supervise, we formulate them as a reinforcement learning (RL) problem and present Omni-R1, an end-to-end RL framework built on Group Relative Policy Optimization. Omni-R1 trains the Global Reasoning System through hierarchical rewards obtained via online collaboration with the Detail Understanding System, requiring only one epoch of RL on small task splits.   Experiments on two challenging benchmarks, namely Referring Audio-Visual Segmentation (RefAVS) and Reasoning Video Object Segmentation (REVOS), show that Omni-R1 not only surpasses strong supervised baselines but also outperforms specialized state-of-the-art models, while substantially improving out-of-domain generalization and mitigating multimodal hallucination. Our results demonstrate the first successful application of RL to large-scale omnimodal reasoning and highlight a scalable path toward universally foundation models.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:17:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20256</guid></item><item><title>MOOSE-Chem2: Exploring LLM Limits in Fine-Grained Scientific Hypothesis
  Discovery via Hierarchical Search</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19209</link><description>A method is proposed to generate detailed scientific hypotheses using LLMs by defining and optimizing a latent reward landscape, outperforming baselines in benchmark evaluations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) have shown promise in automating scientific hypothesis generation, yet existing approaches primarily yield coarse-grained hypotheses lacking critical methodological and experimental details. We introduce and formally define the novel task of fine-grained scientific hypothesis discovery, which entails generating detailed, experimentally actionable hypotheses from coarse initial research directions. We frame this as a combinatorial optimization problem and investigate the upper limits of LLMs' capacity to solve it when maximally leveraged. Specifically, we explore four foundational questions: (1) how to best harness an LLM's internal heuristics to formulate the fine-grained hypothesis it itself would judge as the most promising among all the possible hypotheses it might generate, based on its own internal scoring-thus defining a latent reward landscape over the hypothesis space; (2) whether such LLM-judged better hypotheses exhibit stronger alignment with ground-truth hypotheses; (3) whether shaping the reward landscape using an ensemble of diverse LLMs of similar capacity yields better outcomes than defining it with repeated instances of the strongest LLM among them; and (4) whether an ensemble of identical LLMs provides a more reliable reward landscape than a single LLM. To address these questions, we propose a hierarchical search method that incrementally proposes and integrates details into the hypothesis, progressing from general concepts to specific experimental configurations. We show that this hierarchical process smooths the reward landscape and enables more effective optimization. Empirical evaluations on a new benchmark of expert-annotated fine-grained hypotheses from recent chemistry literature show that our method consistently outperforms strong baselines.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:00:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19209</guid></item><item><title>Hard Negative Contrastive Learning for Fine-Grained Geometric
  Understanding in Large Multimodal Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20152</link><description>A novel hard negative contrastive learning framework improves geometric reasoning in Large Multimodal Models, significantly enhancing their performance compared to existing models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Benefiting from contrastively trained visual encoders on large-scale natural scene images, Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) have achieved remarkable performance across various visual perception tasks. However, the inherent limitations of contrastive learning upon summarized descriptions fundamentally restrict the capabilities of models in meticulous reasoning, particularly in crucial scenarios of geometric problem-solving. To enhance geometric understanding, we propose a novel hard negative contrastive learning framework for the vision encoder, which combines image-based contrastive learning using generation-based hard negatives created by perturbing diagram generation code, and text-based contrastive learning using rule-based negatives derived from modified geometric descriptions and retrieval-based negatives selected based on caption similarity. We train CLIP using our strong negative learning method, namely MMCLIP (Multimodal Math CLIP), and subsequently train an LMM for geometric problem-solving. Experiments show that our trained model, MMGeoLM, significantly outperforms other open-source models on three geometric reasoning benchmarks. Even with a size of 7B, it can rival powerful closed-source models like GPT-4o. We further study the impact of different negative sample construction methods and the number of negative samples on the geometric reasoning performance of LMM, yielding fruitful conclusions. The code and dataset are available at https://github.com/THU-KEG/MMGeoLM.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:59:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20152</guid></item><item><title>Discrete Markov Bridge</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19752</link><description>A novel framework, Discrete Markov Bridge, is introduced for discrete data modeling with Matrix Learning and Score Learning components, demonstrating superior performance compared to existing methods on Text8 and CIFAR-10 datasets.  					AI-generated summary 				 Discrete diffusion has recently emerged as a promising paradigm in discrete data modeling. However, existing methods typically rely on a fixed rate transition matrix during training, which not only limits the expressiveness of latent representations, a fundamental strength of variational methods, but also constrains the overall design space. To address these limitations, we propose Discrete Markov Bridge, a novel framework specifically designed for discrete representation learning. Our approach is built upon two key components: Matrix Learning and Score Learning. We conduct a rigorous theoretical analysis, establishing formal performance guarantees for Matrix Learning and proving the convergence of the overall framework. Furthermore, we analyze the space complexity of our method, addressing practical constraints identified in prior studies. Extensive empirical evaluations validate the effectiveness of the proposed Discrete Markov Bridge, which achieves an Evidence Lower Bound (ELBO) of 1.38 on the Text8 dataset, outperforming established baselines. Moreover, the proposed model demonstrates competitive performance on the CIFAR-10 dataset, achieving results comparable to those obtained by image-specific generation approaches.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:48:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19752</guid></item><item><title>Memory-Efficient Visual Autoregressive Modeling with Scale-Aware KV
  Cache Compression</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19602</link><description>ScaleKV compresses the KV cache in Visual Autoregressive models by differentiating drafters and refiners across transformer layers, reducing memory consumption while maintaining high fidelity.  					AI-generated summary 				 Visual Autoregressive (VAR) modeling has garnered significant attention for its innovative next-scale prediction approach, which yields substantial improvements in efficiency, scalability, and zero-shot generalization. Nevertheless, the coarse-to-fine methodology inherent in VAR results in exponential growth of the KV cache during inference, causing considerable memory consumption and computational redundancy. To address these bottlenecks, we introduce ScaleKV, a novel KV cache compression framework tailored for VAR architectures. ScaleKV leverages two critical observations: varying cache demands across transformer layers and distinct attention patterns at different scales. Based on these insights, ScaleKV categorizes transformer layers into two functional groups: drafters and refiners. Drafters exhibit dispersed attention across multiple scales, thereby requiring greater cache capacity. Conversely, refiners focus attention on the current token map to process local details, consequently necessitating substantially reduced cache capacity. ScaleKV optimizes the multi-scale inference pipeline by identifying scale-specific drafters and refiners, facilitating differentiated cache management tailored to each scale. Evaluation on the state-of-the-art text-to-image VAR model family, Infinity, demonstrates that our approach effectively reduces the required KV cache memory to 10% while preserving pixel-level fidelity.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:30:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19602</guid></item><item><title>Learning to Reason without External Rewards</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19590</link><description>Intuitor, a Reinforcement Learning from Internal Feedback method, uses self-certainty as a reward signal to enable unsupervised learning of large language models, achieving performance comparable to GRPO on benchmarks and superior generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Training large language models (LLMs) for complex reasoning via Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) is effective but limited by reliance on costly, domain-specific supervision. We explore Reinforcement Learning from Internal Feedback (RLIF), a framework that enables LLMs to learn from intrinsic signals without external rewards or labeled data. We propose Intuitor, an RLIF method that uses a model's own confidence, termed self-certainty, as its sole reward signal. Intuitor replaces external rewards in Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) with self-certainty scores, enabling fully unsupervised learning. Experiments demonstrate that Intuitor matches GRPO's performance on mathematical benchmarks while achieving superior generalization to out-of-domain tasks like code generation, without requiring gold solutions or test cases. Our findings show that intrinsic model signals can drive effective learning across domains, offering a scalable alternative to RLVR for autonomous AI systems where verifiable rewards are unavailable. Code is available at https://github.com/sunblaze-ucb/Intuitor</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:30:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19590</guid></item><item><title>From Tens of Hours to Tens of Thousands: Scaling Back-Translation for
  Speech Recognition</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.16972</link><description>Speech Back-Translation enhances multilingual ASR systems by generating high-quality synthetic speech from text corpora, significantly reducing transcription errors.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) have been largely fueled by massive speech corpora. However, extending coverage to diverse languages with limited resources remains a formidable challenge. This paper introduces Speech Back-Translation, a scalable pipeline that improves multilingual ASR models by converting large-scale text corpora into synthetic speech via off-the-shelf text-to-speech (TTS) models. We demonstrate that just tens of hours of real transcribed speech can effectively train TTS models to generate synthetic speech at hundreds of times the original volume while maintaining high quality. To evaluate synthetic speech quality, we develop an intelligibility-based assessment framework and establish clear thresholds for when synthetic data benefits ASR training. Using Speech Back-Translation, we generate more than 500,000 hours of synthetic speech in ten languages and continue pre-training Whisper-large-v3, achieving average transcription error reductions of over 30\%. These results highlight the scalability and effectiveness of Speech Back-Translation for enhancing multilingual ASR systems.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:06:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.16972</guid></item><item><title>WINA: Weight Informed Neuron Activation for Accelerating Large Language
  Model Inference</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19427</link><description>WINA, a training-free sparse activation framework for large language models, improves inference accuracy by considering hidden state magnitudes and weight matrix norms, outperforming existing methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 The growing computational demands of large language models (LLMs) make efficient inference and activation strategies increasingly critical. While recent approaches, such as Mixture-of-Experts (MoE), leverage selective activation but require specialized training, training-free sparse activation methods offer broader applicability and superior resource efficiency through their plug-and-play design. However, many existing methods rely solely on hidden state magnitudes to determine activation, resulting in high approximation errors and suboptimal inference accuracy. To address these limitations, we propose WINA (Weight Informed Neuron Activation), a novel, simple, and training-free sparse activation framework that jointly considers hidden state magnitudes and the column-wise ell_2-norms of weight matrices. We show that this leads to a sparsification strategy that obtains optimal approximation error bounds with theoretical guarantees tighter than existing techniques. Empirically, WINA also outperforms state-of-the-art methods (e.g., TEAL) by up to 2.94% in average performance at the same sparsity levels, across a diverse set of LLM architectures and datasets. These results position WINA as a new performance frontier for training-free sparse activation in LLM inference, advancing training-free sparse activation methods and setting a robust baseline for efficient inference. The source code is available at https://github.com/microsoft/wina.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:40:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19427</guid></item><item><title>G1: Bootstrapping Perception and Reasoning Abilities of Vision-Language
  Model via Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.13426</link><description>VLM-Gym addresses the "knowing-doing" gap in Vision-Language Models by training them in a diverse RL environment, leading to enhanced perception and reasoning abilities that surpass existing models in interactive games.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-Language Models (VLMs) excel in many direct multimodal tasks but struggle to translate this prowess into effective decision-making within interactive, visually rich environments like games. This ``knowing-doing'' gap significantly limits their potential as autonomous agents, as leading VLMs often performing badly in simple games. To address this, we introduce VLM-Gym, a curated reinforcement learning (RL) environment featuring diverse visual games with unified interfaces and adjustable, compositional difficulty, specifically designed for scalable multi-game parallel training. Leveraging VLM-Gym, we train G0 models using pure RL-driven self-evolution, which demonstrate emergent perception and reasoning patterns. To further mitigate challenges arising from game diversity, we develop G1 models. G1 incorporates a perception-enhanced cold start prior to RL fine-tuning. Our resulting G1 models consistently surpass their teacher across all games and outperform leading proprietary models like Claude-3.7-Sonnet-Thinking. Systematic analysis reveals an intriguing finding: perception and reasoning abilities mutually bootstrap each other throughout the RL training process. Source code including VLM-Gym and RL training are released at https://github.com/chenllliang/G1 to foster future research in advancing VLMs as capable interactive agents.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 01:39:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.13426</guid></item><item><title>Position: Mechanistic Interpretability Should Prioritize Feature
  Consistency in SAEs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20254</link><description>Prioritizing feature consistency in sparse autoencoders improves mechanistic interpretability of neural networks by ensuring reliable and interpretable features.  					AI-generated summary 				 Sparse Autoencoders (SAEs) are a prominent tool in mechanistic interpretability (MI) for decomposing neural network activations into interpretable features. However, the aspiration to identify a canonical set of features is challenged by the observed inconsistency of learned SAE features across different training runs, undermining the reliability and efficiency of MI research. This position paper argues that mechanistic interpretability should prioritize feature consistency in SAEs -- the reliable convergence to equivalent feature sets across independent runs. We propose using the Pairwise Dictionary Mean Correlation Coefficient (PW-MCC) as a practical metric to operationalize consistency and demonstrate that high levels are achievable (0.80 for TopK SAEs on LLM activations) with appropriate architectural choices. Our contributions include detailing the benefits of prioritizing consistency; providing theoretical grounding and synthetic validation using a model organism, which verifies PW-MCC as a reliable proxy for ground-truth recovery; and extending these findings to real-world LLM data, where high feature consistency strongly correlates with the semantic similarity of learned feature explanations. We call for a community-wide shift towards systematically measuring feature consistency to foster robust cumulative progress in MI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:50:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20254</guid></item><item><title>BizFinBench: A Business-Driven Real-World Financial Benchmark for
  Evaluating LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19457</link><description>BizFinBench is a benchmark for evaluating large language models in financial applications, revealing distinct performance patterns across various tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models excel in general tasks, yet assessing their reliability in logic-heavy, precision-critical domains like finance, law, and healthcare remains challenging. To address this, we introduce BizFinBench, the first benchmark specifically designed to evaluate LLMs in real-world financial applications. BizFinBench consists of 6,781 well-annotated queries in Chinese, spanning five dimensions: numerical calculation, reasoning, information extraction, prediction recognition, and knowledge-based question answering, grouped into nine fine-grained categories. The benchmark includes both objective and subjective metrics. We also introduce IteraJudge, a novel LLM evaluation method that reduces bias when LLMs serve as evaluators in objective metrics. We benchmark 25 models, including both proprietary and open-source systems. Extensive experiments show that no model dominates across all tasks. Our evaluation reveals distinct capability patterns: (1) In Numerical Calculation, Claude-3.5-Sonnet (63.18) and DeepSeek-R1 (64.04) lead, while smaller models like Qwen2.5-VL-3B (15.92) lag significantly; (2) In Reasoning, proprietary models dominate (ChatGPT-o3: 83.58, Gemini-2.0-Flash: 81.15), with open-source models trailing by up to 19.49 points; (3) In Information Extraction, the performance spread is the largest, with DeepSeek-R1 scoring 71.46, while Qwen3-1.7B scores 11.23; (4) In Prediction Recognition, performance variance is minimal, with top models scoring between 39.16 and 50.00. We find that while current LLMs handle routine finance queries competently, they struggle with complex scenarios requiring cross-concept reasoning. BizFinBench offers a rigorous, business-aligned benchmark for future research. The code and dataset are available at https://github.com/HiThink-Research/BizFinBench.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:58:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19457</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking the Sampling Criteria in Reinforcement Learning for LLM
  Reasoning: A Competence-Difficulty Alignment Perspective</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.17652</link><description>CDAS addresses low sample efficiency in reinforcement learning by aligning model competence with problem difficulty, improving both accuracy and efficiency in mathematical benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement learning exhibits potential in enhancing the reasoning abilities of large language models, yet it is hard to scale for the low sample efficiency during the rollout phase. Existing methods attempt to improve efficiency by scheduling problems based on problem difficulties. However, these approaches suffer from unstable and biased estimations of problem difficulty and fail to capture the alignment between model competence and problem difficulty in RL training, leading to suboptimal results. To tackle these limitations, this paper introduces Competence-Difficulty Alignment Sampling (CDAS), which enables accurate and stable estimation of problem difficulties by aggregating historical performance discrepancies of problems. Then the model competence is quantified to adaptively select problems whose difficulty is in alignment with the model's current competence using a fixed-point system. Experimental results across a range of challenging mathematical benchmarks show that CDAS achieves great improvements in both accuracy and efficiency. CDAS attains the highest average accuracy against baselines and exhibits significant speed advantages compared to Dynamic Sampling, a competitive strategy in DAPO, which is 2.33 times slower than CDAS.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:42:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.17652</guid></item><item><title>Error Typing for Smarter Rewards: Improving Process Reward Models with
  Error-Aware Hierarchical Supervision</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19706</link><description>PathFinder-PRM, a hierarchical and error-aware Process Reward Model, improves mathematical problem-solving by fine-grained error classification and step correctness estimation, achieving state-of-the-art PRMScore with reduced data usage.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Models (LLMs) are prone to hallucination, especially during multi-hop and reasoning-intensive tasks such as mathematical problem solving. While Outcome Reward Models verify only final answers, Process Reward Models (PRMs) score each intermediate step to steer generation toward coherent solutions. We introduce PathFinder-PRM, a novel hierarchical, error-aware discriminative PRM that first classifies math and consistency errors at each step, then combines these fine-grained signals to estimate step correctness. To train PathFinder-PRM, we construct a 400K-sample dataset by enriching the human-annotated PRM800K corpus and RLHFlow Mistral traces with three-dimensional step-level labels. On PRMBench, PathFinder-PRM achieves a new state-of-the-art PRMScore of 67.7, outperforming the prior best (65.5) while using 3 times less data. When applied to reward guided greedy search, our model yields prm@8 48.3, a +1.5 point gain over the strongest baseline. These results demonstrate that decoupled error detection and reward estimation not only boost fine-grained error detection but also substantially improve end-to-end, reward-guided mathematical reasoning with greater data efficiency.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 01:59:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19706</guid></item><item><title>Interleaved Reasoning for Large Language Models via Reinforcement
  Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19640</link><description>A reinforcement learning-guided training paradigm enhances large language models' reasoning efficiency and performance for multi-hop questions by interleaving thinking and answering.  					AI-generated summary 				 Long chain-of-thought (CoT) significantly enhances large language models' (LLM) reasoning capabilities. However, the extensive reasoning traces lead to inefficiencies and an increased time-to-first-token (TTFT). We propose a novel training paradigm that uses reinforcement learning (RL) to guide reasoning LLMs to interleave thinking and answering for multi-hop questions. We observe that models inherently possess the ability to perform interleaved reasoning, which can be further enhanced through RL. We introduce a simple yet effective rule-based reward to incentivize correct intermediate steps, which guides the policy model toward correct reasoning paths by leveraging intermediate signals generated during interleaved reasoning. Extensive experiments conducted across five diverse datasets and three RL algorithms (PPO, GRPO, and REINFORCE++) demonstrate consistent improvements over traditional think-answer reasoning, without requiring external tools. Specifically, our approach reduces TTFT by over 80% on average and improves up to 19.3% in Pass@1 accuracy. Furthermore, our method, trained solely on question answering and logical reasoning datasets, exhibits strong generalization ability to complex reasoning datasets such as MATH, GPQA, and MMLU. Additionally, we conduct in-depth analysis to reveal several valuable insights into conditional reward modeling.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 04:26:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19640</guid></item><item><title>DoctorAgent-RL: A Multi-Agent Collaborative Reinforcement Learning
  System for Multi-Turn Clinical Dialogue</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19630</link><description>DoctorAgent-RL, a reinforcement learning-based multi-agent framework, enhances multi-turn reasoning and diagnostic performance in medical consultations compared to existing systems.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated excellent capabilities in the field of biomedical question answering, but their application in real-world clinical consultations still faces core challenges. Existing systems rely on a one-way information transmission mode where patients must fully describe their symptoms in a single round, leading to nonspecific diagnostic recommendations when complaints are vague. Traditional multi-turn dialogue methods based on supervised learning are constrained by static data-driven paradigms, lacking generalizability and struggling to intelligently extract key clinical information. To address these limitations, we propose DoctorAgent-RL, a reinforcement learning (RL)-based multi-agent collaborative framework that models medical consultations as a dynamic decision-making process under uncertainty. The doctor agent continuously optimizes its questioning strategy within the RL framework through multi-turn interactions with the patient agent, dynamically adjusting its information-gathering path based on comprehensive rewards from the Consultation Evaluator. This RL fine-tuning mechanism enables LLMs to autonomously develop interaction strategies aligned with clinical reasoning logic, rather than superficially imitating patterns in existing dialogue data. Notably, we constructed MTMedDialog, the first English multi-turn medical consultation dataset capable of simulating patient interactions. Experiments demonstrate that DoctorAgent-RL outperforms existing models in both multi-turn reasoning capability and final diagnostic performance, demonstrating practical value in assisting clinical consultations. https://github.com/JarvisUSTC/DoctorAgent-RL</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:26:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19630</guid></item><item><title>Vibe Coding vs. Agentic Coding: Fundamentals and Practical Implications
  of Agentic AI</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19443</link><description>A review contrasts vibe coding and agentic coding paradigms, highlighting their differences in interaction, autonomy, and application areas in AI-assisted software development.  					AI-generated summary 				 This review presents a comprehensive analysis of two emerging paradigms in AI-assisted software development: vibe coding and agentic coding. While both leverage large language models (LLMs), they differ fundamentally in autonomy, architectural design, and the role of the developer. Vibe coding emphasizes intuitive, human-in-the-loop interaction through prompt-based, conversational workflows that support ideation, experimentation, and creative exploration. In contrast, agentic coding enables autonomous software development through goal-driven agents capable of planning, executing, testing, and iterating tasks with minimal human intervention. We propose a detailed taxonomy spanning conceptual foundations, execution models, feedback loops, safety mechanisms, debugging strategies, and real-world tool ecosystems. Through comparative workflow analysis and 20 detailed use cases, we illustrate how vibe systems thrive in early-stage prototyping and education, while agentic systems excel in enterprise-grade automation, codebase refactoring, and CI/CD integration. We further examine emerging trends in hybrid architectures, where natural language interfaces are coupled with autonomous execution pipelines. Finally, we articulate a future roadmap for agentic AI, outlining the infrastructure needed for trustworthy, explainable, and collaborative systems. Our findings suggest that successful AI software engineering will rely not on choosing one paradigm, but on harmonizing their strengths within a unified, human-centered development lifecycle.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 01:42:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19443</guid></item><item><title>InfantAgent-Next: A Multimodal Generalist Agent for Automated Computer
  Interaction</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.10887</link><description>InfantAgent-Next is a multimodal agent that integrates tool-based and vision models in a modular architecture to solve various benchmarks, including OSWorld, GAIA, and SWE-Bench.  					AI-generated summary 				 This paper introduces InfantAgent-Next, a generalist agent capable of interacting with computers in a multimodal manner, encompassing text, images, audio, and video. Unlike existing approaches that either build intricate workflows around a single large model or only provide workflow modularity, our agent integrates tool-based and pure vision agents within a highly modular architecture, enabling different models to collaboratively solve decoupled tasks in a step-by-step manner. Our generality is demonstrated by our ability to evaluate not only pure vision-based real-world benchmarks (i.e., OSWorld), but also more general or tool-intensive benchmarks (e.g., GAIA and SWE-Bench). Specifically, we achieve 7.27% accuracy on OSWorld, higher than Claude-Computer-Use. Codes and evaluation scripts are open-sourced at https://github.com/bin123apple/InfantAgent.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:37:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.10887</guid></item><item><title>The Coverage Principle: A Framework for Understanding Compositional
  Generalization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20278</link><description>The coverage principle highlights limitations in Transformers' compositional generalization, emphasizing the need for new architectures or training methods to achieve systematic compositionality by distinguishing different mechanisms of generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models excel at pattern matching, yet often fall short in systematic compositional generalization. We propose the coverage principle: a data-centric framework showing that models relying primarily on pattern matching for compositional tasks cannot reliably generalize beyond substituting fragments that yield identical results when used in the same contexts. We demonstrate that this framework has a strong predictive power for the generalization capabilities of Transformers. First, we derive and empirically confirm that the training data required for two-hop generalization grows at least quadratically with the token set size, and the training data efficiency does not improve with 20x parameter scaling. Second, for compositional tasks with path ambiguity where one variable affects the output through multiple computational paths, we show that Transformers learn context-dependent state representations that undermine both performance and interoperability. Third, Chain-of-Thought supervision improves training data efficiency for multi-hop tasks but still struggles with path ambiguity. Finally, we outline a mechanism-based taxonomy that distinguishes three ways neural networks can generalize: structure-based (bounded by coverage), property-based (leveraging algebraic invariances), and shared-operator (through function reuse). This conceptual lens contextualizes our results and highlights where new architectural ideas are needed to achieve systematic compositionally. Overall, the coverage principle provides a unified lens for understanding compositional reasoning, and underscores the need for fundamental architectural or training innovations to achieve truly systematic compositionality.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:34:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20278</guid></item><item><title>Done Is Better than Perfect: Unlocking Efficient Reasoning by Structured
  Multi-Turn Decomposition</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19788</link><description>Multi-Turn Decomposition improves efficiency in large reasoning models by breaking down chain-of-thought into manageable turns, reducing token usage and latency while maintaining performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) are criticized for the excessively lengthy Chain-of-Thought (CoT) to derive the final answer, suffering from high first-token and overall latency. Typically, the CoT of LRMs mixes multiple thinking units; each unit attempts to produce a candidate answer to the original query. Hence, a natural idea to improve efficiency is to reduce the unit number. Yet, the fact that the thinking units in vanilla CoT cannot be explicitly managed renders doing so challenging. This paper introduces Multi-Turn Decomposition (MinD) to decode conventional CoT into a sequence of explicit, structured, and turn-wise interactions to bridge the gap. In MinD, the model provides a multi-turn response to the query, where each turn embraces a thinking unit and yields a corresponding answer. The subsequent turns can reflect, verify, revise, or explore alternative approaches to both the thinking and answer parts of earlier ones. This not only makes the answer delivered more swiftly, but also enables explicit controls over the iterative reasoning process (i.e., users may halt or continue at any turn). We follow a supervised fine-tuning (SFT) then reinforcement learning (RL) paradigm to realize MinD. We first rephrase the outputs of an LRM into multi-turn formats by prompting another LLM, and then tune the LRM with such data. Observing that the tuned model tends to consume even more tokens than the original one (probably due to that the multi-turn formats introduce additional answer tokens), we advocate leveraging RL algorithms like GRPO to prioritize correct outputs with fewer turns. Trained on the MATH dataset using R1-Distill models, MinD can achieve up to ~70% reduction in both output token usage and time to first token (TTFT), while maintaining competitive performance on reasoning benchmarks such as MATH-500, AIME24, AMC23, and GPQA-Diamond.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:29:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19788</guid></item><item><title>Towards Holistic Evaluation of Large Audio-Language Models: A
  Comprehensive Survey</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.15957</link><description>A survey proposes a systematic taxonomy for evaluating large audio-language models across dimensions including auditory awareness, knowledge reasoning, dialogue ability, and fairness, to address fragmented benchmarks in the field.  					AI-generated summary 				 With advancements in large audio-language models (LALMs), which enhance large language models (LLMs) with auditory capabilities, these models are expected to demonstrate universal proficiency across various auditory tasks. While numerous benchmarks have emerged to assess LALMs' performance, they remain fragmented and lack a structured taxonomy. To bridge this gap, we conduct a comprehensive survey and propose a systematic taxonomy for LALM evaluations, categorizing them into four dimensions based on their objectives: (1) General Auditory Awareness and Processing, (2) Knowledge and Reasoning, (3) Dialogue-oriented Ability, and (4) Fairness, Safety, and Trustworthiness. We provide detailed overviews within each category and highlight challenges in this field, offering insights into promising future directions. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first survey specifically focused on the evaluations of LALMs, providing clear guidelines for the community. We will release the collection of the surveyed papers and actively maintain it to support ongoing advancements in the field.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:11:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.15957</guid></item><item><title>Which Data Attributes Stimulate Math and Code Reasoning? An
  Investigation via Influence Functions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19949</link><description>Influence functions are used to attribute LLMs' reasoning in math and coding to individual training elements, revealing cross-domain effects and enabling a reweighting strategy that improves model accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable reasoning capabilities in math and coding, often bolstered by post-training on the chain-of-thoughts (CoTs) generated by stronger models. However, existing strategies for curating such training data predominantly rely on heuristics, limiting generalizability and failing to capture subtleties underlying in data. To address these limitations, we leverage influence functions to systematically attribute LLMs' reasoning ability on math and coding to individual training examples, sequences, and tokens, enabling deeper insights into effective data characteristics. Our Influence-based Reasoning Attribution (Infra) uncovers nontrivial cross-domain effects across math and coding tasks: high-difficulty math examples improve both math and code reasoning, while low-difficulty code tasks most effectively benefit code reasoning. Based on these findings, we introduce a simple yet effective dataset reweighting strategy by flipping task difficulty, which doubles AIME24 accuracy from 10\% to 20\% and boosts LiveCodeBench accuracy from 33.8\% to 35.3\% for Qwen2.5-7B-Instruct. Moreover, our fine-grained attribution reveals that the sequence-level exploratory behaviors enhance reasoning performance in both math and code, and the token-level influence patterns are distinct for math and code reasoning: the former prefers natural language logic connectors and the latter emphasizes structural syntax.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 03:00:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19949</guid></item></channel></rss>