<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Confidence Is All You Need: Few-Shot RL Fine-Tuning of Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.06395</link><description>Reinforcement Learning via Self-Confidence (RLSC) improves large language model accuracy using the model's confidence as a reward signal, eliminating the need for human labels or reward engineering.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) excel at reasoning, yet post-training remains critical for aligning their behavior with task goals. Existing reinforcement learning (RL) methods often depend on costly human annotations or external reward models. We propose Reinforcement Learning via Self-Confidence (RLSC), which uses the model's own confidence as reward signals-eliminating the need for labels, preference models, or reward engineering. Applied to Qwen2.5-Math-7B with only 16 samples per question and 10 or 20 training steps, RLSC improves accuracy by +13.4% on AIME2024, +21.2% on MATH500, +21.7% on Minerva Math, +20.8% on Olympiadbench, and +9.7% on AMC23. RLSC provides a simple, scalable post-training method for inference models, requiring only a small number of samples and unlabelled supervision.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 08:32:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.06395</guid></item><item><title>Seedance 1.0: Exploring the Boundaries of Video Generation Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09113</link><description>Seedance 1.0 offers high-performance video generation by integrating advanced data curation, efficient architecture, post-training optimization, and model acceleration, resulting in superior quality and speed.  					AI-generated summary 				 Notable breakthroughs in diffusion modeling have propelled rapid improvements in video generation, yet current foundational model still face critical challenges in simultaneously balancing prompt following, motion plausibility, and visual quality. In this report, we introduce Seedance 1.0, a high-performance and inference-efficient video foundation generation model that integrates several core technical improvements: (i) multi-source data curation augmented with precision and meaningful video captioning, enabling comprehensive learning across diverse scenarios; (ii) an efficient architecture design with proposed training paradigm, which allows for natively supporting multi-shot generation and jointly learning of both text-to-video and image-to-video tasks. (iii) carefully-optimized post-training approaches leveraging fine-grained supervised fine-tuning, and video-specific RLHF with multi-dimensional reward mechanisms for comprehensive performance improvements; (iv) excellent model acceleration achieving ~10x inference speedup through multi-stage distillation strategies and system-level optimizations. Seedance 1.0 can generate a 5-second video at 1080p resolution only with 41.4 seconds (NVIDIA-L20). Compared to state-of-the-art video generation models, Seedance 1.0 stands out with high-quality and fast video generation having superior spatiotemporal fluidity with structural stability, precise instruction adherence in complex multi-subject contexts, native multi-shot narrative coherence with consistent subject representation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 02:38:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09113</guid></item><item><title>Autoregressive Adversarial Post-Training for Real-Time Interactive Video
  Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09350</link><description>Autoregressive adversarial post-training transforms pre-trained latent video diffusion models into real-time, interactive video generators with reduced computational requirements.  					AI-generated summary 				 Existing large-scale video generation models are computationally intensive, preventing adoption in real-time and interactive applications. In this work, we propose autoregressive adversarial post-training (AAPT) to transform a pre-trained latent video diffusion model into a real-time, interactive video generator. Our model autoregressively generates a latent frame at a time using a single neural function evaluation (1NFE). The model can stream the result to the user in real time and receive interactive responses as controls to generate the next latent frame. Unlike existing approaches, our method explores adversarial training as an effective paradigm for autoregressive generation. This not only allows us to design an architecture that is more efficient for one-step generation while fully utilizing the KV cache, but also enables training the model in a student-forcing manner that proves to be effective in reducing error accumulation during long video generation. Our experiments demonstrate that our 8B model achieves real-time, 24fps, streaming video generation at 736x416 resolution on a single H100, or 1280x720 on 8xH100 up to a minute long (1440 frames). Visit our research website at https://seaweed-apt.com/2</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 06:55:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09350</guid></item><item><title>PlayerOne: Egocentric World Simulator</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09995</link><description>PlayerOne is an egocentric realistic world simulator that constructs and generates videos from user-captured images, using a coarse-to-fine training pipeline and advanced motion injection and reconstruction frameworks.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce PlayerOne, the first egocentric realistic world simulator, facilitating immersive and unrestricted exploration within vividly dynamic environments. Given an egocentric scene image from the user, PlayerOne can accurately construct the corresponding world and generate egocentric videos that are strictly aligned with the real scene human motion of the user captured by an exocentric camera. PlayerOne is trained in a coarse-to-fine pipeline that first performs pretraining on large-scale egocentric text-video pairs for coarse-level egocentric understanding, followed by finetuning on synchronous motion-video data extracted from egocentric-exocentric video datasets with our automatic construction pipeline. Besides, considering the varying importance of different components, we design a part-disentangled motion injection scheme, enabling precise control of part-level movements. In addition, we devise a joint reconstruction framework that progressively models both the 4D scene and video frames, ensuring scene consistency in the long-form video generation. Experimental results demonstrate its great generalization ability in precise control of varying human movements and worldconsistent modeling of diverse scenarios. It marks the first endeavor into egocentric real-world simulation and can pave the way for the community to delve into fresh frontiers of world modeling and its diverse applications.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 02:20:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09995</guid></item><item><title>ComfyUI-R1: Exploring Reasoning Models for Workflow Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09790</link><description>ComfyUI-R1, a large reasoning model for automated workflow generation, demonstrates superior performance in creating AI art workflows through long chain-of-thought reasoning and reinforcement learning.  					AI-generated summary 				 AI-generated content has evolved from monolithic models to modular workflows, particularly on platforms like ComfyUI, enabling customization in creative pipelines. However, crafting effective workflows requires great expertise to orchestrate numerous specialized components, presenting a steep learning curve for users. To address this challenge, we introduce ComfyUI-R1, the first large reasoning model for automated workflow generation. Starting with our curated dataset of 4K workflows, we construct long chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning data, including node selection, workflow planning, and code-level workflow representation. ComfyUI-R1 is trained through a two-stage framework: (1) CoT fine-tuning for cold start, adapting models to the ComfyUI domain; (2) reinforcement learning for incentivizing reasoning capability, guided by a fine-grained rule-metric hybrid reward, ensuring format validity, structural integrity, and node-level fidelity. Experiments show that our 7B-parameter model achieves a 97\% format validity rate, along with high pass rate, node-level and graph-level F1 scores, significantly surpassing prior state-of-the-art methods that employ leading closed-source models such as GPT-4o and Claude series. Further analysis highlights the critical role of the reasoning process and the advantage of transforming workflows into code. Qualitative comparison reveals our strength in synthesizing intricate workflows with diverse nodes, underscoring the potential of long CoT reasoning in AI art creation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 02:08:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09790</guid></item><item><title>SeerAttention-R: Sparse Attention Adaptation for Long Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.08889</link><description>SeerAttention-R is a sparse attention framework for reasoning models that maintains high accuracy and achieves significant speedups through optimized sparse decoding kernels.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce SeerAttention-R, a sparse attention framework specifically tailored for the long decoding of reasoning models. Extended from SeerAttention, SeerAttention-R retains the design of learning attention sparsity through a self-distilled gating mechanism, while removing query pooling to accommodate auto-regressive decoding. With a lightweight plug-in gating, SeerAttention-R is flexible and can be easily integrated into existing pretrained model without modifying the original parameters. We demonstrate that SeerAttention-R, trained on just 0.4B tokens, maintains near-lossless reasoning accuracy with 4K token budget in AIME benchmark under large sparse attention block sizes (64/128). Using TileLang, we develop a highly optimized sparse decoding kernel that achieves near-theoretical speedups of up to 9x over FlashAttention-3 on H100 GPU at 90% sparsity. Code is available at: https://github.com/microsoft/SeerAttention.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 02:24:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.08889</guid></item><item><title>Auto-Regressive vs Flow-Matching: a Comparative Study of Modeling
  Paradigms for Text-to-Music Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.08570</link><description>A systematic comparison of Auto-Regressive decoding and Conditional Flow-Matching in text-to-music generation highlights distinct strengths and limitations of each modeling paradigm.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent progress in text-to-music generation has enabled models to synthesize high-quality musical segments, full compositions, and even respond to fine-grained control signals, e.g. chord progressions. State-of-the-art (SOTA) systems differ significantly across many dimensions, such as training datasets, modeling paradigms, and architectural choices. This diversity complicates efforts to evaluate models fairly and pinpoint which design choices most influence performance. While factors like data and architecture are important, in this study we focus exclusively on the modeling paradigm. We conduct a systematic empirical analysis to isolate its effects, offering insights into associated trade-offs and emergent behaviors that can guide future text-to-music generation systems. Specifically, we compare the two arguably most common modeling paradigms: Auto-Regressive decoding and Conditional Flow-Matching. We conduct a controlled comparison by training all models from scratch using identical datasets, training configurations, and similar backbone architectures. Performance is evaluated across multiple axes, including generation quality, robustness to inference configurations, scalability, adherence to both textual and temporally aligned conditioning, and editing capabilities in the form of audio inpainting. This comparative study sheds light on distinct strengths and limitations of each paradigm, providing actionable insights that can inform future architectural and training decisions in the evolving landscape of text-to-music generation. Audio sampled examples are available at: https://huggingface.co/spaces/ortal1602/ARvsFM</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 12:45:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.08570</guid></item><item><title>SWE-Flow: Synthesizing Software Engineering Data in a Test-Driven Manner</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09003</link><description>A novel data synthesis framework, SWE-Flow, uses unit tests to automatically infer development steps and generate a structured schedule for Test-Driven Development (TDD), significantly improving the performance of open models fine-tuned on real-world projects.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce **SWE-Flow**, a novel data synthesis framework grounded in Test-Driven Development (TDD). Unlike existing software engineering data that rely on human-submitted issues, **SWE-Flow** automatically infers incremental development steps directly from unit tests, which inherently encapsulate high-level requirements. The core of **SWE-Flow** is the construction of a Runtime Dependency Graph (RDG), which precisely captures function interactions, enabling the generation of a structured, step-by-step *development schedule*. At each step, **SWE-Flow** produces a partial codebase, the corresponding unit tests, and the necessary code modifications, resulting in fully verifiable TDD tasks. With this approach, we generated 16,061 training instances and 2,020 test instances from real-world GitHub projects, creating the **SWE-Flow-Eval** benchmark. Our experiments show that fine-tuning open model on this dataset significantly improves performance in TDD-based coding. To facilitate further research, we release all code, datasets, models, and Docker images at [Github](https://github.com/Hambaobao/SWE-Flow).</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 01:47:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09003</guid></item><item><title>InterActHuman: Multi-Concept Human Animation with Layout-Aligned Audio
  Conditions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09984</link><description>A new framework enables precise, per-identity control of multiple concepts in end-to-end human animation by enforcing region-specific binding of multi-modal conditions.  					AI-generated summary 				 End-to-end human animation with rich multi-modal conditions, e.g., text, image and audio has achieved remarkable advancements in recent years. However, most existing methods could only animate a single subject and inject conditions in a global manner, ignoring scenarios that multiple concepts could appears in the same video with rich human-human interactions and human-object interactions. Such global assumption prevents precise and per-identity control of multiple concepts including humans and objects, therefore hinders applications. In this work, we discard the single-entity assumption and introduce a novel framework that enforces strong, region-specific binding of conditions from modalities to each identity's spatiotemporal footprint. Given reference images of multiple concepts, our method could automatically infer layout information by leveraging a mask predictor to match appearance cues between the denoised video and each reference appearance. Furthermore, we inject local audio condition into its corresponding region to ensure layout-aligned modality matching in a iterative manner. This design enables the high-quality generation of controllable multi-concept human-centric videos. Empirical results and ablation studies validate the effectiveness of our explicit layout control for multi-modal conditions compared to implicit counterparts and other existing methods.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 03:32:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09984</guid></item><item><title>SAFE: Multitask Failure Detection for Vision-Language-Action Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09937</link><description>SAFE is a failure detector for vision-language-action models that generalizes to unseen tasks by learning from high-level internal features of the models.  					AI-generated summary 				 While vision-language-action models (VLAs) have shown promising robotic behaviors across a diverse set of manipulation tasks, they achieve limited success rates when deployed on novel tasks out-of-the-box. To allow these policies to safely interact with their environments, we need a failure detector that gives a timely alert such that the robot can stop, backtrack, or ask for help. However, existing failure detectors are trained and tested only on one or a few specific tasks, while VLAs require the detector to generalize and detect failures also in unseen tasks and novel environments. In this paper, we introduce the multitask failure detection problem and propose SAFE, a failure detector for generalist robot policies such as VLAs. We analyze the VLA feature space and find that VLAs have sufficient high-level knowledge about task success and failure, which is generic across different tasks. Based on this insight, we design SAFE to learn from VLA internal features and predict a single scalar indicating the likelihood of task failure. SAFE is trained on both successful and failed rollouts, and is evaluated on unseen tasks. SAFE is compatible with different policy architectures. We test it on OpenVLA, pi_0, and pi_0-FAST in both simulated and real-world environments extensively. We compare SAFE with diverse baselines and show that SAFE achieves state-of-the-art failure detection performance and the best trade-off between accuracy and detection time using conformal prediction. More qualitative results can be found at https://vla-safe.github.io/.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 02:38:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09937</guid></item><item><title>Reparameterized LLM Training via Orthogonal Equivalence Transformation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.08001</link><description>POET is a reParameterized training algorithm using Orthogonal Equivalence Transformation to optimize neurons in large language models, ensuring stable training and improved generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 While large language models (LLMs) are driving the rapid advancement of artificial intelligence, effectively and reliably training these large models remains one of the field's most significant challenges. To address this challenge, we propose POET, a novel reParameterized training algorithm that uses Orthogonal Equivalence Transformation to optimize neurons. Specifically, POET reparameterizes each neuron with two learnable orthogonal matrices and a fixed random weight matrix. Because of its provable preservation of spectral properties of weight matrices, POET can stably optimize the objective function with improved generalization. We further develop efficient approximations that make POET flexible and scalable for training large-scale neural networks. Extensive experiments validate the effectiveness and scalability of POET in training LLMs.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:25:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.08001</guid></item><item><title>Time to Talk: LLM Agents for Asynchronous Group Communication in Mafia
  Games</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.05309</link><description>An adaptive asynchronous LLM-agent performs similarly to human players in online Mafia games, demonstrating the potential for integrating LLMs into realistic group settings with complex social dynamics.  					AI-generated summary 				 LLMs are used predominantly in synchronous communication, where a human user and a model communicate in alternating turns. In contrast, many real-world settings are inherently asynchronous. For example, in group chats, online team meetings, or social games, there is no inherent notion of turns; therefore, the decision of when to speak forms a crucial part of the participant's decision making. In this work, we develop an adaptive asynchronous LLM-agent which, in addition to determining what to say, also decides when to say it. To evaluate our agent, we collect a unique dataset of online Mafia games, including both human participants, as well as our asynchronous agent. Overall, our agent performs on par with human players, both in game performance, as well as in its ability to blend in with the other human players. Our analysis shows that the agent's behavior in deciding when to speak closely mirrors human patterns, although differences emerge in message content. We release all our data and code to support and encourage further research for more realistic asynchronous communication between LLM agents. This work paves the way for integration of LLMs into realistic human group settings, from assistance in team discussions to educational and professional environments where complex social dynamics must be navigated.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:18:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.05309</guid></item><item><title>MIRAGE: Multimodal foundation model and benchmark for comprehensive
  retinal OCT image analysis</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.08900</link><description>MIRAGE, a multimodal foundation model, excels in OCT and SLO image classification and segmentation, outperforming existing general and specialized models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Artificial intelligence (AI) has become a fundamental tool for assisting clinicians in analyzing ophthalmic images, such as optical coherence tomography (OCT). However, developing AI models often requires extensive annotation, and existing models tend to underperform on independent, unseen data. Foundation models (FMs), large AI models trained on vast unlabeled datasets, have shown promise in overcoming these challenges. Nonetheless, available FMs for ophthalmology lack extensive validation, especially for segmentation tasks, and focus on a single imaging modality. In this context, we propose MIRAGE, a novel multimodal FM for the analysis of OCT and scanning laser ophthalmoscopy (SLO) images. Additionally, we propose a new evaluation benchmark with OCT/SLO classification and segmentation tasks. The comparison with general and specialized FMs and segmentation methods shows the superiority of MIRAGE in both types of tasks, highlighting its suitability as a basis for the development of robust AI systems for retinal OCT image analysis. Both MIRAGE and the evaluation benchmark are publicly available: https://github.com/j-morano/MIRAGE.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 09:01:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.08900</guid></item><item><title>Branched Schrödinger Bridge Matching</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09007</link><description>BranchSBM, a novel generative modeling framework, extends Schr\"odinger Bridge Matching to model branched stochastic paths and multi-path evolution from a single initial distribution to multiple outcomes.  					AI-generated summary 				 Predicting the intermediate trajectories between an initial and target distribution is a central problem in generative modeling. Existing approaches, such as flow matching and Schr\"odinger Bridge Matching, effectively learn mappings between two distributions by modeling a single stochastic path. However, these methods are inherently limited to unimodal transitions and cannot capture branched or divergent evolution from a common origin to multiple distinct outcomes. To address this, we introduce Branched Schr\"odinger Bridge Matching (BranchSBM), a novel framework that learns branched Schr\"odinger bridges. BranchSBM parameterizes multiple time-dependent velocity fields and growth processes, enabling the representation of population-level divergence into multiple terminal distributions. We show that BranchSBM is not only more expressive but also essential for tasks involving multi-path surface navigation, modeling cell fate bifurcations from homogeneous progenitor states, and simulating diverging cellular responses to perturbations.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 03:02:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09007</guid></item></channel></rss>