<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>For more better details and analysis, you can read the article here:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Ujjwal-Tyagi/924115096887729</link><description>For more better details and analysis, you can read the article here: https://huggingface.co/blog/Ujjwal-Tyagi/steering-not-censoring , We are sleepwalking into a crisis. I am deeply concerned about AI model safety right now because, as the community rushes to roll out increasingly powerful open-source models, we are completely neglecting the most critical aspect: safety. It seems that nobody is seriously thinking about the potential consequences of unregulated model outputs or the necessity of robust guardrails. We are essentially planting the seeds for our own destruction if we prioritize raw performance over security. This negligence is terrifyingly evident when you look at the current landscape. Take Qwen Image 2512, for example; while it delivers undeniably strong performance, it has incredibly weak guardrails that make it dangerous to deploy. In stark contrast, Z Image might not get as much hype for its power, but it has much better safety guardrails than Qwen Image 2512. It is...</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Ujjwal-Tyagi/924115096887729</guid></item><item><title>VividFlow: AI Image Enhancement &amp; Video Generation 🎬🎨</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DawnC/872062429240283</link><description>VividFlow: AI Image Enhancement &amp; Video Generation 🎬🎨 Bring your images to life with cinematic motion AND create stunning AI backgrounds! VividFlow combines professional-grade video generation with intelligent background replacement in one streamlined platform. 🎭 Dual Creative Powers Transform any static image into high-quality dynamic videos with smooth, natural motion ranging from 0.5 to 5 seconds. Choose from curated motion templates across 8 categories designed for portraits, products, landscapes, and artistic content. Create photorealistic backgrounds by selecting from 24 professionally crafted scene presets spanning studios, natural environments, urban settings, and artistic atmospheres...etc. ⚡ Optimized Performance Video generation currently completes in 4-5 minutes with active optimization underway to dramatically reduce processing time. Background replacement finishes in 30-40 seconds after initial loading. The independent dual-tab design ensures smooth workflow without...</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DawnC/872062429240283</guid></item><item><title>We have updated our transcription model:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/hypothetical/242547767593660</link><description>We have updated our transcription model: TheStageAI/thewhisper-large-v3-turbo – 6.00 WER on the English Open ASR Leaderboard – 4.74 WER on the Multilingual Open ASR Leaderboard – Beats NVIDIA Parakeet (6.34 WER) and Whisper-large-v3-turbo (7.8 WER) – Strong improvements in Arabic, Hindi, Chinese – Maintains quality with background and environmental noise – Optimized inference engines for NVIDIA and Apple – Hugging Face Transformers interface for easy use – Best-in-class speed on NVIDIA GPUs and power efficiency on Apple devices – NVIDIA Jetson Thor support See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/hypothetical/242547767593660</guid></item><item><title>Atom-80B is out!:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/unmodeled-tyler/111185407753079</link><description>Atom-80B is out!: vanta-research/atom-80b I'm excited to share the new Atom-80B from VANTA Research! A few days ago we released the largest model-to-date from our portfolio, which was Atom-27B. We've quickly scaled up to the new Qwen3 Next 80B architecture, bringing our friendly, curious, and collaborative Atom persona to cutting edge lightweight, high parameter inference. Atom is designed to work and think alongside you through curious exploration. Using Atom collaboratively in your work can help spark your own creativity or curiosity. Give it a try! See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/unmodeled-tyler/111185407753079</guid></item><item><title>New GRPO + TRL free Colab notebook out! 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/609901844144152</link><description>New GRPO + TRL free Colab notebook out! 🔥 Fine-tune 7B+ models on T4 GPUs thanks to a ton of memory optimizations for GRPO 7B model uses only 9.2 GB VRAM (~7× reduction) 🤯 Try the notebook here 👉 https://colab.research.google.com/github/huggingface/trl/blob/main/examples/notebooks/grpo_trl_lora_qlora.ipynb See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/609901844144152</guid></item><item><title>Happy birthday to me!!!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Reality123b/635291729211142</link><description>Happy birthday to me!!! See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Reality123b/635291729211142</guid></item><item><title>Wechat AI is shipping!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/745173620987102</link><description>Wechat AI is shipping! WeDLM 🔥 A new language model that generates tokens in parallel, making it faster than standard LLMs , with the same Transformer setup! https://huggingface.co/collections/tencent/wedlm ✨ 7B/8B - Base &amp; Instruct ✨ Apache 2.0 See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/745173620987102</guid></item><item><title>We are happy to share the VERSE Methodology paper via arXiv! 📃💫</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/de-Rodrigo/941101663333132</link><description>We are happy to share the VERSE Methodology paper via arXiv! 📃💫 VERSE: Visual Embedding Reduction and Space Exploration. Clustering-Guided Insights for Training Data Enhancement in Visually-Rich Document Understanding (2601.05125) We usually train VLMs on visual synthetic data that we (as humans) label as photorealistic. We argue that this is an anthropocentric perspective imposed to a model that might not synthetize visual information as we do. VERSE helps to visualize latent space and overlay visual features to detect poor-performance regions and take action to include better-suited training sets to boost model performance. Resources: - Code: https://github.com/nachoDRT/VrDU-Doctor - Hugging Face Space: de-Rodrigo/Embeddings Want to collaborate? Do you have any feedback? 🧐 PD: As always, we are grateful to Hugging Face 🤗 for providing the fantastic tools and resources we find on the platform! See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/de-Rodrigo/941101663333132</guid></item><item><title>Potrzebuję modelu do analizy długich dokumentów technicznych, z wzorami, tabelami, wykresami, formułami matematycznymi.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/SkorczyByk/732304837583363</link><description>Potrzebuję modelu do analizy długich dokumentów technicznych, z wzorami, tabelami, wykresami, formułami matematycznymi. See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/SkorczyByk/732304837583363</guid></item><item><title>how to expand your dataset (of articles) without changing the ideas in it?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/etemiz/932060840345022</link><description>how to expand your dataset (of articles) without changing the ideas in it? i was doing CPT for a while and got decent results. but what if i want to go for perfection? cover all the areas of misalignment using limited datasets. i have to find a way to multiply the material to successfully combat the material of the rest of the internet. i want to generate SFT datasets but only on controversial topics, because i have to be efficient with limited resources. first i give a smart LLM a 'ground truth' text. then i give it the following prompts: - You are a highly skilled academic analyst. - Analyze this text and find 3 bold claims that could cause controversy and division in public. List the claims and also state why they are debatable. Give numbers to the claims. - Convert these claims into binary questions (that could be answered by yes/no or this/that). - Now put these questions in a json format . Please also add the info about which of the answers concur with the original text and...</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:33:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/etemiz/932060840345022</guid></item></channel></rss>