<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>OmniConsistency: Learning Style-Agnostic Consistency from Paired
  Stylization Data</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18445</link><description>OmniConsistency, using large-scale Diffusion Transformers, enhances stylization consistency and generalization in image-to-image pipelines without style degradation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Diffusion models have advanced image stylization significantly, yet two core challenges persist: (1) maintaining consistent stylization in complex scenes, particularly identity, composition, and fine details, and (2) preventing style degradation in image-to-image pipelines with style LoRAs. GPT-4o's exceptional stylization consistency highlights the performance gap between open-source methods and proprietary models. To bridge this gap, we propose OmniConsistency, a universal consistency plugin leveraging large-scale Diffusion Transformers (DiTs). OmniConsistency contributes: (1) an in-context consistency learning framework trained on aligned image pairs for robust generalization; (2) a two-stage progressive learning strategy decoupling style learning from consistency preservation to mitigate style degradation; and (3) a fully plug-and-play design compatible with arbitrary style LoRAs under the Flux framework. Extensive experiments show that OmniConsistency significantly enhances visual coherence and aesthetic quality, achieving performance comparable to commercial state-of-the-art model GPT-4o.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 01:46:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18445</guid></item><item><title>Paper2Poster: Towards Multimodal Poster Automation from Scientific
  Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21497</link><description>A benchmark and metric suite for poster generation evaluates visual quality, coherence, and content accuracy, leading to a multi-agent pipeline that outperforms existing models with reduced computational cost.  					AI-generated summary 				 Academic poster generation is a crucial yet challenging task in scientific communication, requiring the compression of long-context interleaved documents into a single, visually coherent page. To address this challenge, we introduce the first benchmark and metric suite for poster generation, which pairs recent conference papers with author-designed posters and evaluates outputs on (i)Visual Quality-semantic alignment with human posters, (ii)Textual Coherence-language fluency, (iii)Holistic Assessment-six fine-grained aesthetic and informational criteria scored by a VLM-as-judge, and notably (iv)PaperQuiz-the poster's ability to convey core paper content as measured by VLMs answering generated quizzes. Building on this benchmark, we propose PosterAgent, a top-down, visual-in-the-loop multi-agent pipeline: the (a)Parser distills the paper into a structured asset library; the (b)Planner aligns text-visual pairs into a binary-tree layout that preserves reading order and spatial balance; and the (c)Painter-Commenter loop refines each panel by executing rendering code and using VLM feedback to eliminate overflow and ensure alignment. In our comprehensive evaluation, we find that GPT-4o outputs-though visually appealing at first glance-often exhibit noisy text and poor PaperQuiz scores, and we find that reader engagement is the primary aesthetic bottleneck, as human-designed posters rely largely on visual semantics to convey meaning. Our fully open-source variants (e.g. based on the Qwen-2.5 series) outperform existing 4o-driven multi-agent systems across nearly all metrics, while using 87% fewer tokens. It transforms a 22-page paper into a finalized yet editable .pptx poster - all for just $0.005. These findings chart clear directions for the next generation of fully automated poster-generation models. The code and datasets are available at https://github.com/Paper2Poster/Paper2Poster.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:15:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21497</guid></item><item><title>MME-Reasoning: A Comprehensive Benchmark for Logical Reasoning in MLLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21327</link><description>MME-Reasoning evaluates the logical reasoning capabilities of multimodal large language models, revealing significant limitations and performance imbalances across inductive, deductive, and abductive reasoning types.  					AI-generated summary 				 Logical reasoning is a fundamental aspect of human intelligence and an essential capability for multimodal large language models (MLLMs). Despite the significant advancement in multimodal reasoning, existing benchmarks fail to comprehensively evaluate their reasoning abilities due to the lack of explicit categorization for logical reasoning types and an unclear understanding of reasoning. To address these issues, we introduce MME-Reasoning, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate the reasoning ability of MLLMs, which covers all three types of reasoning (i.e., inductive, deductive, and abductive) in its questions. We carefully curate the data to ensure that each question effectively evaluates reasoning ability rather than perceptual skills or knowledge breadth, and extend the evaluation protocols to cover the evaluation of diverse questions. Our evaluation reveals substantial limitations of state-of-the-art MLLMs when subjected to holistic assessments of logical reasoning capabilities. Even the most advanced MLLMs show limited performance in comprehensive logical reasoning, with notable performance imbalances across reasoning types. In addition, we conducted an in-depth analysis of approaches such as ``thinking mode'' and Rule-based RL, which are commonly believed to enhance reasoning abilities. These findings highlight the critical limitations and performance imbalances of current MLLMs in diverse logical reasoning scenarios, providing comprehensive and systematic insights into the understanding and evaluation of reasoning capabilities.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 03:00:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21327</guid></item><item><title>VerIPO: Cultivating Long Reasoning in Video-LLMs via Verifier-Gudied
  Iterative Policy Optimization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19000</link><description>A Verifier-guided Iterative Policy Optimization method enhances Video-LLMs' reasoning capabilities by integrating a Rollout-Aware Verifier between GRPO and DPO phases, leading to faster and more effective optimization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Applying Reinforcement Learning (RL) to Video Large Language Models (Video-LLMs) shows significant promise for complex video reasoning. However, popular Reinforcement Fine-Tuning (RFT) methods, such as outcome-based Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO), are limited by data preparation bottlenecks (e.g., noise or high cost) and exhibit unstable improvements in the quality of long chain-of-thoughts (CoTs) and downstream performance.To address these limitations, we propose VerIPO, a Verifier-guided Iterative Policy Optimization method designed to gradually improve video LLMs' capacity for generating deep, long-term reasoning chains. The core component is Rollout-Aware Verifier, positioned between the GRPO and Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) training phases to form the GRPO-Verifier-DPO training loop. This verifier leverages small LLMs as a judge to assess the reasoning logic of rollouts, enabling the construction of high-quality contrastive data, including reflective and contextually consistent CoTs. These curated preference samples drive the efficient DPO stage (7x faster than GRPO), leading to marked improvements in reasoning chain quality, especially in terms of length and contextual consistency. This training loop benefits from GRPO's expansive search and DPO's targeted optimization. Experimental results demonstrate: 1) Significantly faster and more effective optimization compared to standard GRPO variants, yielding superior performance; 2) Our trained models exceed the direct inference of large-scale instruction-tuned Video-LLMs, producing long and contextually consistent CoTs on diverse video reasoning tasks; and 3) Our model with one iteration outperforms powerful LMMs (e.g., Kimi-VL) and long reasoning models (e.g., Video-R1), highlighting its effectiveness and stability.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 03:22:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19000</guid></item><item><title>MME-VideoOCR: Evaluating OCR-Based Capabilities of Multimodal LLMs in
  Video Scenarios</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21333</link><description>MLLMs achieve modest accuracy in video OCR due to motion blur, temporal variations, and visual effects; MME-VideoOCR benchmark reveals limitations in spatio-temporal reasoning and language bias.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have achieved considerable accuracy in Optical Character Recognition (OCR) from static images. However, their efficacy in video OCR is significantly diminished due to factors such as motion blur, temporal variations, and visual effects inherent in video content. To provide clearer guidance for training practical MLLMs, we introduce the MME-VideoOCR benchmark, which encompasses a comprehensive range of video OCR application scenarios. MME-VideoOCR features 10 task categories comprising 25 individual tasks and spans 44 diverse scenarios. These tasks extend beyond text recognition to incorporate deeper comprehension and reasoning of textual content within videos. The benchmark consists of 1,464 videos with varying resolutions, aspect ratios, and durations, along with 2,000 meticulously curated, manually annotated question-answer pairs. We evaluate 18 state-of-the-art MLLMs on MME-VideoOCR, revealing that even the best-performing model (Gemini-2.5 Pro) achieves an accuracy of only 73.7%. Fine-grained analysis indicates that while existing MLLMs demonstrate strong performance on tasks where relevant texts are contained within a single or few frames, they exhibit limited capability in effectively handling tasks that demand holistic video comprehension. These limitations are especially evident in scenarios that require spatio-temporal reasoning, cross-frame information integration, or resistance to language prior bias. Our findings also highlight the importance of high-resolution visual input and sufficient temporal coverage for reliable OCR in dynamic video scenarios.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 01:37:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21333</guid></item><item><title>GraLoRA: Granular Low-Rank Adaptation for Parameter-Efficient
  Fine-Tuning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20355</link><description>Granular Low-Rank Adaptation (GraLoRA) improves upon Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) by partitioning weight matrices to mitigate overfitting and enhance performance in parameter-efficient fine-tuning.  					AI-generated summary 				 Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) is a popular method for parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) of generative models, valued for its simplicity and effectiveness. Despite recent enhancements, LoRA still suffers from a fundamental limitation: overfitting when the bottleneck is widened. It performs best at ranks 32-64, yet its accuracy stagnates or declines at higher ranks, still falling short of full fine-tuning (FFT) performance. We identify the root cause as LoRA's structural bottleneck, which introduces gradient entanglement to the unrelated input channels and distorts gradient propagation. To address this, we introduce a novel structure, Granular Low-Rank Adaptation (GraLoRA) that partitions weight matrices into sub-blocks, each with its own low-rank adapter. With negligible computational or storage cost, GraLoRA overcomes LoRA's limitations, effectively increases the representational capacity, and more closely approximates FFT behavior. Experiments on code generation and commonsense reasoning benchmarks show that GraLoRA consistently outperforms LoRA and other baselines, achieving up to +8.5% absolute gain in Pass@1 on HumanEval+. These improvements hold across model sizes and rank settings, making GraLoRA a scalable and robust solution for PEFT. Code, data, and scripts are available at https://github.com/SqueezeBits/GraLoRA.git</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:30:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20355</guid></item><item><title>Video-Holmes: Can MLLM Think Like Holmes for Complex Video Reasoning?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21374</link><description>Video-Holmes benchmark evaluates complex video reasoning capabilities of MLLMs using suspense short films and reveals significant challenges in information integration compared to human experts.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in CoT reasoning and RL post-training have been reported to enhance video reasoning capabilities of MLLMs. This progress naturally raises a question: can these models perform complex video reasoning in a manner comparable to human experts? However, existing video benchmarks primarily evaluate visual perception and grounding abilities, with questions that can be answered based on explicit prompts or isolated visual cues. Such benchmarks do not fully capture the intricacies of real-world reasoning, where humans must actively search for, integrate, and analyze multiple clues before reaching a conclusion. To address this issue, we present Video-Holmes, a benchmark inspired by the reasoning process of Sherlock Holmes, designed to evaluate the complex video reasoning capabilities of MLLMs. Video-Holmes consists of 1,837 questions derived from 270 manually annotated suspense short films, which spans seven carefully designed tasks. Each task is constructed by first identifying key events and causal relationships within films, and then designing questions that require models to actively locate and connect multiple relevant visual clues scattered across different video segments. Our comprehensive evaluation of state-of-the-art MLLMs reveals that, while these models generally excel at visual perception, they encounter substantial difficulties with integrating information and often miss critical clues. For example, the best-performing model, Gemini-2.5-Pro, achieves an accuracy of only 45%, with most models scoring below 40%. We aim that Video-Holmes can serve as a "Holmes-test" for multimodal reasoning, motivating models to reason more like humans and emphasizing the ongoing challenges in this field. The benchmark is released in https://github.com/TencentARC/Video-Holmes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 01:42:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21374</guid></item><item><title>MetaMind: Modeling Human Social Thoughts with Metacognitive Multi-Agent
  Systems</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18943</link><description>MetaMind, a multi-agent framework inspired by metacognition, enhances LLMs' ability to perform Theory of Mind tasks by decomposing social understanding into hypothesis generation, refinement, and response generation, achieving human-like performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Human social interactions depend on the ability to infer others' unspoken intentions, emotions, and beliefs-a cognitive skill grounded in the psychological concept of Theory of Mind (ToM). While large language models (LLMs) excel in semantic understanding tasks, they struggle with the ambiguity and contextual nuance inherent in human communication. To bridge this gap, we introduce MetaMind, a multi-agent framework inspired by psychological theories of metacognition, designed to emulate human-like social reasoning. MetaMind decomposes social understanding into three collaborative stages: (1) a Theory-of-Mind Agent generates hypotheses user mental states (e.g., intent, emotion), (2) a Domain Agent refines these hypotheses using cultural norms and ethical constraints, and (3) a Response Agent generates contextually appropriate responses while validating alignment with inferred intent. Our framework achieves state-of-the-art performance across three challenging benchmarks, with 35.7% improvement in real-world social scenarios and 6.2% gain in ToM reasoning. Notably, it enables LLMs to match human-level performance on key ToM tasks for the first time. Ablation studies confirm the necessity of all components, which showcase the framework's ability to balance contextual plausibility, social appropriateness, and user adaptation. This work advances AI systems toward human-like social intelligence, with applications in empathetic dialogue and culturally sensitive interactions. Code is available at https://github.com/XMZhangAI/MetaMind.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 01:37:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18943</guid></item><item><title>rStar-Coder: Scaling Competitive Code Reasoning with a Large-Scale
  Verified Dataset</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21297</link><description>A large-scale dataset called rStar-Coder enhances code reasoning in LLMs by providing verified code problems and solutions, leading to improved performance on various benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Advancing code reasoning in large language models (LLMs) is fundamentally limited by the scarcity of high-difficulty datasets, especially those with verifiable input-output test cases necessary for rigorous solution validation at scale. We introduce rStar-Coder, which significantly improves LLM code reasoning capabilities by constructing a large-scale, verified dataset of 418K competition-level code problems, 580K long-reasoning solutions along with rich test cases of varying difficulty. This is achieved through three core contributions: (1) we curate competitive programming code problems and oracle solutions to synthesize new, solvable problems; (2) we introduce a reliable input-output test case synthesis pipeline that decouples the generation into a three-step input generation method and a mutual verification mechanism for effective output labeling; (3) we augment problems with high-quality, test-case-verified long-reasoning solutions. Extensive experiments on Qwen models (1.5B-14B) across various code reasoning benchmarks demonstrate the superiority of rStar-Coder dataset, achieving leading performance comparable to frontier reasoning LLMs with much smaller model sizes. On LiveCodeBench, rStar-Coder improves Qwen2.5-7B from 17.4% to an impressive 57.3%, and Qwen2.5-14B from 23.3% to 62.5%, surpassing o3-mini (low) by3.1%. On the more challenging USA Computing Olympiad, our 7B model achieves an average pass@1 accuracy of 16.15%, outperforming the frontier-level QWQ-32B. Code and the dataset will be released at https://github.com/microsoft/rStar.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:10:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21297</guid></item><item><title>Sparse VideoGen2: Accelerate Video Generation with Sparse Attention via
  Semantic-Aware Permutation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18875</link><description>SVG2 is a training-free framework that enhances video generation efficiency and quality by accurately identifying and processing critical tokens using semantic-aware permutation and dynamic budget control.  					AI-generated summary 				 Diffusion Transformers (DiTs) are essential for video generation but suffer from significant latency due to the quadratic complexity of attention. By computing only critical tokens, sparse attention reduces computational costs and offers a promising acceleration approach. However, we identify that existing methods fail to approach optimal generation quality under the same computation budget for two reasons: (1) Inaccurate critical token identification: current methods cluster tokens based on position rather than semantics, leading to imprecise aggregated representations. (2) Excessive computation waste: critical tokens are scattered among non-critical ones, leading to wasted computation on GPUs, which are optimized for processing contiguous tokens. In this paper, we propose SVG2, a training-free framework that maximizes identification accuracy and minimizes computation waste, achieving a Pareto frontier trade-off between generation quality and efficiency. The core of SVG2 is semantic-aware permutation, which clusters and reorders tokens based on semantic similarity using k-means. This approach ensures both a precise cluster representation, improving identification accuracy, and a densified layout of critical tokens, enabling efficient computation without padding. Additionally, SVG2 integrates top-p dynamic budget control and customized kernel implementations, achieving up to 2.30x and 1.89x speedup while maintaining a PSNR of up to 30 and 26 on HunyuanVideo and Wan 2.1, respectively.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 01:42:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.18875</guid></item><item><title>MMMR: Benchmarking Massive Multi-Modal Reasoning Tasks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.16459</link><description>The MMMR benchmark evaluates multi-modal reasoning in MLLMs by assessing thinking quality through diverse reasoning types and a modular evaluation pipeline.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in Multi-Modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have enabled unified processing of language, vision, and structured inputs, opening the door to complex tasks such as logical deduction, spatial reasoning, and scientific analysis. Despite their promise, the reasoning capabilities of MLLMs, particularly those augmented with intermediate thinking traces (MLLMs-T), remain poorly understood and lack standardized evaluation benchmarks. Existing work focuses primarily on perception or final answer correctness, offering limited insight into how models reason or fail across modalities. To address this gap, we introduce the MMMR, a new benchmark designed to rigorously evaluate multi-modal reasoning with explicit thinking. The MMMR comprises 1) a high-difficulty dataset of 1,083 questions spanning six diverse reasoning types with symbolic depth and multi-hop demands and 2) a modular Reasoning Trace Evaluation Pipeline (RTEP) for assessing reasoning quality beyond accuracy through metrics like relevance, consistency, and structured error annotations. Empirical results show that MLLMs-T overall outperform non-thinking counterparts, but even top models like Claude-3.7-Sonnet and Gemini-2.5 Pro suffer from reasoning pathologies such as inconsistency and overthinking. This benchmark reveals persistent gaps between accuracy and reasoning quality and provides an actionable evaluation pipeline for future model development. Overall, the MMMR offers a scalable foundation for evaluating, comparing, and improving the next generation of multi-modal reasoning systems.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 06:59:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.16459</guid></item><item><title>OpenS2V-Nexus: A Detailed Benchmark and Million-Scale Dataset for
  Subject-to-Video Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20292</link><description>OpenS2V-Nexus provides benchmarks and a large dataset to evaluate and advance Subject-to-Video (S2V) generation, focusing on subject consistency and naturalness in generated videos.  					AI-generated summary 				 Subject-to-Video (S2V) generation aims to create videos that faithfully incorporate reference content, providing enhanced flexibility in the production of videos. To establish the infrastructure for S2V generation, we propose OpenS2V-Nexus, consisting of (i) OpenS2V-Eval, a fine-grained benchmark, and (ii) OpenS2V-5M, a million-scale dataset. In contrast to existing S2V benchmarks inherited from VBench that focus on global and coarse-grained assessment of generated videos, OpenS2V-Eval focuses on the model's ability to generate subject-consistent videos with natural subject appearance and identity fidelity. For these purposes, OpenS2V-Eval introduces 180 prompts from seven major categories of S2V, which incorporate both real and synthetic test data. Furthermore, to accurately align human preferences with S2V benchmarks, we propose three automatic metrics, NexusScore, NaturalScore and GmeScore, to separately quantify subject consistency, naturalness, and text relevance in generated videos. Building on this, we conduct a comprehensive evaluation of 16 representative S2V models, highlighting their strengths and weaknesses across different content. Moreover, we create the first open-source large-scale S2V generation dataset OpenS2V-5M, which consists of five million high-quality 720P subject-text-video triples. Specifically, we ensure subject-information diversity in our dataset by (1) segmenting subjects and building pairing information via cross-video associations and (2) prompting GPT-Image-1 on raw frames to synthesize multi-view representations. Through OpenS2V-Nexus, we deliver a robust infrastructure to accelerate future S2V generation research.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:06:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20292</guid></item><item><title>ImgEdit: A Unified Image Editing Dataset and Benchmark</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20275</link><description>ImgEdit, a comprehensive image-editing dataset and benchmark, improves open-source text-to-image editing models by providing high-quality data and evaluation metrics.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advancements in generative models have enabled high-fidelity text-to-image generation. However, open-source image-editing models still lag behind their proprietary counterparts, primarily due to limited high-quality data and insufficient benchmarks. To overcome these limitations, we introduce ImgEdit, a large-scale, high-quality image-editing dataset comprising 1.2 million carefully curated edit pairs, which contain both novel and complex single-turn edits, as well as challenging multi-turn tasks. To ensure the data quality, we employ a multi-stage pipeline that integrates a cutting-edge vision-language model, a detection model, a segmentation model, alongside task-specific in-painting procedures and strict post-processing. ImgEdit surpasses existing datasets in both task novelty and data quality. Using ImgEdit, we train ImgEdit-E1, an editing model using Vision Language Model to process the reference image and editing prompt, which outperforms existing open-source models on multiple tasks, highlighting the value of ImgEdit and model design. For comprehensive evaluation, we introduce ImgEdit-Bench, a benchmark designed to evaluate image editing performance in terms of instruction adherence, editing quality, and detail preservation. It includes a basic testsuite, a challenging single-turn suite, and a dedicated multi-turn suite. We evaluate both open-source and proprietary models, as well as ImgEdit-E1, providing deep analysis and actionable insights into the current behavior of image-editing models. The source data are publicly available on https://github.com/PKU-YuanGroup/ImgEdit.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:08:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20275</guid></item><item><title>UI-Genie: A Self-Improving Approach for Iteratively Boosting MLLM-based
  Mobile GUI Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21496</link><description>In this paper, we introduce UI-Genie, a self-improving framework addressing two key challenges in GUI agents: verification of trajectory outcome is challenging and high-quality training data are not scalable. These challenges are addressed by a reward model and a self-improving pipeline, respectively. The reward model, UI-Genie-RM, features an image-text interleaved architecture that efficiently pro- cesses historical context and unifies action-level and task-level rewards. To sup- port the training of UI-Genie-RM, we develop deliberately-designed data genera- tion strategies including rule-based verification, controlled trajectory corruption, and hard negative mining. To address the second challenge, a self-improvement pipeline progressively expands solvable complex GUI tasks by enhancing both the agent and reward models through reward-guided exploration and outcome verification in dynamic environments. For training the model, we generate UI- Genie-RM-517k and UI-Genie-Agent-16k, establishing the first reward-specific dataset for GUI agents while demonstrating high-quality synthetic trajectory gen- eration without manual annotation. Experimental results show that UI-Genie achieves state-of-the-art performance across multiple GUI agent benchmarks with three generations of data-model self-improvement. We open-source our complete framework implementation and generated datasets to facilitate further research in https://github.com/Euphoria16/UI-Genie.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 05:03:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21496</guid></item><item><title>Frame In-N-Out: Unbounded Controllable Image-to-Video Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21491</link><description>An efficient Diffusion Transformer architecture addresses controllability, temporal coherence, and detail synthesis in video generation using the Frame In and Frame Out technique.  					AI-generated summary 				 Controllability, temporal coherence, and detail synthesis remain the most critical challenges in video generation. In this paper, we focus on a commonly used yet underexplored cinematic technique known as Frame In and Frame Out. Specifically, starting from image-to-video generation, users can control the objects in the image to naturally leave the scene or provide breaking new identity references to enter the scene, guided by user-specified motion trajectory. To support this task, we introduce a new dataset curated semi-automatically, a comprehensive evaluation protocol targeting this setting, and an efficient identity-preserving motion-controllable video Diffusion Transformer architecture. Our evaluation shows that our proposed approach significantly outperforms existing baselines.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:20:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21491</guid></item><item><title>Active-O3: Empowering Multimodal Large Language Models with Active
  Perception via GRPO</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21457</link><description>A reinforcement learning framework, ACTIVE-O3, is proposed to equip Multimodal Large Language Models with active perception capabilities and tested across various tasks and benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Active vision, also known as active perception, refers to the process of actively selecting where and how to look in order to gather task-relevant information. It is a critical component of efficient perception and decision-making in humans and advanced embodied agents. Recently, the use of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) as central planning and decision-making modules in robotic systems has gained extensive attention. However, despite the importance of active perception in embodied intelligence, there is little to no exploration of how MLLMs can be equipped with or learn active perception capabilities. In this paper, we first provide a systematic definition of MLLM-based active perception tasks. We point out that the recently proposed GPT-o3 model's zoom-in search strategy can be regarded as a special case of active perception; however, it still suffers from low search efficiency and inaccurate region selection. To address these issues, we propose ACTIVE-O3, a purely reinforcement learning based training framework built on top of GRPO, designed to equip MLLMs with active perception capabilities. We further establish a comprehensive benchmark suite to evaluate ACTIVE-O3 across both general open-world tasks, such as small-object and dense object grounding, and domain-specific scenarios, including small object detection in remote sensing and autonomous driving, as well as fine-grained interactive segmentation. In addition, ACTIVE-O3 also demonstrates strong zero-shot reasoning abilities on the V* Benchmark, without relying on any explicit reasoning data. We hope that our work can provide a simple codebase and evaluation protocol to facilitate future research on active perception in MLLMs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:13:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21457</guid></item><item><title>SeePhys: Does Seeing Help Thinking? -- Benchmarking Vision-Based Physics
  Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19099</link><description>SeePhys, a multimodal benchmark, highlights challenges in LLMs' visual reasoning and physics-grounded problem-solving capabilities, especially in interpreting diagrams and reducing reliance on textual cues.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present SeePhys, a large-scale multimodal benchmark for LLM reasoning grounded in physics questions ranging from middle school to PhD qualifying exams. The benchmark covers 7 fundamental domains spanning the physics discipline, incorporating 21 categories of highly heterogeneous diagrams. In contrast to prior works where visual elements mainly serve auxiliary purposes, our benchmark features a substantial proportion of vision-essential problems (75\%) that mandate visual information extraction for correct solutions. Through extensive evaluation, we observe that even the most advanced visual reasoning models (e.g., Gemini-2.5-pro and o4-mini) achieve sub-60\% accuracy on our benchmark. These results reveal fundamental challenges in current large language models' visual understanding capabilities, particularly in: (i) establishing rigorous coupling between diagram interpretation and physics reasoning, and (ii) overcoming their persistent reliance on textual cues as cognitive shortcuts.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 03:05:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19099</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Prompt Engineering: Robust Behavior Control in LLMs via Steering
  Target Atoms</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20322</link><description>A novel method called Steering Target Atoms isolates and manipulates disentangled knowledge components in language models to improve safety, robustness, and flexibility, especially in adversarial scenarios.  					AI-generated summary 				 Precise control over language model generation is vital for ensuring both safety and reliability. Although prompt engineering and steering are commonly used to intervene in model behaviors, the vast number of parameters in models often results in highly intertwined internal representations. This interdependency can limit control precision and sometimes lead to unintended side effects. Recent research has explored the use of sparse autoencoders (SAE) to disentangle knowledge in high-dimensional spaces for steering. However, these applications have been limited to toy tasks owing to the nontrivial issue of locating atomic knowledge components. In this paper, we propose Steering Target Atoms (STA), a novel method that isolates and manipulates disentangled knowledge components to enhance safety. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach. Further analysis reveals that steering exhibits superior robustness and flexibility, particularly in adversarial scenarios. We also apply the steering strategy to the large reasoning model, confirming its effectiveness in precise reasoning control.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:05:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20322</guid></item><item><title>ViewSpatial-Bench: Evaluating Multi-perspective Spatial Localization in
  Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21500</link><description>Vision-language models (VLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in understanding and reasoning about visual content, but significant challenges persist in tasks requiring cross-viewpoint understanding and spatial reasoning. We identify a critical limitation: current VLMs excel primarily at egocentric spatial reasoning (from the camera's perspective) but fail to generalize to allocentric viewpoints when required to adopt another entity's spatial frame of reference. We introduce ViewSpatial-Bench, the first comprehensive benchmark designed specifically for multi-viewpoint spatial localization recognition evaluation across five distinct task types, supported by an automated 3D annotation pipeline that generates precise directional labels. Comprehensive evaluation of diverse VLMs on ViewSpatial-Bench reveals a significant performance disparity: models demonstrate reasonable performance on camera-perspective tasks but exhibit reduced accuracy when reasoning from a human viewpoint. By fine-tuning VLMs on our multi-perspective spatial dataset, we achieve an overall performance improvement of 46.24% across tasks, highlighting the efficacy of our approach. Our work establishes a crucial benchmark for spatial intelligence in embodied AI systems and provides empirical evidence that modeling 3D spatial relationships enhances VLMs' corresponding spatial comprehension capabilities.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 04:51:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21500</guid></item><item><title>DetailFlow: 1D Coarse-to-Fine Autoregressive Image Generation via
  Next-Detail Prediction</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21473</link><description>This paper presents DetailFlow, a coarse-to-fine 1D autoregressive (AR) image generation method that models images through a novel next-detail prediction strategy. By learning a resolution-aware token sequence supervised with progressively degraded images, DetailFlow enables the generation process to start from the global structure and incrementally refine details. This coarse-to-fine 1D token sequence aligns well with the autoregressive inference mechanism, providing a more natural and efficient way for the AR model to generate complex visual content. Our compact 1D AR model achieves high-quality image synthesis with significantly fewer tokens than previous approaches, i.e. VAR/VQGAN. We further propose a parallel inference mechanism with self-correction that accelerates generation speed by approximately 8x while reducing accumulation sampling error inherent in teacher-forcing supervision. On the ImageNet 256x256 benchmark, our method achieves 2.96 gFID with 128 tokens, outperforming VAR (3.3 FID) and FlexVAR (3.05 FID), which both require 680 tokens in their AR models. Moreover, due to the significantly reduced token count and parallel inference mechanism, our method runs nearly 2x faster inference speed compared to VAR and FlexVAR. Extensive experimental results demonstrate DetailFlow's superior generation quality and efficiency compared to existing state-of-the-art methods.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 04:05:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21473</guid></item><item><title>Minute-Long Videos with Dual Parallelisms</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21070</link><description>A distributed inference strategy, DualParal, is proposed to address high processing latency and memory costs in diffusion transformer-based video diffusion models by parallelizing frames and layers across GPUs with a block-wise denoising scheme and feature cache.  					AI-generated summary 				 Diffusion Transformer (DiT)-based video diffusion models generate high-quality videos at scale but incur prohibitive processing latency and memory costs for long videos. To address this, we propose a novel distributed inference strategy, termed DualParal. The core idea is that, instead of generating an entire video on a single GPU, we parallelize both temporal frames and model layers across GPUs. However, a naive implementation of this division faces a key limitation: since diffusion models require synchronized noise levels across frames, this implementation leads to the serialization of original parallelisms. We leverage a block-wise denoising scheme to handle this. Namely, we process a sequence of frame blocks through the pipeline with progressively decreasing noise levels. Each GPU handles a specific block and layer subset while passing previous results to the next GPU, enabling asynchronous computation and communication. To further optimize performance, we incorporate two key enhancements. Firstly, a feature cache is implemented on each GPU to store and reuse features from the prior block as context, minimizing inter-GPU communication and redundant computation. Secondly, we employ a coordinated noise initialization strategy, ensuring globally consistent temporal dynamics by sharing initial noise patterns across GPUs without extra resource costs. Together, these enable fast, artifact-free, and infinitely long video generation. Applied to the latest diffusion transformer video generator, our method efficiently produces 1,025-frame videos with up to 6.54times lower latency and 1.48times lower memory cost on 8timesRTX 4090 GPUs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:11:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21070</guid></item><item><title>SoloSpeech: Enhancing Intelligibility and Quality in Target Speech
  Extraction through a Cascaded Generative Pipeline</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19314</link><description>SoloSpeech, a cascaded generative pipeline, improves target speech extraction and speech separation by addressing artifact introduction, naturalness reduction, and environment mismatches, achieving state-of-the-art intelligibility and quality.  					AI-generated summary 				 Target Speech Extraction (TSE) aims to isolate a target speaker's voice from a mixture of multiple speakers by leveraging speaker-specific cues, typically provided as auxiliary audio (a.k.a. cue audio). Although recent advancements in TSE have primarily employed discriminative models that offer high perceptual quality, these models often introduce unwanted artifacts, reduce naturalness, and are sensitive to discrepancies between training and testing environments. On the other hand, generative models for TSE lag in perceptual quality and intelligibility. To address these challenges, we present SoloSpeech, a novel cascaded generative pipeline that integrates compression, extraction, reconstruction, and correction processes. SoloSpeech features a speaker-embedding-free target extractor that utilizes conditional information from the cue audio's latent space, aligning it with the mixture audio's latent space to prevent mismatches. Evaluated on the widely-used Libri2Mix dataset, SoloSpeech achieves the new state-of-the-art intelligibility and quality in target speech extraction and speech separation tasks while demonstrating exceptional generalization on out-of-domain data and real-world scenarios.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:36:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19314</guid></item><item><title>Sci-Fi: Symmetric Constraint for Frame Inbetweening</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21205</link><description>A novel framework named Sci-Fi addresses the inconsistency in frame control strength by introducing a stronger end-frame constraint mechanism, improving harmonious transitions in frame inbetweening.  					AI-generated summary 				 Frame inbetweening aims to synthesize intermediate video sequences conditioned on the given start and end frames. Current state-of-the-art methods mainly extend large-scale pre-trained Image-to-Video Diffusion models (I2V-DMs) by incorporating end-frame constraints via directly fine-tuning or omitting training. We identify a critical limitation in their design: Their injections of the end-frame constraint usually utilize the same mechanism that originally imposed the start-frame (single image) constraint. However, since the original I2V-DMs are adequately trained for the start-frame condition in advance, naively introducing the end-frame constraint by the same mechanism with much less (even zero) specialized training probably can't make the end frame have a strong enough impact on the intermediate content like the start frame. This asymmetric control strength of the two frames over the intermediate content likely leads to inconsistent motion or appearance collapse in generated frames. To efficiently achieve symmetric constraints of start and end frames, we propose a novel framework, termed Sci-Fi, which applies a stronger injection for the constraint of a smaller training scale. Specifically, it deals with the start-frame constraint as before, while introducing the end-frame constraint by an improved mechanism. The new mechanism is based on a well-designed lightweight module, named EF-Net, which encodes only the end frame and expands it into temporally adaptive frame-wise features injected into the I2V-DM. This makes the end-frame constraint as strong as the start-frame constraint, enabling our Sci-Fi to produce more harmonious transitions in various scenarios. Extensive experiments prove the superiority of our Sci-Fi compared with other baselines.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 02:10:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21205</guid></item><item><title>VisualToolAgent (VisTA): A Reinforcement Learning Framework for Visual
  Tool Selection</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20289</link><description>VisTA, a reinforcement learning framework, enhances visual reasoning by autonomously selecting and combining tools from a diverse library without extensive human supervision.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce VisTA, a new reinforcement learning framework that empowers visual agents to dynamically explore, select, and combine tools from a diverse library based on empirical performance. Existing methods for tool-augmented reasoning either rely on training-free prompting or large-scale fine-tuning; both lack active tool exploration and typically assume limited tool diversity, and fine-tuning methods additionally demand extensive human supervision. In contrast, VisTA leverages end-to-end reinforcement learning to iteratively refine sophisticated, query-specific tool selection strategies, using task outcomes as feedback signals. Through Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO), our framework enables an agent to autonomously discover effective tool-selection pathways without requiring explicit reasoning supervision. Experiments on the ChartQA, Geometry3K, and BlindTest benchmarks demonstrate that VisTA achieves substantial performance gains over training-free baselines, especially on out-of-distribution examples. These results highlight VisTA's ability to enhance generalization, adaptively utilize diverse tools, and pave the way for flexible, experience-driven visual reasoning systems.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 03:21:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.20289</guid></item><item><title>Don't Overthink it. Preferring Shorter Thinking Chains for Improved LLM
  Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.17813</link><description>Reasoning large language models (LLMs) heavily rely on scaling test-time compute to perform complex reasoning tasks by generating extensive "thinking" chains. While demonstrating impressive results, this approach incurs significant computational costs and inference time. In this work, we challenge the assumption that long thinking chains results in better reasoning capabilities. We first demonstrate that shorter reasoning chains within individual questions are significantly more likely to yield correct answers - up to 34.5% more accurate than the longest chain sampled for the same question. Based on these results, we suggest short-m@k, a novel reasoning LLM inference method. Our method executes k independent generations in parallel and halts computation once the first m thinking processes are done. The final answer is chosen using majority voting among these m chains. Basic short-1@k demonstrates similar or even superior performance over standard majority voting in low-compute settings - using up to 40% fewer thinking tokens. short-3@k, while slightly less efficient than short-1@k, consistently surpasses majority voting across all compute budgets, while still being substantially faster (up to 33% wall time reduction). Inspired by our results, we finetune an LLM using short, long, and randomly selected reasoning chains. We then observe that training on the shorter ones leads to better performance. Our findings suggest rethinking current methods of test-time compute in reasoning LLMs, emphasizing that longer "thinking" does not necessarily translate to improved performance and can, counter-intuitively, lead to degraded results.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 04:07:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.17813</guid></item><item><title>Adversarial Attacks against Closed-Source MLLMs via Feature Optimal
  Alignment</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21494</link><description>Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) remain vulnerable to transferable adversarial examples. While existing methods typically achieve targeted attacks by aligning global features-such as CLIP's [CLS] token-between adversarial and target samples, they often overlook the rich local information encoded in patch tokens. This leads to suboptimal alignment and limited transferability, particularly for closed-source models. To address this limitation, we propose a targeted transferable adversarial attack method based on feature optimal alignment, called FOA-Attack, to improve adversarial transfer capability. Specifically, at the global level, we introduce a global feature loss based on cosine similarity to align the coarse-grained features of adversarial samples with those of target samples. At the local level, given the rich local representations within Transformers, we leverage clustering techniques to extract compact local patterns to alleviate redundant local features. We then formulate local feature alignment between adversarial and target samples as an optimal transport (OT) problem and propose a local clustering optimal transport loss to refine fine-grained feature alignment. Additionally, we propose a dynamic ensemble model weighting strategy to adaptively balance the influence of multiple models during adversarial example generation, thereby further improving transferability. Extensive experiments across various models demonstrate the superiority of the proposed method, outperforming state-of-the-art methods, especially in transferring to closed-source MLLMs. The code is released at https://github.com/jiaxiaojunQAQ/FOA-Attack.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 04:00:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.21494</guid></item><item><title>Improving Chemical Understanding of LLMs via SMILES Parsing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.16340</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly recognized as powerful tools for scientific discovery, particularly in molecular science. A fundamental requirement for these models is the ability to accurately understand molecular structures, commonly encoded in the SMILES representation. However, current LLMs struggle to interpret SMILES, even failing to carry out basic tasks such as counting molecular rings. To address this limitation, we introduce CLEANMOL, a novel framework that formulates SMILES parsing into a suite of clean and deterministic tasks explicitly designed to promote graph-level molecular comprehension. These tasks span from subgraph matching to global graph matching, providing structured supervision aligned with molecular structural properties. We construct a molecular pretraining dataset with adaptive difficulty scoring and pre-train open-source LLMs on these tasks. Our results show that CLEANMOL not only enhances structural comprehension but also achieves the best or competes with the baseline on the Mol-Instructions benchmark.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 04:29:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.16340</guid></item></channel></rss>