<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Dynamic Large Concept Models: Latent Reasoning in an Adaptive Semantic Space</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.24617</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) apply uniform computation to all tokens, despite language exhibiting highly non-uniform information density. This token-uniform regime wastes capacity on locally predictable spans while under-allocating computation to semantically critical transitions. We propose Dynamic Large Concept Models (DLCM), a hierarchical language modeling framework that learns semantic boundaries from latent representations and shifts computation from tokens to a compressed concept space where reasoning is more efficient. DLCM discovers variable-length concepts end-to-end without relying on predefined linguistic units. Hierarchical compression fundamentally changes scaling behavior. We introduce the first compression-aware scaling law, which disentangles token-level capacity, concept-level reasoning capacity, and compression ratio, enabling principled compute allocation under fixed FLOPs. To stably train this heterogeneous architecture, we further develop a decoupled μP parametrization that supports zero-shot hyperparameter transfer across widths and compression regimes. At a practical setting (R=4, corresponding to an average of four tokens per concept), DLCM reallocates roughly one-third of inference compute into a higher-capacity reasoning backbone, achieving a +2.69\% average improvement across 12 zero-shot benchmarks under matched inference FLOPs.</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 02:47:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.24617</guid></item><item><title>On the Role of Discreteness in Diffusion LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.22630</link><description>Diffusion models offer appealing properties for language generation, such as parallel decoding and iterative refinement, but the discrete and highly structured nature of text challenges the direct application of diffusion principles. In this paper, we revisit diffusion language modeling from the view of diffusion process and language modeling, and outline five properties that separate diffusion mechanics from language-specific requirements. We first categorize existing approaches into continuous diffusion in embedding space and discrete diffusion over tokens. We then show that each satisfies only part of the five essential properties and therefore reflects a structural trade-off. Through analyses of recent large diffusion language models, we identify two central issues: (i) uniform corruption does not respect how information is distributed across positions, and (ii) token-wise marginal training cannot capture multi-token dependencies during parallel decoding. These observations motivate diffusion processes that align more closely with the structure of text, and encourage future work toward more coherent diffusion language models.</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 02:53:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.22630</guid></item></channel></rss>