<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>🔥 AgenticAI: The Ultimate Multimodal AI with 16 MBTI Girlfriend Personas! 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/seawolf2357/796388354612946</link><description>🔥 AgenticAI: The Ultimate Multimodal AI with 16 MBTI Girlfriend Personas! 🔥 Hello AI community! Today, our team is thrilled to introduce AgenticAI, an innovative open-source AI assistant that combines deep technical capabilities with uniquely personalized interaction. 💘 🛠️ MBTI 16 Types SPACES Collections link seawolf2357/heartsync-mbti-67f793d752ef1fa542e16560 ✨ 16 MBTI Girlfriend Personas Complete MBTI Implementation: All 16 MBTI female personas modeled after iconic characters (Dana Scully, Lara Croft, etc.) Persona Depth: Customize age groups and thinking patterns for hyper-personalized AI interactions Personality Consistency: Each MBTI type demonstrates consistent problem-solving approaches, conversation patterns, and emotional expressions 🚀 Cutting-Edge Multimodal Capabilities Integrated File Analysis: Deep analysis and cross-referencing of images, videos, CSV, PDF, and TXT files Advanced Image Understanding: Interprets complex diagrams, mathematical equations, charts, and...</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/seawolf2357/796388354612946</guid></item><item><title>Shanghai AI Lab - OpenGV team just released InternVL3 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/929657833669065</link><description>Shanghai AI Lab - OpenGV team just released InternVL3 🔥 OpenGVLab/internvl3-67f7f690be79c2fe9d74fe9d ✨ 1/2/8/9/14/38/28B with MIT license ✨ Stronger perception &amp; reasoning vs InternVL 2.5 ✨ Native Multimodal Pre-Training for even better language performance See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/929657833669065</guid></item><item><title>I have made a Rust project with integration of the latest state-of-the-art model for object detection, it outperforms YOLO!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Yehor/936075739202200</link><description>I have made a Rust project with integration of the latest state-of-the-art model for object detection, it outperforms YOLO! Check it out: https://github.com/egorsmkv/rf-detr-usls See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Yehor/936075739202200</guid></item><item><title>**Video**:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/JLouisBiz/947336957437059</link><description>**Video**: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jRKRsGsLfW0 **Integrating large language model with file manager to describe your illegally downloaded movies.** When you have a bunch of movies downloaded by Torrent, you maybe want a description and description is missing. This video shows how you can use the script to invoke the large language model. And then you get a description of a movie in a second or three. See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/JLouisBiz/947336957437059</guid></item><item><title>Super grateful to</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/odellus/648294233512756</link><description>Super grateful to @ marriola for the release of the block diffusion code and model. I'm generating text with diffusion locally! Couldn't be more pleased. See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/odellus/648294233512756</guid></item><item><title>PiFlash</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/S-Dreamer/228566884248971</link><description>PiFlash A simple web-based tool to flash Raspberry Pi OS images to your SD cards. No additional software required! S-Dreamer/piflash See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/S-Dreamer/228566884248971</guid></item><item><title>🚀 We tried something new!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/225557458891562</link><description>🚀 We tried something new! We just published a dataset using a new (for us) preference modality: direct ranking based on aesthetic preference. We ranked a couple of thousand images from most to least preferred, all sampled from the Open Image Preferences v1 dataset by the amazing @ data-is-better-together team. 📊 Check it out here: Rapidata/2k-ranked-images-open-image-preferences-v1 We're really curious to hear your thoughts! Is this kind of ranking interesting or useful to you? Let us know! 💬 If it is, please consider leaving a ❤️ and if we hit 30 ❤️s, we’ll go ahead and rank the full 17k image dataset! See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/225557458891562</guid></item><item><title>Google published a 69-page whitepaper on Prompt Engineering and its best practices, a must-read if you are using LLMs in production:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/hesamation/789492772324435</link><description>Google published a 69-page whitepaper on Prompt Engineering and its best practices, a must-read if you are using LLMs in production: &gt; zero-shot, one-shot, few-shot &gt; system prompting &gt; chain-of-thought (CoT) &gt; ReAct LINK: https://www.kaggle.com/whitepaper-prompt-engineering &gt; code prompting &gt; best practices See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/hesamation/789492772324435</guid></item><item><title>I'm looking for a YouTube video summarizer to run locally.  I did a search, but all of the models and spaces I was able to find here didn't work, which I find surprising, since it's a great tool I already use.  Perhaps one of you can provide a better option, or just tell me what this actually is to get it:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Fishtiks/595357291314987</link><description>I'm looking for a YouTube video summarizer to run locally. I did a search, but all of the models and spaces I was able to find here didn't work, which I find surprising, since it's a great tool I already use. Perhaps one of you can provide a better option, or just tell me what this actually is to get it: https://dev.gptcall.pages.dev/chat#id=&amp;contactName=Youtube+summarizer Other functionality I'd like to see is a genre-based music creation and alteration model. "Make it country" or "do a freestyle rap," as examples. I'm willing to work with someone on this, because I'd need help understanding. I'd also like to make medical AI, like Dr. Samantha, that functions like a PDR well, and doesn't get confused by drug names. See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Fishtiks/595357291314987</guid></item><item><title>What if intelligence didn’t belong to the rich?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/nomadicsynth/772723579239178</link><description>What if intelligence didn’t belong to the rich? What if insight, planning, and innovation were available to everyone? What if we actually leveled the playing field — not by force, but by toolset? See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:18:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/nomadicsynth/772723579239178</guid></item></channel></rss>