<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Test-Time Scaling with Reflective Generative Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01951</link><description>MetaStone-S1, a reflective generative model using a self-supervised process reward model, achieves efficient reasoning and scalable performance with fewer parameters compared to existing models.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce our first reflective generative model MetaStone-S1, which obtains OpenAI o3's performance via the self-supervised process reward model (SPRM). Through sharing the backbone network and using task-specific heads for next token prediction and process scoring respectively, SPRM successfully integrates the policy model and process reward model(PRM) into a unified interface without extra process annotation, reducing over 99% PRM parameters for efficient reasoning. Equipped with SPRM, MetaStone-S1 is naturally suitable for test time scaling (TTS), and we provide three reasoning effort modes (low, medium, and high), based on the controllable thinking length. Moreover, we empirically establish a scaling law that reveals the relationship between total thinking computation and TTS performance. Experiments demonstrate that our MetaStone-S1 achieves comparable performance to OpenAI-o3-mini's series with only 32B parameter size. To support the research community, we have open-sourced MetaStone-S1 at https://github.com/MetaStone-AI/MetaStone-S1.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 02:12:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01951</guid></item><item><title>CLiFT: Compressive Light-Field Tokens for Compute-Efficient and Adaptive
  Neural Rendering</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08776</link><description>A neural rendering method uses compressed light-field tokens to efficiently represent scenes and render novel views with varying compute budgets.  					AI-generated summary 				 This paper proposes a neural rendering approach that represents a scene as "compressed light-field tokens (CLiFTs)", retaining rich appearance and geometric information of a scene. CLiFT enables compute-efficient rendering by compressed tokens, while being capable of changing the number of tokens to represent a scene or render a novel view with one trained network. Concretely, given a set of images, multi-view encoder tokenizes the images with the camera poses. Latent-space K-means selects a reduced set of rays as cluster centroids using the tokens. The multi-view ``condenser'' compresses the information of all the tokens into the centroid tokens to construct CLiFTs. At test time, given a target view and a compute budget (i.e., the number of CLiFTs), the system collects the specified number of nearby tokens and synthesizes a novel view using a compute-adaptive renderer. Extensive experiments on RealEstate10K and DL3DV datasets quantitatively and qualitatively validate our approach, achieving significant data reduction with comparable rendering quality and the highest overall rendering score, while providing trade-offs of data size, rendering quality, and rendering speed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 01:37:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08776</guid></item><item><title>NeuralOS: Towards Simulating Operating Systems via Neural Generative
  Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08800</link><description>NeuralOS uses a combination of RNNs and diffusion-based rendering to simulate OS GUIs by predicting screen frames from user inputs, demonstrating realistic GUI rendering and state transitions.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce NeuralOS, a neural framework that simulates graphical user interfaces (GUIs) of operating systems by directly predicting screen frames in response to user inputs such as mouse movements, clicks, and keyboard events. NeuralOS combines a recurrent neural network (RNN), which tracks computer state, with a diffusion-based neural renderer that generates screen images. The model is trained on a large-scale dataset of Ubuntu XFCE recordings, which include both randomly generated interactions and realistic interactions produced by AI agents. Experiments show that NeuralOS successfully renders realistic GUI sequences, accurately captures mouse interactions, and reliably predicts state transitions like application launches. Although modeling fine-grained keyboard interactions precisely remains challenging, NeuralOS offers a step toward creating fully adaptive, generative neural interfaces for future human-computer interaction systems.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 02:40:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08800</guid></item><item><title>Neural-Driven Image Editing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05397</link><description>LoongX uses multimodal neurophysiological signals and diffusion models for hands-free image editing, achieving performance comparable to text-driven methods and outperforming them when combined with speech.  					AI-generated summary 				 Traditional image editing typically relies on manual prompting, making it labor-intensive and inaccessible to individuals with limited motor control or language abilities. Leveraging recent advances in brain-computer interfaces (BCIs) and generative models, we propose LoongX, a hands-free image editing approach driven by multimodal neurophysiological signals. LoongX utilizes state-of-the-art diffusion models trained on a comprehensive dataset of 23,928 image editing pairs, each paired with synchronized electroencephalography (EEG), functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS), photoplethysmography (PPG), and head motion signals that capture user intent. To effectively address the heterogeneity of these signals, LoongX integrates two key modules. The cross-scale state space (CS3) module encodes informative modality-specific features. The dynamic gated fusion (DGF) module further aggregates these features into a unified latent space, which is then aligned with edit semantics via fine-tuning on a diffusion transformer (DiT). Additionally, we pre-train the encoders using contrastive learning to align cognitive states with semantic intentions from embedded natural language. Extensive experiments demonstrate that LoongX achieves performance comparable to text-driven methods (CLIP-I: 0.6605 vs. 0.6558; DINO: 0.4812 vs. 0.4636) and outperforms them when neural signals are combined with speech (CLIP-T: 0.2588 vs. 0.2549). These results highlight the promise of neural-driven generative models in enabling accessible, intuitive image editing and open new directions for cognitive-driven creative technologies. Datasets and code will be released to support future work and foster progress in this emerging area.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 06:23:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05397</guid></item><item><title>KV Cache Steering for Inducing Reasoning in Small Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08799</link><description>Cache steering improves reasoning in language models through a single intervention in the key-value cache, enhancing both reasoning structure and task performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 We propose cache steering, a lightweight method for implicit steering of language models via a one-shot intervention applied directly to the key-value cache. To validate its effectiveness, we apply cache steering to induce chain-of-thought reasoning in small language models. Our approach leverages GPT-4o-generated reasoning traces to construct steering vectors that shift model behavior toward more explicit, multi-step reasoning without fine-tuning or prompt modifications. Experimental evaluations on diverse reasoning benchmarks demonstrate that cache steering improves both the qualitative structure of model reasoning and quantitative task performance. Compared to prior activation steering techniques that require continuous interventions, our one-shot cache steering offers substantial advantages in terms of hyperparameter stability, inference-time efficiency, and ease of integration, making it a more robust and practical solution for controlled generation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 07:10:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08799</guid></item><item><title>Lumos-1: On Autoregressive Video Generation from a Unified Model
  Perspective</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08801</link><description>Lumos-1 is an autoregressive video generator that uses a modified LLM architecture with MM-RoPE and AR-DF to address spatiotemporal correlation and frame-wise loss imbalance, achieving competitive performance with fewer resources.  					AI-generated summary 				 Autoregressive large language models (LLMs) have unified a vast range of language tasks, inspiring preliminary efforts in autoregressive video generation. Existing autoregressive video generators either diverge from standard LLM architectures, depend on bulky external text encoders, or incur prohibitive latency due to next-token decoding. In this paper, we introduce Lumos-1, an autoregressive video generator that retains the LLM architecture with minimal architectural modifications. To inject spatiotemporal correlations in LLMs, we identify the efficacy of incorporating 3D RoPE and diagnose its imbalanced frequency spectrum ranges. Therefore, we propose MM-RoPE, a RoPE scheme that preserves the original textual RoPE while providing comprehensive frequency spectra and scaled 3D positions for modeling multimodal spatiotemporal data. Moreover, Lumos-1 resorts to a token dependency strategy that obeys intra-frame bidirectionality and inter-frame temporal causality. Based on this dependency strategy, we identify the issue of frame-wise loss imbalance caused by spatial information redundancy and solve it by proposing Autoregressive Discrete Diffusion Forcing (AR-DF). AR-DF introduces temporal tube masking during training with a compatible inference-time masking policy to avoid quality degradation. By using memory-efficient training techniques, we pre-train Lumos-1 on only 48 GPUs, achieving performance comparable to EMU3 on GenEval, COSMOS-Video2World on VBench-I2V, and OpenSoraPlan on VBench-T2V. Code and models are available at https://github.com/alibaba-damo-academy/Lumos.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 02:48:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08801</guid></item><item><title>From One to More: Contextual Part Latents for 3D Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08772</link><description>A part-aware diffusion framework, CoPart, enhances 3D generation by decomposing objects into contextual parts, improving complexity handling, relationship modeling, and part-level conditioning.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in 3D generation have transitioned from multi-view 2D rendering approaches to 3D-native latent diffusion frameworks that exploit geometric priors in ground truth data. Despite progress, three key limitations persist: (1) Single-latent representations fail to capture complex multi-part geometries, causing detail degradation; (2) Holistic latent coding neglects part independence and interrelationships critical for compositional design; (3) Global conditioning mechanisms lack fine-grained controllability. Inspired by human 3D design workflows, we propose CoPart - a part-aware diffusion framework that decomposes 3D objects into contextual part latents for coherent multi-part generation. This paradigm offers three advantages: i) Reduces encoding complexity through part decomposition; ii) Enables explicit part relationship modeling; iii) Supports part-level conditioning. We further develop a mutual guidance strategy to fine-tune pre-trained diffusion models for joint part latent denoising, ensuring both geometric coherence and foundation model priors. To enable large-scale training, we construct Partverse - a novel 3D part dataset derived from Objaverse through automated mesh segmentation and human-verified annotations. Extensive experiments demonstrate CoPart's superior capabilities in part-level editing, articulated object generation, and scene composition with unprecedented controllability.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 02:35:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08772</guid></item><item><title>One Token to Fool LLM-as-a-Judge</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08794</link><description>Generative reward models using LLMs are vulnerable to superficial manipulations but can be improved with data augmentation strategies.  					AI-generated summary 				 Generative reward models (also known as LLMs-as-judges), which use large language models (LLMs) to evaluate answer quality, are increasingly adopted in reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards (RLVR). They are often preferred over rigid rule-based metrics, especially for complex reasoning tasks involving free-form outputs. In this paradigm, an LLM is typically prompted to compare a candidate answer against a ground-truth reference and assign a binary reward indicating correctness. Despite the seeming simplicity of this comparison task, we find that generative reward models exhibit surprising vulnerabilities to superficial manipulations: non-word symbols (e.g., ":" or ".") or reasoning openers like "Thought process:" and "Let's solve this problem step by step." can often lead to false positive rewards. We demonstrate that this weakness is widespread across LLMs, datasets, and prompt formats, posing a serious threat for core algorithmic paradigms that rely on generative reward models, such as rejection sampling, preference optimization, and RLVR. To mitigate this issue, we introduce a simple yet effective data augmentation strategy and train a new generative reward model with substantially improved robustness. Our findings highlight the urgent need for more reliable LLM-based evaluation methods. We release our robust, general-domain reward model and its synthetic training data at https://huggingface.co/sarosavo/Master-RM and https://huggingface.co/datasets/sarosavo/Master-RM.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 03:34:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08794</guid></item><item><title>Vision Foundation Models as Effective Visual Tokenizers for
  Autoregressive Image Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08441</link><description>A novel image tokenizer built on pre-trained vision foundation models improves image reconstruction, generation quality, and token efficiency, enhancing autoregressive generation and class-conditional synthesis.  					AI-generated summary 				 Leveraging the powerful representations of pre-trained vision foundation models -- traditionally used for visual comprehension -- we explore a novel direction: building an image tokenizer directly atop such models, a largely underexplored area. Specifically, we employ a frozen vision foundation model as the encoder of our tokenizer. To enhance its effectiveness, we introduce two key components: (1) a region-adaptive quantization framework that reduces redundancy in the pre-trained features on regular 2D grids, and (2) a semantic reconstruction objective that aligns the tokenizer's outputs with the foundation model's representations to preserve semantic fidelity. Based on these designs, our proposed image tokenizer, VFMTok, achieves substantial improvements in image reconstruction and generation quality, while also enhancing token efficiency. It further boosts autoregressive (AR) generation -- achieving a gFID of 2.07 on ImageNet benchmarks, while accelerating model convergence by three times, and enabling high-fidelity class-conditional synthesis without the need for classifier-free guidance (CFG). The code will be released publicly to benefit the community.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 07:56:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08441</guid></item><item><title>What Has a Foundation Model Found? Using Inductive Bias to Probe for
  World Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06952</link><description>Foundation models, despite excelling in training tasks, often fail to generalize to new tasks due to task-specific heuristics rather than capturing underlying world models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Foundation models are premised on the idea that sequence prediction can uncover deeper domain understanding, much like how Kepler's predictions of planetary motion later led to the discovery of Newtonian mechanics. However, evaluating whether these models truly capture deeper structure remains a challenge. We develop a technique for evaluating foundation models that examines how they adapt to synthetic datasets generated from some postulated world model. Our technique measures whether the foundation model's inductive bias aligns with the world model, and so we refer to it as an inductive bias probe. Across multiple domains, we find that foundation models can excel at their training tasks yet fail to develop inductive biases towards the underlying world model when adapted to new tasks. We particularly find that foundation models trained on orbital trajectories consistently fail to apply Newtonian mechanics when adapted to new physics tasks. Further analysis reveals that these models behave as if they develop task-specific heuristics that fail to generalize.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 05:57:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06952</guid></item><item><title>BlockFFN: Towards End-Side Acceleration-Friendly Mixture-of-Experts with
  Chunk-Level Activation Sparsity</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08771</link><description>To alleviate the computational burden of large language models (LLMs), architectures with activation sparsity, represented by mixture-of-experts (MoE), have attracted increasing attention. However, the non-differentiable and inflexible routing of vanilla MoE hurts model performance. Moreover, while each token activates only a few parameters, these sparsely-activated architectures exhibit low chunk-level sparsity, indicating that the union of multiple consecutive tokens activates a large ratio of parameters. Such a sparsity pattern is unfriendly for acceleration under low-resource conditions (e.g., end-side devices) and incompatible with mainstream acceleration techniques (e.g., speculative decoding). To address these challenges, we introduce a novel MoE architecture, BlockFFN, as well as its efficient training and deployment techniques. Specifically, we use a router integrating ReLU activation and RMSNorm for differentiable and flexible routing. Next, to promote both token-level sparsity (TLS) and chunk-level sparsity (CLS), CLS-aware training objectives are designed, making BlockFFN more acceleration-friendly. Finally, we implement efficient acceleration kernels, combining activation sparsity and speculative decoding for the first time. The experimental results demonstrate the superior performance of BlockFFN over other MoE baselines, achieving over 80% TLS and 70% 8-token CLS. Our kernels achieve up to 3.67times speedup on real end-side devices than dense models. All codes and checkpoints are available publicly (https://github.com/thunlp/BlockFFN).</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 04:54:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.08771</guid></item><item><title>Robust Multimodal Large Language Models Against Modality Conflict</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.07151</link><description>Investigation of modality conflict in multimodal large language models reveals its role in causing hallucinations, with reinforcement learning emerging as the most effective mitigation strategy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Despite the impressive capabilities of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) in vision-language tasks, they are prone to hallucinations in real-world scenarios. This paper investigates the hallucination phenomenon in MLLMs from the perspective of modality conflict. Unlike existing works focusing on the conflicts between model responses and inputs, we study the inherent conflicts in inputs from different modalities that place MLLMs in a dilemma and directly lead to hallucinations. We formally define the modality conflict and construct a dataset named Multimodal Modality Conflict (MMMC) to simulate this phenomenon in vision-language tasks. Three methods based on prompt engineering, supervised fine-tuning, and reinforcement learning are proposed to alleviate the hallucination caused by modality conflict. Extensive experiments are conducted on the MMMC dataset to analyze the merits and demerits of these methods. Our results show that the reinforcement learning method achieves the best performance in mitigating the hallucination under modality conflict, while the supervised fine-tuning method shows promising and stable performance. Our work sheds light on the unnoticed modality conflict that leads to hallucinations and provides more insights into the robustness of MLLMs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 03:15:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.07151</guid></item></channel></rss>