<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Think Before Recommend: Unleashing the Latent Reasoning Power for
  Sequential Recommendation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22675</link><description>Sequential Recommendation (SeqRec) aims to predict the next item by capturing sequential patterns from users' historical interactions, playing a crucial role in many real-world recommender systems. However, existing approaches predominantly adopt a direct forward computation paradigm, where the final hidden state of the sequence encoder serves as the user representation. We argue that this inference paradigm, due to its limited computational depth, struggles to model the complex evolving nature of user preferences and lacks a nuanced understanding of long-tail items, leading to suboptimal performance. To address this issue, we propose ReaRec, the first inference-time computing framework for recommender systems, which enhances user representations through implicit multi-step reasoning. Specifically, ReaRec autoregressively feeds the sequence's last hidden state into the sequential recommender while incorporating special reasoning position embeddings to decouple the original item encoding space from the multi-step reasoning space. Moreover, we introduce two lightweight reasoning-based learning methods, Ensemble Reasoning Learning (ERL) and Progressive Reasoning Learning (PRL), to further effectively exploit ReaRec's reasoning potential. Extensive experiments on five public real-world datasets and different SeqRec architectures demonstrate the generality and effectiveness of our proposed ReaRec. Remarkably, post-hoc analyses reveal that ReaRec significantly elevates the performance ceiling of multiple sequential recommendation backbones by approximately 30\%-50\%. Thus, we believe this work can open a new and promising avenue for future research in inference-time computing for sequential recommendation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 01:59:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22675</guid></item><item><title>Exploring Data Scaling Trends and Effects in Reinforcement Learning from
  Human Feedback</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22230</link><description>Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) is crucial for aligning large language models with human preferences. While recent research has focused on algorithmic improvements, the importance of prompt-data construction has been overlooked. This paper addresses this gap by exploring data-driven bottlenecks in RLHF performance scaling, particularly reward hacking and decreasing response diversity. We introduce a hybrid reward system combining reasoning task verifiers (RTV) and a generative reward model (GenRM) to mitigate reward hacking. We also propose a novel prompt-selection method, Pre-PPO, to maintain response diversity and enhance learning effectiveness. Additionally, we find that prioritizing mathematical and coding tasks early in RLHF training significantly improves performance. Experiments across two model sizes validate our methods' effectiveness and scalability. Results show that RTV is most resistant to reward hacking, followed by GenRM with ground truth, and then GenRM with SFT Best-of-N responses. Our strategies enable rapid capture of subtle task-specific distinctions, leading to substantial improvements in overall RLHF performance. This work highlights the importance of careful data construction and provides practical methods to overcome performance barriers in RLHF.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 02:29:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22230</guid></item><item><title>ORIGEN: Zero-Shot 3D Orientation Grounding in Text-to-Image Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22194</link><description>We introduce ORIGEN, the first zero-shot method for 3D orientation grounding in text-to-image generation across multiple objects and diverse categories. While previous work on spatial grounding in image generation has mainly focused on 2D positioning, it lacks control over 3D orientation. To address this, we propose a reward-guided sampling approach using a pretrained discriminative model for 3D orientation estimation and a one-step text-to-image generative flow model. While gradient-ascent-based optimization is a natural choice for reward-based guidance, it struggles to maintain image realism. Instead, we adopt a sampling-based approach using Langevin dynamics, which extends gradient ascent by simply injecting random noise--requiring just a single additional line of code. Additionally, we introduce adaptive time rescaling based on the reward function to accelerate convergence. Our experiments show that ORIGEN outperforms both training-based and test-time guidance methods across quantitative metrics and user studies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 01:27:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22194</guid></item><item><title>PHYSICS: Benchmarking Foundation Models on University-Level Physics
  Problem Solving</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.21821</link><description>We introduce PHYSICS, a comprehensive benchmark for university-level physics problem solving. It contains 1297 expert-annotated problems covering six core areas: classical mechanics, quantum mechanics, thermodynamics and statistical mechanics, electromagnetism, atomic physics, and optics. Each problem requires advanced physics knowledge and mathematical reasoning. We develop a robust automated evaluation system for precise and reliable validation. Our evaluation of leading foundation models reveals substantial limitations. Even the most advanced model, o3-mini, achieves only 59.9% accuracy, highlighting significant challenges in solving high-level scientific problems. Through comprehensive error analysis, exploration of diverse prompting strategies, and Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG)-based knowledge augmentation, we identify key areas for improvement, laying the foundation for future advancements.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 02:37:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.21821</guid></item><item><title>Segment Any Motion in Videos</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22268</link><description>Moving object segmentation is a crucial task for achieving a high-level understanding of visual scenes and has numerous downstream applications. Humans can effortlessly segment moving objects in videos. Previous work has largely relied on optical flow to provide motion cues; however, this approach often results in imperfect predictions due to challenges such as partial motion, complex deformations, motion blur and background distractions. We propose a novel approach for moving object segmentation that combines long-range trajectory motion cues with DINO-based semantic features and leverages SAM2 for pixel-level mask densification through an iterative prompting strategy. Our model employs Spatio-Temporal Trajectory Attention and Motion-Semantic Decoupled Embedding to prioritize motion while integrating semantic support. Extensive testing on diverse datasets demonstrates state-of-the-art performance, excelling in challenging scenarios and fine-grained segmentation of multiple objects. Our code is available at https://motion-seg.github.io/.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 02:33:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22268</guid></item><item><title>Hi3DGen: High-fidelity 3D Geometry Generation from Images via Normal
  Bridging</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22236</link><description>With the growing demand for high-fidelity 3D models from 2D images, existing methods still face significant challenges in accurately reproducing fine-grained geometric details due to limitations in domain gaps and inherent ambiguities in RGB images. To address these issues, we propose Hi3DGen, a novel framework for generating high-fidelity 3D geometry from images via normal bridging. Hi3DGen consists of three key components: (1) an image-to-normal estimator that decouples the low-high frequency image pattern with noise injection and dual-stream training to achieve generalizable, stable, and sharp estimation; (2) a normal-to-geometry learning approach that uses normal-regularized latent diffusion learning to enhance 3D geometry generation fidelity; and (3) a 3D data synthesis pipeline that constructs a high-quality dataset to support training. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness and superiority of our framework in generating rich geometric details, outperforming state-of-the-art methods in terms of fidelity. Our work provides a new direction for high-fidelity 3D geometry generation from images by leveraging normal maps as an intermediate representation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 02:30:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22236</guid></item><item><title>Free4D: Tuning-free 4D Scene Generation with Spatial-Temporal
  Consistency</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.20785</link><description>We present Free4D, a novel tuning-free framework for 4D scene generation from a single image. Existing methods either focus on object-level generation, making scene-level generation infeasible, or rely on large-scale multi-view video datasets for expensive training, with limited generalization ability due to the scarcity of 4D scene data. In contrast, our key insight is to distill pre-trained foundation models for consistent 4D scene representation, which offers promising advantages such as efficiency and generalizability. 1) To achieve this, we first animate the input image using image-to-video diffusion models followed by 4D geometric structure initialization. 2) To turn this coarse structure into spatial-temporal consistent multiview videos, we design an adaptive guidance mechanism with a point-guided denoising strategy for spatial consistency and a novel latent replacement strategy for temporal coherence. 3) To lift these generated observations into consistent 4D representation, we propose a modulation-based refinement to mitigate inconsistencies while fully leveraging the generated information. The resulting 4D representation enables real-time, controllable rendering, marking a significant advancement in single-image-based 4D scene generation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 04:30:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.20785</guid></item><item><title>A Refined Analysis of Massive Activations in LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22329</link><description>Motivated in part by their relevance for low-precision training and quantization, massive activations in large language models (LLMs) have recently emerged as a topic of interest. However, existing analyses are limited in scope, and generalizability across architectures is unclear. This paper helps address some of these gaps by conducting an analysis of massive activations across a broad range of LLMs, including both GLU-based and non-GLU-based architectures. Our findings challenge several prior assumptions, most importantly: (1) not all massive activations are detrimental, i.e. suppressing them does not lead to an explosion of perplexity or a collapse in downstream task performance; (2) proposed mitigation strategies such as Attention KV bias are model-specific and ineffective in certain cases. We consequently investigate novel hybrid mitigation strategies; in particular pairing Target Variance Rescaling (TVR) with Attention KV bias or Dynamic Tanh (DyT) successfully balances the mitigation of massive activations with preserved downstream model performance in the scenarios we investigated. Our code is available at: https://github.com/bluorion-com/refine_massive_activations.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 02:47:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.22329</guid></item><item><title>SparseFlex: High-Resolution and Arbitrary-Topology 3D Shape Modeling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.21732</link><description>Creating high-fidelity 3D meshes with arbitrary topology, including open surfaces and complex interiors, remains a significant challenge. Existing implicit field methods often require costly and detail-degrading watertight conversion, while other approaches struggle with high resolutions. This paper introduces SparseFlex, a novel sparse-structured isosurface representation that enables differentiable mesh reconstruction at resolutions up to 1024^3 directly from rendering losses. SparseFlex combines the accuracy of Flexicubes with a sparse voxel structure, focusing computation on surface-adjacent regions and efficiently handling open surfaces. Crucially, we introduce a frustum-aware sectional voxel training strategy that activates only relevant voxels during rendering, dramatically reducing memory consumption and enabling high-resolution training. This also allows, for the first time, the reconstruction of mesh interiors using only rendering supervision. Building upon this, we demonstrate a complete shape modeling pipeline by training a variational autoencoder (VAE) and a rectified flow transformer for high-quality 3D shape generation. Our experiments show state-of-the-art reconstruction accuracy, with a ~82% reduction in Chamfer Distance and a ~88% increase in F-score compared to previous methods, and demonstrate the generation of high-resolution, detailed 3D shapes with arbitrary topology. By enabling high-resolution, differentiable mesh reconstruction and generation with rendering losses, SparseFlex significantly advances the state-of-the-art in 3D shape representation and modeling.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 02:52:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.21732</guid></item><item><title>MedAgent-Pro: Towards Multi-modal Evidence-based Medical Diagnosis via
  Reasoning Agentic Workflow</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.18968</link><description>Developing reliable AI systems to assist human clinicians in multi-modal medical diagnosis has long been a key objective for researchers. Recently, Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have gained significant attention and achieved success across various domains. With strong reasoning capabilities and the ability to perform diverse tasks based on user instructions, they hold great potential for enhancing medical diagnosis. However, directly applying MLLMs to the medical domain still presents challenges. They lack detailed perception of visual inputs, limiting their ability to perform quantitative image analysis, which is crucial for medical diagnostics. Additionally, MLLMs often exhibit hallucinations and inconsistencies in reasoning, whereas clinical diagnoses must adhere strictly to established criteria. To address these challenges, we propose MedAgent-Pro, an evidence-based reasoning agentic system designed to achieve reliable, explainable, and precise medical diagnoses. This is accomplished through a hierarchical workflow: at the task level, knowledge-based reasoning generate reliable diagnostic plans for specific diseases following retrieved clinical criteria. While at the case level, multiple tool agents process multi-modal inputs, analyze different indicators according to the plan, and provide a final diagnosis based on both quantitative and qualitative evidence. Comprehensive experiments on both 2D and 3D medical diagnosis tasks demonstrate the superiority and effectiveness of MedAgent-Pro, while case studies further highlight its reliability and interpretability. The code is available at https://github.com/jinlab-imvr/MedAgent-Pro.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 03:43:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.18968</guid></item></channel></rss>