<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>There is no anxiety quite like powering up 2KW of basement compute after rewiring it all. Small bit of trouble with the horizontal 3090 because I misread my motherboard manual, but otherwise so far so good.. Next we see if I've built up enough cooling to hit my target TDP on those 3-slot nvlinked cards especially.  The 4-slot bridges are much easier to work with but their prices went bananas and I couldn't acquire a second, so gotta get a little creative with intakes.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mike-ravkine/305096078349013</link><description>There is no anxiety quite like powering up 2KW of basement compute after rewiring it all. Small bit of trouble with the horizontal 3090 because I misread my motherboard manual, but otherwise so far so good.. Next we see if I've built up enough cooling to hit my target TDP on those 3-slot nvlinked cards especially. The 4-slot bridges are much easier to work with but their prices went bananas and I couldn't acquire a second, so gotta get a little creative with intakes. See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mike-ravkine/305096078349013</guid></item><item><title>Kimi K2 Thinking is now live on the hub 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/911192969719025</link><description>Kimi K2 Thinking is now live on the hub 🔥 moonshotai/Kimi-K2-Thinking ✨ 1T MoE for deep reasoning &amp; tool use ✨ Native INT4 quantization = 2× faster inference ✨ 256K context window ✨ Modified MIT license See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/911192969719025</guid></item><item><title>Hugging Face MCP Server v0.2.40</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/evalstate/266178055669254</link><description>Hugging Face MCP Server v0.2.40 ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ Improved progressive disclosure and descriptions for Jobs tool. See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/evalstate/266178055669254</guid></item><item><title>Load test conducted on the Feetech STS3250 servo motor.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/branikita/234092651364485</link><description>Load test conducted on the Feetech STS3250 servo motor. With a 2 kg load on a 100 mm arm, the motor operated near its limit. At higher acceleration settings, lifting performance decreased noticeably. The temperature increased from 40 °C to 70 °C within 8 minutes. The test highlights the torque and thermal constraints under sustained load conditions. #Robotics #Engineering #ServoMotor #Testing #Feetech #Automation #Mechatronics #Hardware See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/branikita/234092651364485</guid></item><item><title>Org Rate Limits = Free DDoS Invitation? 🤡</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/narugo1992/829929897247800</link><description>Org Rate Limits = Free DDoS Invitation? 🤡 One serious question: Is there any way to actually ban clowns abusing this system? Right now all it takes is one bored script kiddie with a grudge (or too much caffeine) to lawnmower an entire org's API endpoints into the stone age. They get to bathe in 429s while we're sitting here like 🤡 "Gee I wonder whose IP is carpet-bombing us today!" The kicker? Zero accountability. Zero fingerprints. Just vibes™ and chaos. It’s basically a public invitation to hold entire communities hostage while wearing pajamas. "Come for the open-source collaboration, stay for the unhinged DDoS piñata party!" 🎉 Fix when? See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/narugo1992/829929897247800</guid></item><item><title>Qwen Image Models Training - 0 to Hero Level Tutorial - LoRA &amp; Fine Tuning - Base &amp; Edit Model -</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/482948371636786</link><description>Qwen Image Models Training - 0 to Hero Level Tutorial - LoRA &amp; Fine Tuning - Base &amp; Edit Model - https://youtu.be/DPX3eBTuO_Y This is a full comprehensive step-by-step tutorial for how to train Qwen Image models. This tutorial covers how to do LoRA training and full Fine-Tuning / DreamBooth training on Qwen Image models. It covers both the Qwen Image base model and the Qwen Image Edit Plus 2509 model. This tutorial is the product of 21 days of full R&amp;D, costing over $800 in cloud services to find the best configurations for training. Furthermore, we have developed an amazing, ultra-easy-to-use Gradio app to use the legendary Kohya Musubi Tuner trainer with ease. You will be able to train locally on your Windows computer with GPUs with as little as 6 GB of VRAM for both LoRA and Fine-Tuning. Furthermore, I have shown how to train a character (person), a product (perfume) and a style (GTA5 artworks). Tutorial Link : https://youtu.be/DPX3eBTuO_Y See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/482948371636786</guid></item><item><title>FEETECH STS3250 Stall Torque and Repeatability Tests</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/branikita/935466322450846</link><description>FEETECH STS3250 Stall Torque and Repeatability Tests We recently tested the FEETECH STS3250 servo, comparing actual performance with the official specifications. While the datasheet lists a stall torque of 50 kg·cm at 12 V, our real-world measurements showed: - 25 kg·cm sustained torque after protection activation - Up to 48 kg·cm peak torque for a split second Although the built-in protection limits continuous stall torque, the servo demonstrated excellent stability and control precision. Precision and Repeatability: - Repeatability tolerance: ±0.02 mm at the end of a 95 mm arm - Smooth motion response with PID control and 12-bit (4096-step) magnetic encoder - Reliable performance for high-accuracy robotics and automation applications #Feetech #STS3250 #ServoTest #Robotics #Engineering #PrecisionControl #HardwareReview See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/branikita/935466322450846</guid></item><item><title>Introducing ToolsGen 🛠️</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/atasoglu/710262131050494</link><description>Introducing ToolsGen 🛠️ I built a tool to solve a problem I kept running into: creating quality datasets for training LLMs to use tools. ToolsGen takes your JSON tool definitions and automatically generates realistic user requests, corresponding tool calls, and evaluates them using an LLM-as-a-judge pipeline. It outputs datasets ready to use with Hugging Face. What makes it useful: - Generates realistic user requests + tool calls from JSON definitions - LLM-as-a-judge quality scoring with multi-dimensional rubrics - Multiple sampling strategies (random, parameter-aware, semantic) - OpenAI-compatible API support - Outputs JSONL with train/val splits Still early days (API isn't stable yet), but it's already helping me generate tool-calling datasets much faster. Check it out: https://github.com/atasoglu/toolsgen Happy to hear feedback or ideas! See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/atasoglu/710262131050494</guid></item><item><title>🧠 What Is SpeedPaint?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/wang12390/587232658251993</link><description>🧠 What Is SpeedPaint? SpeedPaint is an AI Speed Painting software that simulates how an artist paints — step by step, layer by layer — but at machine speed. Instead of generating a finished image instantly, it paints in motion, giving users a live-brush experience. Miragic-AI/Miragic-Speed-Painting https://miragic.ai/products/speed-painting See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/wang12390/587232658251993</guid></item><item><title>I just got asked about the differences between Blackwell systems and Grace Blackwell systems. What's the difference and how much of a performance gap is there between them?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/flozi00/605713086654593</link><description>I just got asked about the differences between Blackwell systems and Grace Blackwell systems. What's the difference and how much of a performance gap is there between them? https://flozi.net/en/hardware/nvidia/benchmarks/b200-vs-gb200-efficiency-comparison Here's a summary of the key points from the article: GB200 (Grace Blackwell) is a Superchip: It integrates a Grace CPU and two Blackwell GPUs into a single package. B200 is a GPU-only module: It's designed to be paired with x86 or ARM CPUs in more traditional server setups. Performance and Efficiency: Based on MLPerf Training v5.0 benchmarks, the article concludes: GB200 systems are approximately 42% more efficient than B200 systems on average. This is especially true in large-scale deployments (100+ GPUs), where the GB200's integrated design and high-speed NVLink interconnect provide a significant advantage. In smaller, single-node systems (e.g., 8 GPUs), the performance difference is much smaller, around 10-15%. Use Cases:...</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:26:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/flozi00/605713086654593</guid></item></channel></rss>