<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Memory in the Age of AI Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13564</link><description>This survey provides an updated overview of agent memory research, distinguishing its forms, functions, and dynamics, and highlights emerging research directions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Memory has emerged, and will continue to remain, a core capability of foundation model-based agents. As research on agent memory rapidly expands and attracts unprecedented attention, the field has also become increasingly fragmented. Existing works that fall under the umbrella of agent memory often differ substantially in their motivations, implementations, and evaluation protocols, while the proliferation of loosely defined memory terminologies has further obscured conceptual clarity. Traditional taxonomies such as long/short-term memory have proven insufficient to capture the diversity of contemporary agent memory systems. This work aims to provide an up-to-date landscape of current agent memory research. We begin by clearly delineating the scope of agent memory and distinguishing it from related concepts such as LLM memory, retrieval augmented generation (RAG), and context engineering. We then examine agent memory through the unified lenses of forms, functions, and dynamics. From the perspective of forms, we identify three dominant realizations of agent memory, namely token-level, parametric, and latent memory. From the perspective of functions, we propose a finer-grained taxonomy that distinguishes factual, experiential, and working memory. From the perspective of dynamics, we analyze how memory is formed, evolved, and retrieved over time. To support practical development, we compile a comprehensive summary of memory benchmarks and open-source frameworks. Beyond consolidation, we articulate a forward-looking perspective on emerging research frontiers, including memory automation, reinforcement learning integration, multimodal memory, multi-agent memory, and trustworthiness issues. We hope this survey serves not only as a reference for existing work, but also as a conceptual foundation for rethinking memory as a first-class primitive in the design of future agentic intelligence.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:48:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13564</guid></item><item><title>LongVie 2: Multimodal Controllable Ultra-Long Video World Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13604</link><description>LongVie 2, an end-to-end autoregressive framework, enhances controllability, visual quality, and temporal consistency in video world models through three progressive training stages.  					AI-generated summary 				 Building video world models upon pretrained video generation systems represents an important yet challenging step toward general spatiotemporal intelligence. A world model should possess three essential properties: controllability, long-term visual quality, and temporal consistency. To this end, we take a progressive approach-first enhancing controllability and then extending toward long-term, high-quality generation. We present LongVie 2, an end-to-end autoregressive framework trained in three stages: (1) Multi-modal guidance, which integrates dense and sparse control signals to provide implicit world-level supervision and improve controllability; (2) Degradation-aware training on the input frame, bridging the gap between training and long-term inference to maintain high visual quality; and (3) History-context guidance, which aligns contextual information across adjacent clips to ensure temporal consistency. We further introduce LongVGenBench, a comprehensive benchmark comprising 100 high-resolution one-minute videos covering diverse real-world and synthetic environments. Extensive experiments demonstrate that LongVie 2 achieves state-of-the-art performance in long-range controllability, temporal coherence, and visual fidelity, and supports continuous video generation lasting up to five minutes, marking a significant step toward unified video world modeling.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:42:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13604</guid></item><item><title>ReFusion: A Diffusion Large Language Model with Parallel Autoregressive Decoding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13586</link><description>ReFusion, a novel masked diffusion model, improves performance and efficiency by using slot-based parallel decoding, achieving superior results compared to autoregressive models and traditional masked diffusion models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Autoregressive models (ARMs) are hindered by slow sequential inference. While masked diffusion models (MDMs) offer a parallel alternative, they suffer from critical drawbacks: high computational overhead from precluding Key-Value (KV) caching, and incoherent generation arising from learning dependencies over an intractable space of token combinations. To address these limitations, we introduce ReFusion, a novel masked diffusion model that achieves superior performance and efficiency by elevating parallel decoding from the token level to a higher slot level, where each slot is a fixed-length, contiguous sub-sequence. This is achieved through an iterative ``plan-and-infill'' decoding process: a diffusion-based planning step first identifies a set of weakly dependent slots, and an autoregressive infilling step then decodes these selected slots in parallel. The slot-based design simultaneously unlocks full KV cache reuse with a unified causal framework and reduces the learning complexity from the token combination space to a manageable slot-level permutation space. Extensive experiments on seven diverse benchmarks show that ReFusion not only overwhelmingly surpasses prior MDMs with 34% performance gains and an over 18times speedup on average, but also bridges the performance gap to strong ARMs while maintaining a 2.33times average speedup.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:09:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13586</guid></item><item><title>Error-Free Linear Attention is a Free Lunch: Exact Solution from Continuous-Time Dynamics</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12602</link><description>Error-Free Linear Attention (EFLA) is a stable, parallelizable, and theoretically sound linear-time attention mechanism that outperforms DeltaNet in language modeling and downstream tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Linear-time attention and State Space Models (SSMs) promise to solve the quadratic cost bottleneck in long-context language models employing softmax attention. We introduce Error-Free Linear Attention (EFLA), a numerically stable, fully parallelism and generalized formulation of the delta rule. Specifically, we formulate the online learning update as a continuous-time dynamical system and prove that its exact solution is not only attainable but also computable in linear time with full parallelism. By leveraging the rank-1 structure of the dynamics matrix, we directly derive the exact closed-form solution effectively corresponding to the infinite-order Runge-Kutta method. This attention mechanism is theoretically free from error accumulation, perfectly capturing the continuous dynamics while preserving the linear-time complexity. Through an extensive suite of experiments, we show that EFLA enables robust performance in noisy environments, achieving lower language modeling perplexity and superior downstream benchmark performance than DeltaNet without introducing additional parameters. Our work provides a new theoretical foundation for building high-fidelity, scalable linear-time attention models.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:06:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12602</guid></item><item><title>KlingAvatar 2.0 Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13313</link><description>KlingAvatar 2.0 addresses inefficiencies in generating long-duration, high-resolution videos by using a spatio-temporal cascade framework with a Co-Reasoning Director and Negative Director for improved multimodal instruction alignment.  					AI-generated summary 				 Avatar video generation models have achieved remarkable progress in recent years. However, prior work exhibits limited efficiency in generating long-duration high-resolution videos, suffering from temporal drifting, quality degradation, and weak prompt following as video length increases. To address these challenges, we propose KlingAvatar 2.0, a spatio-temporal cascade framework that performs upscaling in both spatial resolution and temporal dimension. The framework first generates low-resolution blueprint video keyframes that capture global semantics and motion, and then refines them into high-resolution, temporally coherent sub-clips using a first-last frame strategy, while retaining smooth temporal transitions in long-form videos. To enhance cross-modal instruction fusion and alignment in extended videos, we introduce a Co-Reasoning Director composed of three modality-specific large language model (LLM) experts. These experts reason about modality priorities and infer underlying user intent, converting inputs into detailed storylines through multi-turn dialogue. A Negative Director further refines negative prompts to improve instruction alignment. Building on these components, we extend the framework to support ID-specific multi-character control. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our model effectively addresses the challenges of efficient, multimodally aligned long-form high-resolution video generation, delivering enhanced visual clarity, realistic lip-teeth rendering with accurate lip synchronization, strong identity preservation, and coherent multimodal instruction following.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:53:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13313</guid></item><item><title>QwenLong-L1.5: Post-Training Recipe for Long-Context Reasoning and Memory Management</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12967</link><description>QwenLong-L1.5 enhances long-context reasoning through data synthesis, stabilized reinforcement learning, and memory-augmented architecture, achieving superior performance on benchmarks and general domains.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce QwenLong-L1.5, a model that achieves superior long-context reasoning capabilities through systematic post-training innovations. The key technical breakthroughs of QwenLong-L1.5 are as follows: (1) Long-Context Data Synthesis Pipeline: We develop a systematic synthesis framework that generates challenging reasoning tasks requiring multi-hop grounding over globally distributed evidence. By deconstructing documents into atomic facts and their underlying relationships, and then programmatically composing verifiable reasoning questions, our approach creates high-quality training data at scale, moving substantially beyond simple retrieval tasks to enable genuine long-range reasoning capabilities. (2) Stabilized Reinforcement Learning for Long-Context Training: To overcome the critical instability in long-context RL, we introduce task-balanced sampling with task-specific advantage estimation to mitigate reward bias, and propose Adaptive Entropy-Controlled Policy Optimization (AEPO) that dynamically regulates exploration-exploitation trade-offs. (3) Memory-Augmented Architecture for Ultra-Long Contexts: Recognizing that even extended context windows cannot accommodate arbitrarily long sequences, we develop a memory management framework with multi-stage fusion RL training that seamlessly integrates single-pass reasoning with iterative memory-based processing for tasks exceeding 4M tokens. Based on Qwen3-30B-A3B-Thinking, QwenLong-L1.5 achieves performance comparable to GPT-5 and Gemini-2.5-Pro on long-context reasoning benchmarks, surpassing its baseline by 9.90 points on average. On ultra-long tasks (1M~4M tokens), QwenLong-L1.5's memory-agent framework yields a 9.48-point gain over the agent baseline. Additionally, the acquired long-context reasoning ability translates to enhanced performance in general domains like scientific reasoning, memory tool using, and extended dialogue.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:59:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12967</guid></item><item><title>NL2Repo-Bench: Towards Long-Horizon Repository Generation Evaluation of Coding Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12730</link><description>NL2Repo Bench evaluates long-horizon software development capabilities of coding agents by assessing their ability to generate complete Python libraries from natural-language requirements.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in coding agents suggest rapid progress toward autonomous software development, yet existing benchmarks fail to rigorously evaluate the long-horizon capabilities required to build complete software systems. Most prior evaluations focus on localized code generation, scaffolded completion, or short-term repair tasks, leaving open the question of whether agents can sustain coherent reasoning, planning, and execution over the extended horizons demanded by real-world repository construction. To address this gap, we present NL2Repo Bench, a benchmark explicitly designed to evaluate the long-horizon repository generation ability of coding agents. Given only a single natural-language requirements document and an empty workspace, agents must autonomously design the architecture, manage dependencies, implement multi-module logic, and produce a fully installable Python library. Our experiments across state-of-the-art open- and closed-source models reveal that long-horizon repository generation remains largely unsolved: even the strongest agents achieve below 40% average test pass rates and rarely complete an entire repository correctly. Detailed analysis uncovers fundamental long-horizon failure modes, including premature termination, loss of global coherence, fragile cross-file dependencies, and inadequate planning over hundreds of interaction steps. NL2Repo Bench establishes a rigorous, verifiable testbed for measuring sustained agentic competence and highlights long-horizon reasoning as a central bottleneck for the next generation of autonomous coding agents.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:21:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12730</guid></item><item><title>MentraSuite: Post-Training Large Language Models for Mental Health Reasoning and Assessment</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.09636</link><description>MentraSuite, a unified framework, advances reliable mental health reasoning using Mindora, a post-trained model with hybrid SFT-RL, evaluated via MentraBench, a benchmark assessing task performance and reasoning quality.  					AI-generated summary 				 Mental health disorders affect hundreds of millions globally, and the Web now serves as a primary medium for accessing support, information, and assessment. Large language models (LLMs) offer scalable and accessible assistance, yet their deployment in mental-health settings remains risky when their reasoning is incomplete, inconsistent, or ungrounded. Existing psychological LLMs emphasize emotional understanding or knowledge recall but overlook the step-wise, clinically aligned reasoning required for appraisal, diagnosis, intervention planning, abstraction, and verification. To address these issues, we introduce MentraSuite, a unified framework for advancing reliable mental-health reasoning. We propose MentraBench, a comprehensive benchmark spanning five core reasoning aspects, six tasks, and 13 datasets, evaluating both task performance and reasoning quality across five dimensions: conciseness, coherence, hallucination avoidance, task understanding, and internal consistency. We further present Mindora, a post-trained model optimized through a hybrid SFT-RL framework with an inconsistency-detection reward to enforce faithful and coherent reasoning. To support training, we construct high-quality trajectories using a novel reasoning trajectory generation strategy, that strategically filters difficult samples and applies a structured, consistency-oriented rewriting process to produce concise, readable, and well-balanced trajectories. Across 20 evaluated LLMs, Mindora achieves the highest average performance on MentraBench and shows remarkable performances in reasoning reliability, demonstrating its effectiveness for complex mental-health scenarios.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:38:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.09636</guid></item><item><title>Openpi Comet: Competition Solution For 2025 BEHAVIOR Challenge</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.10071</link><description>A solution for the 2025 BEHAVIOR Challenge in everyday household tasks using pre-training and post-training techniques substantially outperforms other submissions.  					AI-generated summary 				 The 2025 BEHAVIOR Challenge is designed to rigorously track progress toward solving long-horizon tasks by physical agents in simulated environments. BEHAVIOR-1K focuses on everyday household tasks that people most want robots to assist with and these tasks introduce long-horizon mobile manipulation challenges in realistic settings, bridging the gap between current research and real-world, human-centric applications. This report presents our solution to the 2025 BEHAVIOR Challenge in a very close 2nd place and substantially outperforms the rest of the submissions. Building on π_{0.5}, we focus on systematically building our solution by studying the effects of training techniques and data. Through careful ablations, we show the scaling power in pre-training and post-training phases for competitive performance. We summarize our practical lessons and design recommendations that we hope will provide actionable insights for the broader embodied AI community when adapting powerful foundation models to complex embodied scenarios.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 01:25:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.10071</guid></item><item><title>Spatial-Aware VLA Pretraining through Visual-Physical Alignment from Human Videos</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13080</link><description>A Spatial-Aware VLA Pretraining paradigm improves 3D spatial understanding in robots by aligning 2D visual inputs with 3D actions using dual-encoder architecture with a 3D visual encoder.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models provide a promising paradigm for robot learning by integrating visual perception with language-guided policy learning. However, most existing approaches rely on 2D visual inputs to perform actions in 3D physical environments, creating a significant gap between perception and action grounding. To bridge this gap, we propose a Spatial-Aware VLA Pretraining paradigm that performs explicit alignment between visual space and physical space during pretraining, enabling models to acquire 3D spatial understanding before robot policy learning. Starting from pretrained vision-language models, we leverage large-scale human demonstration videos to extract 3D visual and 3D action annotations, forming a new source of supervision that aligns 2D visual observations with 3D spatial reasoning. We instantiate this paradigm with VIPA-VLA, a dual-encoder architecture that incorporates a 3D visual encoder to augment semantic visual representations with 3D-aware features. When adapted to downstream robot tasks, VIPA-VLA achieves significantly improved grounding between 2D vision and 3D action, resulting in more robust and generalizable robotic policies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:54:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13080</guid></item><item><title>V-REX: Benchmarking Exploratory Visual Reasoning via Chain-of-Questions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.11995</link><description>The V-REX evaluation suite assesses vision-language models' multi-step reasoning and exploration capabilities through a Chain-of-Questions framework, revealing their strengths and weaknesses in planning and following.  					AI-generated summary 				 While many vision-language models (VLMs) are developed to answer well-defined, straightforward questions with highly specified targets, as in most benchmarks, they often struggle in practice with complex open-ended tasks, which usually require multiple rounds of exploration and reasoning in the visual space. Such visual thinking paths not only provide step-by-step exploration and verification as an AI detective but also produce better interpretations of the final answers. However, these paths are challenging to evaluate due to the large exploration space of intermediate steps. To bridge the gap, we develop an evaluation suite, ``Visual Reasoning with multi-step EXploration (V-REX)'', which is composed of a benchmark of challenging visual reasoning tasks requiring native multi-step exploration and an evaluation protocol. V-REX covers rich application scenarios across diverse domains. V-REX casts the multi-step exploratory reasoning into a Chain-of-Questions (CoQ) and disentangles VLMs' capability to (1) Planning: breaking down an open-ended task by selecting a chain of exploratory questions; and (2) Following: answering curated CoQ sequentially to collect information for deriving the final answer. By curating finite options of questions and answers per step, V-REX achieves a reliable quantitative and fine-grained analysis of the intermediate steps. By assessing SOTA proprietary and open-sourced VLMs, we reveal consistent scaling trends, significant differences between planning and following abilities, and substantial room for improvement in multi-step exploratory reasoning.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:44:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.11995</guid></item><item><title>Toward Ambulatory Vision: Learning Visually-Grounded Active View Selection</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13250</link><description>VG-AVS, a task and framework fine-tunes VLMs to select the most informative next viewpoint for visual question answering, enhancing performance and generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision Language Models (VLMs) excel at visual question answering (VQA) but remain limited to snapshot vision, reasoning from static images. In contrast, embodied agents require ambulatory vision, actively moving to obtain more informative views. We introduce Visually Grounded Active View Selection (VG-AVS), a task that selects the most informative next viewpoint using only the visual information in the current image, without relying on scene memory or external knowledge. To support this task, we construct a synthetic dataset with automatically generated paired query-target views and question-answer prompts. We also propose a framework that fine-tunes pretrained VLMs through supervised fine-tuning (SFT) followed by RL-based policy optimization. Our approach achieves strong question answering performance based on viewpoint selection and generalizes robustly to unseen synthetic and real scenes. Furthermore, incorporating our learned VG-AVS framework into existing scene-exploration-based EQA systems improves downstream question-answering accuracy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:11:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13250</guid></item><item><title>VLSA: Vision-Language-Action Models with Plug-and-Play Safety Constraint Layer</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.11891</link><description>AEGIS, a Vision-Language-Safe Action architecture with a plug-and-play safety constraint layer using control barrier functions, enhances safety and performance in robotic manipulation tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in generalizing across diverse robotic manipulation tasks. However, deploying these models in unstructured environments remains challenging due to the critical need for simultaneous task compliance and safety assurance, particularly in preventing potential collisions during physical interactions. In this work, we introduce a Vision-Language-Safe Action (VLSA) architecture, named AEGIS, which contains a plug-and-play safety constraint (SC) layer formulated via control barrier functions. AEGIS integrates directly with existing VLA models to improve safety with theoretical guarantees, while maintaining their original instruction-following performance. To evaluate the efficacy of our architecture, we construct a comprehensive safety-critical benchmark SafeLIBERO, spanning distinct manipulation scenarios characterized by varying degrees of spatial complexity and obstacle intervention. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superiority of our method over state-of-the-art baselines. Notably, AEGIS achieves a 59.16% improvement in obstacle avoidance rate while substantially increasing the task execution success rate by 17.25%. To facilitate reproducibility and future research, we make our code, models, and the benchmark datasets publicly available at https://vlsa-aegis.github.io/.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:54:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.11891</guid></item><item><title>Image Diffusion Preview with Consistency Solver</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13592</link><description>Diffusion Preview uses ConsistencySolver, a high-order trainable solver, to improve quality and consistency in low-step image generation, enhancing interactive user experiences.  					AI-generated summary 				 The slow inference process of image diffusion models significantly degrades interactive user experiences. To address this, we introduce Diffusion Preview, a novel paradigm employing rapid, low-step sampling to generate preliminary outputs for user evaluation, deferring full-step refinement until the preview is deemed satisfactory. Existing acceleration methods, including training-free solvers and post-training distillation, struggle to deliver high-quality previews or ensure consistency between previews and final outputs. We propose ConsistencySolver derived from general linear multistep methods, a lightweight, trainable high-order solver optimized via Reinforcement Learning, that enhances preview quality and consistency. Experimental results demonstrate that ConsistencySolver significantly improves generation quality and consistency in low-step scenarios, making it ideal for efficient preview-and-refine workflows. Notably, it achieves FID scores on-par with Multistep DPM-Solver using 47% fewer steps, while outperforming distillation baselines. Furthermore, user studies indicate our approach reduces overall user interaction time by nearly 50% while maintaining generation quality. Code is available at https://github.com/G-U-N/consolver.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:20:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13592</guid></item><item><title>Aesthetic Alignment Risks Assimilation: How Image Generation and Reward Models Reinforce Beauty Bias and Ideological "Censorship"</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.11883</link><description>State-of-the-art image generation and reward models exhibit bias towards conventional aesthetics, often failing to produce anti-aesthetic images as requested, thus compromising user autonomy and aesthetic diversity.  					AI-generated summary 				 Over-aligning image generation models to a generalized aesthetic preference conflicts with user intent, particularly when ``anti-aesthetic" outputs are requested for artistic or critical purposes. This adherence prioritizes developer-centered values, compromising user autonomy and aesthetic pluralism. We test this bias by constructing a wide-spectrum aesthetics dataset and evaluating state-of-the-art generation and reward models. We find that aesthetic-aligned generation models frequently default to conventionally beautiful outputs, failing to respect instructions for low-quality or negative imagery. Crucially, reward models penalize anti-aesthetic images even when they perfectly match the explicit user prompt. We confirm this systemic bias through image-to-image editing and evaluation against real abstract artworks.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:06:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.11883</guid></item><item><title>RecTok: Reconstruction Distillation along Rectified Flow</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13421</link><description>RecTok improves diffusion models by enriching forward flow semantics and enhancing reconstruction, achieving state-of-the-art results with high-dimensional visual tokenizers.  					AI-generated summary 				 Visual tokenizers play a crucial role in diffusion models. The dimensionality of latent space governs both reconstruction fidelity and the semantic expressiveness of the latent feature. However, a fundamental trade-off is inherent between dimensionality and generation quality, constraining existing methods to low-dimensional latent spaces. Although recent works have leveraged vision foundation models to enrich the semantics of visual tokenizers and accelerate convergence, high-dimensional tokenizers still underperform their low-dimensional counterparts. In this work, we propose RecTok, which overcomes the limitations of high-dimensional visual tokenizers through two key innovations: flow semantic distillation and reconstruction--alignment distillation. Our key insight is to make the forward flow in flow matching semantically rich, which serves as the training space of diffusion transformers, rather than focusing on the latent space as in previous works. Specifically, our method distills the semantic information in VFMs into the forward flow trajectories in flow matching. And we further enhance the semantics by introducing a masked feature reconstruction loss. Our RecTok achieves superior image reconstruction, generation quality, and discriminative performance. It achieves state-of-the-art results on the gFID-50K under both with and without classifier-free guidance settings, while maintaining a semantically rich latent space structure. Furthermore, as the latent dimensionality increases, we observe consistent improvements. Code and model are available at https://shi-qingyu.github.io/rectok.github.io.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 06:35:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13421</guid></item><item><title>LitePT: Lighter Yet Stronger Point Transformer</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13689</link><description>A new 3D point cloud backbone model, LitePT, uses convolutions for early stages and attention for deeper layers, incorporating PointROPE for positional encoding, achieving efficient performance with fewer resources.  					AI-generated summary 				 Modern neural architectures for 3D point cloud processing contain both convolutional layers and attention blocks, but the best way to assemble them remains unclear. We analyse the role of different computational blocks in 3D point cloud networks and find an intuitive behaviour: convolution is adequate to extract low-level geometry at high-resolution in early layers, where attention is expensive without bringing any benefits; attention captures high-level semantics and context in low-resolution, deep layers more efficiently. Guided by this design principle, we propose a new, improved 3D point cloud backbone that employs convolutions in early stages and switches to attention for deeper layers. To avoid the loss of spatial layout information when discarding redundant convolution layers, we introduce a novel, training-free 3D positional encoding, PointROPE. The resulting LitePT model has 3.6times fewer parameters, runs 2times faster, and uses 2times less memory than the state-of-the-art Point Transformer V3, but nonetheless matches or even outperforms it on a range of tasks and datasets. Code and models are available at: https://github.com/prs-eth/LitePT.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:25:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13689</guid></item><item><title>Directional Textual Inversion for Personalized Text-to-Image Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13672</link><description>Directional Textual Inversion (DTI) improves text-to-image personalization by constraining learned tokens to unit magnitude, enhancing prompt conditioning and enabling smooth interpolation between concepts.  					AI-generated summary 				 Textual Inversion (TI) is an efficient approach to text-to-image personalization but often fails on complex prompts. We trace these failures to embedding norm inflation: learned tokens drift to out-of-distribution magnitudes, degrading prompt conditioning in pre-norm Transformers. Empirically, we show semantics are primarily encoded by direction in CLIP token space, while inflated norms harm contextualization; theoretically, we analyze how large magnitudes attenuate positional information and hinder residual updates in pre-norm blocks. We propose Directional Textual Inversion (DTI), which fixes the embedding magnitude to an in-distribution scale and optimizes only direction on the unit hypersphere via Riemannian SGD. We cast direction learning as MAP with a von Mises-Fisher prior, yielding a constant-direction prior gradient that is simple and efficient to incorporate. Across personalization tasks, DTI improves text fidelity over TI and TI-variants while maintaining subject similarity. Crucially, DTI's hyperspherical parameterization enables smooth, semantically coherent interpolation between learned concepts (slerp), a capability that is absent in standard TI. Our findings suggest that direction-only optimization is a robust and scalable path for prompt-faithful personalization.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:40:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13672</guid></item><item><title>Video Reality Test: Can AI-Generated ASMR Videos fool VLMs and Humans?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13281</link><description>The Video Reality Test benchmark evaluates the realism and detection of AI-generated ASMR videos with audio, revealing that even the best models can deceive VLMs and humans, highlighting limitations in perceptual fidelity and audio-visual consistency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in video generation have produced vivid content that are often indistinguishable from real videos, making AI-generated video detection an emerging societal challenge. Prior AIGC detection benchmarks mostly evaluate video without audio, target broad narrative domains, and focus on classification solely. Yet it remains unclear whether state-of-the-art video generation models can produce immersive, audio-paired videos that reliably deceive humans and VLMs. To this end, we introduce Video Reality Test, an ASMR-sourced video benchmark suite for testing perceptual realism under tight audio-visual coupling, featuring the following dimensions: (i) Immersive ASMR video-audio sources. Built on carefully curated real ASMR videos, the benchmark targets fine-grained action-object interactions with diversity across objects, actions, and backgrounds. (ii) Peer-Review evaluation. An adversarial creator-reviewer protocol where video generation models act as creators aiming to fool reviewers, while VLMs serve as reviewers seeking to identify fakeness. Our experimental findings show: The best creator Veo3.1-Fast even fools most VLMs: the strongest reviewer (Gemini 2.5-Pro) achieves only 56\% accuracy (random 50\%), far below that of human experts (81.25\%). Adding audio improves real-fake discrimination, yet superficial cues such as watermarks can still significantly mislead models. These findings delineate the current boundary of video generation realism and expose limitations of VLMs in perceptual fidelity and audio-visual consistency. Our code is available at https://github.com/video-reality-test/video-reality-test.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:55:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13281</guid></item><item><title>START: Spatial and Textual Learning for Chart Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07186</link><description>START enhances multimodal large language models by integrating spatial and textual learning through chart-element grounding and chart-to-code generation, improving chart understanding and performance across benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Chart understanding is crucial for deploying multimodal large language models (MLLMs) in real-world scenarios such as analyzing scientific papers and technical reports. Unlike natural images, charts pair a structured visual layout (spatial property) with an underlying data representation (textual property) -- grasping both is essential for precise, fine-grained chart reasoning. Motivated by this observation, we propose START, the Spatial and Textual learning for chART understanding. Specifically, we introduce (i) chart-element grounding and (ii) chart-to-code generation to strengthen an MLLM's understanding of both chart visual layout and data details. To facilitate spatial and textual learning, we propose the START-Dataset generated with a novel data-generation pipeline that first leverages an MLLM to translate real chart images into executable chart code, recovering the underlying data representation while preserving the visual distribution of real-world charts. We then evolve the code with a Large Language Model (LLM) to ascertain the positions of chart elements that capture the chart's visual structure, addressing challenges that existing methods cannot handle. To evaluate a model's ability to understand chart spatial structures, we propose the Chart Spatial understanding Benchmark (CS-Bench), filling a critical gap in comprehensive chart understanding evaluation. Leveraging spatial and textual learning, START delivers consistent gains across model sizes and benchmarks over the base models and surpasses prior state-of-the-art by a clear margin. Code, data and models will be publicly available.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:36:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.07186</guid></item><item><title>DiffusionBrowser: Interactive Diffusion Previews via Multi-Branch Decoders</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13690</link><description>DiffusionBrowser enables interactive video preview generation and control during the denoising process, enhancing user experience and revealing model composition details.  					AI-generated summary 				 Video diffusion models have revolutionized generative video synthesis, but they are imprecise, slow, and can be opaque during generation -- keeping users in the dark for a prolonged period. In this work, we propose DiffusionBrowser, a model-agnostic, lightweight decoder framework that allows users to interactively generate previews at any point (timestep or transformer block) during the denoising process. Our model can generate multi-modal preview representations that include RGB and scene intrinsics at more than 4times real-time speed (less than 1 second for a 4-second video) that convey consistent appearance and motion to the final video. With the trained decoder, we show that it is possible to interactively guide the generation at intermediate noise steps via stochasticity reinjection and modal steering, unlocking a new control capability. Moreover, we systematically probe the model using the learned decoders, revealing how scene, object, and other details are composed and assembled during the otherwise black-box denoising process.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 06:23:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13690</guid></item><item><title>Towards Interactive Intelligence for Digital Humans</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13674</link><description>Interactive Intelligence, realized through Mio framework, enables advanced digital humans with personality, adaptive interactions, and self-evolution, surpassing current benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Interactive Intelligence, a novel paradigm of digital human that is capable of personality-aligned expression, adaptive interaction, and self-evolution. To realize this, we present Mio (Multimodal Interactive Omni-Avatar), an end-to-end framework composed of five specialized modules: Thinker, Talker, Face Animator, Body Animator, and Renderer. This unified architecture integrates cognitive reasoning with real-time multimodal embodiment to enable fluid, consistent interaction. Furthermore, we establish a new benchmark to rigorously evaluate the capabilities of interactive intelligence. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our framework achieves superior performance compared to state-of-the-art methods across all evaluated dimensions. Together, these contributions move digital humans beyond superficial imitation toward intelligent interaction.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:08:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13674</guid></item></channel></rss>