<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Hunyuan-A13B 🔥 New MoE LLM by TencentHunyuan</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/115721386328243</link><description>Hunyuan-A13B 🔥 New MoE LLM by TencentHunyuan tencent/Hunyuan-A13B-Instruct ✨80B total / 13B active params ✨256K context window ✨Dual-mode reasoning: fast &amp; slow thinking ✨Efficient inference (GQA + quantization) See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/115721386328243</guid></item><item><title>It's been a bit since I took a step back and looked at</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/jsulz/866221600890917</link><description>It's been a bit since I took a step back and looked at xet-team progress to migrate Hugging Face from Git LFS to Xet, but every time I do it boggles the mind. A month ago there were 5,500 users/orgs on Xet with 150K repos and 4PB. Today? 🤗 700,000 users/orgs 📈 350,000 repos 🚀 15PB Meanwhile, our migrations have pushed throughput to numbers that are bonkers. In June, we hit upload speeds of 577Gb/s (crossing 500Gb/s for the first time). These are hard numbers to put into context, but let's try: The latest run of the Common Crawl from commoncrawl was 471 TB. We now have ~32 crawls stored in Xet. At peak upload speed we could move the latest crawl into Xet in about two hours. We're moving to a new phase in the process, so stay tuned. This shift in gears means it's also time to roll up our sleeves and look at all the bytes we have and the value we're adding to the community. I already have some homework from @ RichardErkhov to look at the dedupe across their uploads, and I'll be doing...</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/jsulz/866221600890917</guid></item><item><title>Three big AI copyright updates this week alone. Tracking it all is getting almost impossible!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/569299354714492</link><description>Three big AI copyright updates this week alone. Tracking it all is getting almost impossible! That’s why @ BrigitteTousi and I built this interactive tracker to keep you up to date fdaudens/ai-copyright-lawsuits (Prototyped in minutes with DeepSite!) See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/569299354714492</guid></item><item><title>SnowflakeCore-G1 development update: We're building a 24-layer transformer with 32K context and 1024 embedding dimensions - pretty ambitious! Even running at batch_size=1 with heavy gradient accumulation, we're hitting memory walls at 300GB RAM. Scaling up to ~1TB will take some time, but the architecture is looking promising. Thanks for following along with the journey! 😅</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/FlameF0X/436788445658511</link><description>SnowflakeCore-G1 development update: We're building a 24-layer transformer with 32K context and 1024 embedding dimensions - pretty ambitious! Even running at batch_size=1 with heavy gradient accumulation, we're hitting memory walls at 300GB RAM. Scaling up to ~1TB will take some time, but the architecture is looking promising. Thanks for following along with the journey! 😅 See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/FlameF0X/436788445658511</guid></item><item><title>As you might have already heard, FLUX.1-Kontext-dev is now released and taken the generative community by storm!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/a-r-r-o-w/674823997424742</link><description>As you might have already heard, FLUX.1-Kontext-dev is now released and taken the generative community by storm! In case you haven't come across it, you can get started with Kontext using 🤗 diffusers. See the official [model]( black-forest-labs/FLUX.1-Kontext-dev ) and [docs]( https://huggingface.co/docs/diffusers/main/en/api/pipelines/flux#flux ). Want to know how inference companies like Fal &amp; Replicate are able to run the model so fast and in under 2 seconds per image? Check out this [gist]( https://gist.github.com/a-r-r-o-w/d08c37e8bd3e9c26b4ce80360be148c6 ) for some details! See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/a-r-r-o-w/674823997424742</guid></item><item><title>Mind2Web 2 is out - this time featuring eval and benchmark for deep research🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Jaward/802029609122095</link><description>Mind2Web 2 is out - this time featuring eval and benchmark for deep research🔥 Paper: Mind2Web 2: Evaluating Agentic Search with Agent-as-a-Judge (2506.21506) Project: https://osu-nlp-group.github.io/Mind2Web-2/ See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Jaward/802029609122095</guid></item><item><title>This is what efficient AI looks like: Gemma 3n just dropped - a natively multimodal model that runs entirely on your device. No cloud. No API calls.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/514291892599532</link><description>This is what efficient AI looks like: Gemma 3n just dropped - a natively multimodal model that runs entirely on your device. No cloud. No API calls. 🧠 Text, image, audio, and video - handled locally. ⚡️Only needs 2B in GPU memory to run 🤯 First sub-10B model to hit 1300+ Elo ✅ Plug-and-play with Hugging Face, MLX, llama.cpp, and more. Plus: Multilingual out of the box (140+ languages), fine-tune in a free Colab notebook. google/gemma-3n-685065323f5984ef315c93f4 See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/514291892599532</guid></item><item><title>🤗 Here’s a fun educational video I made to show how Sheets and AI can upgrade your structured content.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Ameeeee/808240826417311</link><description>🤗 Here’s a fun educational video I made to show how Sheets and AI can upgrade your structured content. Better tables and clearer messages with just a little help from open-source AI! aisheets/sheets See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Ameeeee/808240826417311</guid></item><item><title>🔥BEST DEBUG PROMPT FOR CLAUDE_CODE</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/samihalawa/553684674682033</link><description>🔥BEST DEBUG PROMPT FOR CLAUDE_CODE 😲FIXES ANY REPO How can I prompt you so there will not be any More bug or thing? So list the 20 kind of errors and bugs more common in a codebase like this one and create a comprehensive table list of each of them and all the main files and fucnionality and fix until cross all out . Don 't add complexity. Ignore security. Only fatal problems Proceed in the most exhaustive and comprehensive way possible. Don' t miss a line of code. SYSTEMATICALLY FIX EVERYTHING See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/samihalawa/553684674682033</guid></item><item><title>🚀 Real-Time On-Device AI Agent with Polaris-4B — Run It Yourself, No Cloud, No Cost</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/yeonseok-zeticai/894951796717498</link><description>🚀 Real-Time On-Device AI Agent with Polaris-4B — Run It Yourself, No Cloud, No Cost We just deployed a real-time on-device AI agent using the Polaris-4B-Preview model — one of the top-performing &lt;6B open LLMs on Hugging Face. 📱 What’s remarkable? This model runs entirely on a mobile device, without cloud, and without any manual optimization. It was built using ZETIC.MLange, and the best part? ➡️ It’s totally automated, free to use, and anyone can do it. You don’t need to write deployment code, tweak backends, or touch device-specific SDKs. Just upload your model — and ZETIC.MLange handles the rest. 🧠 About the Model - Model: Polaris-4B-Preview - Size: ~4B parameters - Ranking: Top 3 on Hugging Face LLM Leaderboard (&lt;6B) - Tokenizer: Token-incremental inference supported - Modifications: None — stock weights, just optimized for mobile ⚙️ What ZETIC.MLange Does ZETIC.MLange is a fully automated deployment framework for On-Device AI, built for AI engineers who want to focus on models —...</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:19:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/yeonseok-zeticai/894951796717498</guid></item></channel></rss>