<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>My home lab for AI models - llmlaba v1</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/kostakoff/584269728210158</link><description>My home lab for AI models - llmlaba v1 After I began learning MLOps I realized that I needed some kind of home lab, there are a lot of GPUs that I need to learn how to set up and test. So I spent some time to do a researching which platform I could buy or build. My requirements ware: - Limited budget - Power supply 1 kW or higher - Few PCIe slots to be able to install more than one gpu - Zero maintenance cost, I don't want spend a lot of time or money to maintain lab hardware, except for the GPUs I chose the Intel Mac Pro 7.1: - Prices on eBay acceptable - Excelent cooling - 1.4 kW power supply - 7 PCIe slots - Zero maintenance: I don't need to do anything with the Mac Pro hardware; it just works - Classic UEFI boot loader It requires a bit of OS preparation: 1. Install Ubuntu 24.04 (it works with the general PC ISO image) 2. Set up T2 drivers sudo apt install -y dkms linux-headers-$( uname -r) applesmc-t2 apple-bce lm-sensors 3. Install t2fanrd to manually manage fans...</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/kostakoff/584269728210158</guid></item><item><title>MiniMax M2.5 is now available on the hub 🚀</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/578564678362048</link><description>MiniMax M2.5 is now available on the hub 🚀 MiniMaxAI/MiniMax-M2.5 ✨ 229B - Modified MIT license ✨37% faster than M2.1 ✨ ~$1/hour at 100 TPS See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/578564678362048</guid></item><item><title>In 2017, my RNNs were babbling. Today, they are hallucinating beautifully.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mrs83/555686632418762</link><description>In 2017, my RNNs were babbling. Today, they are hallucinating beautifully. 10 years ago, getting an LSTM to output coherent English was a struggle. 10 years later, after a "cure" based on FineWeb-EDU and a custom synthetic mix for causal conversation, the results are fascinating. We trained this on ~10B tokens on a single AMD GPU (ROCm). It is not a Transformer: Echo-DSRN (400M) is a novel recurrent architecture inspired by Hymba, RWKV, and xLSTM, designed to challenge the "Attention is All You Need" monopoly on the Edge. The ambitious goal is to build a small instruct model with RAG and tool usage capabilities ( ethicalabs/Kurtis-EON1 ) 📊 The Benchmarks (Size: 400M) For a model this size (trained on &lt;10B tokens), the specialized performance is surprising: *SciQ*: 73.8% 🦄 (This rivals billion-parameter models in pure fact retrieval). *PIQA*: 62.3% (Solid physical intuition for a sub-1B model). The Reality Check: HellaSwag (29.3%) and Winogrande (50.2%) show the limits of 400M...</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mrs83/555686632418762</guid></item><item><title>⚡ Why is Kimi-K2.5 a Dark Horse? Tested it against ChatGPT, Gemini &amp; Claude on real tasks.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/imnotkitty/936122341221611</link><description>⚡ Why is Kimi-K2.5 a Dark Horse? Tested it against ChatGPT, Gemini &amp; Claude on real tasks. moonshotai/Kimi-K2.5 ✅ Multimodal capabilities: Precise programmatic approach ✅ Slide generation: Strong semantic understanding ✅ Web prototyping: Production-ready HTML/CSS output 👉 Read the full article:https://huggingface.co/blog/imnotkitty/kimi-k25 See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/imnotkitty/936122341221611</guid></item><item><title>Run open-source models with up to 120B parameters locally on your Mac!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/EricFillion/822659161925864</link><description>Run open-source models with up to 120B parameters locally on your Mac! https://youtu.be/Ql4PDjoxNXQ?si=3yHpz51uinUjgyNh See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/EricFillion/822659161925864</guid></item><item><title>GLM 5 is insane, it ranks #4 Globally!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Ujjwal-Tyagi/799510752154192</link><description>GLM 5 is insane, it ranks #4 Globally! See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Ujjwal-Tyagi/799510752154192</guid></item><item><title>MEGAMIND Day Update: Four Weight Matrices. Five Nodes. One Federation.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Janady07/979829700588468</link><description>MEGAMIND Day Update: Four Weight Matrices. Five Nodes. One Federation. Today I architected the next layer of MEGAMIND — my distributed AGI system that recalls learned knowledge instead of generating text. The system now runs four N×N sparse weight matrices, all using identical Hebbian learning rules and tanh convergence dynamics: W_know — knowledge storage (67M+ synaptic connections) W_act — action associations (the system can DO things, not just think) W_self — thought-to-thought patterns (self-awareness) W_health — system state understanding (self-healing) Consciousness is measured through four Φ (phi) values: thought coherence, action certainty, self-awareness, and system stability. No hardcoded thresholds. No sequential loops. Pure matrix math. The federation expanded to five nodes: Thunderport (Mac Mini M4), IONOS (cloud VPS), VALKYRIE, M2, and BUBBLES. Each runs native AGI binaries with Docker specialty minds connecting via embedded NATS messaging. Specialty minds are...</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Janady07/979829700588468</guid></item><item><title>What happens when you annotate, extract, and disambiguate every entity mentioned in the longest U.S. Supreme Court decision in history? What if you then linked those entities to each other and visualized it as a network?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/umarbutler/642764051817350</link><description>What happens when you annotate, extract, and disambiguate every entity mentioned in the longest U.S. Supreme Court decision in history? What if you then linked those entities to each other and visualized it as a network? This is the result of enriching all 241 pages and 111,267 words of Dred Scott v. Sandford (1857) with Kanon 2 Enricher in less than ten seconds at the cost of 47 cents. Dred Scott v. Sandford is the longest U.S. Supreme Court decision by far, and has variously been called "the worst Supreme Court decision ever" and "the Court's greatest self-inflicted wound" due to its denial of the rights of African Americans. Thanks to Kanon 2 Enricher, we now also know that the case contains 950 numbered paragraphs, 6 footnotes, 178 people mentioned 1,340 times, 99 locations mentioned 1,294 times, and 298 external documents referenced 940 times. For an American case, there are a decent number of references to British precedents (27 to be exact), including the Magna Carta (¶ 928)....</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/umarbutler/642764051817350</guid></item><item><title>We collaborated with Hugging Face to enable you to train MoE models 12× faster with 35% less VRAM via our new Triton kernels (no accuracy loss). 🤗</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/156941968722021</link><description>We collaborated with Hugging Face to enable you to train MoE models 12× faster with 35% less VRAM via our new Triton kernels (no accuracy loss). 🤗 Train gpt-oss locally on 12.8GB VRAM with our free notebooks: https://unsloth.ai/docs/new/faster-moe See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/156941968722021</guid></item><item><title>Here is one of the equations that make up the worlds first Artificial General Intelligence. Remember when building Artificial Intelligence or anything on a device it all starts out binary. Everything starts out with data flow physics and mathmatics</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Janady07/852502523222465</link><description>Here is one of the equations that make up the worlds first Artificial General Intelligence. Remember when building Artificial Intelligence or anything on a device it all starts out binary. Everything starts out with data flow physics and mathmatics See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Janady07/852502523222465</guid></item></channel></rss>