<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>VisuLogic: A Benchmark for Evaluating Visual Reasoning in Multi-modal
  Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15279</link><description>Visual reasoning is a core component of human intelligence and a critical capability for advanced multimodal models. Yet current reasoning evaluations of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) often rely on text descriptions and allow language-based reasoning shortcuts, failing to measure genuine vision-centric reasoning. To address this, we introduce VisuLogic: a benchmark of 1,000 human-verified problems across six categories (e.g., quantitative shifts, spatial relations, attribute comparisons). These various types of questions can be evaluated to assess the visual reasoning capabilities of MLLMs from multiple perspectives. We evaluate leading MLLMs on this benchmark and analyze their results to identify common failure modes. Most models score below 30% accuracy-only slightly above the 25% random baseline and far below the 51.4% achieved by humans-revealing significant gaps in visual reasoning. Furthermore, we provide a supplementary training dataset and a reinforcement-learning baseline to support further progress.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 02:52:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15279</guid></item><item><title>Trillion 7B Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15431</link><description>We introduce Trillion-7B, the most token-efficient Korean-centric multilingual LLM available. Our novel Cross-lingual Document Attention (XLDA) mechanism enables highly efficient and effective knowledge transfer from English to target languages like Korean and Japanese. Combined with optimized data mixtures, language-specific filtering, and tailored tokenizer construction, Trillion-7B achieves competitive performance while dedicating only 10\% of its 2T training tokens to multilingual data and requiring just 59.4K H100 GPU hours (\$148K) for full training. Comprehensive evaluations across 27 benchmarks in four languages demonstrate Trillion-7B's robust multilingual performance and exceptional cross-lingual consistency.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 02:39:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15431</guid></item><item><title>Decoupled Global-Local Alignment for Improving Compositional
  Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16801</link><description>Contrastive Language-Image Pre-training (CLIP) has achieved success on multiple downstream tasks by aligning image and text modalities. However, the nature of global contrastive learning limits CLIP's ability to comprehend compositional concepts, such as relations and attributes. Although recent studies employ global hard negative samples to improve compositional understanding, these methods significantly compromise the model's inherent general capabilities by forcibly distancing textual negative samples from images in the embedding space. To overcome this limitation, we introduce a Decoupled Global-Local Alignment (DeGLA) framework that improves compositional understanding while substantially mitigating losses in general capabilities. To optimize the retention of the model's inherent capabilities, we incorporate a self-distillation mechanism within the global alignment process, aligning the learnable image-text encoder with a frozen teacher model derived from an exponential moving average. Under the constraint of self-distillation, it effectively mitigates the catastrophic forgetting of pretrained knowledge during fine-tuning. To improve compositional understanding, we first leverage the in-context learning capability of Large Language Models (LLMs) to construct about 2M high-quality negative captions across five types. Subsequently, we propose the Image-Grounded Contrast (IGC) loss and Text-Grounded Contrast (TGC) loss to enhance vision-language compositionally. Extensive experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of the DeGLA framework. Compared to previous state-of-the-art methods, DeGLA achieves an average enhancement of 3.5% across the VALSE, SugarCrepe, and ARO benchmarks. Concurrently, it obtains an average performance improvement of 13.0% on zero-shot classification tasks across eleven datasets. Our code will be released at https://github.com/xiaoxing2001/DeGLA</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 04:34:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16801</guid></item><item><title>I-Con: A Unifying Framework for Representation Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16929</link><description>As the field of representation learning grows, there has been a proliferation of different loss functions to solve different classes of problems. We introduce a single information-theoretic equation that generalizes a large collection of modern loss functions in machine learning. In particular, we introduce a framework that shows that several broad classes of machine learning methods are precisely minimizing an integrated KL divergence between two conditional distributions: the supervisory and learned representations. This viewpoint exposes a hidden information geometry underlying clustering, spectral methods, dimensionality reduction, contrastive learning, and supervised learning. This framework enables the development of new loss functions by combining successful techniques from across the literature. We not only present a wide array of proofs, connecting over 23 different approaches, but we also leverage these theoretical results to create state-of-the-art unsupervised image classifiers that achieve a +8% improvement over the prior state-of-the-art on unsupervised classification on ImageNet-1K. We also demonstrate that I-Con can be used to derive principled debiasing methods which improve contrastive representation learners.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 04:15:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16929</guid></item><item><title>Pre-DPO: Improving Data Utilization in Direct Preference Optimization
  Using a Guiding Reference Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15843</link><description>Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) simplifies reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) for large language models (LLMs) by directly optimizing human preferences without an explicit reward model. We find that during DPO training, the reference model plays the role of a data weight adjuster. However, the common practice of initializing the policy and reference models identically in DPO can lead to inefficient data utilization and impose a performance ceiling. Meanwhile, the lack of a reference model in Simple Preference Optimization (SimPO) reduces training robustness and necessitates stricter conditions to prevent catastrophic forgetting. In this work, we propose Pre-DPO, a simple yet effective DPO-based training paradigm that enhances preference optimization performance by leveraging a guiding reference model. This reference model provides foresight into the optimal policy state achievable through the training preference data, serving as a guiding mechanism that adaptively assigns higher weights to samples more suitable for the model and lower weights to those less suitable. Extensive experiments on AlpacaEval 2.0 and Arena-Hard v0.1 benchmarks demonstrate that Pre-DPO consistently improves the performance of both DPO and SimPO, without relying on external models or additional data.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 01:32:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15843</guid></item><item><title>A Comprehensive Survey in LLM(-Agent) Full Stack Safety: Data, Training
  and Deployment</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15585</link><description>The remarkable success of Large Language Models (LLMs) has illuminated a promising pathway toward achieving Artificial General Intelligence for both academic and industrial communities, owing to their unprecedented performance across various applications. As LLMs continue to gain prominence in both research and commercial domains, their security and safety implications have become a growing concern, not only for researchers and corporations but also for every nation. Currently, existing surveys on LLM safety primarily focus on specific stages of the LLM lifecycle, e.g., deployment phase or fine-tuning phase, lacking a comprehensive understanding of the entire "lifechain" of LLMs. To address this gap, this paper introduces, for the first time, the concept of "full-stack" safety to systematically consider safety issues throughout the entire process of LLM training, deployment, and eventual commercialization. Compared to the off-the-shelf LLM safety surveys, our work demonstrates several distinctive advantages: (I) Comprehensive Perspective. We define the complete LLM lifecycle as encompassing data preparation, pre-training, post-training, deployment and final commercialization. To our knowledge, this represents the first safety survey to encompass the entire lifecycle of LLMs. (II) Extensive Literature Support. Our research is grounded in an exhaustive review of over 800+ papers, ensuring comprehensive coverage and systematic organization of security issues within a more holistic understanding. (III) Unique Insights. Through systematic literature analysis, we have developed reliable roadmaps and perspectives for each chapter. Our work identifies promising research directions, including safety in data generation, alignment techniques, model editing, and LLM-based agent systems. These insights provide valuable guidance for researchers pursuing future work in this field.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 04:45:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15585</guid></item><item><title>DreamO: A Unified Framework for Image Customization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16915</link><description>Recently, extensive research on image customization (e.g., identity, subject, style, background, etc.) demonstrates strong customization capabilities in large-scale generative models. However, most approaches are designed for specific tasks, restricting their generalizability to combine different types of condition. Developing a unified framework for image customization remains an open challenge. In this paper, we present DreamO, an image customization framework designed to support a wide range of tasks while facilitating seamless integration of multiple conditions. Specifically, DreamO utilizes a diffusion transformer (DiT) framework to uniformly process input of different types. During training, we construct a large-scale training dataset that includes various customization tasks, and we introduce a feature routing constraint to facilitate the precise querying of relevant information from reference images. Additionally, we design a placeholder strategy that associates specific placeholders with conditions at particular positions, enabling control over the placement of conditions in the generated results. Moreover, we employ a progressive training strategy consisting of three stages: an initial stage focused on simple tasks with limited data to establish baseline consistency, a full-scale training stage to comprehensively enhance the customization capabilities, and a final quality alignment stage to correct quality biases introduced by low-quality data. Extensive experiments demonstrate that the proposed DreamO can effectively perform various image customization tasks with high quality and flexibly integrate different types of control conditions.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 03:48:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16915</guid></item></channel></rss>