<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Babel: Open Multilingual Large Language Models Serving Over 90% of Global Speakers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.00865</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized natural language processing (NLP), yet open-source multilingual LLMs remain scarce, with existing models often limited in language coverage. Such models typically prioritize well-resourced languages, while widely spoken but under-resourced languages are often overlooked. To address this disparity, we introduce Babel, an open multilingual LLM that covers the top 25 languages by number of speakers, supports over 90% of the global population, and includes many languages neglected by other open multilingual LLMs. Unlike traditional continue pretraining approaches, Babel expands its parameter count through a layer extension technique that elevates Babel's performance ceiling. We introduce two variants: Babel-9B, designed for efficient inference and fine-tuning, and Babel-83B, which sets a new standard for open multilingual LLMs. Extensive evaluations on multilingual tasks demonstrate its superior performance compared to open LLMs of comparable size. In addition, using open-source supervised fine-tuning datasets, Babel achieves remarkable performance, with Babel-9B-Chat leading among 10B-sized LLMs and Babel-83B-Chat setting a new standard for multilingual tasks, reaching the same level of commercial models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 02:49:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.00865</guid></item><item><title>ABC: Achieving Better Control of Multimodal Embeddings using VLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.00329</link><description>Visual embedding models excel at zero-shot tasks like visual retrieval and classification. However, these models cannot be used for tasks that contain ambiguity or require user instruction. These tasks necessitate a multimodal embedding model, which outputs embeddings that combine visual and natural language input. Existing CLIP-based approaches embed images and text independently, and fuse the result. We find that this results in weak interactions between modalities, and poor user control over the representation. We introduce ABC, an open-source multimodal embedding model that uses a vision-language model backbone to deeply integrate image features with natural language instructions. ABC achieves bestfor-size performance on MSCOCO image-to-text retrieval and is the top performing model on classification and VQA tasks in the Massive Multimodal Embedding Benchmark. With a strongly unified vision-language representation, ABC can use natural language to solve subtle and potentially ambiguous visual retrieval problems. To evaluate this capability, we design CtrlBench, a benchmark that requires interleaving textual instructions with image content for correct retrieval. ABC advances the state of multimodal embeddings by offering high-quality representations and flexible natural language control. Our model and datasets are available at our project page.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 02:33:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.00329</guid></item><item><title>KodCode: A Diverse, Challenging, and Verifiable Synthetic Dataset for Coding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.02951</link><description>We introduce KodCode, a synthetic dataset that addresses the persistent challenge of acquiring high-quality, verifiable training data across diverse difficulties and domains for training Large Language Models for coding. Existing code-focused resources typically fail to ensure either the breadth of coverage (e.g., spanning simple coding tasks to advanced algorithmic problems) or verifiable correctness (e.g., unit tests). In contrast, KodCode comprises question-solution-test triplets that are systematically validated via a self-verification procedure. Our pipeline begins by synthesizing a broad range of coding questions, then generates solutions and test cases with additional attempts allocated to challenging problems. Finally, post-training data synthesis is done by rewriting questions into diverse formats and generating responses under a test-based reject sampling procedure from a reasoning model (DeepSeek R1). This pipeline yields a large-scale, robust and diverse coding dataset. KodCode is suitable for supervised fine-tuning and the paired unit tests also provide great potential for RL tuning. Fine-tuning experiments on coding benchmarks (HumanEval(+), MBPP(+), BigCodeBench, and LiveCodeBench) demonstrate that KodCode-tuned models achieve state-of-the-art performance, surpassing models like Qwen2.5-Coder-32B-Instruct and DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-70B.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 02:31:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.02951</guid></item><item><title>GEN3C: 3D-Informed World-Consistent Video Generation with Precise Camera Control</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.03751</link><description>We present GEN3C, a generative video model with precise Camera Control and temporal 3D Consistency. Prior video models already generate realistic videos, but they tend to leverage little 3D information, leading to inconsistencies, such as objects popping in and out of existence. Camera control, if implemented at all, is imprecise, because camera parameters are mere inputs to the neural network which must then infer how the video depends on the camera. In contrast, GEN3C is guided by a 3D cache: point clouds obtained by predicting the pixel-wise depth of seed images or previously generated frames. When generating the next frames, GEN3C is conditioned on the 2D renderings of the 3D cache with the new camera trajectory provided by the user. Crucially, this means that GEN3C neither has to remember what it previously generated nor does it have to infer the image structure from the camera pose. The model, instead, can focus all its generative power on previously unobserved regions, as well as advancing the scene state to the next frame. Our results demonstrate more precise camera control than prior work, as well as state-of-the-art results in sparse-view novel view synthesis, even in challenging settings such as driving scenes and monocular dynamic video. Results are best viewed in videos. Check out our webpage! https://research.nvidia.com/labs/toronto-ai/GEN3C/</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 03:13:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.03751</guid></item><item><title>Retrieval Models Aren't Tool-Savvy: Benchmarking Tool Retrieval for Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01763</link><description>Tool learning aims to augment large language models (LLMs) with diverse tools, enabling them to act as agents for solving practical tasks. Due to the limited context length of tool-using LLMs, adopting information retrieval (IR) models to select useful tools from large toolsets is a critical initial step. However, the performance of IR models in tool retrieval tasks remains underexplored and unclear. Most tool-use benchmarks simplify this step by manually pre-annotating a small set of relevant tools for each task, which is far from the real-world scenarios. In this paper, we propose ToolRet, a heterogeneous tool retrieval benchmark comprising 7.6k diverse retrieval tasks, and a corpus of 43k tools, collected from existing datasets. We benchmark six types of models on ToolRet. Surprisingly, even the models with strong performance in conventional IR benchmarks, exhibit poor performance on ToolRet. This low retrieval quality degrades the task pass rate of tool-use LLMs. As a further step, we contribute a large-scale training dataset with over 200k instances, which substantially optimizes the tool retrieval ability of IR models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 05:12:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01763</guid></item><item><title>FLAME: A Federated Learning Benchmark for Robotic Manipulation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01729</link><description>Recent progress in robotic manipulation has been fueled by large-scale datasets collected across diverse environments. Training robotic manipulation policies on these datasets is traditionally performed in a centralized manner, raising concerns regarding scalability, adaptability, and data privacy. While federated learning enables decentralized, privacy-preserving training, its application to robotic manipulation remains largely unexplored. We introduce FLAME (Federated Learning Across Manipulation Environments), the first benchmark designed for federated learning in robotic manipulation. FLAME consists of: (i) a set of large-scale datasets of over 160,000 expert demonstrations of multiple manipulation tasks, collected across a wide range of simulated environments; (ii) a training and evaluation framework for robotic policy learning in a federated setting. We evaluate standard federated learning algorithms in FLAME, showing their potential for distributed policy learning and highlighting key challenges. Our benchmark establishes a foundation for scalable, adaptive, and privacy-aware robotic learning.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 05:11:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01729</guid></item><item><title>Benchmarking Large Language Models for Multi-Language Software Vulnerability Detection</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01449</link><description>Recent advancements in generative AI have led to the widespread adoption of large language models (LLMs) in software engineering, addressing numerous long-standing challenges. However, a comprehensive study examining the capabilities of LLMs in software vulnerability detection (SVD), a crucial aspect of software security, is currently lacking. Existing research primarily focuses on evaluating LLMs using C/C++ datasets. It typically explores only one or two strategies among prompt engineering, instruction tuning, and sequence classification fine-tuning for open-source LLMs. Consequently, there is a significant knowledge gap regarding the effectiveness of diverse LLMs in detecting vulnerabilities across various programming languages. To address this knowledge gap, we present a comprehensive empirical study evaluating the performance of LLMs on the SVD task. We have compiled a comprehensive dataset comprising 8,260 vulnerable functions in Python, 7,505 in Java, and 28,983 in JavaScript. We assess five open-source LLMs using multiple approaches, including prompt engineering, instruction tuning, and sequence classification fine-tuning. These LLMs are benchmarked against five fine-tuned small language models and two open-source static application security testing tools. Furthermore, we explore two avenues to improve LLM performance on SVD: a) Data perspective: Retraining models using downsampled balanced datasets. b) Model perspective: Investigating ensemble learning methods that combine predictions from multiple LLMs. Our comprehensive experiments demonstrate that SVD remains a challenging task for LLMs. This study provides a thorough understanding of the role of LLMs in SVD and offers practical insights for future advancements in leveraging generative AI to enhance software security practices.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 05:11:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01449</guid></item><item><title>CognitiveDrone: A VLA Model and Evaluation Benchmark for Real-Time Cognitive Task Solving and Reasoning in UAVs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01378</link><description>This paper introduces CognitiveDrone, a novel Vision-Language-Action (VLA) model tailored for complex Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) tasks that demand advanced cognitive abilities. Trained on a dataset comprising over 8,000 simulated flight trajectories across three key categories-Human Recognition, Symbol Understanding, and Reasoning-the model generates real-time 4D action commands based on first-person visual inputs and textual instructions. To further enhance performance in intricate scenarios, we propose CognitiveDrone-R1, which integrates an additional Vision-Language Model (VLM) reasoning module to simplify task directives prior to high-frequency control. Experimental evaluations using our open-source benchmark, CognitiveDroneBench, reveal that while a racing-oriented model (RaceVLA) achieves an overall success rate of 31.3%, the base CognitiveDrone model reaches 59.6%, and CognitiveDrone-R1 attains a success rate of 77.2%. These results demonstrate improvements of up to 30% in critical cognitive tasks, underscoring the effectiveness of incorporating advanced reasoning capabilities into UAV control systems. Our contributions include the development of a state-of-the-art VLA model for UAV control and the introduction of the first dedicated benchmark for assessing cognitive tasks in drone operations. The complete repository is available at cognitivedrone.github.io</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 05:10:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01378</guid></item><item><title>SwiLTra-Bench: The Swiss Legal Translation Benchmark</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01372</link><description>In Switzerland legal translation is uniquely important due to the country's four official languages and requirements for multilingual legal documentation. However, this process traditionally relies on professionals who must be both legal experts and skilled translators -- creating bottlenecks and impacting effective access to justice. To address this challenge, we introduce SwiLTra-Bench, a comprehensive multilingual benchmark of over 180K aligned Swiss legal translation pairs comprising laws, headnotes, and press releases across all Swiss languages along with English, designed to evaluate LLM-based translation systems. Our systematic evaluation reveals that frontier models achieve superior translation performance across all document types, while specialized translation systems excel specifically in laws but under-perform in headnotes. Through rigorous testing and human expert validation, we demonstrate that while fine-tuning open SLMs significantly improves their translation quality, they still lag behind the best zero-shot prompted frontier models such as Claude-3.5-Sonnet. Additionally, we present SwiLTra-Judge, a specialized LLM evaluation system that aligns best with human expert assessments.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 05:10:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.01372</guid></item><item><title>Interact, Instruct to Improve: A LLM-Driven Parallel Actor-Reasoner Framework for Enhancing Autonomous Vehicle Interactions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.00502</link><description>Autonomous Vehicles (AVs) have entered the commercialization stage, but their limited ability to interact and express intentions still poses challenges in interactions with Human-driven Vehicles (HVs). Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) enable bidirectional human-machine communication, but the conflict between slow inference speed and the need for real-time decision-making challenges practical deployment. To address these issues, this paper introduces a parallel Actor-Reasoner framework designed to enable explicit bidirectional AV-HV interactions across multiple scenarios. First, by facilitating interactions between the LLM-driven Reasoner and heterogeneous simulated HVs during training, an interaction memory database, referred to as the Actor, is established. Then, by introducing the memory partition module and the two-layer memory retrieval module, the Actor's ability to handle heterogeneous HVs is significantly enhanced. Ablation studies and comparisons with other decision-making methods demonstrate that the proposed Actor-Reasoner framework significantly improves safety and efficiency. Finally, with the combination of the external Human-Machine Interface (eHMI) information derived from Reasoner's reasoning and the feasible action solutions retrieved from the Actor, the effectiveness of the proposed Actor-Reasoner is confirmed in multi-scenario field interactions. Our code is available at https://github.com/FanGShiYuu/Actor-Reasoner.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 02:37:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.00502</guid></item></channel></rss>