<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Mindscape-Aware Retrieval Augmented Generation for Improved Long Context Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17220</link><description>MiA-RAG, a Mindscape-Aware Retrieval-Augmented Generation system, enhances LLM-based RAG with global context awareness through hierarchical summarization, improving long-context tasks and evidence-based understanding.  					AI-generated summary 				 Humans understand long and complex texts by relying on a holistic semantic representation of the content. This global view helps organize prior knowledge, interpret new information, and integrate evidence dispersed across a document, as revealed by the Mindscape-Aware Capability of humans in psychology. Current Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems lack such guidance and therefore struggle with long-context tasks. In this paper, we propose Mindscape-Aware RAG (MiA-RAG), the first approach that equips LLM-based RAG systems with explicit global context awareness. MiA-RAG builds a mindscape through hierarchical summarization and conditions both retrieval and generation on this global semantic representation. This enables the retriever to form enriched query embeddings and the generator to reason over retrieved evidence within a coherent global context. We evaluate MiA-RAG across diverse long-context and bilingual benchmarks for evidence-based understanding and global sense-making. It consistently surpasses baselines, and further analysis shows that it aligns local details with a coherent global representation, enabling more human-like long-context retrieval and reasoning.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 03:11:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17220</guid></item><item><title>InsertAnywhere: Bridging 4D Scene Geometry and Diffusion Models for Realistic Video Object Insertion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17504</link><description>InsertAnywhere framework enhances video object insertion by generating geometrically consistent and visually coherent scenarios through 4D aware mask generation and diffusion-based synthesis.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in diffusion-based video generation have opened new possibilities for controllable video editing, yet realistic video object insertion (VOI) remains challenging due to limited 4D scene understanding and inadequate handling of occlusion and lighting effects. We present InsertAnywhere, a new VOI framework that achieves geometrically consistent object placement and appearance-faithful video synthesis. Our method begins with a 4D aware mask generation module that reconstructs the scene geometry and propagates user specified object placement across frames while maintaining temporal coherence and occlusion consistency. Building upon this spatial foundation, we extend a diffusion based video generation model to jointly synthesize the inserted object and its surrounding local variations such as illumination and shading. To enable supervised training, we introduce ROSE++, an illumination aware synthetic dataset constructed by transforming the ROSE object removal dataset into triplets of object removed video, object present video, and a VLM generated reference image. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that our framework produces geometrically plausible and visually coherent object insertions across diverse real world scenarios, significantly outperforming existing research and commercial models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 02:37:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17504</guid></item><item><title>MAI-UI Technical Report: Real-World Centric Foundation GUI Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.22047</link><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:33:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.22047</guid></item><item><title>See Less, See Right: Bi-directional Perceptual Shaping For Multimodal Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.22120</link><description>Large vision-language models (VLMs) often benefit from intermediate visual cues, either injected via external tools or generated as latent visual tokens during reasoning, but these mechanisms still overlook fine-grained visual evidence (e.g., polylines in charts), generalize poorly across domains, and incur high inference-time cost. In this paper, we propose Bi-directional Perceptual Shaping (BiPS), which transforms question-conditioned masked views into bidirectional where-to-look signals that shape perception during training. BiPS first applies a KL-consistency constraint between the original image and an evidence-preserving view that keeps only question-relevant regions, encouraging coarse but complete coverage of supporting pixels. It then applies a KL-separation constraint between the original and an evidence-ablated view where critical pixels are masked so the image no longer supports the original answer, discouraging text-only shortcuts (i.e., answering from text alone) and enforcing fine-grained visual reliance. Across eight benchmarks, BiPS boosts Qwen2.5-VL-7B by 8.2% on average and shows strong out-of-domain generalization to unseen datasets and image types.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 02:56:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.22120</guid></item><item><title>TimeBill: Time-Budgeted Inference for Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.21859</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in time-critical systems, such as robotics, autonomous driving, embodied intelligence, and industrial automation, where generating accurate responses within a given time budget is crucial for decision-making, control, or safety-critical tasks. However, the auto-regressive generation process of LLMs makes it challenging to model and estimate the end-to-end execution time. Furthermore, existing efficient inference methods based on a fixed key-value (KV) cache eviction ratio struggle to adapt to varying tasks with diverse time budgets, where an improper eviction ratio may lead to incomplete inference or a drop in response performance. In this paper, we propose TimeBill, a novel time-budgeted inference framework for LLMs that balances the inference efficiency and response performance. To be more specific, we propose a fine-grained response length predictor (RLP) and an execution time estimator (ETE) to accurately predict the end-to-end execution time of LLMs. Following this, we develop a time-budgeted efficient inference approach that adaptively adjusts the KV cache eviction ratio based on execution time prediction and the given time budget. Finally, through extensive experiments, we demonstrate the advantages of TimeBill in improving task completion rate and maintaining response performance under various overrun strategies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 03:39:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.21859</guid></item><item><title>SVBench: Evaluation of Video Generation Models on Social Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.21507</link><description>Recent text-to-video generation models exhibit remarkable progress in visual realism, motion fidelity, and text-video alignment, yet they remain fundamentally limited in their ability to generate socially coherent behavior. Unlike humans, who effortlessly infer intentions, beliefs, emotions, and social norms from brief visual cues, current models tend to render literal scenes without capturing the underlying causal or psychological logic. To systematically evaluate this gap, we introduce the first benchmark for social reasoning in video generation. Grounded in findings from developmental and social psychology, our benchmark organizes thirty classic social cognition paradigms into seven core dimensions, including mental-state inference, goal-directed action, joint attention, social coordination, prosocial behavior, social norms, and multi-agent strategy. To operationalize these paradigms, we develop a fully training-free agent-based pipeline that (i) distills the reasoning mechanism of each experiment, (ii) synthesizes diverse video-ready scenarios, (iii) enforces conceptual neutrality and difficulty control through cue-based critique, and (iv) evaluates generated videos using a high-capacity VLM judge across five interpretable dimensions of social reasoning. Using this framework, we conduct the first large-scale study across seven state-of-the-art video generation systems. Our results reveal substantial performance gaps: while modern models excel in surface-level plausibility, they systematically fail in intention recognition, belief reasoning, joint attention, and prosocial inference.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 03:34:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.21507</guid></item><item><title>SWE-RM: Execution-free Feedback For Software Engineering Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.21919</link><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:33:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.21919</guid></item><item><title>UniPercept: Towards Unified Perceptual-Level Image Understanding across Aesthetics, Quality, Structure, and Texture</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.21675</link><description>Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have achieved remarkable progress in visual understanding tasks such as visual grounding, segmentation, and captioning. However, their ability to perceive perceptual-level image features remains limited. In this work, we present UniPercept-Bench, a unified framework for perceptual-level image understanding across three key domains: Aesthetics, Quality, Structure and Texture. We establish a hierarchical definition system and construct large-scale datasets to evaluate perceptual-level image understanding. Based on this foundation, we develop a strong baseline UniPercept trained via Domain-Adaptive Pre-Training and Task-Aligned RL, enabling robust generalization across both Visual Rating (VR) and Visual Question Answering (VQA) tasks. UniPercept outperforms existing MLLMs on perceptual-level image understanding and can serve as a plug-and-play reward model for text-to-image generation. This work defines Perceptual-Level Image Understanding in the era of MLLMs and, through the introduction of a comprehensive benchmark together with a strong baseline, provides a solid foundation for advancing perceptual-level multimodal image understanding.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 03:10:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.21675</guid></item><item><title>ProEdit: Inversion-based Editing From Prompts Done Right</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.22118</link><description>Inversion-based visual editing provides an effective and training-free way to edit an image or a video based on user instructions. Existing methods typically inject source image information during the sampling process to maintain editing consistency. However, this sampling strategy overly relies on source information, which negatively affects the edits in the target image (e.g., failing to change the subject's atributes like pose, number, or color as instructed). In this work, we propose ProEdit to address this issue both in the attention and the latent aspects. In the attention aspect, we introduce KV-mix, which mixes KV features of the source and the target in the edited region, mitigating the influence of the source image on the editing region while maintaining background consistency. In the latent aspect, we propose Latents-Shift, which perturbs the edited region of the source latent, eliminating the influence of the inverted latent on the sampling. Extensive experiments on several image and video editing benchmarks demonstrate that our method achieves SOTA performance. In addition, our design is plug-and-play, which can be seamlessly integrated into existing inversion and editing methods, such as RF-Solver, FireFlow and UniEdit.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 02:37:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.22118</guid></item></channel></rss>