<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Ovi - Generate Videos With Audio Like VEO 3 or SORA 2 - Run Locally - Open Source for Free</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/329376915558167</link><description>Ovi - Generate Videos With Audio Like VEO 3 or SORA 2 - Run Locally - Open Source for Free Download and install : https://www.patreon.com/posts/140393220 Quick demo tutorial : https://youtu.be/uE0QabiHmRw Ovi: Twin Backbone Cross-Modal Fusion for Audio-Video Generation Project page : https://aaxwaz.github.io/Ovi/ SECourses Ovi Pro Premium App Features Full scale ultra advanced app for Ovi - an open source project that can generate videos from both text prompts and image + text prompts with real audio. Project page is here : https://aaxwaz.github.io/Ovi/ I have developed an ultra advanced Gradio app and much better pipeline that fully supports block swapping Now we can generate full quality videos with as low as 8.2 GB VRAM Hopefully I will work on dynamic on load FP8_Scaled tomorrow to improve VRAM even further So more VRAM optimizations will come hopefully tomorrow Our implemented block swapping is the very best one out there - I took the approach from famous Kohya Musubi tuner The...</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/329376915558167</guid></item><item><title>Try the Hugging Face Space demo for</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/704561076669428</link><description>Try the Hugging Face Space demo for Logics-MLLM/Logics-Parsing , the latest multimodal VLM from the Logics Team at Alibaba Group. It enables end-to-end document parsing with precise content extraction in markdown format, and it also generates a clean HTML representation of the document while preserving its logical structure. 🤗🔥 Additionally, I’ve integrated one of my recent works — prithivMLmods/Gliese-OCR-7B-Post1.0 — which also excels at document comprehension. ⭐ Space / App : prithivMLmods/Logics-Parsing-VLM 📄 Technical Report by the Logics Team, Alibaba Group : Logics-Parsing Technical Report (2509.19760) ⚡ Collections : prithivMLmods/multimodal-implementations-67c9982ea04b39f0608badb0 Other Pages: ➔ Multimodal VLMs - July'25 : prithivMLmods/multimodal-vlms-until-july25-688312e6b840e1e156f13027 ➔ Multimodal VLMs - Aug'25 : prithivMLmods/multimodal-vlms-aug25-68a56aac39fe8084f3c168bd ➔ VL caption — &lt; Sep 15 ’25 : prithivMLmods/vl-caption-sep-15-25-68c7f6d737985c63c13e2391 . . ....</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/704561076669428</guid></item><item><title>How to compress long code context? 📚</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/YerbaPage/558970453952386</link><description>How to compress long code context? 📚 Check out our LongCodeZip! Paper just got accepted to ASE 2025. 🔥 Code: https://github.com/YerbaPage/LongCodeZip Paper: LongCodeZip: Compress Long Context for Code Language Models (2510.00446) See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/YerbaPage/558970453952386</guid></item><item><title>Introducing a Hugging Face Tutorial on Regression</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/SelmaNajih001/436109607618945</link><description>Introducing a Hugging Face Tutorial on Regression While Hugging Face offers extensive tutorials on classification and NLP tasks, there is very little guidance on performing regression tasks with Transformers. In my latest article, I provide a step-by-step guide to running regression using Hugging Face, applying it to financial news data to predict stock returns. In this tutorial, you will learn how to: -Prepare and preprocess textual and numerical data for regression -Configure a Transformer model for regression tasks -Apply the model to real-world financial datasets with fully reproducible code Read the full article here: https://huggingface.co/blog/SelmaNajih001/how-to-run-a-regression-using-hugging-face The dataset used: SelmaNajih001/FinancialClassification See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/SelmaNajih001/436109607618945</guid></item><item><title>🚀 Exciting News! We've released a Performance Marketing Expert Dataset from Hawky.ai [www.hawky.ai]</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Sri-Vigneshwar-DJ/952078344859787</link><description>🚀 Exciting News! We've released a Performance Marketing Expert Dataset from Hawky.ai [www.hawky.ai] Hawky-ai This dataset empowers AI models with cutting-edge strategies for Meta, Google Ads, and TikTok campaigns. It includes: 1. Multi-platform strategies for e-commerce, DTC, B2B, and more 2. Creative optimization and audience targeting insights 3. ROI-driven recommendations based on 2025 best practices Sri-Vigneshwar-DJ/Performance-Marketing-Data See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Sri-Vigneshwar-DJ/952078344859787</guid></item><item><title>Ever wanted an open‑source deep research agent? Meet Deepresearch‑Agent 🔍🤖</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Parveshiiii/260243419840768</link><description>Ever wanted an open‑source deep research agent? Meet Deepresearch‑Agent 🔍🤖 1. Multi‑step reasoning: Reflects between steps, fills gaps, iterates until evidence is solid. 2. Research‑augmented: Generates queries, searches, synthesizes, and cites sources. 3. Fullstack + LLM‑friendly: React/Tailwind frontend, LangGraph/FastAPI backend; works with OpenAI/Gemini. 🔗 GitHub: https://github.com/Parveshiiii/Deepresearch-Agent See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Parveshiiii/260243419840768</guid></item><item><title>Sora 2 invitation code, share your Sora 2 invitation code!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/404Zen/898612621867670</link><description>Sora 2 invitation code, share your Sora 2 invitation code! Also, you can use the imini AI platform directly: https://imini.com/ See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/404Zen/898612621867670</guid></item><item><title>✅ New Article: *Cosmic Exploration PoC — Part 4*</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/kanaria007/107464223968156</link><description>✅ New Article: *Cosmic Exploration PoC — Part 4* Title: 🚀 PoC for Space Exploration with Structured Intelligence Computers (SIC) — Long-Horizon Starship Simulation 🔗 https://huggingface.co/blog/kanaria007/cosmic-exploration-starship --- Summary: Exploration across stars is not a question of distance — it is a question of *time*. This PoC tests whether mission identity, ethics, and governance can endure across centuries of generational drift and uncertainty. A starship becomes more than transport: it is a *self-sustaining arc of civilization*. &gt; The challenge is not propulsion. &gt; *It is continuity of mind and mission.* --- Why It Matters: • Demonstrates structural continuity over simulated 500-year journeys • Validates conflict mediation and governance stability without collapse • Proves that ethics and identity can persist across generations --- What’s Inside: • Starship OS integrating resilience, ethics, and memory loops • Simulation of generational conflict, scarcity events, value...</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/kanaria007/107464223968156</guid></item><item><title>🥊  Big Code Arena is live!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ZennyKenny/911264518414164</link><description>🥊 Big Code Arena is live! bigcode/arena 💡 bigcode is an open scientific collaboration working on responsible training of large language models for coding applications. 👉 The Arena ranks LLMs based on their ability to support natural language vibe coding requests in a competitive format, based on feedback from human reviewers. 🧠 It was a pleasure to contribute to this project led by @ terryyz and appear as an additional contributor in the Big Code Arena paper. See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ZennyKenny/911264518414164</guid></item><item><title>Plextek just launched free access to a real-world radar dataset for experimentation, aimed at supporting system integrators, AI, and ML innovators!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/InezCornell/283687499249287</link><description>Plextek just launched free access to a real-world radar dataset for experimentation, aimed at supporting system integrators, AI, and ML innovators! Radar is an essential sensing technology, but access to high-quality data can often be a barrier for researchers and developers. By making this dataset freely available, Plextek is helping to accelerate innovation in areas ranging from autonomous systems to advanced defence applications. Get yours here for free: https://www.plextek.com/learn/radar-data-for-experimentation/ See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/InezCornell/283687499249287</guid></item></channel></rss>