<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>You can now run Kimi K2 Thinking locally with our Dynamic 1-bit GGUFs:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/603265034116639</link><description>You can now run Kimi K2 Thinking locally with our Dynamic 1-bit GGUFs: unsloth/Kimi-K2-Thinking-GGUF We shrank the 1T model to 245GB (-62%) &amp; retained ~85% of accuracy on Aider Polyglot. Run on &gt;247GB RAM for fast inference. We also collaborated with the Moonshot AI Kimi team on a system prompt fix! 🥰 Guide + fix details: https://docs.unsloth.ai/models/kimi-k2-thinking-how-to-run-locally See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/603265034116639</guid></item><item><title>Qwen Image Base Model Training vs FLUX SRPO Training 20 images comparison (top ones Qwen bottom ones FLUX) - Same Dataset (28 imgs) - I can't return back to FLUX such as massive difference - Qwen destroys the FLUX at complex prompts and emotions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/857881021159484</link><description>Qwen Image Base Model Training vs FLUX SRPO Training 20 images comparison (top ones Qwen bottom ones FLUX) - Same Dataset (28 imgs) - I can't return back to FLUX such as massive difference - Qwen destroys the FLUX at complex prompts and emotions Full tutorial link &gt; https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DPX3eBTuO_Y Info This is a full comprehensive step-by-step tutorial for how to train Qwen Image models. This tutorial covers how to do LoRA training and full Fine-Tuning / DreamBooth training on Qwen Image models. It covers both the Qwen Image base model and the Qwen Image Edit Plus 2509 model. This tutorial is the product of 21 days of full R&amp;D, costing over $800 in cloud services to find the best configurations for training. Furthermore, we have developed an amazing, ultra-easy-to-use Gradio app to use the legendary Kohya Musubi Tuner trainer with ease. You will be able to train locally on your Windows computer with GPUs with as little as 6 GB of VRAM for both LoRA and Fine-Tuning....</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/857881021159484</guid></item><item><title>In November, with</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/branikita/750415743005221</link><description>In November, with Robonine are starting work on the next version of the SO ARM 102 manipulator. The version will be open source and agreed upon with @ therobotbuilder the creator of the original manipulator. We are planning to: - increase positioning accuracy by approximately 2x using Feetech STS 3250 motors - increase working payload from 200g to 300g - increase rigidity using parametric design optimization and stiffer plastic - increase length to 550 mm - increase folding angles - use ISO 9409-1-50-4-M6 mounting standard for the gripper - use a parallel gripper in the default version - update the mounting plate for different camera types, M3 grid with 12.5 mm pitch - add table mounting standard 80x80 M8 The number of degrees of freedom and basic kinematics will remain the same. Are there other things missing for working with SO ARM 100? - Any standard inputs/outputs, for example? - Status indicators? - Perhaps some types of mounting for third-party grippers are more preferable? -...</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/branikita/750415743005221</guid></item><item><title>Introducing Photo-Mate-v2, based on FLUX.1-Kontext-dev, for advanced image manipulation tasks. It supports transforming scenes into top-down/bottom-up perspectives, CAM-right/left-view and its reverse, as well as general kontext-specified object removal. Below is the list of demos and adapters.🔥🤗</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/314473561569432</link><description>Introducing Photo-Mate-v2, based on FLUX.1-Kontext-dev, for advanced image manipulation tasks. It supports transforming scenes into top-down/bottom-up perspectives, CAM-right/left-view and its reverse, as well as general kontext-specified object removal. Below is the list of demos and adapters.🔥🤗 ➤ Spaces [Demo] : prithivMLmods/Kontext-Photo-Mate-v2 Kontext-Adapters : ✦ Kontext-Bottom-Up-View: prithivMLmods/Kontext-Bottom-Up-View ✦ Kontext-CAM-Right-View: prithivMLmods/Kontext-CAM-Right-View ✦ Kontext-Top-Down-View: prithivMLmods/Kontext-Top-Down-View ✦ Kontext-CAM-Left-View: prithivMLmods/Kontext-CAM-Left-View ✦ Kontext-CAM-Right-View: prithivMLmods/Kontext-CAM-Right-View ✦ Kontext-Unblur-Upscale: prithivMLmods/Kontext-Unblur-Upscale ✦ Kontext-0811-exp: prithivMLmods/Kontext-0811-exp Photo-Mate Collection: ✦ Kontext CAM Angles: https://huggingface.co/collections/prithivMLmods/kontext-cam-angles ✦ i2i - Kontext (exp): https://huggingface.co/collections/prithivMLmods/i2i-kontext-exp...</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/314473561569432</guid></item><item><title>💸🤑You don’t need 100 GPUs to train something amazing!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/lunarflu/887027437678824</link><description>💸🤑You don’t need 100 GPUs to train something amazing! Our Smol Training Playbook teaches you a better path to world-class LLMs, for free! Check out the #1 trending space on 🤗 : HuggingFaceTB/smol-training-playbook See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/lunarflu/887027437678824</guid></item><item><title>Hugging Face MCP Server v0.2.40</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/evalstate/266178055669254</link><description>Hugging Face MCP Server v0.2.40 ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ Improved progressive disclosure and descriptions for Jobs tool. See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/evalstate/266178055669254</guid></item><item><title>I just threw Qwen3-0.6B in BF16 into an on device AI drag race on AMD Strix Halo with vLLM:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mitkox/956503968449347</link><description>I just threw Qwen3-0.6B in BF16 into an on device AI drag race on AMD Strix Halo with vLLM: 564 tokens/sec on short 100-token sprints 96 tokens/sec on 8K-token marathons TL;DR You don't just run AI on AMD. You negotiate with it. The hardware absolutely delivers. Spoiler alert; there is exactly ONE configuration where vLLM + ROCm + Triton + PyTorch + Drivers + Ubuntu Kernel to work at the same time. Finding it required the patience of a saint Consumer AMD for AI inference is the ultimate "budget warrior" play, insane performance-per-euro, but you need hardcore technical skills that would make a senior sysadmin nod in quiet respect. See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mitkox/956503968449347</guid></item><item><title>7+ Main precision formats used in AI:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/707388483660581</link><description>7+ Main precision formats used in AI: Precision is very important in AI as it shapes how accurate and efficient models are. It controls how finely numbers are represented, approximating real-world values with formats like fixed-point and floating-point. A recent BF16 → FP16 study renewed attention to precision impact. Here are the main precision types used in AI, from full precision for training to ultra-low precision for inference: 1. FP32 (Float32): Standard full-precision float used in most training: 1 sign bit, 8 exponent bits, 23 mantissa bits. Default for backward-compatible training and baseline numerical stability 2. FP16 (Float16) → https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10947v6 Half-precision float. It balances accuracy and efficiency. 1 sign bit, 5 exponent bits, 10 mantissa bits. Common on NVIDIA Tensor Cores and mixed-precision setups. There’s now a new wave of using it in reinforcement learning: https://www.turingpost.com/p/fp16 3. BF16 (BFloat16) →...</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/707388483660581</guid></item><item><title>To make agent work for us when we sleep, we must break the curse of sessions.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/onekq/334078561878389</link><description>To make agent work for us when we sleep, we must break the curse of sessions. See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/onekq/334078561878389</guid></item><item><title>There is no anxiety quite like powering up 2KW of basement compute after rewiring it all. Small bit of trouble with the horizontal 3090 because I misread my motherboard manual, but otherwise so far so good.. Next we see if I've built up enough cooling to hit my target TDP on those 3-slot nvlinked cards especially.  The 4-slot bridges are much easier to work with but their prices went bananas and I couldn't acquire a second, so gotta get a little creative with intakes.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mike-ravkine/305096078349013</link><description>There is no anxiety quite like powering up 2KW of basement compute after rewiring it all. Small bit of trouble with the horizontal 3090 because I misread my motherboard manual, but otherwise so far so good.. Next we see if I've built up enough cooling to hit my target TDP on those 3-slot nvlinked cards especially. The 4-slot bridges are much easier to work with but their prices went bananas and I couldn't acquire a second, so gotta get a little creative with intakes. See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:34:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mike-ravkine/305096078349013</guid></item></channel></rss>