<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>You can now run MiniMax-2.5 locally! 🚀</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/750340203924335</link><description>You can now run MiniMax-2.5 locally! 🚀 At 230B parameters, MiniMax-2.5 is the strongest LLM under 700B params, delivering SOTA agentic coding &amp; chat. Run Dynamic 3/4-bit on a 128GB Mac for 20 tokens/s. Guide: https://unsloth.ai/docs/models/minimax-2.5 GGUF: unsloth/MiniMax-M2.5-GGUF See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/750340203924335</guid></item><item><title>My home lab for AI models - llmlaba v1</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/kostakoff/584269728210158</link><description>My home lab for AI models - llmlaba v1 After I began learning MLOps I realized that I needed some kind of home lab, there are a lot of GPUs that I need to learn how to set up and test. So I spent some time to do a researching which platform I could buy or build. My requirements ware: - Limited budget - Power supply 1 kW or higher - Few PCIe slots to be able to install more than one gpu - Zero maintenance cost, I don't want spend a lot of time or money to maintain lab hardware, except for the GPUs I chose the Intel Mac Pro 7.1: - Prices on eBay acceptable - Excelent cooling - 1.4 kW power supply - 7 PCIe slots - Zero maintenance: I don't need to do anything with the Mac Pro hardware; it just works - Classic UEFI boot loader It requires a bit of OS preparation: 1. Install Ubuntu 24.04 (it works with the general PC ISO image) 2. Set up T2 drivers sudo apt install -y dkms linux-headers-$( uname -r) applesmc-t2 apple-bce lm-sensors 3. Install t2fanrd to manually manage fans...</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/kostakoff/584269728210158</guid></item><item><title>You can now run Qwen3.5 locally! 💜</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/198614576061440</link><description>You can now run Qwen3.5 locally! 💜 Qwen3.5-397B-A17B is an open MoE vision reasoning LLM for agentic coding &amp; chat. It performs on par with Gemini 3 Pro, Claude Opus 4.5 &amp; GPT-5.2. GGUF: unsloth/Qwen3.5-397B-A17B-GGUF Run Dynamic 3-bit on a 192GB Mac for 20 tokens/s. Guide: https://unsloth.ai/docs/models/qwen3.5 See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/198614576061440</guid></item><item><title>Here is one of the equations that make up the worlds first Artificial General Intelligence. Remember when building Artificial Intelligence or anything on a device it all starts out binary. Everything starts out with data flow physics and mathmatics</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Janady07/852502523222465</link><description>Here is one of the equations that make up the worlds first Artificial General Intelligence. Remember when building Artificial Intelligence or anything on a device it all starts out binary. Everything starts out with data flow physics and mathmatics See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Janady07/852502523222465</guid></item><item><title>MiniMax M2.5 is now available on the hub 🚀</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/578564678362048</link><description>MiniMax M2.5 is now available on the hub 🚀 MiniMaxAI/MiniMax-M2.5 ✨ 229B - Modified MIT license ✨37% faster than M2.1 ✨ ~$1/hour at 100 TPS See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/578564678362048</guid></item><item><title>Gemma 3 (1b, 4b, 12b and 27b) - Uncensored full Reasoning/Thinking models fine tuned using top distill datasets.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DavidAU/658014279530502</link><description>Gemma 3 (1b, 4b, 12b and 27b) - Uncensored full Reasoning/Thinking models fine tuned using top distill datasets. 20 Gemma 3 models 1B, 4B, 12B and 27B with full reasoning using GLM 4.7 Flash, GPT, Claude and Gemini datasets and more fully fine tuned using Unsloth. Most models are Heretic'ed (uncensored) first, and tuned second. This vastly improves the model. Models are also bench marked and in almost all cases exceed org model metrics - and in some cases by a lot. Enjoy the freedom and more powerful THINKING/REASONING and UNCENSORED Gemma 3s ! https://huggingface.co/collections/DavidAU/gemma-3-reasoning-thinking-models-incl-uncensored See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DavidAU/658014279530502</guid></item><item><title>Dropping the Qwen3 VL Series of Unredacted MAX-VL models. These models have undergone multi-stage training to minimize refusal rates through continuous abliterated optimization. You can find the models in BF16, FP8-Dynamic, and GGUF formats at the links below.🔥🚀</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/560324615932995</link><description>Dropping the Qwen3 VL Series of Unredacted MAX-VL models. These models have undergone multi-stage training to minimize refusal rates through continuous abliterated optimization. You can find the models in BF16, FP8-Dynamic, and GGUF formats at the links below.🔥🚀 Unredacted MAX - VL: ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-4B-Instruct-Unredacted-MAX ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-4B-Thinking-Unredacted-MAX ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-8B-Instruct-Unredacted-MAX ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-8B-Thinking-Unredacted-MAX Unredacted MAX - VL [FP8] ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-4B-Instruct-Unredacted-MAX-FP8 ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-4B-Thinking-Unredacted-MAX-FP8 ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-8B-Instruct-Unredacted-MAX-FP8 ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-8B-Thinking-Unredacted-MAX-FP8 Unredacted MAX - VL [GGUF] ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-4B-Instruct-Unredacted-MAX-GGUF ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-4B-Thinking-Unredacted-MAX-GGUF ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-8B-Instruct-Unredacted-MAX-GGUF ➜ prithivMLmods/Qwen3-VL-8B-Thinking-Unredacted-MAX-GGUF...</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/560324615932995</guid></item><item><title>is the chat feature down? recently I can not have success to get responses for my prompts.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/demirytu/616984337971296</link><description>is the chat feature down? recently I can not have success to get responses for my prompts. See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/demirytu/616984337971296</guid></item><item><title>While doing various projects I kept running into situations where I wanted to be able to have representative samples of some of the current large SOTA datasets that were smaller so I didn't need to worry about slicing or anything else at runtime.  So, I created sub datasets making sure to keep the same ratios of data sources.  Each dataset card provides info for what's in it.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/krisbailey/322212397790634</link><description>While doing various projects I kept running into situations where I wanted to be able to have representative samples of some of the current large SOTA datasets that were smaller so I didn't need to worry about slicing or anything else at runtime. So, I created sub datasets making sure to keep the same ratios of data sources. Each dataset card provides info for what's in it. 100M token datasets: RedPajama v2 100M Falcon RefinedWeb 100M Cosmopedia 100M 1B token datasets: Fineweb-edu 1B RedPajama v1 1B RedPajama v2 1B (use this one) Cosmopedia 1B 10B token datasets: RedPajama v1 10B Cosmopedia 10B Collection here: https://huggingface.co/collections/krisbailey/bite-size-data See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/krisbailey/322212397790634</guid></item><item><title>In 2017, my RNNs were babbling. Today, they are hallucinating beautifully.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mrs83/555686632418762</link><description>In 2017, my RNNs were babbling. Today, they are hallucinating beautifully. 10 years ago, getting an LSTM to output coherent English was a struggle. 10 years later, after a "cure" based on FineWeb-EDU and a custom synthetic mix for causal conversation, the results are fascinating. We trained this on ~10B tokens on a single AMD GPU (ROCm). It is not a Transformer: Echo-DSRN (400M) is a novel recurrent architecture inspired by Hymba, RWKV, and xLSTM, designed to challenge the "Attention is All You Need" monopoly on the Edge. The ambitious goal is to build a small instruct model with RAG and tool usage capabilities ( ethicalabs/Kurtis-EON1 ) 📊 The Benchmarks (Size: 400M) For a model this size (trained on &lt;10B tokens), the specialized performance is surprising: *SciQ*: 73.8% 🦄 (This rivals billion-parameter models in pure fact retrieval). *PIQA*: 62.3% (Solid physical intuition for a sub-1B model). The Reality Check: HellaSwag (29.3%) and Winogrande (50.2%) show the limits of 400M...</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mrs83/555686632418762</guid></item></channel></rss>