<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>FusionAudio-1.2M: Towards Fine-grained Audio Captioning with Multimodal
  Contextual Fusion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01111</link><description>A novel two-stage pipeline using specialized pretrained models and a large language model enhances audio caption quality by integrating diverse multimodal cues and contextual information.  					AI-generated summary 				 High-quality, large-scale audio captioning is crucial for advancing audio understanding, yet current automated methods often generate captions that lack fine-grained detail and contextual accuracy, primarily due to their reliance on limited unimodal or superficial multimodal information. Drawing inspiration from human auditory perception, which adeptly integrates cross-modal cues and performs sophisticated auditory scene analysis, we introduce a novel two-stage automated pipeline. This pipeline first employs specialized pretrained models to extract diverse contextual cues (e.g., speech, music, general sounds, and visual information from associated video). A large language model (LLM) then synthesizes these rich, multimodal inputs to generate detailed and context-aware audio captions. Key contributions of this work include: (1) the proposed scalable method for fine-grained audio caption generation; (2) FusionAudio, a new large-scale dataset comprising 1.2 million such detailed captions, combined with 6 million QA pairs; and (3) enhanced audio models developed using FusionAudio, specifically a CLAP-based audio encoder with superior audio-text alignment and instruction following. This paper paves the way for more nuanced and accurate automated understanding of complex audio environments. Code and data can be found in https://github.com/satsuki2486441738/FusionAudio.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 03:29:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01111</guid></item><item><title>Audio-Aware Large Language Models as Judges for Speaking Styles</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.05984</link><description>Audio-aware large language models can assess speaking styles in audio inputs, demonstrating performance comparable to human judges in evaluating synthesized speech along dimensions like emotion, volume, and pitch.  					AI-generated summary 				 Audio-aware large language models (ALLMs) can understand the textual and non-textual information in the audio input. In this paper, we explore using ALLMs as an automatic judge to assess the speaking styles of speeches. We use ALLM judges to evaluate the speeches generated by SLMs on two tasks: voice style instruction following and role-playing. The speaking style we consider includes emotion, volume, speaking pace, word emphasis, pitch control, and non-verbal elements. We use four spoken language models (SLMs) to complete the two tasks and use humans and ALLMs to judge the SLMs' responses. We compare two ALLM judges, GPT-4o-audio and Gemini-2.5-pro, with human evaluation results and show that the agreement between Gemini and human judges is comparable to the agreement between human evaluators. These promising results show that ALLMs can be used as a judge to evaluate SLMs. Our results also reveal that current SLMs, even GPT-4o-audio, still have room for improvement in controlling the speaking style and generating natural dialogues.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 01:58:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.05984</guid></item><item><title>Leveraging Self-Attention for Input-Dependent Soft Prompting in LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.05629</link><description>A new method using input-dependent soft prompting with a self-attention mechanism improves parameter-efficient fine-tuning for large language models, enhancing zero-shot domain transfer.  					AI-generated summary 				 The performance of large language models in domain-specific tasks necessitates fine-tuning, which is computationally expensive and technically challenging. This paper focuses on parameter-efficient fine-tuning using soft prompting, a promising approach that adapts pre-trained models to downstream tasks by learning a small set of parameters. We propose a novel Input Dependent Soft Prompting technique with a self-Attention Mechanism (ID-SPAM) that generates soft prompts based on the input tokens and attends different tokens with varying importance. Our method is simple and efficient, keeping the number of trainable parameters small. We show the merits of the proposed approach compared to state-of-the-art techniques on various tasks and show the improved zero shot domain transfer capability.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 02:57:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.05629</guid></item><item><title>3DFlowAction: Learning Cross-Embodiment Manipulation from 3D Flow World
  Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.06199</link><description>A 3D flow world model learned from human and robot manipulation data, using video diffusion and GPT-4o, enables robots to perform diverse manipulation tasks with strong generalization and cross-embodiment adaptation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Manipulation has long been a challenging task for robots, while humans can effortlessly perform complex interactions with objects, such as hanging a cup on the mug rack. A key reason is the lack of a large and uniform dataset for teaching robots manipulation skills. Current robot datasets often record robot action in different action spaces within a simple scene. This hinders the robot to learn a unified and robust action representation for different robots within diverse scenes. Observing how humans understand a manipulation task, we find that understanding how the objects should move in the 3D space is a critical clue for guiding actions. This clue is embodiment-agnostic and suitable for both humans and different robots. Motivated by this, we aim to learn a 3D flow world model from both human and robot manipulation data. This model predicts the future movement of the interacting objects in 3D space, guiding action planning for manipulation. Specifically, we synthesize a large-scale 3D optical flow dataset, named ManiFlow-110k, through a moving object auto-detect pipeline. A video diffusion-based world model then learns manipulation physics from these data, generating 3D optical flow trajectories conditioned on language instructions. With the generated 3D object optical flow, we propose a flow-guided rendering mechanism, which renders the predicted final state and leverages GPT-4o to assess whether the predicted flow aligns with the task description. This equips the robot with a closed-loop planning ability. Finally, we consider the predicted 3D optical flow as constraints for an optimization policy to determine a chunk of robot actions for manipulation. Extensive experiments demonstrate strong generalization across diverse robotic manipulation tasks and reliable cross-embodiment adaptation without hardware-specific training.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 03:12:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.06199</guid></item><item><title>MORSE-500: A Programmatically Controllable Video Benchmark to
  Stress-Test Multimodal Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.05523</link><description>MORSE-500, a video benchmark with 500 scripted clips, evaluates multimodal reasoning across six categories, highlighting performance gaps in abstract and planning tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Despite rapid advances in vision-language models (VLMs), current benchmarks for multimodal reasoning fall short in three key dimensions. First, they overwhelmingly rely on static images, failing to capture the temporal complexity of real-world environments. Second, they narrowly focus on mathematical problem-solving, neglecting the broader spectrum of reasoning skills -- including abstract, physical, planning, spatial, and temporal capabilities -- required for robust multimodal intelligence. Third, many benchmarks quickly saturate, offering limited headroom for diagnosing failure modes or measuring continued progress. We introduce MORSE-500 (Multimodal Reasoning Stress-test Environment), a video benchmark composed of 500 fully scripted clips with embedded questions spanning six complementary reasoning categories. Each instance is programmatically generated using deterministic Python scripts (via Manim, Matplotlib, MoviePy), generative video models, and curated real footage. This script-driven design allows fine-grained control over visual complexity, distractor density, and temporal dynamics -- enabling difficulty to be scaled systematically as models improve. Unlike static benchmarks that become obsolete once saturated, MORSE-500 is built to evolve: its controllable generation pipeline supports the creation of arbitrarily challenging new instances, making it ideally suited for stress-testing next-generation models. Initial experiments with state-of-the-art systems -- including various Gemini 2.5 Pro and OpenAI o3 which represent the strongest available at the time, alongside strong open-source models -- reveal substantial performance gaps across all categories, with particularly large deficits in abstract and planning tasks. We release the full dataset, generation scripts, and evaluation harness to support transparent, reproducible, and forward-looking multimodal reasoning research.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 04:40:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.05523</guid></item><item><title>HASHIRU: Hierarchical Agent System for Hybrid Intelligent Resource
  Utilization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.04255</link><description>HASHIRU, a novel MAS framework, enhances flexibility, resource efficiency, and adaptability by dynamically managing specialized agents and using a hybrid intelligence approach with smaller, local LLMs and external APIs.  					AI-generated summary 				 Rapid Large Language Model (LLM) advancements are fueling autonomous Multi-Agent System (MAS) development. However, current frameworks often lack flexibility, resource awareness, model diversity, and autonomous tool creation. This paper introduces HASHIRU (Hierarchical Agent System for Hybrid Intelligent Resource Utilization), a novel MAS framework enhancing flexibility, resource efficiency, and adaptability. HASHIRU features a "CEO" agent dynamically managing specialized "employee" agents, instantiated based on task needs and resource constraints (cost, memory). Its hybrid intelligence prioritizes smaller, local LLMs (via Ollama) while flexibly using external APIs and larger models when necessary. An economic model with hiring/firing costs promotes team stability and efficient resource allocation. The system also includes autonomous API tool creation and a memory function. Evaluations on tasks like academic paper review (58% success), safety assessments (100% on a JailbreakBench subset), and complex reasoning (outperforming Gemini 2.0 Flash on GSM8K: 96% vs. 61%; JEEBench: 80% vs. 68.3%; SVAMP: 92% vs. 84%) demonstrate HASHIRU's capabilities. Case studies illustrate its self-improvement via autonomous cost model generation, tool integration, and budget management. HASHIRU offers a promising approach for more robust, efficient, and adaptable MAS through dynamic hierarchical control, resource-aware hybrid intelligence, and autonomous functional extension. Source code and benchmarks are available at https://github.com/HASHIRU-AI/HASHIRU and https://github.com/HASHIRU-AI/HASHIRUBench respectively, and a live demo is available at https://hashiruagentx-hashiruai.hf.space upon request.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 05:19:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.04255</guid></item></channel></rss>