<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>DeCLIP: Decoupled Learning for Open-Vocabulary Dense Perception</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.04410</link><description>Dense visual prediction tasks have been constrained by their reliance on predefined categories, limiting their applicability in real-world scenarios where visual concepts are unbounded. While Vision-Language Models (VLMs) like CLIP have shown promise in open-vocabulary tasks, their direct application to dense prediction often leads to suboptimal performance due to limitations in local feature representation. In this work, we present our observation that CLIP's image tokens struggle to effectively aggregate information from spatially or semantically related regions, resulting in features that lack local discriminability and spatial consistency. To address this issue, we propose DeCLIP, a novel framework that enhances CLIP by decoupling the self-attention module to obtain ``content'' and ``context'' features respectively. The ``content'' features are aligned with image crop representations to improve local discriminability, while ``context'' features learn to retain the spatial correlations under the guidance of vision foundation models, such as DINO. Extensive experiments demonstrate that DeCLIP significantly outperforms existing methods across multiple open-vocabulary dense prediction tasks, including object detection and semantic segmentation. Code is available at magenta{https://github.com/xiaomoguhz/DeCLIP}.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 07:54:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.04410</guid></item><item><title>BLIP3-o: A Family of Fully Open Unified Multimodal Models-Architecture,
  Training and Dataset</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.09568</link><description>Unifying image understanding and generation has gained growing attention in recent research on multimodal models. Although design choices for image understanding have been extensively studied, the optimal model architecture and training recipe for a unified framework with image generation remain underexplored. Motivated by the strong potential of autoregressive and diffusion models for high-quality generation and scalability, we conduct a comprehensive study of their use in unified multimodal settings, with emphasis on image representations, modeling objectives, and training strategies. Grounded in these investigations, we introduce a novel approach that employs a diffusion transformer to generate semantically rich CLIP image features, in contrast to conventional VAE-based representations. This design yields both higher training efficiency and improved generative quality. Furthermore, we demonstrate that a sequential pretraining strategy for unified models-first training on image understanding and subsequently on image generation-offers practical advantages by preserving image understanding capability while developing strong image generation ability. Finally, we carefully curate a high-quality instruction-tuning dataset BLIP3o-60k for image generation by prompting GPT-4o with a diverse set of captions covering various scenes, objects, human gestures, and more. Building on our innovative model design, training recipe, and datasets, we develop BLIP3-o, a suite of state-of-the-art unified multimodal models. BLIP3-o achieves superior performance across most of the popular benchmarks spanning both image understanding and generation tasks. To facilitate future research, we fully open-source our models, including code, model weights, training scripts, and pretraining and instruction tuning datasets.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 01:37:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.09568</guid></item><item><title>Insights into DeepSeek-V3: Scaling Challenges and Reflections on
  Hardware for AI Architectures</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.09343</link><description>The rapid scaling of large language models (LLMs) has unveiled critical limitations in current hardware architectures, including constraints in memory capacity, computational efficiency, and interconnection bandwidth. DeepSeek-V3, trained on 2,048 NVIDIA H800 GPUs, demonstrates how hardware-aware model co-design can effectively address these challenges, enabling cost-efficient training and inference at scale. This paper presents an in-depth analysis of the DeepSeek-V3/R1 model architecture and its AI infrastructure, highlighting key innovations such as Multi-head Latent Attention (MLA) for enhanced memory efficiency, Mixture of Experts (MoE) architectures for optimized computation-communication trade-offs, FP8 mixed-precision training to unlock the full potential of hardware capabilities, and a Multi-Plane Network Topology to minimize cluster-level network overhead. Building on the hardware bottlenecks encountered during DeepSeek-V3's development, we engage in a broader discussion with academic and industry peers on potential future hardware directions, including precise low-precision computation units, scale-up and scale-out convergence, and innovations in low-latency communication fabrics. These insights underscore the critical role of hardware and model co-design in meeting the escalating demands of AI workloads, offering a practical blueprint for innovation in next-generation AI systems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 06:52:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.09343</guid></item><item><title>VCRBench: Exploring Long-form Causal Reasoning Capabilities of Large
  Video Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.08455</link><description>Despite recent advances in video understanding, the capabilities of Large Video Language Models (LVLMs) to perform video-based causal reasoning remains underexplored, largely due to the absence of relevant and dedicated benchmarks for evaluating causal reasoning in visually grounded and goal-driven settings. To fill this gap, we introduce a novel benchmark named Video-based long-form Causal Reasoning (VCRBench). We create VCRBench using procedural videos of simple everyday activities, where the steps are deliberately shuffled with each clip capturing a key causal event, to test whether LVLMs can identify, reason about, and correctly sequence the events needed to accomplish a specific goal. Moreover, the benchmark is carefully designed to prevent LVLMs from exploiting linguistic shortcuts, as seen in multiple-choice or binary QA formats, while also avoiding the challenges associated with evaluating open-ended QA. Our evaluation of state-of-the-art LVLMs on VCRBench suggests that these models struggle with video-based long-form causal reasoning, primarily due to their difficulty in modeling long-range causal dependencies directly from visual observations. As a simple step toward enabling such capabilities, we propose Recognition-Reasoning Decomposition (RRD), a modular approach that breaks video-based causal reasoning into two sub-tasks of video recognition and causal reasoning. Our experiments on VCRBench show that RRD significantly boosts accuracy on VCRBench, with gains of up to 25.2%. Finally, our thorough analysis reveals interesting insights, for instance, that LVLMs primarily rely on language knowledge for complex video-based long-form causal reasoning tasks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 06:28:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.08455</guid></item></channel></rss>