<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>From Scores to Skills: A Cognitive Diagnosis Framework for Evaluating
  Financial Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.13491</link><description>FinCDM, a cognitive diagnosis framework, evaluates financial LLMs at the knowledge-skill level using a comprehensive dataset, revealing hidden knowledge gaps and supporting more trustworthy model development.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown promise for financial applications, yet their suitability for this high-stakes domain remains largely unproven due to inadequacies in existing benchmarks. Existing benchmarks solely rely on score-level evaluation, summarizing performance with a single score that obscures the nuanced understanding of what models truly know and their precise limitations. They also rely on datasets that cover only a narrow subset of financial concepts, while overlooking other essentials for real-world applications. To address these gaps, we introduce FinCDM, the first cognitive diagnosis evaluation framework tailored for financial LLMs, enabling the evaluation of LLMs at the knowledge-skill level, identifying what financial skills and knowledge they have or lack based on their response patterns across skill-tagged tasks, rather than a single aggregated number. We construct CPA-QKA, the first cognitively informed financial evaluation dataset derived from the Certified Public Accountant (CPA) examination, with comprehensive coverage of real-world accounting and financial skills. It is rigorously annotated by domain experts, who author, validate, and annotate questions with high inter-annotator agreement and fine-grained knowledge labels. Our extensive experiments on 30 proprietary, open-source, and domain-specific LLMs show that FinCDM reveals hidden knowledge gaps, identifies under-tested areas such as tax and regulatory reasoning overlooked by traditional benchmarks, and uncovers behavioral clusters among models. FinCDM introduces a new paradigm for financial LLM evaluation by enabling interpretable, skill-aware diagnosis that supports more trustworthy and targeted model development, and all datasets and evaluation scripts will be publicly released to support further research.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:34:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.13491</guid></item><item><title>FutureX: An Advanced Live Benchmark for LLM Agents in Future Prediction</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.11987</link><description>FutureX is a dynamic, live benchmark for evaluating LLM agents in future prediction tasks, addressing challenges in real-time updates and data contamination.  					AI-generated summary 				 Future prediction is a complex task for LLM agents, requiring a high level of analytical thinking, information gathering, contextual understanding, and decision-making under uncertainty. Agents must not only gather and interpret vast amounts of dynamic information but also integrate diverse data sources, weigh uncertainties, and adapt predictions based on emerging trends, just as human experts do in fields like politics, economics, and finance. Despite its importance, no large-scale benchmark exists for evaluating agents on future prediction, largely due to challenges in handling real-time updates and retrieving timely, accurate answers. To address this, we introduce FutureX, a dynamic and live evaluation benchmark specifically designed for LLM agents performing future prediction tasks. FutureX is the largest and most diverse live benchmark for future prediction, supporting real-time daily updates and eliminating data contamination through an automated pipeline for question gathering and answer collection. We evaluate 25 LLM/agent models, including those with reasoning, search capabilities, and integration of external tools such as the open-source Deep Research Agent and closed-source Deep Research models. This comprehensive evaluation assesses agents' adaptive reasoning and performance in dynamic environments. Additionally, we provide in-depth analyses of agents' failure modes and performance pitfalls in future-oriented tasks, including the vulnerability to fake web pages and the temporal validity. Our goal is to establish a dynamic, contamination-free evaluation standard that drives the development of LLM agents capable of performing at the level of professional human analysts in complex reasoning and predictive thinking.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:09:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.11987</guid></item><item><title>Tinker: Diffusion's Gift to 3D--Multi-View Consistent Editing From
  Sparse Inputs without Per-Scene Optimization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14811</link><description>Tinker is a framework for high-fidelity 3D editing using pretrained diffusion models, enabling multi-view consistency with minimal per-scene training.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Tinker, a versatile framework for high-fidelity 3D editing that operates in both one-shot and few-shot regimes without any per-scene finetuning. Unlike prior techniques that demand extensive per-scene optimization to ensure multi-view consistency or to produce dozens of consistent edited input views, Tinker delivers robust, multi-view consistent edits from as few as one or two images. This capability stems from repurposing pretrained diffusion models, which unlocks their latent 3D awareness. To drive research in this space, we curate the first large-scale multi-view editing dataset and data pipeline, spanning diverse scenes and styles. Building on this dataset, we develop our framework capable of generating multi-view consistent edited views without per-scene training, which consists of two novel components: (1) Referring multi-view editor: Enables precise, reference-driven edits that remain coherent across all viewpoints. (2) Any-view-to-video synthesizer: Leverages spatial-temporal priors from video diffusion to perform high-quality scene completion and novel-view generation even from sparse inputs. Through extensive experiments, Tinker significantly reduces the barrier to generalizable 3D content creation, achieving state-of-the-art performance on editing, novel-view synthesis, and rendering enhancement tasks. We believe that Tinker represents a key step towards truly scalable, zero-shot 3D editing. Project webpage: https://aim-uofa.github.io/Tinker</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:20:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14811</guid></item><item><title>MeshCoder: LLM-Powered Structured Mesh Code Generation from Point Clouds</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14879</link><description>MeshCoder reconstructs complex 3D objects from point clouds into editable Blender Python scripts, enhancing shape-to-code reconstruction and 3D shape understanding through a multimodal large language model.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reconstructing 3D objects into editable programs is pivotal for applications like reverse engineering and shape editing. However, existing methods often rely on limited domain-specific languages (DSLs) and small-scale datasets, restricting their ability to model complex geometries and structures. To address these challenges, we introduce MeshCoder, a novel framework that reconstructs complex 3D objects from point clouds into editable Blender Python scripts. We develop a comprehensive set of expressive Blender Python APIs capable of synthesizing intricate geometries. Leveraging these APIs, we construct a large-scale paired object-code dataset, where the code for each object is decomposed into distinct semantic parts. Subsequently, we train a multimodal large language model (LLM) that translates 3D point cloud into executable Blender Python scripts. Our approach not only achieves superior performance in shape-to-code reconstruction tasks but also facilitates intuitive geometric and topological editing through convenient code modifications. Furthermore, our code-based representation enhances the reasoning capabilities of LLMs in 3D shape understanding tasks. Together, these contributions establish MeshCoder as a powerful and flexible solution for programmatic 3D shape reconstruction and understanding.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:20:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14879</guid></item><item><title>RynnEC: Bringing MLLMs into Embodied World</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14160</link><description>RynnEC, a video multimodal large language model with a region-centric approach, achieves state-of-the-art performance in object property understanding, segmentation, and spatial reasoning, using an egocentric video pipeline and a region-centered benchmark.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce RynnEC, a video multimodal large language model designed for embodied cognition. Built upon a general-purpose vision-language foundation model, RynnEC incorporates a region encoder and a mask decoder, enabling flexible region-level video interaction. Despite its compact architecture, RynnEC achieves state-of-the-art performance in object property understanding, object segmentation, and spatial reasoning. Conceptually, it offers a region-centric video paradigm for the brain of embodied agents, providing fine-grained perception of the physical world and enabling more precise interactions. To mitigate the scarcity of annotated 3D datasets, we propose an egocentric video based pipeline for generating embodied cognition data. Furthermore, we introduce RynnEC-Bench, a region-centered benchmark for evaluating embodied cognitive capabilities. We anticipate that RynnEC will advance the development of general-purpose cognitive cores for embodied agents and facilitate generalization across diverse embodied tasks. The code, model checkpoints, and benchmark are available at: https://github.com/alibaba-damo-academy/RynnEC</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:27:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14160</guid></item><item><title>Quantization Meets dLLMs: A Systematic Study of Post-training
  Quantization for Diffusion LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14896</link><description>A systematic study on quantizing diffusion large language models identifies challenges and evaluates state-of-the-art methods across various configurations to improve deployment on edge devices.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in diffusion large language models (dLLMs) have introduced a promising alternative to autoregressive (AR) LLMs for natural language generation tasks, leveraging full attention and denoising-based decoding strategies. However, the deployment of these models on edge devices remains challenging due to their massive parameter scale and high resource demands. While post-training quantization (PTQ) has emerged as a widely adopted technique for compressing AR LLMs, its applicability to dLLMs remains largely unexplored. In this work, we present the first systematic study on quantizing diffusion-based language models. We begin by identifying the presence of activation outliers, characterized by abnormally large activation values that dominate the dynamic range. These outliers pose a key challenge to low-bit quantization, as they make it difficult to preserve precision for the majority of values. More importantly, we implement state-of-the-art PTQ methods and conduct a comprehensive evaluation across multiple task types and model variants. Our analysis is structured along four key dimensions: bit-width, quantization method, task category, and model type. Through this multi-perspective evaluation, we offer practical insights into the quantization behavior of dLLMs under different configurations. We hope our findings provide a foundation for future research in efficient dLLM deployment. All codes and experimental setups will be released to support the community.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 04:14:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14896</guid></item><item><title>NVIDIA Nemotron Nano 2: An Accurate and Efficient Hybrid
  Mamba-Transformer Reasoning Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14444</link><description>Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2, a hybrid Mamba-Transformer model, enhances reasoning workload throughput and accuracy by replacing self-attention layers with Mamba-2 layers and using the Minitron strategy for compression.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2, a hybrid Mamba-Transformer language model designed to increase throughput for reasoning workloads while achieving state-of-the-art accuracy compared to similarly-sized models. Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2 builds on the Nemotron-H architecture, in which the majority of the self-attention layers in the common Transformer architecture are replaced with Mamba-2 layers, to achieve improved inference speed when generating the long thinking traces needed for reasoning. We create Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2 by first pre-training a 12-billion-parameter model (Nemotron-Nano-12B-v2-Base) on 20 trillion tokens using an FP8 training recipe. After aligning Nemotron-Nano-12B-v2-Base, we employ the Minitron strategy to compress and distill the model with the goal of enabling inference on up to 128k tokens on a single NVIDIA A10G GPU (22GiB of memory, bfloat16 precision). Compared to existing similarly-sized models (e.g., Qwen3-8B), we show that Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2 achieves on-par or better accuracy on reasoning benchmarks while achieving up to 6x higher inference throughput in reasoning settings like 8k input and 16k output tokens. We are releasing Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2, Nemotron-Nano12B-v2-Base, and Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2-Base checkpoints along with the majority of our pre- and post-training datasets on Hugging Face.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 04:11:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14444</guid></item><item><title>DuPO: Enabling Reliable LLM Self-Verification via Dual Preference
  Optimization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14460</link><description>DuPO is a dual learning framework that generates annotation-free feedback using a generalized duality, enhancing performance across various tasks without relying on costly labels.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present DuPO, a dual learning-based preference optimization framework that generates annotation-free feedback via a generalized duality. DuPO addresses two key limitations: Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR)'s reliance on costly labels and applicability restricted to verifiable tasks, and traditional dual learning's restriction to strictly dual task pairs (e.g., translation and back-translation). Specifically, DuPO decomposes a primal task's input into known and unknown components, then constructs its dual task to reconstruct the unknown part using the primal output and known information (e.g., reversing math solutions to recover hidden variables), broadening applicability to non-invertible tasks. The quality of this reconstruction serves as a self-supervised reward to optimize the primal task, synergizing with LLMs' ability to instantiate both tasks via a single model. Empirically, DuPO achieves substantial gains across diverse tasks: it enhances the average translation quality by 2.13 COMET over 756 directions, boosts the mathematical reasoning accuracy by an average of 6.4 points on three challenge benchmarks, and enhances performance by 9.3 points as an inference-time reranker (trading computation for accuracy). These results position DuPO as a scalable, general, and annotation-free paradigm for LLM optimization.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 04:11:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14460</guid></item><item><title>Local Scale Equivariance with Latent Deep Equilibrium Canonicalizer</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14187</link><description>A deep equilibrium canonicalizer (DEC) enhances local scale equivariance in deep networks, improving performance and consistency on ImageNet.  					AI-generated summary 				 Scale variation is a fundamental challenge in computer vision. Objects of the same class can have different sizes, and their perceived size is further affected by the distance from the camera. These variations are local to the objects, i.e., different object sizes may change differently within the same image. To effectively handle scale variations, we present a deep equilibrium canonicalizer (DEC) to improve the local scale equivariance of a model. DEC can be easily incorporated into existing network architectures and can be adapted to a pre-trained model. Notably, we show that on the competitive ImageNet benchmark, DEC improves both model performance and local scale consistency across four popular pre-trained deep-nets, e.g., ViT, DeiT, Swin, and BEiT. Our code is available at https://github.com/ashiq24/local-scale-equivariance.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 04:17:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.14187</guid></item></channel></rss>