<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>MMGR: Multi-Modal Generative Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14691</link><description>MMGR evaluates video and image models across reasoning abilities in multiple domains, revealing performance gaps and highlighting limitations in perceptual data and causal correctness.  					AI-generated summary 				 Video foundation models generate visually realistic and temporally coherent content, but their reliability as world simulators depends on whether they capture physical, logical, and spatial constraints. Existing metrics such as Frechet Video Distance (FVD) emphasize perceptual quality and overlook reasoning failures, including violations of causality, physics, and global consistency. We introduce MMGR (Multi-Modal Generative Reasoning Evaluation and Benchmark), a principled evaluation framework based on five reasoning abilities: Physical, Logical, 3D Spatial, 2D Spatial, and Temporal. MMGR evaluates generative reasoning across three domains: Abstract Reasoning (ARC-AGI, Sudoku), Embodied Navigation (real-world 3D navigation and localization), and Physical Commonsense (sports and compositional interactions). MMGR applies fine-grained metrics that require holistic correctness across both video and image generation. We benchmark leading video models (Veo-3, Sora-2, Wan-2.2) and image models (Nano-banana, Nano-banana Pro, GPT-4o-image, Qwen-image), revealing strong performance gaps across domains. Models show moderate success on Physical Commonsense tasks but perform poorly on Abstract Reasoning (below 10 percent accuracy on ARC-AGI) and struggle with long-horizon spatial planning in embodied settings. Our analysis highlights key limitations in current models, including overreliance on perceptual data, weak global state consistency, and objectives that reward visual plausibility over causal correctness. MMGR offers a unified diagnostic benchmark and a path toward reasoning-aware generative world models.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:08:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14691</guid></item><item><title>RoboTracer: Mastering Spatial Trace with Reasoning in Vision-Language Models for Robotics</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13660</link><description>RoboTracer, a 3D-aware visual language model, enhances spatial tracing by combining supervised and reinforcement fine-tuning with a universal spatial encoder and regression-supervised decoder, achieving state-of-the-art performance on TraceSpatial-Bench.  					AI-generated summary 				 Spatial tracing, as a fundamental embodied interaction ability for robots, is inherently challenging as it requires multi-step metric-grounded reasoning compounded with complex spatial referring and real-world metric measurement. However, existing methods struggle with this compositional task. To this end, we propose RoboTracer, a 3D-aware VLM that first achieves both 3D spatial referring and measuring via a universal spatial encoder and a regression-supervised decoder to enhance scale awareness during supervised fine-tuning (SFT). Moreover, RoboTracer advances multi-step metric-grounded reasoning via reinforcement fine-tuning (RFT) with metric-sensitive process rewards, supervising key intermediate perceptual cues to accurately generate spatial traces. To support SFT and RFT training, we introduce TraceSpatial, a large-scale dataset of 30M QA pairs, spanning outdoor/indoor/tabletop scenes and supporting complex reasoning processes (up to 9 steps). We further present TraceSpatial-Bench, a challenging benchmark filling the gap to evaluate spatial tracing. Experimental results show that RoboTracer surpasses baselines in spatial understanding, measuring, and referring, with an average success rate of 79.1%, and also achieves SOTA performance on TraceSpatial-Bench by a large margin, exceeding Gemini-2.5-Pro by 36% accuracy. Notably, RoboTracer can be integrated with various control policies to execute long-horizon, dynamic tasks across diverse robots (UR5, G1 humanoid) in cluttered real-world scenes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:32:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13660</guid></item><item><title>Scone: Bridging Composition and Distinction in Subject-Driven Image Generation via Unified Understanding-Generation Modeling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12675</link><description>Scone integrates composition and distinction in image generation by using a two-stage training scheme with semantic alignment and attention-based masking, outperforming existing models on benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Subject-driven image generation has advanced from single- to multi-subject composition, while neglecting distinction, the ability to identify and generate the correct subject when inputs contain multiple candidates. This limitation restricts effectiveness in complex, realistic visual settings. We propose Scone, a unified understanding-generation method that integrates composition and distinction. Scone enables the understanding expert to act as a semantic bridge, conveying semantic information and guiding the generation expert to preserve subject identity while minimizing interference. A two-stage training scheme first learns composition, then enhances distinction through semantic alignment and attention-based masking. We also introduce SconeEval, a benchmark for evaluating both composition and distinction across diverse scenarios. Experiments demonstrate that Scone outperforms existing open-source models in composition and distinction tasks on two benchmarks. Our model, benchmark, and training data are available at: https://github.com/Ryann-Ran/Scone.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:48:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12675</guid></item><item><title>WorldPlay: Towards Long-Term Geometric Consistency for Real-Time Interactive World Modeling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14614</link><description>WorldPlay is a streaming video diffusion model that achieves real-time, interactive world modeling with long-term geometric consistency by using a Dual Action Representation, Reconstituted Context Memory, and Context Forcing.  					AI-generated summary 				 This paper presents WorldPlay, a streaming video diffusion model that enables real-time, interactive world modeling with long-term geometric consistency, resolving the trade-off between speed and memory that limits current methods. WorldPlay draws power from three key innovations. 1) We use a Dual Action Representation to enable robust action control in response to the user's keyboard and mouse inputs. 2) To enforce long-term consistency, our Reconstituted Context Memory dynamically rebuilds context from past frames and uses temporal reframing to keep geometrically important but long-past frames accessible, effectively alleviating memory attenuation. 3) We also propose Context Forcing, a novel distillation method designed for memory-aware model. Aligning memory context between the teacher and student preserves the student's capacity to use long-range information, enabling real-time speeds while preventing error drift. Taken together, WorldPlay generates long-horizon streaming 720p video at 24 FPS with superior consistency, comparing favorably with existing techniques and showing strong generalization across diverse scenes. Project page and online demo can be found: https://3d-models.hunyuan.tencent.com/world/ and https://3d.hunyuan.tencent.com/sceneTo3D.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:54:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14614</guid></item><item><title>MemFlow: Flowing Adaptive Memory for Consistent and Efficient Long Video Narratives</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14699</link><description>MemFlow dynamically updates a memory bank by retrieving relevant historical frames for each video chunk, ensuring narrative coherence and generation efficiency with minimal computational overhead.  					AI-generated summary 				 The core challenge for streaming video generation is maintaining the content consistency in long context, which poses high requirement for the memory design. Most existing solutions maintain the memory by compressing historical frames with predefined strategies. However, different to-generate video chunks should refer to different historical cues, which is hard to satisfy with fixed strategies. In this work, we propose MemFlow to address this problem. Specifically, before generating the coming chunk, we dynamically update the memory bank by retrieving the most relevant historical frames with the text prompt of this chunk. This design enables narrative coherence even if new event happens or scenario switches in future frames. In addition, during generation, we only activate the most relevant tokens in the memory bank for each query in the attention layers, which effectively guarantees the generation efficiency. In this way, MemFlow achieves outstanding long-context consistency with negligible computation burden (7.9% speed reduction compared with the memory-free baseline) and keeps the compatibility with any streaming video generation model with KV cache.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:11:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14699</guid></item><item><title>RecGPT-V2 Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14503</link><description>RecGPT-V2 enhances recommender systems by integrating a Hierarchical Multi-Agent System, Hybrid Representation Inference, Meta-Prompting, constrained reinforcement learning, and an Agent-as-a-Judge framework to improve efficiency, explanation diversity, generalization, and human preference alignment.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable potential in transforming recommender systems from implicit behavioral pattern matching to explicit intent reasoning. While RecGPT-V1 successfully pioneered this paradigm by integrating LLM-based reasoning into user interest mining and item tag prediction, it suffers from four fundamental limitations: (1) computational inefficiency and cognitive redundancy across multiple reasoning routes; (2) insufficient explanation diversity in fixed-template generation; (3) limited generalization under supervised learning paradigms; and (4) simplistic outcome-focused evaluation that fails to match human standards.   To address these challenges, we present RecGPT-V2 with four key innovations. First, a Hierarchical Multi-Agent System restructures intent reasoning through coordinated collaboration, eliminating cognitive duplication while enabling diverse intent coverage. Combined with Hybrid Representation Inference that compresses user-behavior contexts, our framework reduces GPU consumption by 60% and improves exclusive recall from 9.39% to 10.99%. Second, a Meta-Prompting framework dynamically generates contextually adaptive prompts, improving explanation diversity by +7.3%. Third, constrained reinforcement learning mitigates multi-reward conflicts, achieving +24.1% improvement in tag prediction and +13.0% in explanation acceptance. Fourth, an Agent-as-a-Judge framework decomposes assessment into multi-step reasoning, improving human preference alignment. Online A/B tests on Taobao demonstrate significant improvements: +2.98% CTR, +3.71% IPV, +2.19% TV, and +11.46% NER. RecGPT-V2 establishes both the technical feasibility and commercial viability of deploying LLM-powered intent reasoning at scale, bridging the gap between cognitive exploration and industrial utility.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:18:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14503</guid></item><item><title>ShowTable: Unlocking Creative Table Visualization with Collaborative Reflection and Refinement</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13303</link><description>ShowTable, a pipeline combining MLLMs and diffusion models, excels in creative table visualization by generating high-fidelity infographics from data tables, outperforming existing methods in multi-modal reasoning and error correction.  					AI-generated summary 				 While existing generation and unified models excel at general image generation, they struggle with tasks requiring deep reasoning, planning, and precise data-to-visual mapping abilities beyond general scenarios. To push beyond the existing limitations, we introduce a new and challenging task: creative table visualization, requiring the model to generate an infographic that faithfully and aesthetically visualizes the data from a given table. To address this challenge, we propose ShowTable, a pipeline that synergizes MLLMs with diffusion models via a progressive self-correcting process. The MLLM acts as the central orchestrator for reasoning the visual plan and judging visual errors to provide refined instructions, the diffusion execute the commands from MLLM, achieving high-fidelity results. To support this task and our pipeline, we introduce three automated data construction pipelines for training different modules. Furthermore, we introduce TableVisBench, a new benchmark with 800 challenging instances across 5 evaluation dimensions, to assess performance on this task. Experiments demonstrate that our pipeline, instantiated with different models, significantly outperforms baselines, highlighting its effective multi-modal reasoning, generation, and error correction capabilities.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 04:18:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13303</guid></item><item><title>VersatileFFN: Achieving Parameter Efficiency in LLMs via Adaptive Wide-and-Deep Reuse</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14531</link><description>The rapid scaling of Large Language Models (LLMs) has achieved remarkable performance, but it also leads to prohibitive memory costs. Existing parameter-efficient approaches such as pruning and quantization mainly compress pretrained models without enhancing architectural capacity, thereby hitting the representational ceiling of the base model. In this work, we propose VersatileFFN, a novel feed-forward network (FFN) that enables flexible reuse of parameters in both width and depth dimensions within a fixed parameter budget. Inspired by the dual-process theory of cognition, VersatileFFN comprises two adaptive pathways: a width-versatile path that generates a mixture of sub-experts from a single shared FFN, mimicking sparse expert routing without increasing parameters, and a depth-versatile path that recursively applies the same FFN to emulate deeper processing for complex tokens. A difficulty-aware gating dynamically balances the two pathways, steering "easy" tokens through the efficient width-wise route and allocating deeper iterative refinement to "hard" tokens. Crucially, both pathways reuse the same parameters, so all additional capacity comes from computation rather than memory. Experiments across diverse benchmarks and model scales demonstrate the effectiveness of the method. The code will be available at https://github.com/huawei-noah/noah-research/tree/master/VersatileFFN.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:54:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14531</guid></item><item><title>A4-Agent: An Agentic Framework for Zero-Shot Affordance Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14442</link><description>A4-Agent, a training-free framework, decouples affordance prediction into three stages using specialized pre-trained models to enhance generalization and performance in real-world settings.  					AI-generated summary 				 Affordance prediction, which identifies interaction regions on objects based on language instructions, is critical for embodied AI. Prevailing end-to-end models couple high-level reasoning and low-level grounding into a single monolithic pipeline and rely on training over annotated datasets, which leads to poor generalization on novel objects and unseen environments. In this paper, we move beyond this paradigm by proposing A4-Agent, a training-free agentic framework that decouples affordance prediction into a three-stage pipeline. Our framework coordinates specialized foundation models at test time: (1) a Dreamer that employs generative models to visualize how an interaction would look; (2) a Thinker that utilizes large vision-language models to decide what object part to interact with; and (3) a Spotter that orchestrates vision foundation models to precisely locate where the interaction area is. By leveraging the complementary strengths of pre-trained models without any task-specific fine-tuning, our zero-shot framework significantly outperforms state-of-the-art supervised methods across multiple benchmarks and demonstrates robust generalization to real-world settings.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:29:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14442</guid></item><item><title>SS4D: Native 4D Generative Model via Structured Spacetime Latents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14284</link><description>SS4D synthesizes dynamic 3D objects from monocular video using a native 4D generative model with structured spacetime latents, ensuring high fidelity, temporal coherence, and structural consistency.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present SS4D, a native 4D generative model that synthesizes dynamic 3D objects directly from monocular video. Unlike prior approaches that construct 4D representations by optimizing over 3D or video generative models, we train a generator directly on 4D data, achieving high fidelity, temporal coherence, and structural consistency. At the core of our method is a compressed set of structured spacetime latents. Specifically, (1) To address the scarcity of 4D training data, we build on a pre-trained single-image-to-3D model, preserving strong spatial consistency. (2) Temporal consistency is enforced by introducing dedicated temporal layers that reason across frames. (3) To support efficient training and inference over long video sequences, we compress the latent sequence along the temporal axis using factorized 4D convolutions and temporal downsampling blocks. In addition, we employ a carefully designed training strategy to enhance robustness against occlusion</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 04:52:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14284</guid></item><item><title>Feedforward 3D Editing via Text-Steerable Image-to-3D</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13678</link><description>Steer3D enables text-based editing of AI-generated 3D assets by adapting ControlNet for image-to-3D generation with flow-matching training and Direct Preference Optimization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent progress in image-to-3D has opened up immense possibilities for design, AR/VR, and robotics. However, to use AI-generated 3D assets in real applications, a critical requirement is the capability to edit them easily. We present a feedforward method, Steer3D, to add text steerability to image-to-3D models, which enables editing of generated 3D assets with language. Our approach is inspired by ControlNet, which we adapt to image-to-3D generation to enable text steering directly in a forward pass. We build a scalable data engine for automatic data generation, and develop a two-stage training recipe based on flow-matching training and Direct Preference Optimization (DPO). Compared to competing methods, Steer3D more faithfully follows the language instruction and maintains better consistency with the original 3D asset, while being 2.4x to 28.5x faster. Steer3D demonstrates that it is possible to add a new modality (text) to steer the generation of pretrained image-to-3D generative models with 100k data. Project website: https://glab-caltech.github.io/steer3d/</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:52:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13678</guid></item><item><title>Olmo 3</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13961</link><description>Olmo 3, a family of state-of-the-art fully-open language models at 7B and 32B parameter scales, excels in long-context reasoning, function calling, coding, instruction following, general chat, and knowledge recall.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Olmo 3, a family of state-of-the-art, fully-open language models at the 7B and 32B parameter scales. Olmo 3 model construction targets long-context reasoning, function calling, coding, instruction following, general chat, and knowledge recall. This release includes the entire model flow, i.e., the full lifecycle of the family of models, including every stage, checkpoint, data point, and dependency used to build it. Our flagship model, Olmo 3 Think 32B, is the strongest fully-open thinking model released to-date.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:46:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13961</guid></item><item><title>EVOLVE-VLA: Test-Time Training from Environment Feedback for Vision-Language-Action Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14666</link><description>EVOLVE-VLA, a test-time training framework for Vision-Language-Action models, enables continuous adaptation through environmental interaction with minimal task-specific demonstrations, achieving significant improvements in performance and generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Achieving truly adaptive embodied intelligence requires agents that learn not just by imitating static demonstrations, but by continuously improving through environmental interaction, which is akin to how humans master skills through practice. Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models have advanced robotic manipulation by leveraging large language models, yet remain fundamentally limited by Supervised Finetuning (SFT): requiring hundreds of demonstrations per task, rigidly memorizing trajectories, and failing to adapt when deployment conditions deviate from training. We introduce EVOLVE-VLA, a test-time training framework enabling VLAs to continuously adapt through environment interaction with minimal or zero task-specific demonstrations. The key technical challenge is replacing oracle reward signals (unavailable at test time) with autonomous feedback. We address this through a learned progress estimator providing dense feedback, and critically, we design our framework to ``tame'' this inherently noisy signal via two mechanisms: (1) an accumulative progress estimation mechanism smoothing noisy point-wise estimates, and (2) a progressive horizon extension strategy enabling gradual policy evolution. EVOLVE-VLA achieves substantial gains: +8.6\% on long-horizon tasks, +22.0\% in 1-shot learning, and enables cross-task generalization -- achieving 20.8\% success on unseen tasks without task-specific demonstrations training (vs. 0\% for pure SFT). Qualitative analysis reveals emergent capabilities absent in demonstrations, including error recovery and novel strategies. This work represents a critical step toward VLAs that truly learn and adapt, moving beyond static imitation toward continuous self-improvements.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:09:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14666</guid></item><item><title>Efficient-DLM: From Autoregressive to Diffusion Language Models, and Beyond in Speed</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14067</link><description>AR-to-dLM conversion enhances diffusion language models' efficiency and speed while maintaining task accuracy through refined attention patterns and token masking strategies.  					AI-generated summary 				 Diffusion language models (dLMs) have emerged as a promising paradigm that enables parallel, non-autoregressive generation, but their learning efficiency lags behind that of autoregressive (AR) language models when trained from scratch. To this end, we study AR-to-dLM conversion to transform pretrained AR models into efficient dLMs that excel in speed while preserving AR models' task accuracy. We achieve this by identifying limitations in the attention patterns and objectives of existing AR-to-dLM methods and then proposing principles and methodologies for more effective AR-to-dLM conversion. Specifically, we first systematically compare different attention patterns and find that maintaining pretrained AR weight distributions is critical for effective AR-to-dLM conversion. As such, we introduce a continuous pretraining scheme with a block-wise attention pattern, which remains causal across blocks while enabling bidirectional modeling within each block. We find that this approach can better preserve pretrained AR models' weight distributions than fully bidirectional modeling, in addition to its known benefit of enabling KV caching, and leads to a win-win in accuracy and efficiency. Second, to mitigate the training-test gap in mask token distributions (uniform vs. highly left-to-right), we propose a position-dependent token masking strategy that assigns higher masking probabilities to later tokens during training to better mimic test-time behavior. Leveraging this framework, we conduct extensive studies of dLMs' attention patterns, training dynamics, and other design choices, providing actionable insights into scalable AR-to-dLM conversion. These studies lead to the Efficient-DLM family, which outperforms state-of-the-art AR models and dLMs, e.g., our Efficient-DLM 8B achieves +5.4%/+2.7% higher accuracy with 4.5x/2.7x higher throughput compared to Dream 7B and Qwen3 4B, respectively.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:17:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14067</guid></item><item><title>Sparse-LaViDa: Sparse Multimodal Discrete Diffusion Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14008</link><description>Sparse-LaViDa accelerates Masked Discrete Diffusion Models by dynamically truncating masked tokens during inference, maintaining quality and achieving up to a 2x speedup across various tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Masked Discrete Diffusion Models (MDMs) have achieved strong performance across a wide range of multimodal tasks, including image understanding, generation, and editing. However, their inference speed remains suboptimal due to the need to repeatedly process redundant masked tokens at every sampling step. In this work, we propose Sparse-LaViDa, a novel modeling framework that dynamically truncates unnecessary masked tokens at each inference step to accelerate MDM sampling. To preserve generation quality, we introduce specialized register tokens that serve as compact representations for the truncated tokens. Furthermore, to ensure consistency between training and inference, we design a specialized attention mask that faithfully matches the truncated sampling procedure during training. Built upon the state-of-the-art unified MDM LaViDa-O, Sparse-LaViDa achieves up to a 2x speedup across diverse tasks including text-to-image generation, image editing, and mathematical reasoning, while maintaining generation quality.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:01:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14008</guid></item><item><title>Comparative Analysis of LLM Abliteration Methods: A Cross-Architecture Evaluation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13655</link><description>Four abliteration tools are evaluated for their effectiveness in removing refusal representations from large language models, with findings showing variability in capability preservation and distribution shift across different models and tools.  					AI-generated summary 				 Safety alignment mechanisms in large language models prevent responses to harmful queries through learned refusal behavior, yet these same mechanisms impede legitimate research applications including cognitive modeling, adversarial testing, and security analysis. While abliteration techniques enable surgical removal of refusal representations through directional orthogonalization, the relative effectiveness of available implementations remains uncharacterized. This study evaluates four abliteration tools (Heretic, DECCP, ErisForge, FailSpy) across sixteen instruction-tuned models (7B-14B parameters), reporting tool compatibility on all 16 models and quantitative metrics on subsets dictated by tool support. Single-pass methods demonstrated superior capability preservation on the benchmarked subset (avg GSM8K change across three models: ErisForge -0.28 pp; DECCP -0.13 pp), while Bayesian-optimized abliteration produced variable distribution shift (KL divergence: 0.043-1.646) with model-dependent capability impact. These findings provide researchers with evidence-based selection criteria for abliteration tool deployment across diverse model architectures. The principal finding indicates that mathematical reasoning capabilities exhibit the highest sensitivity to abliteration interventions, with GSM8K change ranging from +1.51 pp to -18.81 pp (-26.5% relative) depending on tool selection and model architecture.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:11:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13655</guid></item><item><title>RePo: Language Models with Context Re-Positioning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14391</link><description>RePo, a novel context re-positioning mechanism in LLMs, reduces extraneous cognitive load by differentiably assigning token positions, enhancing performance on noisy and long contexts without compromising short-context tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 In-context learning is fundamental to modern Large Language Models (LLMs); however, prevailing architectures impose a rigid and fixed contextual structure by assigning linear or constant positional indices. Drawing on Cognitive Load Theory (CLT), we argue that this uninformative structure increases extraneous cognitive load, consuming finite working memory capacity that should be allocated to deep reasoning and attention allocation. To address this, we propose RePo, a novel mechanism that reduces extraneous load via context re-positioning. Unlike standard approaches, RePo utilizes a differentiable module, f_φ, to assign token positions that capture contextual dependencies, rather than replying on pre-defined integer range. By continually pre-training on the OLMo-2 1B backbone, we demonstrate that RePo significantly enhances performance on tasks involving noisy contexts, structured data, and longer context length, while maintaining competitive performance on general short-context tasks. Detailed analysis reveals that RePo successfully allocate higher attention to distant but relevant information, assign positions in dense and non-linear space, and capture the intrinsic structure of the input context. Our code is available at https://github.com/SakanaAI/repo.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:02:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14391</guid></item><item><title>MobileWorldBench: Towards Semantic World Modeling For Mobile Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14014</link><description>A novel vision-language model framework improves task success rates for mobile GUI agents by using semantic world models instead of pixel-based predictions.  					AI-generated summary 				 World models have shown great utility in improving the task performance of embodied agents. While prior work largely focuses on pixel-space world models, these approaches face practical limitations in GUI settings, where predicting complex visual elements in future states is often difficult. In this work, we explore an alternative formulation of world modeling for GUI agents, where state transitions are described in natural language rather than predicting raw pixels. First, we introduce MobileWorldBench, a benchmark that evaluates the ability of vision-language models (VLMs) to function as world models for mobile GUI agents. Second, we release MobileWorld, a large-scale dataset consisting of 1.4M samples, that significantly improves the world modeling capabilities of VLMs. Finally, we propose a novel framework that integrates VLM world models into the planning framework of mobile agents, demonstrating that semantic world models can directly benefit mobile agents by improving task success rates. The code and dataset is available at https://github.com/jacklishufan/MobileWorld</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:05:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14014</guid></item></channel></rss>