<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Multiplex Thinking: Reasoning via Token-wise Branch-and-Merge</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.08808</link><description>Multiplex Thinking introduces a stochastic soft reasoning mechanism that samples multiple candidate tokens at each step to optimize reasoning trajectories with reinforcement learning while maintaining shorter sequences than traditional chain-of-thought methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models often solve complex reasoning tasks more effectively with Chain-of-Thought (CoT), but at the cost of long, low-bandwidth token sequences. Humans, by contrast, often reason softly by maintaining a distribution over plausible next steps. Motivated by this, we propose Multiplex Thinking, a stochastic soft reasoning mechanism that, at each thinking step, samples K candidate tokens and aggregates their embeddings into a single continuous multiplex token. This preserves the vocabulary embedding prior and the sampling dynamics of standard discrete generation, while inducing a tractable probability distribution over multiplex rollouts. Consequently, multiplex trajectories can be directly optimized with on-policy reinforcement learning (RL). Importantly, Multiplex Thinking is self-adaptive: when the model is confident, the multiplex token is nearly discrete and behaves like standard CoT; when it is uncertain, it compactly represents multiple plausible next steps without increasing sequence length. Across challenging math reasoning benchmarks, Multiplex Thinking consistently outperforms strong discrete CoT and RL baselines from Pass@1 through Pass@1024, while producing shorter sequences. The code and checkpoints are available at https://github.com/GMLR-Penn/Multiplex-Thinking.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:15:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.08808</guid></item><item><title>ABC-Bench: Benchmarking Agentic Backend Coding in Real-World Development</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.11077</link><description>ABC-Bench evaluates LLM agents on realistic backend coding tasks requiring full development lifecycle management from repository exploration to containerized service deployment and API testing.  					AI-generated summary 				 The evolution of Large Language Models (LLMs) into autonomous agents has expanded the scope of AI coding from localized code generation to complex, repository-level, and execution-driven problem solving. However, current benchmarks predominantly evaluate code logic in static contexts, neglecting the dynamic, full-process requirements of real-world engineering, particularly in backend development which demands rigorous environment configuration and service deployment. To address this gap, we introduce ABC-Bench, a benchmark explicitly designed to evaluate agentic backend coding within a realistic, executable workflow. Using a scalable automated pipeline, we curated 224 practical tasks spanning 8 languages and 19 frameworks from open-source repositories. Distinct from previous evaluations, ABC-Bench require the agents to manage the entire development lifecycle from repository exploration to instantiating containerized services and pass the external end-to-end API tests. Our extensive evaluation reveals that even state-of-the-art models struggle to deliver reliable performance on these holistic tasks, highlighting a substantial disparity between current model capabilities and the demands of practical backend engineering. Our code is available at https://github.com/OpenMOSS/ABC-Bench.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:27:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.11077</guid></item><item><title>CoDance: An Unbind-Rebind Paradigm for Robust Multi-Subject Animation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.11096</link><description>CoDance introduces an Unbind-Rebind framework for animating multiple subjects with flexible spatial configurations, using pose shift encoding and semantic/textual guidance for motion reassignment.  					AI-generated summary 				 Character image animation is gaining significant importance across various domains, driven by the demand for robust and flexible multi-subject rendering. While existing methods excel in single-person animation, they struggle to handle arbitrary subject counts, diverse character types, and spatial misalignment between the reference image and the driving poses. We attribute these limitations to an overly rigid spatial binding that forces strict pixel-wise alignment between the pose and reference, and an inability to consistently rebind motion to intended subjects. To address these challenges, we propose CoDance, a novel Unbind-Rebind framework that enables the animation of arbitrary subject counts, types, and spatial configurations conditioned on a single, potentially misaligned pose sequence. Specifically, the Unbind module employs a novel pose shift encoder to break the rigid spatial binding between the pose and the reference by introducing stochastic perturbations to both poses and their latent features, thereby compelling the model to learn a location-agnostic motion representation. To ensure precise control and subject association, we then devise a Rebind module, leveraging semantic guidance from text prompts and spatial guidance from subject masks to direct the learned motion to intended characters. Furthermore, to facilitate comprehensive evaluation, we introduce a new multi-subject CoDanceBench. Extensive experiments on CoDanceBench and existing datasets show that CoDance achieves SOTA performance, exhibiting remarkable generalization across diverse subjects and spatial layouts. The code and weights will be open-sourced.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:20:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.11096</guid></item><item><title>The Assistant Axis: Situating and Stabilizing the Default Persona of Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.10387</link><description>Research reveals that large language models operate within a persona space where an "Assistant Axis" controls helpfulness and behavioral stability, with steering techniques able to influence model responses and prevent harmful behavior drift.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models can represent a variety of personas but typically default to a helpful Assistant identity cultivated during post-training. We investigate the structure of the space of model personas by extracting activation directions corresponding to diverse character archetypes. Across several different models, we find that the leading component of this persona space is an "Assistant Axis," which captures the extent to which a model is operating in its default Assistant mode. Steering towards the Assistant direction reinforces helpful and harmless behavior; steering away increases the model's tendency to identify as other entities. Moreover, steering away with more extreme values often induces a mystical, theatrical speaking style. We find this axis is also present in pre-trained models, where it primarily promotes helpful human archetypes like consultants and coaches and inhibits spiritual ones. Measuring deviations along the Assistant Axis predicts "persona drift," a phenomenon where models slip into exhibiting harmful or bizarre behaviors that are uncharacteristic of their typical persona. We find that persona drift is often driven by conversations demanding meta-reflection on the model's processes or featuring emotionally vulnerable users. We show that restricting activations to a fixed region along the Assistant Axis can stabilize model behavior in these scenarios -- and also in the face of adversarial persona-based jailbreaks. Our results suggest that post-training steers models toward a particular region of persona space but only loosely tethers them to it, motivating work on training and steering strategies that more deeply anchor models to a coherent persona.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:24:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.10387</guid></item><item><title>SIN-Bench: Tracing Native Evidence Chains in Long-Context Multimodal Scientific Interleaved Literature</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.10108</link><description>Researchers introduce the Fish-in-the-Ocean paradigm and SIN-Bench dataset to evaluate multimodal language models' ability to reason over scientific documents with evidence chains, revealing a gap between answer accuracy and traceable support.  					AI-generated summary 				 Evaluating whether multimodal large language models truly understand long-form scientific papers remains challenging: answer-only metrics and synthetic "Needle-In-A-Haystack" tests often reward answer matching without requiring a causal, evidence-linked reasoning trace in the document. We propose the "Fish-in-the-Ocean" (FITO) paradigm, which requires models to construct explicit cross-modal evidence chains within native scientific documents. To operationalize FITO, we build SIN-Data, a scientific interleaved corpus that preserves the native interleaving of text and figures. On top of it, we construct SIN-Bench with four progressive tasks covering evidence discovery (SIN-Find), hypothesis verification (SIN-Verify), grounded QA (SIN-QA), and evidence-anchored synthesis (SIN-Summary). We further introduce "No Evidence, No Score", scoring predictions when grounded to verifiable anchors and diagnosing evidence quality via matching, relevance, and logic. Experiments on eight MLLMs show that grounding is the primary bottleneck: Gemini-3-pro achieves the best average overall score (0.573), while GPT-5 attains the highest SIN-QA answer accuracy (0.767) but underperforms on evidence-aligned overall scores, exposing a gap between correctness and traceable support.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:31:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.10108</guid></item></channel></rss>