<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Drag-and-Drop LLMs: Zero-Shot Prompt-to-Weights</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.16406</link><description>Drag-and-Drop LLMs generate task-specific parameters through prompt-conditioned parameter generation, achieving significant efficiency gains and cross-domain generalization without per-task training.  					AI-generated summary 				 Modern Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning (PEFT) methods such as low-rank adaptation (LoRA) reduce the cost of customizing large language models (LLMs), yet still require a separate optimization run for every downstream dataset. We introduce Drag-and-Drop LLMs (\textit{DnD)}, a prompt-conditioned parameter generator that eliminates per-task training by mapping a handful of unlabeled task prompts directly to LoRA weight updates. A lightweight text encoder distills each prompt batch into condition embeddings, which are then transformed by a cascaded hyper-convolutional decoder into the full set of LoRA matrices. Once trained in a diverse collection of prompt-checkpoint pairs, DnD produces task-specific parameters in seconds, yielding i) up to 12,000times lower overhead than full fine-tuning, ii) average gains up to 30\% in performance over the strongest training LoRAs on unseen common-sense reasoning, math, coding, and multimodal benchmarks, and iii) robust cross-domain generalization despite never seeing the target data or labels. Our results demonstrate that prompt-conditioned parameter generation is a viable alternative to gradient-based adaptation for rapidly specializing LLMs. Our project is available at https://jerryliang24.github.io/DnD{https://jerryliang24.github.io/DnD}.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 04:09:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.16406</guid></item><item><title>PAROAttention: Pattern-Aware ReOrdering for Efficient Sparse and
  Quantized Attention in Visual Generation Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.16054</link><description>PAROAttention reorganizes visual attention patterns to enable efficient sparsification and quantization, reducing memory and computational costs with minimal impact on performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 In visual generation, the quadratic complexity of attention mechanisms results in high memory and computational costs, especially for longer token sequences required in high-resolution image or multi-frame video generation. To address this, prior research has explored techniques such as sparsification and quantization. However, these techniques face significant challenges under low density and reduced bitwidths. Through systematic analysis, we identify that the core difficulty stems from the dispersed and irregular characteristics of visual attention patterns. Therefore, instead of introducing specialized sparsification and quantization design to accommodate such patterns, we propose an alternative strategy: *reorganizing* the attention pattern to alleviate the challenges. Inspired by the local aggregation nature of visual feature extraction, we design a novel **Pattern-Aware token ReOrdering (PARO)** technique, which unifies the diverse attention patterns into a hardware-friendly block-wise pattern. This unification substantially simplifies and enhances both sparsification and quantization. We evaluate the performance-efficiency trade-offs of various design choices and finalize a methodology tailored for the unified pattern. Our approach, **PAROAttention**, achieves video and image generation with lossless metrics, and nearly identical results from full-precision (FP) baselines, while operating at notably lower density (~20%-30%) and bitwidth (**INT8/INT4**), achieving a **1.9x** to **2.7x** end-to-end latency speedup.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 05:22:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.16054</guid></item><item><title>Vision-Guided Chunking Is All You Need: Enhancing RAG with Multimodal
  Document Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.16035</link><description>A novel multimodal document chunking approach using Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) enhances RAG performance by accurately processing complex PDF documents, including multi-page tables and embedded visuals.  					AI-generated summary 				 Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems have revolutionized information retrieval and question answering, but traditional text-based chunking methods struggle with complex document structures, multi-page tables, embedded figures, and contextual dependencies across page boundaries. We present a novel multimodal document chunking approach that leverages Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) to process PDF documents in batches while maintaining semantic coherence and structural integrity. Our method processes documents in configurable page batches with cross-batch context preservation, enabling accurate handling of tables spanning multiple pages, embedded visual elements, and procedural content. We evaluate our approach on a curated dataset of PDF documents with manually crafted queries, demonstrating improvements in chunk quality and downstream RAG performance. Our vision-guided approach achieves better accuracy compared to traditional vanilla RAG systems, with qualitative analysis showing superior preservation of document structure and semantic coherence.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 04:43:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.16035</guid></item><item><title>VIKI-R: Coordinating Embodied Multi-Agent Cooperation via Reinforcement
  Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09049</link><description>VIKI-Bench and VIKI-R provide a benchmark and framework for evaluating and improving visual-driven cooperation among diverse embodied agents using vision-language models and reinforcement learning.  					AI-generated summary 				 Coordinating multiple embodied agents in dynamic environments remains a core challenge in artificial intelligence, requiring both perception-driven reasoning and scalable cooperation strategies. While recent works have leveraged large language models (LLMs) for multi-agent planning, a few have begun to explore vision-language models (VLMs) for visual reasoning. However, these VLM-based approaches remain limited in their support for diverse embodiment types. In this work, we introduce VIKI-Bench, the first hierarchical benchmark tailored for embodied multi-agent cooperation, featuring three structured levels: agent activation, task planning, and trajectory perception. VIKI-Bench includes diverse robot embodiments, multi-view visual observations, and structured supervision signals to evaluate reasoning grounded in visual inputs. To demonstrate the utility of VIKI-Bench, we propose VIKI-R, a two-stage framework that fine-tunes a pretrained vision-language model (VLM) using Chain-of-Thought annotated demonstrations, followed by reinforcement learning under multi-level reward signals. Our extensive experiments show that VIKI-R significantly outperforms baselines method across all task levels. Furthermore, we show that reinforcement learning enables the emergence of compositional cooperation patterns among heterogeneous agents. Together, VIKI-Bench and VIKI-R offer a unified testbed and method for advancing multi-agent, visual-driven cooperation in embodied AI systems.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 03:01:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.09049</guid></item><item><title>DreamCube: 3D Panorama Generation via Multi-plane Synchronization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.17206</link><description>Multi-plane synchronization extends 2D foundation models to 3D panorama generation, introducing DreamCube to achieve diverse appearances and accurate geometry.  					AI-generated summary 				 3D panorama synthesis is a promising yet challenging task that demands high-quality and diverse visual appearance and geometry of the generated omnidirectional content. Existing methods leverage rich image priors from pre-trained 2D foundation models to circumvent the scarcity of 3D panoramic data, but the incompatibility between 3D panoramas and 2D single views limits their effectiveness. In this work, we demonstrate that by applying multi-plane synchronization to the operators from 2D foundation models, their capabilities can be seamlessly extended to the omnidirectional domain. Based on this design, we further introduce DreamCube, a multi-plane RGB-D diffusion model for 3D panorama generation, which maximizes the reuse of 2D foundation model priors to achieve diverse appearances and accurate geometry while maintaining multi-view consistency. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach in panoramic image generation, panoramic depth estimation, and 3D scene generation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 03:11:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.17206</guid></item><item><title>Hunyuan-GameCraft: High-dynamic Interactive Game Video Generation with
  Hybrid History Condition</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.17201</link><description>Hunyuan-GameCraft is a novel framework for high-dynamic interactive video generation in game environments that addresses limitations in dynamics, generality, and efficiency through unified input representation, hybrid history-conditioned training, and model distillation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in diffusion-based and controllable video generation have enabled high-quality and temporally coherent video synthesis, laying the groundwork for immersive interactive gaming experiences. However, current methods face limitations in dynamics, generality, long-term consistency, and efficiency, which limit the ability to create various gameplay videos. To address these gaps, we introduce Hunyuan-GameCraft, a novel framework for high-dynamic interactive video generation in game environments. To achieve fine-grained action control, we unify standard keyboard and mouse inputs into a shared camera representation space, facilitating smooth interpolation between various camera and movement operations. Then we propose a hybrid history-conditioned training strategy that extends video sequences autoregressively while preserving game scene information. Additionally, to enhance inference efficiency and playability, we achieve model distillation to reduce computational overhead while maintaining consistency across long temporal sequences, making it suitable for real-time deployment in complex interactive environments. The model is trained on a large-scale dataset comprising over one million gameplay recordings across over 100 AAA games, ensuring broad coverage and diversity, then fine-tuned on a carefully annotated synthetic dataset to enhance precision and control. The curated game scene data significantly improves the visual fidelity, realism and action controllability. Extensive experiments demonstrate that Hunyuan-GameCraft significantly outperforms existing models, advancing the realism and playability of interactive game video generation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 03:05:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.17201</guid></item><item><title>Hunyuan3D 2.5: Towards High-Fidelity 3D Assets Generation with Ultimate
  Details</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.16504</link><description>Hunyuan3D 2.5, a suite of 3D diffusion models, advances shape and texture generation with a new LATTICE model and physical-based rendering in a multi-view architecture.  					AI-generated summary 				 In this report, we present Hunyuan3D 2.5, a robust suite of 3D diffusion models aimed at generating high-fidelity and detailed textured 3D assets. Hunyuan3D 2.5 follows two-stages pipeline of its previous version Hunyuan3D 2.0, while demonstrating substantial advancements in both shape and texture generation. In terms of shape generation, we introduce a new shape foundation model -- LATTICE, which is trained with scaled high-quality datasets, model-size, and compute. Our largest model reaches 10B parameters and generates sharp and detailed 3D shape with precise image-3D following while keeping mesh surface clean and smooth, significantly closing the gap between generated and handcrafted 3D shapes. In terms of texture generation, it is upgraded with phyiscal-based rendering (PBR) via a novel multi-view architecture extended from Hunyuan3D 2.0 Paint model. Our extensive evaluation shows that Hunyuan3D 2.5 significantly outperforms previous methods in both shape and end-to-end texture generation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 02:55:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.16504</guid></item><item><title>InfiniPot-V: Memory-Constrained KV Cache Compression for Streaming Video
  Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.15745</link><description>InfiniPot-V is a training-free, query-agnostic framework that compresses the key-value cache during video encoding to maintain a fixed memory cap for streaming video understanding, enhancing real-time performance and accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Modern multimodal large language models (MLLMs) can reason over hour-long video, yet their key-value (KV) cache grows linearly with time--quickly exceeding the fixed memory of phones, AR glasses, and edge robots. Prior compression schemes either assume the whole video and user query are available offline or must first build the full cache, so memory still scales with stream length. InfiniPot-V is the first training-free, query-agnostic framework that enforces a hard, length-independent memory cap for streaming video understanding. During video encoding it monitors the cache and, once a user-set threshold is reached, runs a lightweight compression pass that (i) removes temporally redundant tokens via Temporal-axis Redundancy (TaR) metric and (ii) keeps semantically significant tokens via Value-Norm (VaN) ranking. Across four open-source MLLMs and four long-video and two streaming-video benchmarks, InfiniPot-V cuts peak GPU memory by up to 94%, sustains real-time generation, and matches or surpasses full-cache accuracy--even in multi-turn dialogues. By dissolving the KV cache bottleneck without retraining or query knowledge, InfiniPot-V closes the gap for on-device streaming video assistants.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 08:40:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.15745</guid></item><item><title>Long-term Traffic Simulation with Interleaved Autoregressive Motion and
  Scenario Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.17213</link><description>InfGen, a unified next-token prediction model, enables stable long-term traffic simulation by interleaving closed-loop motion simulation and scene generation.  					AI-generated summary 				 An ideal traffic simulator replicates the realistic long-term point-to-point trip that a self-driving system experiences during deployment. Prior models and benchmarks focus on closed-loop motion simulation for initial agents in a scene. This is problematic for long-term simulation. Agents enter and exit the scene as the ego vehicle enters new regions. We propose InfGen, a unified next-token prediction model that performs interleaved closed-loop motion simulation and scene generation. InfGen automatically switches between closed-loop motion simulation and scene generation mode. It enables stable long-term rollout simulation. InfGen performs at the state-of-the-art in short-term (9s) traffic simulation, and significantly outperforms all other methods in long-term (30s) simulation. The code and model of InfGen will be released at https://orangesodahub.github.io/InfGen</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 08:47:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.17213</guid></item><item><title>UniFork: Exploring Modality Alignment for Unified Multimodal
  Understanding and Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.17202</link><description>A Y-shaped architecture, UniFork, balances shared learning and task specialization for unified image understanding and generation, outperforming conventional fully shared Transformer models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Unified image understanding and generation has emerged as a promising paradigm in multimodal artificial intelligence. Despite recent progress, the optimal architectural design for such unified models remains an open challenge. In this work, we start by analyzing the modality alignment behaviors of task-specific expert models for understanding and generation, as well as current unified models. Our analysis reveals a crucial observation: understanding tasks benefit from a progressively increasing modality alignment across network depth, which helps build up semantic information for better comprehension; In contrast, generation tasks follow a different trend: modality alignment increases in the early layers but decreases in the deep layers to recover spatial details. These divergent alignment patterns create a fundamental conflict in fully shared Transformer backbones, where a uniform representational flow often leads to performance compromises across two tasks. Motivated by this finding, we introduce UniFork, a novel Y-shaped architecture that shares the shallow layers for cross-task representation learning, while employing task-specific branches in deeper layers to avoid task interference. This design effectively balances shared learning and task specialization. Through extensive ablation experiments, we demonstrate that Unifork consistently outperforms conventional fully shared Transformer architectures, and achieves performance on par with or better than task-specific models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 09:21:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.17202</guid></item><item><title>Reranking-based Generation for Unbiased Perspective Summarization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.15925</link><description>Reranking and preference tuning improve the quality of perspective summaries generated by LLMs, as measured by language model-based metrics that outperform traditional ones.  					AI-generated summary 				 Generating unbiased summaries in real-world settings such as political perspective summarization remains a crucial application of Large Language Models (LLMs). Yet, existing evaluation frameworks rely on traditional metrics for measuring key attributes such as coverage and faithfulness without verifying their applicability, and efforts to develop improved summarizers are still nascent. We address these gaps by (1) identifying reliable metrics for measuring perspective summary quality, and (2) investigating the efficacy of LLM-based methods beyond zero-shot inference. Namely, we build a test set for benchmarking metric reliability using human annotations and show that traditional metrics underperform compared to language model-based metrics, which prove to be strong evaluators. Using these metrics, we show that reranking-based methods yield strong results, and preference tuning with synthetically generated and reranking-labeled data further boosts performance. Our findings aim to contribute to the reliable evaluation and development of perspective summarization methods.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 03:17:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.15925</guid></item><item><title>Hunyuan3D 2.1: From Images to High-Fidelity 3D Assets with
  Production-Ready PBR Material</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.15442</link><description>The tutorial provides a comprehensive guide on using Hunyuan3D 2.1 for generating high-resolution, textured 3D models, covering data preparation, model architecture, training, evaluation, and deployment.  					AI-generated summary 				 3D AI-generated content (AIGC) is a passionate field that has significantly accelerated the creation of 3D models in gaming, film, and design. Despite the development of several groundbreaking models that have revolutionized 3D generation, the field remains largely accessible only to researchers, developers, and designers due to the complexities involved in collecting, processing, and training 3D models. To address these challenges, we introduce Hunyuan3D 2.1 as a case study in this tutorial. This tutorial offers a comprehensive, step-by-step guide on processing 3D data, training a 3D generative model, and evaluating its performance using Hunyuan3D 2.1, an advanced system for producing high-resolution, textured 3D assets. The system comprises two core components: the Hunyuan3D-DiT for shape generation and the Hunyuan3D-Paint for texture synthesis. We will explore the entire workflow, including data preparation, model architecture, training strategies, evaluation metrics, and deployment. By the conclusion of this tutorial, you will have the knowledge to finetune or develop a robust 3D generative model suitable for applications in gaming, virtual reality, and industrial design.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 08:47:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.15442</guid></item></channel></rss>