<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>🌾 NH Prediction: AI System for Korean Agricultural Price Forecasting 🌾</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/openfree/102455854917725</link><description>🌾 NH Prediction: AI System for Korean Agricultural Price Forecasting 🌾 📊 Project Introduction Price volatility in agricultural markets has significant impacts from producers to consumers! NH Prediction is an innovative system that utilizes cutting-edge AI technology to predict Korean agricultural wholesale prices based on extensive data spanning 40 years. 🚀 VIDraft/NH-Prediction ginipick/NH-Korea 🧠 VIDraft's 14 Enhanced Prediction Models The VIDraft research team has developed 14 advanced prediction models by reinforcing existing forecasting approaches: 🔮 VID-SARIMA Series: Precisely models seasonality and trends (up to 99.99% accuracy) ⚖️ VID-ETS Series: Captures multiplicative/additive variation patterns 📈 VID-Holt/Holt-Winters: Simultaneous analysis of linear trends and seasonality 📉 VID-MovingAverage/WeightedMA: Noise removal and medium-term trend identification 🔍 VID-Fourier+LR: Hybrid approach capturing complex periodicity ✨ Key Features 🌟 Item-Specific Optimization:...</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/openfree/102455854917725</guid></item><item><title>🧬 Hey everyone! Just released **OpenEvolve** - an open-source implementation of Google DeepMind's AlphaEvolve system.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/735622263233891</link><description>🧬 Hey everyone! Just released **OpenEvolve** - an open-source implementation of Google DeepMind's AlphaEvolve system. It's an evolutionary coding agent that uses LLMs to discover and optimize algorithms. I successfully replicated DeepMind's results on circle packing (99.97% match!) and evolved a random search into a simulated annealing algorithm. ✨ Key features: - Evolves entire codebases (not just single functions) - Works with any OpenAI-compatible API - LLM ensemble approach for better results - Multi-objective optimization 👉 Check it out: GitHub: https://github.com/codelion/openevolve Blog post: https://huggingface.co/blog/codelion/openevolve Would love to hear your thoughts or answer any questions about it! See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/735622263233891</guid></item><item><title>hey hey</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/reach-vb/415173057781918</link><description>hey hey @ mradermacher - VB from Hugging Face here, we'd love to onboard you over to our optimised xet backend! 💥 as you know we're in the process of upgrading our storage backend to xet (which helps us scale and offer blazingly fast upload/ download speeds too): https://huggingface.co/blog/xet-on-the-hub and now that we are certain that the backend can scale with even big models like Llama 4/ Qwen 3 - we;re moving to the next phase of inviting impactful orgs and users on the hub over as you are a big part of the open source ML community - we would love to onboard you next and create some excitement about it in the community too! in terms of actual steps - it should be as simple as one of the org admins to join hf.co/join/xet - we'll take care of the rest. p.s. you'd need to have a the latest hf_xet version of huggingface_hub lib but everything else should be the same: https://huggingface.co/docs/hub/storage-backends#using-xet-storage p.p.s. this is fully backwards compatible so...</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/reach-vb/415173057781918</guid></item><item><title>ByteDance is absolutely cooking lately🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/709690582361356</link><description>ByteDance is absolutely cooking lately🔥 BAGEL 🥯 7B active parameter open multimodal foundation model by Bytedance Seed team. ByteDance-Seed/BAGEL-7B-MoT ✨ Apache 2.0 ✨ Outperforms top VLMs (Qwen2.5-VL &amp; InternVL-2.5) ✨ Mixture-of-Transformer-Experts + dual encoders ✨ Trained on trillions of interleaved tokens See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/709690582361356</guid></item><item><title>Video link :</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/454841394174188</link><description>Video link : https://youtu.be/gFMUChHgXYk VEO 3 AI Video Generation is Literally Insane with Perfect Audio! - 60 User Generated Wild Examples - Finally We can Expect Native Audio Supported Open Source Video Gen Models Video link : https://youtu.be/gFMUChHgXYk Google Unveils Veo 3: A Game-Changing AI Video Generator with Native Audio Published May 21, 2025 At Google I/O 2025, held on May 20–21 in Mountain View, California, Google announced the launch of Veo 3, its latest AI-powered video generation model, marking a significant leap in creative technology. This third-generation model, succeeding Veo 2, introduces groundbreaking features, most notably its ability to generate high-quality videos with integrated audio, including dialogue, sound effects, and ambient noise. Alongside Veo 3, Google introduced Flow, a new AI-driven video editing suite designed to empower filmmakers and content creators. Here’s an in-depth look at Veo 3, its capabilities, and its potential to reshape AI...</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/454841394174188</guid></item><item><title>Despite the emergence of combining LLM and DiT architectures for T2I synthesis, its design remains severely understudied.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sayakpaul/592772325865027</link><description>Despite the emergence of combining LLM and DiT architectures for T2I synthesis, its design remains severely understudied. This was done long ago and got into CVPR25 -- super excited to finally share it now, along with the data and code ♥️ We explore several architectural choices that affect this design. We provide an open &amp; reproducible training recipe that works at scale. Works like Playground v3 have already explored a deep fusion between an LLM and a DiT, sharing their representations through layerwise attention. They exhibit excellent performance on T2I. Despite its compelling results and other performance virtues, it remains unexplored, which is what we want to improve in our work. Specifically, we take a pre-trained LLM (Gemma-2B) and trainable DiT, and set out to explore what makes a "good deep fusion" between the two for T2I. We explore several key questions in the work, such as: Q1: How should we do attention? We considered several alternatives. PixArt-Alpha like attention...</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sayakpaul/592772325865027</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin 🔥 A multimodal document image parsing model from ByteDance</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/681444668762731</link><description>Dolphin 🔥 A multimodal document image parsing model from ByteDance , built on an analyze-then-parse paradigm. ByteDance/Dolphin ✨ MIT licensed ✨ Handles text, tables, figures &amp; formulas via: - Reading-order layout analysis - Parallel parsing with smart prompts See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/681444668762731</guid></item><item><title>Heyo</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/jsulz/285043040409517</link><description>Heyo @ RichardErkhov the xet-team at Hugging face was wondering if you wanted to join the fun and jump over to Xet storage. 🤗 We've been onboarding folks https://huggingface.co/blog/xet-on-the-hub know the backend can scale (Llama 4 and Qwen 3 are on Xet), is great for working with quants (see xet-team/quantization-dedup ), and we're pushing on inviting impactful orgs and users on the Hub. You fit the bill. We'd love to onboard you, get some feedback, and create some excitement 🎉 The steps are pretty straightforward - join the waitlist at hf.co/join/xet and we'll take care of the rest. The system is fully backward compatible, so you shouldn't notice a thing. BUT to get the best experience when uploading/downloading, make sure you have hf_xet installed alongside the latest huggingface_hub What do you think? See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/jsulz/285043040409517</guid></item><item><title>It was the week of video generation at</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/789898391077513</link><description>It was the week of video generation at @ huggingface , on top of many new LLMs, VLMs and more! Let’s have a wrap 🌯 merve/may-16-releases-682aeed23b97eb0fe965345c LLMs 💬 &gt; Alibaba Qwen released WorldPM-72B, new World Preference Model trained with 15M preference samples (OS) &gt; II-Medical-8B, new LLM for medical reasoning that comes in 8B by Intelligent-Internet &gt; TRAIL is a new dataset by Patronus for trace error reasoning for agents (OS) Multimodal 🖼️💬 &gt; Salesforce Research released BLIP3o, a new any-to-any model with image-text input and image-text output 💬it’s based on an image encoder, a text decoder and a DiT, and comes in 8B &gt; They also released pre-training and fine-tuning datasets &gt; MMMG is a multimodal generation benchmark for image, audio, text (interleaved) Image Generation ⏯️ &gt; Alibaba Wan-AI released Wan2.1-VACE, video foundation model for image and text to video, video-to-audio and more tasks, comes in 1.3B and 14B (OS) &gt; ZuluVision released MoviiGen1.1, new cinematic...</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/789898391077513</guid></item><item><title>Hello everyone. I've built a medical AI assistant application.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/pranavupadhyaya52/196223267192478</link><description>Hello everyone. I've built a medical AI assistant application. pranavupadhyaya52/MediWiki_Medical_Assistant It is a multimodal chatbot and can accept text, radiology images, prescription and lab reports (currently it only accepts one image per chat.) and audio files (wav and MP3 extension files). It is built on top of a finetuned Llama 3.2 11B vision instruct. It also uses a 41000 medically related question answer pair stored in the form of chromadb embedding for Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). Please let me know your thoughts on my project and how I can improve it further. Thank you. See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:23:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/pranavupadhyaya52/196223267192478</guid></item></channel></rss>