<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>ZeroSearch: Incentivize the Search Capability of LLMs without Searching</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.04588</link><description>Effective information searching is essential for enhancing the reasoning and generation capabilities of large language models (LLMs). Recent research has explored using reinforcement learning (RL) to improve LLMs' search capabilities by interacting with live search engines in real-world environments. While these approaches show promising results, they face two major challenges: (1) Uncontrolled Document Quality: The quality of documents returned by search engines is often unpredictable, introducing noise and instability into the training process. (2) Prohibitively High API Costs: RL training requires frequent rollouts, potentially involving hundreds of thousands of search requests, which incur substantial API expenses and severely constrain scalability. To address these challenges, we introduce ZeroSearch, a reinforcement learning framework that incentivizes the search capabilities of LLMs without interacting with real search engines. Our approach begins with lightweight supervised fine-tuning to transform the LLM into a retrieval module capable of generating both relevant and noisy documents in response to a query. During RL training, we employ a curriculum-based rollout strategy that incrementally degrades the quality of generated documents, progressively eliciting the model's reasoning ability by exposing it to increasingly challenging retrieval scenarios. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ZeroSearch effectively incentivizes the search capabilities of LLMs using a 3B LLM as the retrieval module. Remarkably, a 7B retrieval module achieves comparable performance to the real search engine, while a 14B retrieval module even surpasses it. Furthermore, it generalizes well across both base and instruction-tuned models of various parameter sizes and is compatible with a wide range of RL algorithms.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 02:24:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.04588</guid></item><item><title>Benchmarking LLMs' Swarm intelligence</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.04364</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) show potential for complex reasoning, yet their capacity for emergent coordination in Multi-Agent Systems (MAS) when operating under strict constraints-such as limited local perception and communication, characteristic of natural swarms-remains largely unexplored, particularly concerning the nuances of swarm intelligence. Existing benchmarks often do not fully capture the unique challenges of decentralized coordination that arise when agents operate with incomplete spatio-temporal information. To bridge this gap, we introduce SwarmBench, a novel benchmark designed to systematically evaluate the swarm intelligence capabilities of LLMs acting as decentralized agents. SwarmBench features five foundational MAS coordination tasks within a configurable 2D grid environment, forcing agents to rely primarily on local sensory input (k x k view) and local communication. We propose metrics for coordination effectiveness and analyze emergent group dynamics. Evaluating several leading LLMs in a zero-shot setting, we find significant performance variations across tasks, highlighting the difficulties posed by local information constraints. While some coordination emerges, results indicate limitations in robust planning and strategy formation under uncertainty in these decentralized scenarios. Assessing LLMs under swarm-like conditions is crucial for realizing their potential in future decentralized systems. We release SwarmBench as an open, extensible toolkit-built upon a customizable and scalable physical system with defined mechanical properties. It provides environments, prompts, evaluation scripts, and the comprehensive experimental datasets generated, aiming to foster reproducible research into LLM-based MAS coordination and the theoretical underpinnings of Embodied MAS. Our code repository is available at https://github.com/x66ccff/swarmbench.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 02:38:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.04364</guid></item></channel></rss>