<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Beyond the 80/20 Rule: High-Entropy Minority Tokens Drive Effective
  Reinforcement Learning for LLM Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01939</link><description>Token entropy patterns are crucial in RLVR, with high-entropy tokens significantly impacting reasoning performance and model optimization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) has emerged as a powerful approach to enhancing the reasoning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), while its mechanisms are not yet well understood. In this work, we undertake a pioneering exploration of RLVR through the novel perspective of token entropy patterns, comprehensively analyzing how different tokens influence reasoning performance. By examining token entropy patterns in Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning, we observe that only a small fraction of tokens exhibit high entropy, and these tokens act as critical forks that steer the model toward diverse reasoning pathways. Furthermore, studying how entropy patterns evolve during RLVR training reveals that RLVR largely adheres to the base model's entropy patterns, primarily adjusting the entropy of high-entropy tokens. These findings highlight the significance of high-entropy tokens (i.e., forking tokens) to RLVR. We ultimately improve RLVR by restricting policy gradient updates to forking tokens and uncover a finding even beyond the 80/20 rule: utilizing only 20% of the tokens while maintaining performance comparable to full-gradient updates on the Qwen3-8B base model and significantly surpassing full-gradient updates on the Qwen3-32B (+11.04 on AIME'25 and +7.71 on AIME'24) and Qwen3-14B (+4.79 on AIME'25 and +5.21 on AIME'24) base models, highlighting a strong scaling trend. In contrast, training exclusively on the 80% lowest-entropy tokens leads to a marked decline in performance. These findings indicate that the efficacy of RLVR primarily arises from optimizing the high-entropy tokens that decide reasoning directions. Collectively, our results highlight the potential to understand RLVR through a token-entropy perspective and optimize RLVR by leveraging high-entropy minority tokens to further improve LLM reasoning.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 04:39:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01939</guid></item><item><title>Taming LLMs by Scaling Learning Rates with Gradient Grouping</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01049</link><description>SGG, an optimizer wrapper, enhances adaptive learning rates for large language models by grouping gradients and applying cluster-specific scaling, improving convergence and stability.  					AI-generated summary 				 Training large language models (LLMs) poses challenges due to their massive scale and heterogeneous architectures. While adaptive optimizers like AdamW help address gradient variations, they still struggle with efficient and effective parameter-wise learning rate estimation, resulting in training instability, slow convergence, and poor compatibility with parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) techniques. This work introduces Scaling with Gradient Grouping (SGG), an optimizer wrapper that improves adaptive learning rate estimation by dynamic grouping and group-specific scaling. SGG first groups gradient statistics in each layer into clusters and then applies cluster-specific scaling to calibrate learning rates for each parameter, thus imposing collective group-wise constraints while maintaining precise per-parameter adaptation. Experiments on diverse (M)LLM benchmarks show that SGG integrates seamlessly with existing optimizers, and offers consistent gains and faster convergence over baselines, with various model sizes. Its stability across varying batch sizes and learning rates establishes SGG as a robust choice for LLM optimization.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 02:22:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01049</guid></item><item><title>Jigsaw-R1: A Study of Rule-based Visual Reinforcement Learning with
  Jigsaw Puzzles</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23590</link><description>Rule-based reinforcement learning applied to multimodal large language models demonstrates effective generalization in visual tasks, particularly using jigsaw puzzles, outperforming supervised fine-tuning.  					AI-generated summary 				 The application of rule-based reinforcement learning (RL) to multimodal large language models (MLLMs) introduces unique challenges and potential deviations from findings in text-only domains, particularly for perception-heavy tasks. This paper provides a comprehensive study of rule-based visual RL, using jigsaw puzzles as a structured experimental framework. Jigsaw puzzles offer inherent ground truth, adjustable difficulty, and demand complex decision-making, making them ideal for this study. Our research reveals several key findings: Firstly, we find that MLLMs, initially performing near to random guessing on the simplest jigsaw puzzles, achieve near-perfect accuracy and generalize to complex, unseen configurations through fine-tuning. Secondly, training on jigsaw puzzles can induce generalization to other visual tasks, with effectiveness tied to specific task configurations. Thirdly, MLLMs can learn and generalize with or without explicit reasoning, though open-source models often favor direct answering. Consequently, even when trained for step-by-step reasoning, they can ignore the thinking process in deriving the final answer. Fourthly, we observe that complex reasoning patterns appear to be pre-existing rather than emergent, with their frequency increasing alongside training and task difficulty. Finally, our results demonstrate that RL exhibits more effective generalization than Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT), and an initial SFT cold start phase can hinder subsequent RL optimization. Although these observations are based on jigsaw puzzles and may vary across other visual tasks, this research contributes a valuable piece of jigsaw to the larger puzzle of collective understanding rule-based visual RL and its potential in multimodal learning. The code is available at: https://github.com/zifuwanggg/Jigsaw-R1.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:26:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23590</guid></item><item><title>ARIA: Training Language Agents with Intention-Driven Reward Aggregation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00539</link><description>ARIA aggregates rewards in an intention space to mitigate reward sparsity and improve policy optimization in language-based reinforcement learning tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) have enabled agents to perform complex reasoning and decision-making through free-form language interactions. However, in open-ended language action environments (e.g., negotiation or question-asking games), the action space can be formulated as a joint distribution over tokens, resulting in an exponentially large action space. Sampling actions in such a space can lead to extreme reward sparsity, which brings large reward variance, hindering effective reinforcement learning (RL). To address this, we propose ARIA, a method that Aggregates Rewards in Intention space to enable efficient and effective language Agents training. ARIA aims to project natural language actions from the high-dimensional joint token distribution space into a low-dimensional intention space, where semantically similar actions are clustered and assigned shared rewards. This intention-aware reward aggregation reduces reward variance by densifying reward signals, fostering better policy optimization. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ARIA not only significantly reduces policy gradient variance, but also delivers substantial performance gains of an average of 9.95% across four downstream tasks, consistently outperforming offline and online RL baselines.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 04:20:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00539</guid></item><item><title>LoHoVLA: A Unified Vision-Language-Action Model for Long-Horizon
  Embodied Tasks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00411</link><description>A unified vision language action framework, LoHoVLA, combines a large pretrained vision language model with hierarchical closed-loop control to improve performance on long-horizon embodied tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Real-world embodied agents face long-horizon tasks, characterized by high-level goals demanding multi-step solutions beyond single actions. Successfully navigating these requires both high-level task planning (i.e., decomposing goals into sub-tasks) and low-level motion control (i.e., generating precise robot actions). While existing vision language action (VLA) models and hierarchical architectures offer potential in embodied tasks, the former often falter in planning, and the latter can suffer from coordination issues, both hampering performance. We introduce a new unified VLA framework for long-horizon tasks, dubbed LoHoVLA, to overcome these limitations. LoHoVLA leverages a large pretrained vision language model (VLM) as the backbone to jointly generate language and action tokens for sub-task generation and robot action prediction, respectively. This shared representation promotes better generalization across tasks. Additionally, LoHoVLA embraces a hierarchical closed-loop control mechanism to mitigate errors originating from both high-level planning and low-level control. To train LoHoVLA, we introduce LoHoSet, a dataset built on the Ravens simulator, containing 20 long-horizon tasks, each with 1,000 expert demonstrations composed of visual observations, linguistic goals, sub-tasks, and robot actions. Experimental results show that LoHoVLA significantly surpasses both hierarchical and standard VLA approaches on long-horizon embodied tasks in the Ravens simulator. These findings underscore the promise of unified architectures for advancing generalizable embodied intelligence.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 05:24:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00411</guid></item><item><title>SmolVLA: A Vision-Language-Action Model for Affordable and Efficient
  Robotics</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01844</link><description>SmolVLA is a compact, efficient vision-language-action model that achieves competitive performance at reduced computational costs and can be deployed on consumer-grade hardware.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-language models (VLMs) pretrained on large-scale multimodal datasets encode rich visual and linguistic knowledge, making them a strong foundation for robotics. Rather than training robotic policies from scratch, recent approaches adapt VLMs into vision-language-action (VLA) models that enable natural language-driven perception and control. However, existing VLAs are typically massive--often with billions of parameters--leading to high training costs and limited real-world deployability. Moreover, they rely on academic and industrial datasets, overlooking the growing availability of community-collected data from affordable robotic platforms. In this work, we present SmolVLA, a small, efficient, and community-driven VLA that drastically reduces both training and inference costs, while retaining competitive performance. SmolVLA is designed to be trained on a single GPU and deployed on consumer-grade GPUs or even CPUs. To further improve responsiveness, we introduce an asynchronous inference stack decoupling perception and action prediction from action execution, allowing higher control rates with chunked action generation. Despite its compact size, SmolVLA achieves performance comparable to VLAs that are 10x larger. We evaluate SmolVLA on a range of both simulated as well as real-world robotic benchmarks and release all code, pretrained models, and training data.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 09:01:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01844</guid></item><item><title>ShapeLLM-Omni: A Native Multimodal LLM for 3D Generation and
  Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01853</link><description>A native 3D large language model, ShapeLLM-Omni, is proposed to understand and generate 3D assets and text, trained using a 3D vector-quantized variational autoencoder and a new 3D-Alpaca dataset.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recently, the powerful text-to-image capabilities of ChatGPT-4o have led to growing appreciation for native multimodal large language models. However, its multimodal capabilities remain confined to images and text. Yet beyond images, the ability to understand and generate 3D content is equally crucial. To address this gap, we propose ShapeLLM-Omni-a native 3D large language model capable of understanding and generating 3D assets and text in any sequence. First, we train a 3D vector-quantized variational autoencoder (VQVAE), which maps 3D objects into a discrete latent space to achieve efficient and accurate shape representation and reconstruction. Building upon the 3D-aware discrete tokens, we innovatively construct a large-scale continuous training dataset named 3D-Alpaca, encompassing generation, comprehension, and editing, thus providing rich resources for future research and training. Finally, by performing instruction-based training of the Qwen-2.5-vl-7B-Instruct model on the 3D-Alpaca dataset. Our work provides an effective attempt at extending multimodal models with basic 3D capabilities, which contributes to future research in 3D-native AI. Project page: https://github.com/JAMESYJL/ShapeLLM-Omni</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 05:27:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01853</guid></item><item><title>Learning Video Generation for Robotic Manipulation with Collaborative
  Trajectory Control</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01943</link><description>A novel framework, RoboMaster, enhances trajectory-controlled video generation for robotic manipulation by modeling inter-object dynamics through a collaborative trajectory formulation, achieving state-of-the-art performance on the Bridge V2 dataset.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in video diffusion models have demonstrated strong potential for generating robotic decision-making data, with trajectory conditions further enabling fine-grained control. However, existing trajectory-based methods primarily focus on individual object motion and struggle to capture multi-object interaction crucial in complex robotic manipulation. This limitation arises from multi-feature entanglement in overlapping regions, which leads to degraded visual fidelity. To address this, we present RoboMaster, a novel framework that models inter-object dynamics through a collaborative trajectory formulation. Unlike prior methods that decompose objects, our core is to decompose the interaction process into three sub-stages: pre-interaction, interaction, and post-interaction. Each stage is modeled using the feature of the dominant object, specifically the robotic arm in the pre- and post-interaction phases and the manipulated object during interaction, thereby mitigating the drawback of multi-object feature fusion present during interaction in prior work. To further ensure subject semantic consistency throughout the video, we incorporate appearance- and shape-aware latent representations for objects. Extensive experiments on the challenging Bridge V2 dataset, as well as in-the-wild evaluation, demonstrate that our method outperforms existing approaches, establishing new state-of-the-art performance in trajectory-controlled video generation for robotic manipulation.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:27:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01943</guid></item><item><title>Temporal In-Context Fine-Tuning for Versatile Control of Video Diffusion
  Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00996</link><description>Temporal In-Context Fine-Tuning (TIC-FT) enhances pretrained video diffusion models for diverse conditional generation tasks with minimal data and without architectural changes.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in text-to-video diffusion models have enabled high-quality video synthesis, but controllable generation remains challenging, particularly under limited data and compute. Existing fine-tuning methods for conditional generation often rely on external encoders or architectural modifications, which demand large datasets and are typically restricted to spatially aligned conditioning, limiting flexibility and scalability. In this work, we introduce Temporal In-Context Fine-Tuning (TIC-FT), an efficient and versatile approach for adapting pretrained video diffusion models to diverse conditional generation tasks. Our key idea is to concatenate condition and target frames along the temporal axis and insert intermediate buffer frames with progressively increasing noise levels. These buffer frames enable smooth transitions, aligning the fine-tuning process with the pretrained model's temporal dynamics. TIC-FT requires no architectural changes and achieves strong performance with as few as 10-30 training samples. We validate our method across a range of tasks, including image-to-video and video-to-video generation, using large-scale base models such as CogVideoX-5B and Wan-14B. Extensive experiments show that TIC-FT outperforms existing baselines in both condition fidelity and visual quality, while remaining highly efficient in both training and inference. For additional results, visit https://kinam0252.github.io/TIC-FT/</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 04:55:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00996</guid></item><item><title>MiCRo: Mixture Modeling and Context-aware Routing for Personalized
  Preference Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24846</link><description>MiCRo, a two-stage framework, improves personalized preference learning for large language models by leveraging binary preference datasets and dynamically adapting mixture weights based on context, effectively capturing diverse human preferences.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reward modeling is a key step in building safe foundation models when applying reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) to align Large Language Models (LLMs). However, reward modeling based on the Bradley-Terry (BT) model assumes a global reward function, failing to capture the inherently diverse and heterogeneous human preferences. Hence, such oversimplification limits LLMs from supporting personalization and pluralistic alignment. Theoretically, we show that when human preferences follow a mixture distribution of diverse subgroups, a single BT model has an irreducible error. While existing solutions, such as multi-objective learning with fine-grained annotations, help address this issue, they are costly and constrained by predefined attributes, failing to fully capture the richness of human values. In this work, we introduce MiCRo, a two-stage framework that enhances personalized preference learning by leveraging large-scale binary preference datasets without requiring explicit fine-grained annotations. In the first stage, MiCRo introduces context-aware mixture modeling approach to capture diverse human preferences. In the second stage, MiCRo integrates an online routing strategy that dynamically adapts mixture weights based on specific context to resolve ambiguity, allowing for efficient and scalable preference adaptation with minimal additional supervision. Experiments on multiple preference datasets demonstrate that MiCRo effectively captures diverse human preferences and significantly improves downstream personalization.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 05:21:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24846</guid></item><item><title>REASONING GYM: Reasoning Environments for Reinforcement Learning with
  Verifiable Rewards</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24760</link><description>Reasoning Gym provides a library of reasoning environments with verifiable rewards and procedural data generation for reinforcement learning, enabling the evaluation and training of reasoning models at varying difficulty levels.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Reasoning Gym (RG), a library of reasoning environments for reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards. It provides over 100 data generators and verifiers spanning multiple domains including algebra, arithmetic, computation, cognition, geometry, graph theory, logic, and various common games. Its key innovation is the ability to generate virtually infinite training data with adjustable complexity, unlike most previous reasoning datasets, which are typically fixed. This procedural generation approach allows for continuous evaluation across varying difficulty levels. Our experimental results demonstrate the efficacy of RG in both evaluating and reinforcement learning of reasoning models.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:32:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24760</guid></item><item><title>AReaL: A Large-Scale Asynchronous Reinforcement Learning System for
  Language Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24298</link><description>AReaL, a fully asynchronous reinforcement learning system, decouples generation and training to achieve higher GPU utilization and up to 2.57x training speedup for large language models on reasoning tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement learning (RL) has become a trending paradigm for training large language models (LLMs), particularly for reasoning tasks. Effective RL for LLMs requires massive parallelization and poses an urgent need for efficient training systems. Most existing large-scale RL systems for LLMs are synchronous by alternating generation and training in a batch setting, where the rollouts in each training batch are generated by the same (or latest) model. This stabilizes RL training but suffers from severe system-level inefficiency. Generation must wait until the longest output in the batch is completed before model update, resulting in GPU underutilization. We present AReaL, a fully asynchronous RL system that completely decouples generation from training. Rollout workers in AReaL continuously generate new outputs without waiting, while training workers update the model whenever a batch of data is collected. AReaL also incorporates a collection of system-level optimizations, leading to substantially higher GPU utilization. To stabilize RL training, AReaL balances the workload of rollout and training workers to control data staleness, and adopts a staleness-enhanced PPO variant to better handle outdated training samples. Extensive experiments on math and code reasoning benchmarks show that AReaL achieves up to 2.57times training speedup compared to the best synchronous systems with the same number of GPUs and matched or even improved final performance. The code of AReaL is available at https://github.com/inclusionAI/AReaL/.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:09:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24298</guid></item><item><title>Cora: Correspondence-aware image editing using few step diffusion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23907</link><description>Cora framework enhances image editing through correspondence-aware noise correction and interpolated attention maps, excelling in structure and texture preservation and generation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Image editing is an important task in computer graphics, vision, and VFX, with recent diffusion-based methods achieving fast and high-quality results. However, edits requiring significant structural changes, such as non-rigid deformations, object modifications, or content generation, remain challenging. Existing few step editing approaches produce artifacts such as irrelevant texture or struggle to preserve key attributes of the source image (e.g., pose). We introduce Cora, a novel editing framework that addresses these limitations by introducing correspondence-aware noise correction and interpolated attention maps. Our method aligns textures and structures between the source and target images through semantic correspondence, enabling accurate texture transfer while generating new content when necessary. Cora offers control over the balance between content generation and preservation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that, quantitatively and qualitatively, Cora excels in maintaining structure, textures, and identity across diverse edits, including pose changes, object addition, and texture refinements. User studies confirm that Cora delivers superior results, outperforming alternatives.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:21:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23907</guid></item><item><title>DyePack: Provably Flagging Test Set Contamination in LLMs Using
  Backdoors</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23001</link><description>DyePack, a framework using backdoor attacks, identifies models that leveraged benchmark test sets during training by introducing benign backdoor samples, ensuring precise false positive rates while preventing false accusations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Open benchmarks are essential for evaluating and advancing large language models, offering reproducibility and transparency. However, their accessibility makes them likely targets of test set contamination. In this work, we introduce DyePack, a framework that leverages backdoor attacks to identify models that used benchmark test sets during training, without requiring access to the loss, logits, or any internal details of the model. Like how banks mix dye packs with their money to mark robbers, DyePack mixes backdoor samples with the test data to flag models that trained on it. We propose a principled design incorporating multiple backdoors with stochastic targets, enabling exact false positive rate (FPR) computation when flagging every model. This provably prevents false accusations while providing strong evidence for every detected case of contamination. We evaluate DyePack on five models across three datasets, covering both multiple-choice and open-ended generation tasks. For multiple-choice questions, it successfully detects all contaminated models with guaranteed FPRs as low as 0.000073% on MMLU-Pro and 0.000017% on Big-Bench-Hard using eight backdoors. For open-ended generation tasks, it generalizes well and identifies all contaminated models on Alpaca with a guaranteed false positive rate of just 0.127% using six backdoors.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 01:46:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23001</guid></item><item><title>Reasoning Like an Economist: Post-Training on Economic Problems Induces
  Strategic Generalization in LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00577</link><description>Post-training techniques such as Supervised Fine-Tuning and Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards improve the reasoning and economic rationality of Large Language Models in multi-agent scenarios through domain-aligned training.  					AI-generated summary 				 Directly training Large Language Models (LLMs) for Multi-Agent Systems (MAS) remains challenging due to intricate reward modeling, dynamic agent interactions, and demanding generalization requirements. This paper explores whether post-training techniques, specifically Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) and Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR), can effectively generalize to multi-agent scenarios. We use economic reasoning as a testbed, leveraging its strong foundations in mathematics and game theory, its demand for structured analytical reasoning, and its relevance to real-world applications such as market design, resource allocation, and policy analysis. We introduce Recon (Reasoning like an ECONomist), a 7B-parameter open-source LLM post-trained on a hand-curated dataset of 2,100 high-quality economic reasoning problems. Comprehensive evaluation on economic reasoning benchmarks and multi-agent games reveals clear improvements in structured reasoning and economic rationality. These results underscore the promise of domain-aligned post-training for enhancing reasoning and agent alignment, shedding light on the roles of SFT and RL in shaping model behavior. Code is available at https://github.com/MasterZhou1/Recon .</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:02:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00577</guid></item><item><title>VisualSphinx: Large-Scale Synthetic Vision Logic Puzzles for RL</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23977</link><description>VisualSphinx provides a large-scale synthetic dataset to improve multimodal reasoning in vision language models, enhancing performance on various logical reasoning tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision language models (VLMs) are expected to perform effective multimodal reasoning and make logically coherent decisions, which is critical to tasks such as diagram understanding and spatial problem solving. However, current VLM reasoning lacks large-scale and well-structured training datasets. To bridge this gap, we propose VisualSphinx, a first-of-its-kind large-scale synthetic visual logical reasoning training data. To tackle the challenge of image synthesis with grounding answers, we propose a rule-to-image synthesis pipeline, which extracts and expands puzzle rules from seed questions and generates the code of grounding synthesis image synthesis for puzzle sample assembly. Experiments demonstrate that VLM trained using GRPO on VisualSphinx benefit from logical coherence and readability of our dataset and exhibit improved performance on logical reasoning tasks. The enhanced reasoning capabilities developed from VisualSphinx also benefit other reasoning tasks such as algebraic reasoning, arithmetic reasoning and geometry reasoning.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 02:38:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23977</guid></item><item><title>From Token to Action: State Machine Reasoning to Mitigate Overthinking
  in Information Retrieval</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23059</link><description>State Machine Reasoning (SMR) improves information retrieval performance and reduces token usage in large language models by addressing overthinking through a discrete action framework.  					AI-generated summary 				 Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting enables complex reasoning in large language models (LLMs), including applications in information retrieval (IR). However, it often leads to overthinking, where models produce excessively long and semantically redundant traces with little or no benefit. We identify two key challenges in IR: redundant trajectories that revisit similar states and misguided reasoning that diverges from user intent. To address these, we propose State Machine Reasoning (SMR), a transition-based reasoning framework composed of discrete actions (Refine, Rerank, Stop) that support early stopping and fine-grained control. Experiments on the BEIR and BRIGHT benchmarks show that SMR improves retrieval performance (nDCG@10) by 3.4% while reducing token usage by 74.4%. It generalizes across LLMs and retrievers without requiring task-specific tuning, offering a practical alternative to conventional CoT reasoning. The code and details are available at https://github.com/ldilab/SMR.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:12:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23059</guid></item><item><title>WHEN TO ACT, WHEN TO WAIT: Modeling Structural Trajectories for Intent
  Triggerability in Task-Oriented Dialogue</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01881</link><description>STORM frameworks facilitates collaborative intent formation in task-oriented dialogue systems by modeling asymmetric information dynamics between UserLLM and AgentLLM.  					AI-generated summary 				 Task-oriented dialogue systems often face difficulties when user utterances seem semantically complete but lack necessary structural information for appropriate system action. This arises because users frequently do not fully understand their own needs, while systems require precise intent definitions. Current LLM-based agents cannot effectively distinguish between linguistically complete and contextually triggerable expressions, lacking frameworks for collaborative intent formation. We present STORM, a framework modeling asymmetric information dynamics through conversations between UserLLM (full internal access) and AgentLLM (observable behavior only). STORM produces annotated corpora capturing expression trajectories and latent cognitive transitions, enabling systematic analysis of collaborative understanding development. Our contributions include: (1) formalizing asymmetric information processing in dialogue systems; (2) modeling intent formation tracking collaborative understanding evolution; and (3) evaluation metrics measuring internal cognitive improvements alongside task performance. Experiments across four language models reveal that moderate uncertainty (40-60%) can outperform complete transparency in certain scenarios, with model-specific patterns suggesting reconsideration of optimal information completeness in human-AI collaboration. These findings contribute to understanding asymmetric reasoning dynamics and inform uncertainty-calibrated dialogue system design.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:08:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01881</guid></item><item><title>EarthMind: Towards Multi-Granular and Multi-Sensor Earth Observation
  with Large Multimodal Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01667</link><description>EarthMind is a vision-language framework that uses spatial attention prompting and cross-modal fusion for efficient multi-granular and multi-sensor Earth Observation data understanding, outperforming larger models on specialized benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) have demonstrated strong performance in various vision-language tasks. However, they often struggle to comprehensively understand Earth Observation (EO) data, which is critical for monitoring the environment and the effects of human activity on it. In this work, we present EarthMind, a novel vision-language framework for multi-granular and multi-sensor EO data understanding. EarthMind features two core components: (1) Spatial Attention Prompting (SAP), which reallocates attention within the LLM to enhance pixel-level understanding; and (2) Cross-modal Fusion, which aligns heterogeneous modalities into a shared space and adaptively reweighs tokens based on their information density for effective fusion. To facilitate multi-sensor fusion evaluation, we propose EarthMind-Bench, a comprehensive benchmark with over 2,000 human-annotated multi-sensor image-question pairs, covering a wide range of perception and reasoning tasks. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of EarthMind. It achieves state-of-the-art performance on EarthMind-Bench, surpassing GPT-4o despite being only 4B in scale. Moreover, EarthMind outperforms existing methods on multiple public EO benchmarks, showcasing its potential to handle both multi-granular and multi-sensor challenges in a unified framework.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:56:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01667</guid></item><item><title>Learning from Videos for 3D World: Enhancing MLLMs with 3D Vision
  Geometry Priors</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24625</link><description>A novel Video-3D Geometry Large Language Model (VG LLM) extracts 3D information directly from video sequences to enhance 3D scene understanding without additional 3D data, achieving competitive results in various tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Previous research has investigated the application of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) in understanding 3D scenes by interpreting them as videos. These approaches generally depend on comprehensive 3D data inputs, such as point clouds or reconstructed Bird's-Eye View (BEV) maps. In our research, we advance this field by enhancing the capability of MLLMs to understand and reason in 3D spaces directly from video data, without the need for additional 3D input. We propose a novel and efficient method, the Video-3D Geometry Large Language Model (VG LLM). Our approach employs a 3D visual geometry encoder that extracts 3D prior information from video sequences. This information is integrated with visual tokens and fed into the MLLM. Extensive experiments have shown that our method has achieved substantial improvements in various tasks related to 3D scene understanding and spatial reasoning, all directly learned from video sources. Impressively, our 4B model, which does not rely on explicit 3D data inputs, achieves competitive results compared to existing state-of-the-art methods, and even surpasses the Gemini-1.5-Pro in the VSI-Bench evaluations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 01:54:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24625</guid></item><item><title>Incentivizing Reasoning for Advanced Instruction-Following of Large
  Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01413</link><description>A method is proposed to enhance large language models in handling complex instructions through incentivized reasoning and reinforcement learning, improving performance and reducing computational load.  					AI-generated summary 				 Existing large language models (LLMs) face challenges of following complex instructions, especially when multiple constraints are present and organized in paralleling, chaining, and branching structures. One intuitive solution, namely chain-of-thought (CoT), is expected to universally improve capabilities of LLMs. However, we find that the vanilla CoT exerts a negative impact on performance due to its superficial reasoning pattern of simply paraphrasing the instructions. It fails to peel back the compositions of constraints for identifying their relationship across hierarchies of types and dimensions. To this end, we propose a systematic method to boost LLMs in dealing with complex instructions via incentivizing reasoning for test-time compute scaling. First, we stem from the decomposition of complex instructions under existing taxonomies and propose a reproducible data acquisition method. Second, we exploit reinforcement learning (RL) with verifiable rule-centric reward signals to cultivate reasoning specifically for instruction following. We address the shallow, non-essential nature of reasoning under complex instructions via sample-wise contrast for superior CoT enforcement. We also exploit behavior cloning of experts to facilitate steady distribution shift from fast-thinking LLMs to skillful reasoners. Extensive evaluations on seven comprehensive benchmarks confirm the validity of the proposed method, where a 1.5B LLM achieves 11.74% gains with performance comparable to a 8B LLM. Codes and data are available at https://github.com/yuleiqin/RAIF.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:36:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01413</guid></item><item><title>Stepsize anything: A unified learning rate schedule for
  budgeted-iteration training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24452</link><description>A unified budget-aware learning rate schedule is proposed to optimize training within limited iteration budgets, outperforming traditional schedules across various tasks and network architectures.  					AI-generated summary 				 The expanding computational costs and limited resources underscore the critical need for budgeted-iteration training, which aims to achieve optimal learning within predetermined iteration budgets.While learning rate schedules fundamentally govern the performance of different networks and tasks, particularly in budgeted-iteration scenarios, their design remains largely heuristic, lacking theoretical foundations.In addition, the optimal learning rate schedule requires extensive trial-and-error selection, making the training process inefficient.In this work, we propose the Unified Budget-Aware (UBA) schedule, a theoretically grounded learning rate schedule that consistently outperforms commonly-used schedules among diverse architectures and tasks under different constrained training budgets.First, we bridge the gap by constructing a novel training budget-aware optimization framework, which explicitly accounts for the robustness to landscape curvature variations.From this framework, we derive the UBA schedule, controlled by a single hyper-parameter varphi that provides a trade-off between flexibility and simplicity, eliminating the need for per-network numerical optimization. Moreover, we establish a theoretical connection between varphi and the condition number, adding interpretation and justification to our approach. Besides, we prove the convergence for different values of varphi.We offer practical guidelines for its selection via theoretical analysis and empirical results.xtensive experimental results show that UBA consistently surpasses the commonly-used schedules across diverse vision and language tasks, spanning network architectures (e.g., ResNet, OLMo) and scales, under different training-iteration budgets.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 06:02:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24452</guid></item><item><title>OWSM v4: Improving Open Whisper-Style Speech Models via Data Scaling and
  Cleaning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00338</link><description>The OWSM project is enhanced with a large-scale, cleaned web dataset, leading to improved multilingual speech models comparable to leading industrial models.  					AI-generated summary 				 The Open Whisper-style Speech Models (OWSM) project has developed a series of fully open speech foundation models using academic-scale resources, but their training data remains insufficient. This work enhances OWSM by integrating YODAS, a large-scale web-crawled dataset with a Creative Commons license. However, incorporating YODAS is nontrivial due to its wild nature, which introduces challenges such as incorrect language labels and audio-text misalignments. To address this, we develop a scalable data-cleaning pipeline using public toolkits, yielding a dataset with 166,000 hours of speech across 75 languages. Our new series of OWSM v4 models, trained on this curated dataset alongside existing OWSM data, significantly outperform previous versions on multilingual benchmarks. Our models even match or surpass frontier industrial models like Whisper and MMS in multiple scenarios. We will publicly release the cleaned YODAS data, pre-trained models, and all associated scripts via the ESPnet toolkit.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 03:09:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00338</guid></item><item><title>CodeV-R1: Reasoning-Enhanced Verilog Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24183</link><description>CodeV-R1, an RLVR framework for Verilog generation, achieves state-of-the-art performance in EDA using a rule-based testbench, round-trip data synthesis, and adaptive RLVR training.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) trained via reinforcement learning with verifiable reward (RLVR) have achieved breakthroughs on tasks with explicit, automatable verification, such as software programming and mathematical problems. Extending RLVR to electronic design automation (EDA), especially automatically generating hardware description languages (HDLs) like Verilog from natural-language (NL) specifications, however, poses three key challenges: the lack of automated and accurate verification environments, the scarcity of high-quality NL-code pairs, and the prohibitive computation cost of RLVR. To this end, we introduce CodeV-R1, an RLVR framework for training Verilog generation LLMs. First, we develop a rule-based testbench generator that performs robust equivalence checking against golden references. Second, we propose a round-trip data synthesis method that pairs open-source Verilog snippets with LLM-generated NL descriptions, verifies code-NL-code consistency via the generated testbench, and filters out inequivalent examples to yield a high-quality dataset. Third, we employ a two-stage "distill-then-RL" training pipeline: distillation for the cold start of reasoning abilities, followed by adaptive DAPO, our novel RLVR algorithm that can reduce training cost by adaptively adjusting sampling rate. The resulting model, CodeV-R1-7B, achieves 68.6% and 72.9% pass@1 on VerilogEval v2 and RTLLM v1.1, respectively, surpassing prior state-of-the-art by 12~20%, while matching or even exceeding the performance of 671B DeepSeek-R1. We will release our model, training pipeline, and dataset to facilitate research in EDA and LLM communities.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:28:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24183</guid></item><item><title>VAU-R1: Advancing Video Anomaly Understanding via Reinforcement
  Fine-Tuning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23504</link><description>VAU-R1 uses Multimodal Large Language Models with Reinforcement Fine-Tuning to enhance video anomaly reasoning, complemented by VAU-Bench, a Chain-of-Thought benchmark for evaluating anomaly understanding.  					AI-generated summary 				 Video Anomaly Understanding (VAU) is essential for applications such as smart cities, security surveillance, and disaster alert systems, yet remains challenging due to its demand for fine-grained spatio-temporal perception and robust reasoning under ambiguity. Despite advances in anomaly detection, existing methods often lack interpretability and struggle to capture the causal and contextual aspects of abnormal events. This limitation is further compounded by the absence of comprehensive benchmarks for evaluating reasoning ability in anomaly scenarios. To address both challenges, we introduce VAU-R1, a data-efficient framework built upon Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs), which enhances anomaly reasoning through Reinforcement Fine-Tuning (RFT). Besides, we propose VAU-Bench, the first Chain-of-Thought benchmark tailored for video anomaly reasoning, featuring multiple-choice QA, detailed rationales, temporal annotations, and descriptive captions. Empirical results show that VAU-R1 significantly improves question answering accuracy, temporal grounding, and reasoning coherence across diverse contexts. Together, our method and benchmark establish a strong foundation for interpretable and reasoning-aware video anomaly understanding. Our code is available at https://github.com/GVCLab/VAU-R1.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 01:31:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.23504</guid></item><item><title>zip2zip: Inference-Time Adaptive Vocabularies for Language Models via
  Token Compression</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01084</link><description>A framework called zip2zip dynamically adjusts token vocabulary in LLMs at inference time using LZW compression, reducing token sequence length and improving inference speed.  					AI-generated summary 				 Tokenization efficiency plays a critical role in the performance and cost of large language models (LLMs), yet most models rely on static tokenizers optimized for general-purpose corpora. These tokenizers' fixed vocabularies often fail to adapt to domain- or language-specific inputs, leading to longer token sequences and higher computational costs. We introduce zip2zip, a framework that enables LLMs to dynamically adjust token vocabulary at inference time, allowing for fewer generated tokens and thus faster inference. zip2zip consists of three key components: (1) a tokenizer based on Lempel-Ziv-Welch (LZW) compression that incrementally compresses tokens into reusable "hypertokens" on the fly; (2) an embedding layer that computes embeddings for newly formed hypertokens at runtime; and (3) a causal language modeling variant that trains the model to operate on hypertokenized, compressed sequences. We show that an existing LLM can be zip2zip-fied in 10 GPU-hours via parameter-efficient finetuning. The resulting zip2zip LLMs effectively learn to use hypertokens at inference time, reducing input and output sequence length by 20-60\%, with significant improvements in inference latency.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:35:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01084</guid></item><item><title>SATA-BENCH: Select All That Apply Benchmark for Multiple Choice
  Questions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00643</link><description>SATA-BENCH evaluates LLMs on multi-answer questions, revealing selections biases and proposing Choice Funnel to improve accuracy and reduce costs in multi-answer reasoning tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly evaluated on single-answer multiple-choice tasks, yet many real-world problems require identifying all correct answers from a set of options. This capability remains underexplored. We introduce SATA-BENCH, the first dedicated benchmark for evaluating LLMs on Select All That Apply (SATA) questions across diverse domains, including reading comprehension, law, and biomedicine. Our evaluation of 27 open-source and proprietary models reveals a significant gap: even the strongest model achieves only 41.8% exact match, exposing LLMs' inability to reliably identify all correct answers. We find that this weakness stems from two core challenges: selection bias - models favor certain choices regardless of content, and count bias - models fail to predict the correct number of answers. To address these issues, we propose Choice Funnel, a decoding strategy that combines token debiasing with adaptive thresholding to guide models toward complete and accurate selections. Choice Funnel achieves up to 29% higher exact match than competitive baselines while reducing inference cost by over 64%. Our findings expose fundamental limitations in current LLMs and introduce a new framework for diagnosing and improving multi-answer reasoning. We release SATA-BENCH and Choice Funnel to promote LLM development for robust decision-making in realistic, multi-answer applications.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 02:52:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00643</guid></item><item><title>Cascading Adversarial Bias from Injection to Distillation in Language
  Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24842</link><description>Adversarial injection of biased content can significantly propagate from teacher to student models during distillation, leading to frequent biased responses in both targeted and untargeted scenarios across various bias types and modalities.  					AI-generated summary 				 Model distillation has become essential for creating smaller, deployable language models that retain larger system capabilities. However, widespread deployment raises concerns about resilience to adversarial manipulation. This paper investigates vulnerability of distilled models to adversarial injection of biased content during training. We demonstrate that adversaries can inject subtle biases into teacher models through minimal data poisoning, which propagates to student models and becomes significantly amplified. We propose two propagation modes: Untargeted Propagation, where bias affects multiple tasks, and Targeted Propagation, focusing on specific tasks while maintaining normal behavior elsewhere. With only 25 poisoned samples (0.25% poisoning rate), student models generate biased responses 76.9% of the time in targeted scenarios - higher than 69.4% in teacher models. For untargeted propagation, adversarial bias appears 6x-29x more frequently in student models on unseen tasks. We validate findings across six bias types (targeted advertisements, phishing links, narrative manipulations, insecure coding practices), various distillation methods, and different modalities spanning text and code generation. Our evaluation reveals shortcomings in current defenses - perplexity filtering, bias detection systems, and LLM-based autorater frameworks - against these attacks. Results expose significant security vulnerabilities in distilled models, highlighting need for specialized safeguards. We propose practical design principles for building effective adversarial bias mitigation strategies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:05:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24842</guid></item><item><title>Pro3D-Editor : A Progressive-Views Perspective for Consistent and
  Precise 3D Editing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00512</link><description>A progressive-views paradigm with Pro3D-Editor achieves consistent 3D editing by propagating semantics from key views to less edited ones.  					AI-generated summary 				 Text-guided 3D editing aims to precisely edit semantically relevant local 3D regions, which has significant potential for various practical applications ranging from 3D games to film production. Existing methods typically follow a view-indiscriminate paradigm: editing 2D views indiscriminately and projecting them back into 3D space. However, they overlook the different cross-view interdependencies, resulting in inconsistent multi-view editing. In this study, we argue that ideal consistent 3D editing can be achieved through a progressive-views paradigm, which propagates editing semantics from the editing-salient view to other editing-sparse views. Specifically, we propose Pro3D-Editor, a novel framework, which mainly includes Primary-view Sampler, Key-view Render, and Full-view Refiner. Primary-view Sampler dynamically samples and edits the most editing-salient view as the primary view. Key-view Render accurately propagates editing semantics from the primary view to other key views through its Mixture-of-View-Experts Low-Rank Adaption (MoVE-LoRA). Full-view Refiner edits and refines the 3D object based on the edited multi-views. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method outperforms existing methods in editing accuracy and spatial consistency.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 08:41:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00512</guid></item><item><title>MagiCodec: Simple Masked Gaussian-Injected Codec for High-Fidelity
  Reconstruction and Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00385</link><description>MagiCodec, a Transformer-based audio codec, enhances semantic tokenization while maintaining high reconstruction quality, improving compatibility with generative models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Neural audio codecs have made significant strides in efficiently mapping raw audio waveforms into discrete token representations, which are foundational for contemporary audio generative models. However, most existing codecs are optimized primarily for reconstruction quality, often at the expense of the downstream modelability of the encoded tokens. Motivated by the need to overcome this bottleneck, we introduce MagiCodec, a novel single-layer, streaming Transformer-based audio codec. MagiCodec is designed with a multistage training pipeline that incorporates Gaussian noise injection and latent regularization, explicitly targeting the enhancement of semantic expressiveness in the generated codes while preserving high reconstruction fidelity. We analytically derive the effect of noise injection in the frequency domain, demonstrating its efficacy in attenuating high-frequency components and fostering robust tokenization. Extensive experimental evaluations show that MagiCodec surpasses state-of-the-art codecs in both reconstruction quality and downstream tasks. Notably, the tokens produced by MagiCodec exhibit Zipf-like distributions, as observed in natural languages, thereby improving compatibility with language-model-based generative architectures. The code and pre-trained models are available at https://github.com/Ereboas/MagiCodec.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 05:58:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00385</guid></item><item><title>ComposeAnything: Composite Object Priors for Text-to-Image Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24086</link><description>Generating images from text involving complex and novel object arrangements remains a significant challenge for current text-to-image (T2I) models. Although prior layout-based methods improve object arrangements using spatial constraints with 2D layouts, they often struggle to capture 3D positioning and sacrifice quality and coherence. In this work, we introduce ComposeAnything, a novel framework for improving compositional image generation without retraining existing T2I models. Our approach first leverages the chain-of-thought reasoning abilities of LLMs to produce 2.5D semantic layouts from text, consisting of 2D object bounding boxes enriched with depth information and detailed captions. Based on this layout, we generate a spatial and depth aware coarse composite of objects that captures the intended composition, serving as a strong and interpretable prior that replaces stochastic noise initialization in diffusion-based T2I models. This prior guides the denoising process through object prior reinforcement and spatial-controlled denoising, enabling seamless generation of compositional objects and coherent backgrounds, while allowing refinement of inaccurate priors. ComposeAnything outperforms state-of-the-art methods on the T2I-CompBench and NSR-1K benchmarks for prompts with 2D/3D spatial arrangements, high object counts, and surreal compositions. Human evaluations further demonstrate that our model generates high-quality images with compositions that faithfully reflect the text.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 09:23:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.24086</guid></item><item><title>Think Again! The Effect of Test-Time Compute on Preferences, Opinions,
  and Beliefs of Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19621</link><description>The Preference, Opinion, and Belief survey assesses the subjective tendencies and biases of Large Language Models across various domains and highlights a trend of increased bias in newer model versions.  					AI-generated summary 				 As Large Language Models (LLMs) become deeply integrated into human life and increasingly influence decision-making, it's crucial to evaluate whether and to what extent they exhibit subjective preferences, opinions, and beliefs. These tendencies may stem from biases within the models, which may shape their behavior, influence the advice and recommendations they offer to users, and potentially reinforce certain viewpoints. This paper presents the Preference, Opinion, and Belief survey (POBs), a benchmark developed to assess LLMs' subjective inclinations across societal, cultural, ethical, and personal domains. We applied our benchmark to evaluate leading open- and closed-source LLMs, measuring desired properties such as reliability, neutrality, and consistency. In addition, we investigated the effect of increasing the test-time compute, through reasoning and self-reflection mechanisms, on those metrics. While effective in other tasks, our results show that these mechanisms offer only limited gains in our domain. Furthermore, we reveal that newer model versions are becoming less consistent and more biased toward specific viewpoints, highlighting a blind spot and a concerning trend. POBS: https://ibm.github.io/POBS</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:43:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2505.19621</guid></item><item><title>WebChoreArena: Evaluating Web Browsing Agents on Realistic Tedious Web
  Tasks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01952</link><description>Powered by a large language model (LLM), a web browsing agent operates web browsers in a human-like manner and offers a highly transparent path toward automating a wide range of everyday tasks. As web agents become increasingly capable and demonstrate proficiency in general browsing tasks, a critical question emerges: Can they go beyond general browsing to robustly handle tasks that are tedious and complex, or chores that humans often avoid doing themselves? In this paper, we introduce WebChoreArena, a new fully reproducible benchmark comprising 532 carefully curated tasks designed to extend the scope of WebArena beyond general browsing to more labor-intensive and tedious tasks. WebChoreArena systematically integrates three key challenges: (i) Massive Memory tasks requiring accurate retrieval of large amounts of information in the observations, (ii) Calculation tasks demanding precise mathematical reasoning, and (iii) Long-Term Memory tasks necessitating long-term memory across multiple webpages. Built on top of the fully reproducible and widely adopted four WebArena simulation environments, WebChoreArena ensures strict reproducibility and enables fair, direct comparisons with the established WebArena benchmark, offering key insights into agent progress. Our experimental results demonstrate that as LLMs evolve, represented by GPT-4o, Claude 3.7 Sonnet, and Gemini 2.5 Pro, significant improvements in performance are observed on WebChoreArena. These findings suggest that WebChoreArena is well-suited to measure the advancement of state-of-the-art LLMs with greater clarity. Nevertheless, the results also indicate that even with Gemini 2.5 Pro, there remains substantial room for improvement compared to WebArena, highlighting the increased challenges posed by WebChoreArena.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 09:22:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.01952</guid></item><item><title>Massively Multilingual Adaptation of Large Language Models Using
  Bilingual Translation Data</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00469</link><description>Bilingual translation data enhances language transfer and performance in massively multilingual language adaptation of the Llama3 family of models.  					AI-generated summary 				 This paper investigates a critical design decision in the practice of massively multilingual continual pre-training -- the inclusion of parallel data. Specifically, we study the impact of bilingual translation data for massively multilingual language adaptation of the Llama3 family of models to 500 languages. To this end, we construct the MaLA bilingual translation corpus, containing data from more than 2,500 language pairs. Subsequently, we develop the EMMA-500 Llama 3 suite of four massively multilingual models -- continually pre-trained from the Llama 3 family of base models extensively on diverse data mixes up to 671B tokens -- and explore the effect of continual pre-training with or without bilingual translation data. Comprehensive evaluation across 7 tasks and 12 benchmarks demonstrates that bilingual data tends to enhance language transfer and performance, particularly for low-resource languages. We open-source the MaLA corpus, EMMA-500 Llama 3 suite artefacts, code, and model generations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:13:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.00469</guid></item></channel></rss>