<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>DEER: Draft with Diffusion, Verify with Autoregressive Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15176</link><description>DEER framework uses diffusion large language models for efficient speculative decoding, overcoming the limitations of autoregressive drafters with better speed and draft quality.  					AI-generated summary 				 Efficiency, as a critical practical challenge for LLM-driven agentic and reasoning systems, is increasingly constrained by the inherent latency of autoregressive (AR) decoding. Speculative decoding mitigates this cost through a draft-verify scheme, yet existing approaches rely on AR draft models (a.k.a., drafters), which introduce two fundamental issues: (1) step-wise uncertainty accumulation leads to a progressive collapse of trust between the target model and the drafter, and (2) inherently sequential decoding of AR drafters. Together, these factors cause limited speedups. In this paper, we show that a diffusion large language model (dLLM) drafters can naturally overcome these issues through its fundamentally different probabilistic modeling and efficient parallel decoding strategy. Building on this insight, we introduce DEER, an efficient speculative decoding framework that drafts with diffusion and verifies with AR models. To enable high-quality drafting, DEER employs a two-stage training pipeline to align the dLLM-based drafters with the target AR model, and further adopts single-step decoding to generate long draft segments. Experiments show DEER reaches draft acceptance lengths of up to 32 tokens, far surpassing the 10 tokens achieved by EAGLE-3. Moreover, on HumanEval with Qwen3-30B-A3B, DEER attains a 5.54x speedup, while EAGLE-3 achieves only 2.41x. Code, model, demo, etc, will be available at https://czc726.github.io/DEER/</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:14:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15176</guid></item><item><title>Fast and Accurate Causal Parallel Decoding using Jacobi Forcing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14681</link><description>Jacobi Forcing is a progressive distillation method that enables efficient parallel decoding of transformer-based models while maintaining performance, significantly reducing inference latency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multi-token generation has emerged as a promising paradigm for accelerating transformer-based large model inference. Recent efforts primarily explore diffusion Large Language Models (dLLMs) for parallel decoding to reduce inference latency. To achieve AR-level generation quality, many techniques adapt AR models into dLLMs to enable parallel decoding. However, they suffer from limited speedup compared to AR models due to a pretrain-to-posttrain mismatch. Specifically, the masked data distribution in post-training deviates significantly from the real-world data distribution seen during pretraining, and dLLMs rely on bidirectional attention, which conflicts with the causal prior learned during pretraining and hinders the integration of exact KV cache reuse. To address this, we introduce Jacobi Forcing, a progressive distillation paradigm where models are trained on their own generated parallel decoding trajectories, smoothly shifting AR models into efficient parallel decoders while preserving their pretrained causal inference property. The models trained under this paradigm, Jacobi Forcing Model, achieves 3.8x wall-clock speedup on coding and math benchmarks with minimal loss in performance. Based on Jacobi Forcing Models' trajectory characteristics, we introduce multi-block decoding with rejection recycling, which enables up to 4.5x higher token acceptance count per iteration and nearly 4.0x wall-clock speedup, effectively trading additional compute for lower inference latency. Our code is available at https://github.com/hao-ai-lab/JacobiForcing.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:27:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14681</guid></item><item><title>HyperVL: An Efficient and Dynamic Multimodal Large Language Model for Edge Devices</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14052</link><description>HyperVL, an efficient multimodal large language model for on-device inference, uses image tiling, Visual Resolution Compressor, and Dual Consistency Learning to reduce memory usage, latency, and power consumption while maintaining performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Current multimodal large lanauge models possess strong perceptual and reasoning capabilities, however high computational and memory requirements make them difficult to deploy directly on on-device environments. While small-parameter models are progressively endowed with strong general capabilities, standard Vision Transformer (ViT) encoders remain a critical bottleneck, suffering from excessive latency and memory consumption when processing high-resolution inputs.To address these challenges, we introduce HyperVL, an efficient multimodal large language model tailored for on-device inference. HyperVL adopts an image-tiling strategy to cap peak memory usage and incorporates two novel techniques: (1) a Visual Resolution Compressor (VRC) that adaptively predicts optimal encoding resolutions to eliminate redundant computation, and (2) Dual Consistency Learning (DCL), which aligns multi-scale ViT encoders within a unified framework, enabling dynamic switching between visual branches under a shared LLM. Extensive experiments demonstrate that HyperVL achieves state-of-the-art performance among models of comparable size across multiple benchmarks. Furthermore, it significantly significantly reduces latency and power consumption on real mobile devices, demonstrating its practicality for on-device multimodal inference.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:04:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14052</guid></item><item><title>Skyra: AI-Generated Video Detection via Grounded Artifact Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15693</link><description>Skyra, a specialized multimodal large language model, detects and explains visual artifacts in AI-generated videos using a novel dataset and two-stage training strategy, outperforming existing methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 The misuse of AI-driven video generation technologies has raised serious social concerns, highlighting the urgent need for reliable AI-generated video detectors. However, most existing methods are limited to binary classification and lack the necessary explanations for human interpretation. In this paper, we present Skyra, a specialized multimodal large language model (MLLM) that identifies human-perceivable visual artifacts in AI-generated videos and leverages them as grounded evidence for both detection and explanation. To support this objective, we construct ViF-CoT-4K for Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT), which represents the first large-scale AI-generated video artifact dataset with fine-grained human annotations. We then develop a two-stage training strategy that systematically enhances our model's spatio-temporal artifact perception, explanation capability, and detection accuracy. To comprehensively evaluate Skyra, we introduce ViF-Bench, a benchmark comprising 3K high-quality samples generated by over ten state-of-the-art video generators. Extensive experiments demonstrate that Skyra surpasses existing methods across multiple benchmarks, while our evaluation yields valuable insights for advancing explainable AI-generated video detection.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:01:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15693</guid></item><item><title>Universal Reasoning Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14693</link><description>The Universal Reasoning Model enhances Universal Transformers with short convolution and truncated backpropagation to improve reasoning performance on ARC-AGI tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Universal transformers (UTs) have been widely used for complex reasoning tasks such as ARC-AGI and Sudoku, yet the specific sources of their performance gains remain underexplored. In this work, we systematically analyze UTs variants and show that improvements on ARC-AGI primarily arise from the recurrent inductive bias and strong nonlinear components of Transformer, rather than from elaborate architectural designs. Motivated by this finding, we propose the Universal Reasoning Model (URM), which enhances the UT with short convolution and truncated backpropagation. Our approach substantially improves reasoning performance, achieving state-of-the-art 53.8% pass@1 on ARC-AGI 1 and 16.0% pass@1 on ARC-AGI 2. Our code is avaliable at https://github.com/zitian-gao/URM.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:52:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14693</guid></item><item><title>IC-Effect: Precise and Efficient Video Effects Editing via In-Context Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15635</link><description>IC-Effect, an instruction-guided DiT-based framework, synthesizes complex video VFX effects while preserving spatial and temporal consistency using a two-stage training strategy and spatiotemporal sparse tokenization.  					AI-generated summary 				 We propose IC-Effect, an instruction-guided, DiT-based framework for few-shot video VFX editing that synthesizes complex effects (\eg flames, particles and cartoon characters) while strictly preserving spatial and temporal consistency. Video VFX editing is highly challenging because injected effects must blend seamlessly with the background, the background must remain entirely unchanged, and effect patterns must be learned efficiently from limited paired data. However, existing video editing models fail to satisfy these requirements. IC-Effect leverages the source video as clean contextual conditions, exploiting the contextual learning capability of DiT models to achieve precise background preservation and natural effect injection. A two-stage training strategy, consisting of general editing adaptation followed by effect-specific learning via Effect-LoRA, ensures strong instruction following and robust effect modeling. To further improve efficiency, we introduce spatiotemporal sparse tokenization, enabling high fidelity with substantially reduced computation. We also release a paired VFX editing dataset spanning 15 high-quality visual styles. Extensive experiments show that IC-Effect delivers high-quality, controllable, and temporally consistent VFX editing, opening new possibilities for video creation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:31:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15635</guid></item><item><title>Can LLMs Guide Their Own Exploration? Gradient-Guided Reinforcement Learning for LLM Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15687</link><description>G2RL, a gradient-guided reinforcement learning framework, enhances exploration in large language models by leveraging the model's own update geometry, leading to improved performance on various reasoning benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement learning has become essential for strengthening the reasoning abilities of large language models, yet current exploration mechanisms remain fundamentally misaligned with how these models actually learn. Entropy bonuses and external semantic comparators encourage surface level variation but offer no guarantee that sampled trajectories differ in the update directions that shape optimization. We propose G2RL, a gradient guided reinforcement learning framework in which exploration is driven not by external heuristics but by the model own first order update geometry. For each response, G2RL constructs a sequence level feature from the model final layer sensitivity, obtainable at negligible cost from a standard forward pass, and measures how each trajectory would reshape the policy by comparing these features within a sampled group. Trajectories that introduce novel gradient directions receive a bounded multiplicative reward scaler, while redundant or off manifold updates are deemphasized, yielding a self referential exploration signal that is naturally aligned with PPO style stability and KL control. Across math and general reasoning benchmarks (MATH500, AMC, AIME24, AIME25, GPQA, MMLUpro) on Qwen3 base 1.7B and 4B models, G2RL consistently improves pass@1, maj@16, and pass@k over entropy based GRPO and external embedding methods. Analyzing the induced geometry, we find that G2RL expands exploration into substantially more orthogonal and often opposing gradient directions while maintaining semantic coherence, revealing that a policy own update space provides a far more faithful and effective basis for guiding exploration in large language model reinforcement learning.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:52:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15687</guid></item><item><title>Robust and Calibrated Detection of Authentic Multimedia Content</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15182</link><description>A resynthesis framework enhances deepfake detection by verifying authenticity with low false positive rates and robustness against efficient adversaries, supporting multiple modalities.  					AI-generated summary 				 Generative models can synthesize highly realistic content, so-called deepfakes, that are already being misused at scale to undermine digital media authenticity. Current deepfake detection methods are unreliable for two reasons: (i) distinguishing inauthentic content post-hoc is often impossible (e.g., with memorized samples), leading to an unbounded false positive rate (FPR); and (ii) detection lacks robustness, as adversaries can adapt to known detectors with near-perfect accuracy using minimal computational resources. To address these limitations, we propose a resynthesis framework to determine if a sample is authentic or if its authenticity can be plausibly denied. We make two key contributions focusing on the high-precision, low-recall setting against efficient (i.e., compute-restricted) adversaries. First, we demonstrate that our calibrated resynthesis method is the most reliable approach for verifying authentic samples while maintaining controllable, low FPRs. Second, we show that our method achieves adversarial robustness against efficient adversaries, whereas prior methods are easily evaded under identical compute budgets. Our approach supports multiple modalities and leverages state-of-the-art inversion techniques.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:50:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15182</guid></item><item><title>MMSI-Video-Bench: A Holistic Benchmark for Video-Based Spatial Intelligence</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.10863</link><description>MMSI-Video-Bench is a comprehensive benchmark for video-based spatial intelligence in MLLMs, revealing significant gaps between human and AI performance and highlighting challenges in geometric reasoning, motion grounding, and cross-video correspondence.  					AI-generated summary 				 Spatial understanding over continuous visual input is crucial for MLLMs to evolve into general-purpose assistants in physical environments. Yet there is still no comprehensive benchmark that holistically assesses the progress toward this goal. In this work, we introduce MMSI-Video-Bench, a fully human-annotated benchmark for video-based spatial intelligence in MLLMs. It operationalizes a four-level framework, Perception, Planning, Prediction, and Cross-Video Reasoning, through 1,106 questions grounded in 1,278 clips from 25 datasets and in-house videos. Each item is carefully designed and reviewed by 3DV experts with explanatory rationales to ensure precise, unambiguous grounding. Leveraging its diverse data sources and holistic task coverage, MMSI-Video-Bench also supports three domain-oriented sub-benchmarks (Indoor Scene Perception Bench, Robot Bench and Grounding Bench) for targeted capability assessment. We evaluate 25 strong open-source and proprietary MLLMs, revealing a striking human--AI gap: many models perform near chance, and the best reasoning model lags humans by nearly 60%. We further find that spatially fine-tuned models still fail to generalize effectively on our benchmark. Fine-grained error analysis exposes systematic failures in geometric reasoning, motion grounding, long-horizon prediction, and cross-video correspondence. We also show that typical frame-sampling strategies transfer poorly to our reasoning-intensive benchmark, and that neither 3D spatial cues nor chain-of-thought prompting yields meaningful gains. We expect our benchmark to establish a solid testbed for advancing video-based spatial intelligence.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:21:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.10863</guid></item><item><title>Step-GUI Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15431</link><description>A self-evolving training pipeline with the Calibrated Step Reward System and GUI-MCP protocol improve GUI automation efficiency, accuracy, and privacy in real-world scenarios.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in multimodal large language models unlock unprecedented opportunities for GUI automation. However, a fundamental challenge remains: how to efficiently acquire high-quality training data while maintaining annotation reliability? We introduce a self-evolving training pipeline powered by the Calibrated Step Reward System, which converts model-generated trajectories into reliable training signals through trajectory-level calibration, achieving &gt;90% annotation accuracy with 10-100x lower cost. Leveraging this pipeline, we introduce Step-GUI, a family of models (4B/8B) that achieves state-of-the-art GUI performance (8B: 80.2% AndroidWorld, 48.5% OSWorld, 62.6% ScreenShot-Pro) while maintaining robust general capabilities. As GUI agent capabilities improve, practical deployment demands standardized interfaces across heterogeneous devices while protecting user privacy. To this end, we propose GUI-MCP, the first Model Context Protocol for GUI automation with hierarchical architecture that combines low-level atomic operations and high-level task delegation to local specialist models, enabling high-privacy execution where sensitive data stays on-device. Finally, to assess whether agents can handle authentic everyday usage, we introduce AndroidDaily, a benchmark grounded in real-world mobile usage patterns with 3146 static actions and 235 end-to-end tasks across high-frequency daily scenarios (8B: static 89.91%, end-to-end 52.50%). Our work advances the development of practical GUI agents and demonstrates strong potential for real-world deployment in everyday digital interactions.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:25:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15431</guid></item><item><title>DiffusionVL: Translating Any Autoregressive Models into Diffusion Vision Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15713</link><description>DiffusionVL, a family of diffusion vision language models derived from autoregressive models through fine-tuning, achieves performance improvements and faster inference speeds compared to existing models.  					AI-generated summary 				 In recent multimodal research, the diffusion paradigm has emerged as a promising alternative to the autoregressive paradigm (AR), owing to its unique decoding advantages. However, due to the capability limitations of the base diffusion language model, the performance of the diffusion vision language model (dVLM) still lags significantly behind that of mainstream models. This leads to a simple yet fundamental question: Is it possible to construct dVLMs based on existing powerful AR models? In response, we propose DiffusionVL, a dVLM family that could be translated from any powerful AR models. Through simple fine-tuning, we successfully adapt AR pre-trained models into the diffusion paradigm. This approach yields two key observations: (1) The paradigm shift from AR-based multimodal models to diffusion is remarkably effective. (2) Direct conversion of an AR language model to a dVLM is also feasible, achieving performance competitive with LLaVA-style visual-instruction-tuning. Further, we introduce a block-decoding design into dVLMs that supports arbitrary-length generation and KV cache reuse, achieving a significant inference speedup. We conduct a large number of experiments. Despite training with less than 5% of the data required by prior methods, DiffusionVL achieves a comprehensive performance improvement-a 34.4% gain on the MMMU-Pro (vision) bench and 37.5% gain on the MME (Cog.) bench-alongside a 2x inference speedup. The model and code are released at https://github.com/hustvl/DiffusionVL.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:35:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15713</guid></item><item><title>Qwen-Image-Layered: Towards Inherent Editability via Layer Decomposition</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15603</link><description>Qwen-Image-Layered decomposes images into semantically disentangled RGBA layers using a diffusion model, enabling independent editing of each layer and improving decomposition quality and consistency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent visual generative models often struggle with consistency during image editing due to the entangled nature of raster images, where all visual content is fused into a single canvas. In contrast, professional design tools employ layered representations, allowing isolated edits while preserving consistency. Motivated by this, we propose Qwen-Image-Layered, an end-to-end diffusion model that decomposes a single RGB image into multiple semantically disentangled RGBA layers, enabling inherent editability, where each RGBA layer can be independently manipulated without affecting other content. To support variable-length decomposition, we introduce three key components: (1) an RGBA-VAE to unify the latent representations of RGB and RGBA images; (2) a VLD-MMDiT (Variable Layers Decomposition MMDiT) architecture capable of decomposing a variable number of image layers; and (3) a Multi-stage Training strategy to adapt a pretrained image generation model into a multilayer image decomposer. Furthermore, to address the scarcity of high-quality multilayer training images, we build a pipeline to extract and annotate multilayer images from Photoshop documents (PSD). Experiments demonstrate that our method significantly surpasses existing approaches in decomposition quality and establishes a new paradigm for consistent image editing. Our code and models are released on https://github.com/QwenLM/Qwen-Image-Layered{https://github.com/QwenLM/Qwen-Image-Layered}</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:24:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15603</guid></item><item><title>VABench: A Comprehensive Benchmark for Audio-Video Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.09299</link><description>VABench is a benchmark framework for evaluating audio-video generation models, covering text-to-audio-video, image-to-audio-video, and stereo audio-video tasks with 15 evaluation dimensions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in video generation have been remarkable, enabling models to produce visually compelling videos with synchronized audio. While existing video generation benchmarks provide comprehensive metrics for visual quality, they lack convincing evaluations for audio-video generation, especially for models aiming to generate synchronized audio-video outputs. To address this gap, we introduce VABench, a comprehensive and multi-dimensional benchmark framework designed to systematically evaluate the capabilities of synchronous audio-video generation. VABench encompasses three primary task types: text-to-audio-video (T2AV), image-to-audio-video (I2AV), and stereo audio-video generation. It further establishes two major evaluation modules covering 15 dimensions. These dimensions specifically assess pairwise similarities (text-video, text-audio, video-audio), audio-video synchronization, lip-speech consistency, and carefully curated audio and video question-answering (QA) pairs, among others. Furthermore, VABench covers seven major content categories: animals, human sounds, music, environmental sounds, synchronous physical sounds, complex scenes, and virtual worlds. We provide a systematic analysis and visualization of the evaluation results, aiming to establish a new standard for assessing video generation models with synchronous audio capabilities and to promote the comprehensive advancement of the field.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:48:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.09299</guid></item><item><title>End-to-End Training for Autoregressive Video Diffusion via Self-Resampling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15702</link><description>Resampling Forcing is introduced as a teacher-free framework to train autoregressive video diffusion models with improved temporal consistency using self-resampling and history routing.  					AI-generated summary 				 Autoregressive video diffusion models hold promise for world simulation but are vulnerable to exposure bias arising from the train-test mismatch. While recent works address this via post-training, they typically rely on a bidirectional teacher model or online discriminator. To achieve an end-to-end solution, we introduce Resampling Forcing, a teacher-free framework that enables training autoregressive video models from scratch and at scale. Central to our approach is a self-resampling scheme that simulates inference-time model errors on history frames during training. Conditioned on these degraded histories, a sparse causal mask enforces temporal causality while enabling parallel training with frame-level diffusion loss. To facilitate efficient long-horizon generation, we further introduce history routing, a parameter-free mechanism that dynamically retrieves the top-k most relevant history frames for each query. Experiments demonstrate that our approach achieves performance comparable to distillation-based baselines while exhibiting superior temporal consistency on longer videos owing to native-length training.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 04:04:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15702</guid></item><item><title>WAY: Estimation of Vessel Destination in Worldwide AIS Trajectory</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13190</link><description>A novel deep learning architecture, WAY, uses nested sequence structures and spatial grids for accurate long-term vessel destination estimation from AIS data, incorporating CASP blocks and Gradient Dropout for improved performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 The Automatic Identification System (AIS) enables data-driven maritime surveillance but suffers from reliability issues and irregular intervals. We address vessel destination estimation using global-scope AIS data by proposing a differentiated approach that recasts long port-to-port trajectories as a nested sequence structure. Using spatial grids, this method mitigates spatio-temporal bias while preserving detailed resolution. We introduce a novel deep learning architecture, WAY, designed to process these reformulated trajectories for long-term destination estimation days to weeks in advance. WAY comprises a trajectory representation layer and Channel-Aggregative Sequential Processing (CASP) blocks. The representation layer generates multi-channel vector sequences from kinematic and non-kinematic features. CASP blocks utilize multi-headed channel- and self-attention for aggregation and sequential information delivery. Additionally, we propose a task-specialized Gradient Dropout (GD) technique to enable many-to-many training on single labels, preventing biased feedback surges by stochastically blocking gradient flow based on sample length. Experiments on 5-year AIS data demonstrate WAY's superiority over conventional spatial grid-based approaches regardless of trajectory progression. Results further confirm that adopting GD leads to performance gains. Finally, we explore WAY's potential for real-world application through multitask learning for ETA estimation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:59:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13190</guid></item><item><title>VTCBench: Can Vision-Language Models Understand Long Context with Vision-Text Compression?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15649</link><description>A benchmark evaluates the performance of vision-language models on understanding long-context information compressed into dense visual representations, revealing significant limitations in capturing long-term dependencies.  					AI-generated summary 				 The computational and memory overheads associated with expanding the context window of LLMs severely limit their scalability. A noteworthy solution is vision-text compression (VTC), exemplified by frameworks like DeepSeek-OCR and Glyph, which convert long texts into dense 2D visual representations, thereby achieving token compression ratios of 3x-20x. However, the impact of this high information density on the core long-context capabilities of vision-language models (VLMs) remains under-investigated. To address this gap, we introduce the first benchmark for VTC and systematically assess the performance of VLMs across three long-context understanding settings: VTC-Retrieval, which evaluates the model's ability to retrieve and aggregate information; VTC-Reasoning, which requires models to infer latent associations to locate facts with minimal lexical overlap; and VTC-Memory, which measures comprehensive question answering within long-term dialogue memory. Furthermore, we establish the VTCBench-Wild to simulate diverse input scenarios.We comprehensively evaluate leading open-source and proprietary models on our benchmarks. The results indicate that, despite being able to decode textual information (e.g., OCR) well, most VLMs exhibit a surprisingly poor long-context understanding ability with VTC-compressed information, failing to capture long associations or dependencies in the context.This study provides a deep understanding of VTC and serves as a foundation for designing more efficient and scalable VLMs.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:45:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15649</guid></item><item><title>Is Nano Banana Pro a Low-Level Vision All-Rounder? A Comprehensive Evaluation on 14 Tasks and 40 Datasets</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15110</link><description>Nano Banana Pro excels in subjective visual quality across low-level vision tasks without fine-tuning but struggles with traditional reference-based quantitative metrics due to generative model stochasticity.  					AI-generated summary 				 The rapid evolution of text-to-image generation models has revolutionized visual content creation. While commercial products like Nano Banana Pro have garnered significant attention, their potential as generalist solvers for traditional low-level vision challenges remains largely underexplored. In this study, we investigate the critical question: Is Nano Banana Pro a Low-Level Vision All-Rounder? We conducted a comprehensive zero-shot evaluation across 14 distinct low-level tasks spanning 40 diverse datasets. By utilizing simple textual prompts without fine-tuning, we benchmarked Nano Banana Pro against state-of-the-art specialist models. Our extensive analysis reveals a distinct performance dichotomy: while Nano Banana Pro demonstrates superior subjective visual quality, often hallucinating plausible high-frequency details that surpass specialist models, it lags behind in traditional reference-based quantitative metrics. We attribute this discrepancy to the inherent stochasticity of generative models, which struggle to maintain the strict pixel-level consistency required by conventional metrics. This report identifies Nano Banana Pro as a capable zero-shot contender for low-level vision tasks, while highlighting that achieving the high fidelity of domain specialists remains a significant hurdle.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:27:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15110</guid></item><item><title>SAGE: Training Smart Any-Horizon Agents for Long Video Reasoning with Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13874</link><description>The paper proposes SAGE, a multi-turn reasoning system for video that mimics human behavior, using synthetic data and reinforcement learning to improve performance on long videos.  					AI-generated summary 				 As humans, we are natural any-horizon reasoners, i.e., we can decide whether to iteratively skim long videos or watch short ones in full when necessary for a given task. With this in mind, one would expect video reasoning models to reason flexibly across different durations. However, SOTA models are still trained to predict answers in a single turn while processing a large number of frames, akin to watching an entire long video, requiring significant resources. This raises the question: Is it possible to develop performant any-horizon video reasoning systems? Inspired by human behavior, we first propose SAGE, an agent system that performs multi-turn reasoning on long videos while handling simpler problems in a single turn. Secondly, we introduce an easy synthetic data generation pipeline using Gemini-2.5-Flash to train the orchestrator, SAGE-MM, which lies at the core of SAGE. We further propose an effective RL post-training recipe essential for instilling any-horizon reasoning ability in SAGE-MM. Thirdly, we curate SAGE-Bench with an average duration of greater than 700 seconds for evaluating video reasoning ability in real-world entertainment use cases. Lastly, we empirically validate the effectiveness of our system, data, and RL recipe, observing notable improvements of up to 6.1% on open-ended video reasoning tasks, as well as an impressive 8.2% improvement on videos longer than 10 minutes.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:39:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13874</guid></item><item><title>SCOPE: Prompt Evolution for Enhancing Agent Effectiveness</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15374</link><description>SCOPE enhances LLM agents' context management through prompt evolution, improving task success rates in dynamic environments without human intervention.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Model (LLM) agents are increasingly deployed in environments that generate massive, dynamic contexts. However, a critical bottleneck remains: while agents have access to this context, their static prompts lack the mechanisms to manage it effectively, leading to recurring Corrective and Enhancement failures. To address this capability gap, we introduce SCOPE (Self-evolving Context Optimization via Prompt Evolution). SCOPE frames context management as an online optimization problem, synthesizing guidelines from execution traces to automatically evolve the agent's prompt. We propose a Dual-Stream mechanism that balances tactical specificity (resolving immediate errors) with strategic generality (evolving long-term principles). Furthermore, we introduce Perspective-Driven Exploration to maximize strategy coverage, increasing the likelihood that the agent has the correct strategy for any given task. Experiments on the HLE benchmark show that SCOPE improves task success rates from 14.23\% to 38.64\% without human intervention. We make our code publicly available at https://github.com/JarvisPei/SCOPE.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:49:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15374</guid></item><item><title>VOYAGER: A Training Free Approach for Generating Diverse Datasets using LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12072</link><description>Voyager is a method that uses determinantal point processes to iteratively generate diverse synthetic datasets for model evaluation and training.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly being used to generate synthetic datasets for the evaluation and training of downstream models. However, prior work has noted that such generated data lacks diversity. In this paper, we propose Voyager, a novel principled approach to generate diverse datasets. Our approach is iterative and directly optimizes a mathematical quantity that optimizes the diversity of the dataset using the machinery of determinantal point processes. Furthermore, our approach is training-free, applicable to closed-source models, and scalable. In addition to providing theoretical justification for the working of our method, we also demonstrate through comprehensive experiments that Voyager significantly outperforms popular baseline approaches by providing a 1.5-3x improvement in diversity.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:13:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.12072</guid></item><item><title>In Pursuit of Pixel Supervision for Visual Pre-training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15715</link><description>Pixio, an enhanced masked autoencoder, demonstrates competitive performance across various downstream tasks using pixel-space self-supervised learning, outperforming latent-space approaches.  					AI-generated summary 				 At the most basic level, pixels are the source of the visual information through which we perceive the world. Pixels contain information at all levels, ranging from low-level attributes to high-level concepts. Autoencoders represent a classical and long-standing paradigm for learning representations from pixels or other raw inputs. In this work, we demonstrate that autoencoder-based self-supervised learning remains competitive today and can produce strong representations for downstream tasks, while remaining simple, stable, and efficient. Our model, codenamed "Pixio", is an enhanced masked autoencoder (MAE) with more challenging pre-training tasks and more capable architectures. The model is trained on 2B web-crawled images with a self-curation strategy with minimal human curation. Pixio performs competitively across a wide range of downstream tasks in the wild, including monocular depth estimation (e.g., Depth Anything), feed-forward 3D reconstruction (i.e., MapAnything), semantic segmentation, and robot learning, outperforming or matching DINOv3 trained at similar scales. Our results suggest that pixel-space self-supervised learning can serve as a promising alternative and a complement to latent-space approaches.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:26:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.15715</guid></item><item><title>Simultaneous Tactile-Visual Perception for Learning Multimodal Robot Manipulation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.09851</link><description>TacThru-UMI, a system combining a TacThru sensor with a Transformer-based Diffusion Policy, achieves superior performance in robotic manipulation tasks by integrating simultaneous multimodal perception.  					AI-generated summary 				 Robotic manipulation requires both rich multimodal perception and effective learning frameworks to handle complex real-world tasks. See-through-skin (STS) sensors, which combine tactile and visual perception, offer promising sensing capabilities, while modern imitation learning provides powerful tools for policy acquisition. However, existing STS designs lack simultaneous multimodal perception and suffer from unreliable tactile tracking. Furthermore, integrating these rich multimodal signals into learning-based manipulation pipelines remains an open challenge. We introduce TacThru, an STS sensor enabling simultaneous visual perception and robust tactile signal extraction, and TacThru-UMI, an imitation learning framework that leverages these multimodal signals for manipulation. Our sensor features a fully transparent elastomer, persistent illumination, novel keyline markers, and efficient tracking, while our learning system integrates these signals through a Transformer-based Diffusion Policy. Experiments on five challenging real-world tasks show that TacThru-UMI achieves an average success rate of 85.5%, significantly outperforming the baselines of alternating tactile-visual (66.3%) and vision-only (55.4%). The system excels in critical scenarios, including contact detection with thin and soft objects and precision manipulation requiring multimodal coordination. This work demonstrates that combining simultaneous multimodal perception with modern learning frameworks enables more precise, adaptable robotic manipulation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:48:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.09851</guid></item><item><title>Hybrid Attribution Priors for Explainable and Robust Model Training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14719</link><description>A novel framework, Class-Aware Attribution Prior (CAP), enhances language model interpretability and robustness by guiding the model to capture fine-grained class distinctions and combining with existing attribution methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 Small language models (SLMs) are widely used in tasks that require low latency and lightweight deployment, particularly classification. As interpretability and robustness gain increasing importance, explanation-guided learning has emerged as an effective framework by introducing attribution-based supervision during training; however, deriving general and reliable attribution priors remains a significant challenge. Through an analysis of representative attribution methods in classification settings, we find that although these methods can reliably highlight class-relevant tokens, they often focus on common keywords shared by semantically similar classes. Because such classes are already difficult to distinguish under standard training, these attributions provide insufficient discriminative cues, limiting their ability to improve model differentiation. To overcome this limitation, we propose Class-Aware Attribution Prior (CAP), a novel attribution prior extraction framework that guides language models toward capturing fine-grained class distinctions and producing more salient, discriminative attribution priors. Building on this idea, we further introduce CAP Hybrid, which combines priors from CAP with those from existing attribution techniques to form a more comprehensive and balanced supervisory signal. By aligning a model's self-attribution with these enriched priors, our approach encourages the learning of diverse, decision-relevant features. Extensive experiments in full-data, few-shot, and adversarial scenarios demonstrate that our method consistently enhances both interpretability and robustness.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:05:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.14719</guid></item><item><title>LikeBench: Evaluating Subjective Likability in LLMs for Personalization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13077</link><description>LikeBench introduces a multi-session evaluation framework to measure the likability of LLMs by their ability to adapt to user preferences across multiple dimensions, demonstrating that strong memory performance does not necessarily equate to higher likability.  					AI-generated summary 				 A personalized LLM should remember user facts, apply them correctly, and adapt over time to provide responses that the user prefers. Existing LLM personalization benchmarks are largely centered on two axes: accurately recalling user information and accurately applying remembered information in downstream tasks. We argue that a third axis, likability, is both subjective and central to user experience, yet under-measured by current benchmarks. To measure likability holistically, we introduce LikeBench, a multi-session, dynamic evaluation framework that measures likability across multiple dimensions by how much an LLM can adapt over time to a user's preferences to provide more likable responses. In LikeBench, the LLMs engage in conversation with a simulated user and learn preferences only from the ongoing dialogue. As the interaction unfolds, models try to adapt to responses, and after each turn, they are evaluated for likability across seven dimensions by the same simulated user. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to decompose likability into multiple diagnostic metrics: emotional adaptation, formality matching, knowledge adaptation, reference understanding, conversation length fit, humor fit, and callback, which makes it easier to pinpoint where a model falls short. To make the simulated user more realistic and discriminative, LikeBench uses fine-grained, psychologically grounded descriptive personas rather than the coarse high/low trait rating based personas used in prior work. Our benchmark shows that strong memory performance does not guarantee high likability: DeepSeek R1, with lower memory accuracy (86%, 17 facts/profile), outperformed Qwen3 by 28% on likability score despite Qwen3's higher memory accuracy (93%, 43 facts/profile). Even SOTA models like GPT-5 adapt well in short exchanges but show only limited robustness in longer, noisier interactions.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 04:38:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.13077</guid></item></channel></rss>