<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>I made a real time voice agent with FastRTC, smolagents, and hugging face inference providers. Check it out in this space:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/burtenshaw/742649076372470</link><description>I made a real time voice agent with FastRTC, smolagents, and hugging face inference providers. Check it out in this space: 🔗 burtenshaw/coworking_agent See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/burtenshaw/742649076372470</guid></item><item><title>Has OpenGVLab Lumina Outperformed OpenAI’s Model?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/366338815946143</link><description>Has OpenGVLab Lumina Outperformed OpenAI’s Model? We’ve just released the results from a large-scale human evaluation (400k annotations) of OpenGVLab’s newest text-to-image model, Lumina. Surprisingly, Lumina outperforms OpenAI’s DALL-E 3 in terms of alignment, although it ranks #6 in our overall human preference benchmark. To support further development in text-to-image models, we’re making our entire human-annotated dataset publicly available. If you’re working on model improvements and need high-quality data, feel free to explore. We welcome your feedback and look forward to any insights you might share! Rapidata/OpenGVLab_Lumina_t2i_human_preference See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/366338815946143</guid></item><item><title>O1 Embedder: Transforming Retrieval Models with Reasoning Capabilities</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/singhsidhukuldeep/419917039256941</link><description>O1 Embedder: Transforming Retrieval Models with Reasoning Capabilities Researchers from University of Science and Technology of China and Beijing Academy of Artificial Intelligence have developed a novel retrieval model that mimics the slow-thinking capabilities of reasoning-focused LLMs like OpenAI's O1 and DeepSeek's R1. Unlike traditional embedding models that directly match queries with documents, O1 Embedder first generates thoughtful reflections about the query before performing retrieval. This two-step process significantly improves performance on complex retrieval tasks, especially those requiring intensive reasoning or zero-shot generalization to new domains. The technical implementation is fascinating: - The model integrates two essential functions: Thinking and Embedding - It uses an "Exploration-Refinement" data synthesis workflow where initial thoughts are generated by an LLM and refined by a retrieval committee - A multi-task training method fine-tunes a pre-trained...</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/singhsidhukuldeep/419917039256941</guid></item><item><title>Quick POC: Turn a Hugging Face dataset card into a short podcast introducing the dataset using all open models.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/davanstrien/855251141208457</link><description>Quick POC: Turn a Hugging Face dataset card into a short podcast introducing the dataset using all open models. I think I'm the only weirdo who would enjoy listening to something like this though 😅 Here is an example for eth-nlped/stepverify See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/davanstrien/855251141208457</guid></item><item><title>✨🎉Duality.ai just released a multiclass object detection dataset for YOLOv8, as well as a tutorial on how to create your own multiclass dataset!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/331073083077260</link><description>✨🎉Duality.ai just released a multiclass object detection dataset for YOLOv8, as well as a tutorial on how to create your own multiclass dataset! Carefully crafted (not GenAI created) synthetic data that ACTUALLY trains a model that works in the physical world. Create a free FalconEDU account, and download the 1000 image and annotation dataset - https://falcon.duality.ai/secure/documentation/ex3-dataset?sidebarMode=learn -or- Follow along with Exercise 3: Multiclass Object Detection to start creating - https://falcon.duality.ai/secure/documentation/ex3-objdetection-multiclass -or- Download this Colab notebook to see the data work, no hardware required - https://falcon.duality.ai/secure/documentation/ex3-dataset?sidebarMode=learn See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/331073083077260</guid></item><item><title>A comprehensive matrix for which format should you use.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ngxson/723185341195650</link><description>A comprehensive matrix for which format should you use. Read more on my blog post: https://huggingface.co/blog/ngxson/common-ai-model-formats | Hardware | GGUF | PyTorch | Safetensors | ONNX | | ----------------- | ----------- | ------------------------ | -------------------------- | ------- | | CPU | ✅ (best) | 🟡 | 🟡 | ✅ | | GPU | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ | | Mobile | ✅ | 🟡 (via executorch) | ❌ | ✅ | | Apple silicon | ✅ | 🟡 | ✅ (via MLX framework) | ✅ | See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ngxson/723185341195650</guid></item><item><title>After running some 3DMark and FurMark benchmarks on Windows to make sure that my new 5090 is not causing melting cables [1] and some nice shots with a thermal camera (I don't think that's too much), running some fine-tuning experiments with my favorite Flair &amp; Transformers libraries are very easy to perform.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/stefan-it/989004577410802</link><description>After running some 3DMark and FurMark benchmarks on Windows to make sure that my new 5090 is not causing melting cables [1] and some nice shots with a thermal camera (I don't think that's too much), running some fine-tuning experiments with my favorite Flair &amp; Transformers libraries are very easy to perform. Important steps: Good idea is to start with a fresh Ubuntu 24.04 installation with latest CUDA 12.8 and the open NVIDIA driver - follow more advices from [2]: sudo apt -y install cuda-toolkit-12-8 nvidia-open I tried update from an existing Ubuntu installation with an older CUDA and driver version and it resulted in a non-startable system. If you are using PyTorch 2.6 with built CUDA 12.6 it will result in: NVIDIA Graphics Device with CUDA capability sm_120 is not compatible with the current PyTorch installation. The current PyTorch install supports CUDA capabilities sm_50 sm_60 sm_70 sm_75 sm_80 sm_86 sm_90. But no worries! For PyTorch you need just to use a nightly 2.7 version...</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/stefan-it/989004577410802</guid></item><item><title>Is this the best tool to extract clean info from PDFs, handwriting and complex documents yet?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/636972739498133</link><description>Is this the best tool to extract clean info from PDFs, handwriting and complex documents yet? Open source olmOCR just dropped and the results are impressive. Tested the free demo with various documents, including a handwritten Claes Oldenburg letter. The speed is impressive: 3000 tokens/second on your own GPU - that's 1/32 the cost of GPT-4o ($190/million pages). Game-changer for content extraction and digital archives. To achieve this, Ai2 trained a 7B vision language model on 260K pages from 100K PDFs using "document anchoring" - combining PDF metadata with page images. Best part: it actually understands document structure (columns, tables, equations) instead of just jumbling everything together like most OCR tools. Their human eval results back this up. 👉 Try the demo: https://olmocr.allenai.org Going right into the AI toolkit: JournalistsonHF/ai-toolkit See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/636972739498133</guid></item><item><title>Dropping some of the custom fine-tunes based on SigLIP2,</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/305640045790864</link><description>Dropping some of the custom fine-tunes based on SigLIP2, with a single-label classification problem type! 🌀🧤 - AI vs Deepfake vs Real : prithivMLmods/AI-vs-Deepfake-vs-Real-Siglip2 - Deepfake Detect : prithivMLmods/Deepfake-Detect-Siglip2 - Fire Detection : prithivMLmods/Fire-Detection-Siglip2 - Deepfake Quality Assess : prithivMLmods/Deepfake-Quality-Assess-Siglip2 - Guard Against Unsafe Content : prithivMLmods/Guard-Against-Unsafe-Content-Siglip2 🌠Collection : prithivMLmods/siglip2-custom-67bcdb2de8fe96b99fb4e19e See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/305640045790864</guid></item><item><title>What if AI becomes as ubiquitous as the internet, but runs locally and transparently on our devices?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/113970261627099</link><description>What if AI becomes as ubiquitous as the internet, but runs locally and transparently on our devices? Fascinating TED talk by @ thomwolf on open source AI and its future impact. Imagine this for AI: instead of black box models running in distant data centers, we get transparent AI that runs locally on our phones and laptops, often without needing internet access. If the original team moves on? No problem - resilience is one of the beauties of open source. Anyone (companies, collectives, or individuals) can adapt and fix these models. This is a compelling vision of AI's future that solves many of today's concerns around AI transparency and centralized control. Watch the full talk here: https://www.ted.com/talks/thomas_wolf_what_if_ai_just_works See translation</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/113970261627099</guid></item></channel></rss>