<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Eka-Eval : A Comprehensive Evaluation Framework for Large Language
  Models in Indian Languages</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01853</link><description>EKA-EVAL is a comprehensive multilingual evaluation framework for large language models, supporting diverse benchmarks and features for efficient distributed inference and GPU usage.  					AI-generated summary 				 The rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs) has intensified the need for evaluation frameworks that go beyond English centric benchmarks and address the requirements of linguistically diverse regions such as India. We present EKA-EVAL, a unified and production-ready evaluation framework that integrates over 35 benchmarks, including 10 Indic-specific datasets, spanning categories like reasoning, mathematics, tool use, long-context understanding, and reading comprehension. Compared to existing Indian language evaluation tools, EKA-EVAL offers broader benchmark coverage, with built-in support for distributed inference, quantization, and multi-GPU usage. Our systematic comparison positions EKA-EVAL as the first end-to-end, extensible evaluation suite tailored for both global and Indic LLMs, significantly lowering the barrier to multilingual benchmarking. The framework is open-source and publicly available at https://github.com/lingo-iitgn/ eka-eval and a part of ongoing EKA initiative (https://eka.soket.ai), which aims to scale up to over 100 benchmarks and establish a robust, multilingual evaluation ecosystem for LLMs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 04:36:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01853</guid></item><item><title>How Well Does GPT-4o Understand Vision? Evaluating Multimodal Foundation
  Models on Standard Computer Vision Tasks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01955</link><description>Multimodal foundation models, despite being primarily trained on image-text tasks, demonstrate respectable performance across various vision tasks when adapted through prompt chaining, though they fall short compared to specialized models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multimodal foundation models, such as GPT-4o, have recently made remarkable progress, but it is not clear where exactly these models stand in terms of understanding vision. In this paper, we benchmark the performance of popular multimodal foundation models (GPT-4o, o4-mini, Gemini 1.5 Pro and Gemini 2.0 Flash, Claude 3.5 Sonnet, Qwen2-VL, Llama 3.2) on standard computer vision tasks (semantic segmentation, object detection, image classification, depth and surface normal prediction) using established datasets (e.g., COCO, ImageNet and its variants, etc).   The main challenges to performing this are: 1) most models are trained to output text and cannot natively express versatile domains, such as segments or 3D geometry, and 2) many leading models are proprietary and accessible only at an API level, i.e., there is no weight access to adapt them. We address these challenges by translating standard vision tasks into equivalent text-promptable and API-compatible tasks via prompt chaining to create a standardized benchmarking framework.   We observe that 1) the models are not close to the state-of-the-art specialist models at any task. However, 2) they are respectable generalists; this is remarkable as they are presumably trained on primarily image-text-based tasks. 3) They perform semantic tasks notably better than geometric ones. 4) While the prompt-chaining techniques affect performance, better models exhibit less sensitivity to prompt variations. 5) GPT-4o performs the best among non-reasoning models, securing the top position in 4 out of 6 tasks, 6) reasoning models, e.g. o3, show improvements in geometric tasks, and 7) a preliminary analysis of models with native image generation, like the latest GPT-4o, shows they exhibit quirks like hallucinations and spatial misalignments.</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 08:21:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01955</guid></item></channel></rss>