<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>10 awesome advanced LoRA approaches</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/445000542637232</link><description>10 awesome advanced LoRA approaches Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) is the go-to method for efficient model fine-tuning that adds small low-rank matrices instead of retraining full models. The field isn’t standing still – new LoRA variants push the limits of efficiency, generalization, and personalization. So we’re sharing 10 of the latest LoRA approaches you should know about: 1. Mixture-of-LoRA-experts → Mixture of Low-Rank Adapter Experts in Generalizable Audio Deepfake Detection (2509.13878) Adds multiple low-rank adapters (LoRA) into a model’s layers, and a routing mechanism activates the most suitable ones for each input. This lets the model adapt better to new unseen conditions 2. Amortized Bayesian Meta-Learning for LoRA (ABMLL) → Amortized Bayesian Meta-Learning for Low-Rank Adaptation of Large Language Models (2508.14285) Balances global and task-specific parameters within a Bayesian framework to improve uncertainty calibration and generalization to new tasks without high...</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/445000542637232</guid></item><item><title>Trustworthy AI evals has been an industry challenge for the last few years, so what's missing?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/salma-remyx/977986978639462</link><description>Trustworthy AI evals has been an industry challenge for the last few years, so what's missing? Causal Reasoning. Model based eval frameworks can't tell you if your changes actually improved user outcomes - you need to take a systems level approach. At Remyx, we’re building the intelligence layer for AI experimentation. Check out this example on how we start laying the scaffolding to launch controlled experiments to turn your hypotheses into insights on what drives performance for your application. Check out the latest at Remyx in our docs: https://docs.remyx.ai Try your first experiment today! https://engine.remyx.ai See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/salma-remyx/977986978639462</guid></item><item><title>The Bias is YOU - LLMs Mirror Your Own Assumptions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Tanaybh/360553614352968</link><description>The Bias is YOU - LLMs Mirror Your Own Assumptions AI doesn't just have bias - it reflects yours. When you ask a question with positive framing, you get positive answers. Ask with negative framing, you get negative answers. The AI becomes a mirror of your own assumptions. Your framing determines the answer - The same topic yields opposite responses based on how you ask AIs amplify your sentiment - Negative questions often get even MORE negative responses This affects everyone - From students doing research to professionals making decisions Why This Matters This isn't a technical glitch - it's fundamental to how these systems work. They're trained on human language, and humans frame things with bias. The AI learned to match that framing. Think about the implications: - Medical professionals seeking second opinions - Students researching controversial topics - Business leaders evaluating strategies - Anyone using AI for important decisions The Stochastic Mirror Effect Let's call this...</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Tanaybh/360553614352968</guid></item><item><title>Just released a preview of Moondream 3!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/vikhyatk/428307575853218</link><description>Just released a preview of Moondream 3! moondream/moondream3-preview This is a 9B parameter, 2B active MoE VLM with state of the art visual reasoning capabilities. More details in the release blog post: https://moondream.ai/blog/moondream-3-preview See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/vikhyatk/428307575853218</guid></item><item><title>Discussing  iMini Nano Banana – Practical AI Templates for Creative Workflows</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Ethank01/541492789102968</link><description>Discussing iMini Nano Banana – Practical AI Templates for Creative Workflows 🎙️I’ve been experimenting with imini nano banana recently, and the new batch of 100+ AI templates feels like a real shift in how we handle creative workflows. 🎨One example: the photo-to-hand-drawn sketch template. I tested it with a travel photo (a blonde girl in front of the Eiffel Tower) → the output was a clean, consistent hand-drawn sketch in seconds. Normally, this would take manual editing in Photoshop/Illustrator, but the AI template cut the process down to a single click. 💡From a workflow perspective, this could streamline tasks for: Designers: quick iterations on style variations Marketers: generating campaign visuals at scale Content creators: producing unique artwork without advanced editing skills 🖌️If anyone here has tested imini nano banana in professional projects, I’d like to hear how it fits into your pipeline. Full details: https://imini.com/nano-banana See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Ethank01/541492789102968</guid></item><item><title>Turn Your Dog’s Photo into a 3D Figurine with Nano Banana 🐶✨</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Monica997/115477940297105</link><description>Turn Your Dog’s Photo into a 3D Figurine with Nano Banana 🐶✨ Just tested out the new Nano Banana feature, and I’m honestly impressed. I uploaded a single photo of my corgi, and within minutes, it generated a detailed 3D figurine model. What makes this really interesting for tech and design folks: AI-powered 2D → 3D conversion (no manual modeling required) Preserves character consistency even with multiple images Export options for 3D printing or digital use (OBJ, FBX, STL) Works with pets, people, and even illustrated characters For anyone into 3D modeling, collectibles, or architecture visualization, this is a game-changer. Imagine transforming static photos into tangible 3D assets with just a few clicks. Here’s the link if you want to try it out: https://imini.com/nano-banana Has anyone else here tested Nano Banana for pets or other personal projects? Would love to hear your results! See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Monica997/115477940297105</guid></item><item><title>Announcing our new work on "Repository Level Question Answering"! 🎉</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/YerbaPage/735409135497339</link><description>Announcing our new work on "Repository Level Question Answering"! 🎉 We introduce SWE-QA, a repository-level code QA benchmark with 576 real-world questions that require a deep understanding of the entire codebase to answer. Curious about the limits of today's LLMs on complex codebases? Check out our paper and open-source data! 💻🧠 Link 👇 https://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14635 https://github.com/peng-weihan/SWE-QA-Bench #LLM #AI #SoftwareEngineering #Benchmark See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/YerbaPage/735409135497339</guid></item><item><title>Rolling Benchmarks - Evaluating AI Agents on Unseen GitHub Repos</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/salma-remyx/953215218627820</link><description>Rolling Benchmarks - Evaluating AI Agents on Unseen GitHub Repos Static benchmarks are prone to leaderboard hacking and training data contamination, so how about a dynamic/rolling benchmark? By limiting submissions to only freshly published code, we could evaluate based on consistency over time with rolling averages instead of finding agents overfit to a static benchmark. Can rolling benchmarks bring us closer to evaluating agents in a way more closely aligned with their real-world applications? Perhaps a new direction for agent evaluation? Would love to hear what you think about this! More on reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/LocalLLaMA/comments/1nmvw7a/rolling_benchmarks_evaluating_ai_agents_on_unseen/ See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/salma-remyx/953215218627820</guid></item><item><title>Claude Opus 4.1 is slightly better than Opus 4, but still behind GPT-5</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/onekq/332042657908085</link><description>Claude Opus 4.1 is slightly better than Opus 4, but still behind GPT-5 onekq-ai/WebApp1K-models-leaderboard See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/onekq/332042657908085</guid></item><item><title>🚀 Adaptive Classifier v0.0.17 Released - Major Accuracy Improvements!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/536269233496700</link><description>🚀 Adaptive Classifier v0.0.17 Released - Major Accuracy Improvements! We've just released a major update fixing critical bugs that were causing 40-50% accuracy drops in our enterprise classifiers! Key Fixes: • Fixed k-parameter prediction bug causing massive accuracy loss • Improved incremental learning for new classes • Enhanced weight preservation during model updates Dramatic Results: • fraud-detection: 43.9% → 92.7% (+48.8%) adaptive-classifier/fraud-detection • business-sentiment: 88.9% → 98.8% (+9.9%) adaptive-classifier/business-sentiment expense-category: 26.7% → 84.2% (+57.5%) adaptive-classifier/expense-category • language-detection: 98.8% → 100% (+1.2%) adaptive-classifier/language-detection 15/17 enterprise classifiers now maintain ≤5% accuracy difference from original performance! Other High-Performing Models: • email-security (93.8%): adaptive-classifier/email-security • content-moderation (100%): adaptive-classifier/content-moderation • pii-detection (100%): adaptive-...</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 05:22:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/536269233496700</guid></item></channel></rss>