<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Eka-Eval : A Comprehensive Evaluation Framework for Large Language
  Models in Indian Languages</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01853</link><description>EKA-EVAL is a comprehensive multilingual evaluation framework for large language models, supporting diverse benchmarks and features for efficient distributed inference and GPU usage.  					AI-generated summary 				 The rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs) has intensified the need for evaluation frameworks that go beyond English centric benchmarks and address the requirements of linguistically diverse regions such as India. We present EKA-EVAL, a unified and production-ready evaluation framework that integrates over 35 benchmarks, including 10 Indic-specific datasets, spanning categories like reasoning, mathematics, tool use, long-context understanding, and reading comprehension. Compared to existing Indian language evaluation tools, EKA-EVAL offers broader benchmark coverage, with built-in support for distributed inference, quantization, and multi-GPU usage. Our systematic comparison positions EKA-EVAL as the first end-to-end, extensible evaluation suite tailored for both global and Indic LLMs, significantly lowering the barrier to multilingual benchmarking. The framework is open-source and publicly available at https://github.com/lingo-iitgn/ eka-eval and a part of ongoing EKA initiative (https://eka.soket.ai), which aims to scale up to over 100 benchmarks and establish a robust, multilingual evaluation ecosystem for LLMs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 04:36:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01853</guid></item></channel></rss>