<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>🚀 Introducing MOUSE: Space Research Thinking on HuggingFace Spaces</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ginipick/923354082387927</link><description>🚀 Introducing MOUSE: Space Research Thinking on HuggingFace Spaces 🚀 How to Get Started ginipick/spaces-research-think Welcome to **MOUSE: Space Research Thinking** – an innovative HuggingFace Spaces project designed to transform how you analyze and interact with Python code. Whether you're a developer, researcher, or simply passionate about coding, this tool provides state-of-the-art analysis, summarization, and usage guidance, all powered by advanced AI. --- ## 🌟 Key Features - **Real-Time Code Analysis** Instantly dissect your Python code to reveal its structure, functionality, and potential applications. Our tool delivers: - **Background &amp; Necessity**: Understand the context behind the code. - **Functional Utility &amp; Value**: Highlight core functionalities and benefits. - **Distinctive Features**: Discover what sets the project apart. - **Target Audience &amp; Applications**: Identify who can benefit and how. - **Expected Impact**: Envision the improvements and innovations the code...</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ginipick/923354082387927</guid></item><item><title>Now the Hugging Face agent course is getting real! With frameworks like smolagents, LlamaIndex, and LangChain.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/burtenshaw/352638065928004</link><description>Now the Hugging Face agent course is getting real! With frameworks like smolagents, LlamaIndex, and LangChain. 🔗 Follow the org for updates https://huggingface.co/agents-course This week we are releasing the first framework unit in the course and it’s on smolagents. This is what the unit covers: - why should you use smolagents vs another library? - how to build agents that use code - build multiagents systems - use vision language models for browser use The team has been working flat out on this for a few weeks. Led by @ sergiopaniego and supported by smolagents author @ m-ric . See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/burtenshaw/352638065928004</guid></item><item><title>Dropping some of the custom fine-tunes based on SigLIP2,</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/305640045790864</link><description>Dropping some of the custom fine-tunes based on SigLIP2, with a single-label classification problem type! 🌀🧤 - AI vs Deepfake vs Real : prithivMLmods/AI-vs-Deepfake-vs-Real-Siglip2 - Deepfake Detect : prithivMLmods/Deepfake-Detect-Siglip2 - Fire Detection : prithivMLmods/Fire-Detection-Siglip2 - Deepfake Quality Assess : prithivMLmods/Deepfake-Quality-Assess-Siglip2 - Guard Against Unsafe Content : prithivMLmods/Guard-Against-Unsafe-Content-Siglip2 🌠Collection : prithivMLmods/siglip2-custom-67bcdb2de8fe96b99fb4e19e See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/305640045790864</guid></item><item><title>Getting WebRTC and Websockets right in python is very tricky. If you've tried to wrap an LLM in a real-time audio layer then you know what I'm talking about.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/freddyaboulton/628292960317038</link><description>Getting WebRTC and Websockets right in python is very tricky. If you've tried to wrap an LLM in a real-time audio layer then you know what I'm talking about. That's where FastRTC comes in! It makes WebRTC and Websocket streams super easy with minimal code and overhead. Check out our org: hf.co/fastrtc See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/freddyaboulton/628292960317038</guid></item><item><title>She arrived 😍</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/stefan-it/765581033311913</link><description>She arrived 😍 [Expect more models soon...] See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/stefan-it/765581033311913</guid></item><item><title>Wan2.1 🔥📹 new OPEN video model by Alibaba Wan team!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/200256238569001</link><description>Wan2.1 🔥📹 new OPEN video model by Alibaba Wan team! Model: Wan-AI/Wan2.1-T2V-14B Demo: Wan-AI/Wan2.1 ✨Apache 2.0 ✨8.19GB VRAM, runs on most GPUs ✨Multi-Tasking: T2V, I2V, Video Editing, T2I, V2A ✨Text Generation: Supports Chinese &amp; English ✨Powerful Video VAE: Encode/decode 1080P w/ temporal precision See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/200256238569001</guid></item><item><title>We now have a Deep Research for academia: SurveyX automatically writes academic surveys nearly indistinguishable from human-written ones 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/m-ric/788543954757847</link><description>We now have a Deep Research for academia: SurveyX automatically writes academic surveys nearly indistinguishable from human-written ones 🔥 Researchers from Beijing and Shanghai just published the first application of a deep research system to academia: their algorithm, given a question, can give you a survey of all papers on the subject. To make a research survey, you generally follow two steps, preparation (collect and organize papers) and writing (outline creation, writing, polishing). Researchers followed the same two steps and automated them. 🎯 For the preparation part, a key part is find all the important references on the given subject. Researchers first cast a wide net of all relevant papers. But then finding the really important ones is like distilling knowledge from a haystack of information. To solve this challenge, they built an “AttributeTree” object that structures key information from citations. Ablating these AttributeTrees significantly decreased structure and...</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/m-ric/788543954757847</guid></item><item><title>🔥 Agents can do anything!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/alvarobartt/393660009896131</link><description>🔥 Agents can do anything! @ microsoft Research just announced the release of Magma 8B! Magma is a new Visual Language Model (VLM) with 8B parameters for multi-modal agents designed to handle complex interactions across virtual and real environments; and it's MIT licensed! Magma comes with exciting new features such as: - Introduces the Set-of-Mark and Trace-of-Mark techniques for fine-tuning - Leverages a large amount of unlabeled video data to learn the spatial-temporal grounding and planning - A strong generalization and ability to be fine-tuned for other agentic tasks - SOTA in different multi-modal benchmarks spanning across UI navigation, robotics manipulation, image / video understanding and spatial understanding and reasoning - Generates goal-driven visual plans and actions for agentic use cases Model: microsoft/Magma-8B Technical Report: Magma: A Foundation Model for Multimodal AI Agents (2502.13130) See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/alvarobartt/393660009896131</guid></item><item><title>Hello!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MrOvkill/644352837710754</link><description>Hello! I was just playing around with Python's MIDI library and Colab's code generation, accidentally cooked up a quick n' dirty audio synthesis template. Have fun! https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1d-AF6jygCwmoJvAa9nnEMe5ROidnMJNY?usp=sharing -&lt;3 See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MrOvkill/644352837710754</guid></item><item><title>🚀 Just launched: A toolkit of 20 powerful AI tools that journalists can use right now - transcribe, analyze, create. 100% free &amp; open-source.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/982146976081521</link><description>🚀 Just launched: A toolkit of 20 powerful AI tools that journalists can use right now - transcribe, analyze, create. 100% free &amp; open-source. Been testing all these tools myself and created a searchable collection of the most practical ones - from audio transcription to image generation to document analysis. No coding needed, no expensive subscriptions. Some highlights I've tested personally: - Private, on-device transcription with speaker ID in 100+ languages using Whisper - Website scraping that just works - paste a URL, get structured data - Local image editing with tools like Finegrain (impressive results) - Document chat using Qwen 2.5 72B (handles technical papers well) Sharing this early because the best tools come from the community. Drop your favorite tools in the comments or join the discussion on what to add next! 👉 JournalistsonHF/ai-toolkit See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:21:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/982146976081521</guid></item></channel></rss>