<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>🚀 Idea Transformer:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/openfree/269373246432749</link><description>🚀 Idea Transformer: Idea Transformer: Infinity is an innovative tool that unlocks infinite creativity by generating unique transformation ideas and design images from up to three keywords and a chosen category. Leveraging a state-of-the-art diffusion pipeline, real-time translation, and a powerful LLM, it delivers fresh ideas every time. 🎨✨ openfree/Idea-Transformer Key Features Diverse Ideas: Randomly selects creative variations from your keywords and category — the possibilities are nearly endless! 🎲 Unique Design Images: Your text prompt produces striking, varied design images via the diffusion model. 🖼️ Real-Time Translation &amp; Expansion: Korean inputs are automatically translated and enriched using an advanced LLM for high-quality output. 🔄 Dual-Language Support: Enjoy an intuitive Gradio interface with separate English and Korean tabs for a global audience. 🌍 Explore a Wide Range of Categories: Sensor Functions 📡: Creative changes in sensor technologies. Size &amp; Shape Change 📏:...</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/openfree/269373246432749</guid></item><item><title>We just crossed 1,500,000 public models on Hugging Face (and 500k spaces, 330k datasets, 50k papers). One new repository is created every 15 seconds. Congratulations all!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/clem/238420842235482</link><description>We just crossed 1,500,000 public models on Hugging Face (and 500k spaces, 330k datasets, 50k papers). One new repository is created every 15 seconds. Congratulations all! See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/clem/238420842235482</guid></item><item><title>📢 Our EMOVA paper has been accepted by CVPR 2025, and we are glad to release all resources, including code (training &amp; inference), datasets (training &amp; evaluation), and checkpoints (EMOVA-3B/7B/72B)!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/KaiChen1998/260621109030490</link><description>📢 Our EMOVA paper has been accepted by CVPR 2025, and we are glad to release all resources, including code (training &amp; inference), datasets (training &amp; evaluation), and checkpoints (EMOVA-3B/7B/72B)! 🤗 EMOVA is a novel end-to-end omni-modal LLM that can see, hear and speak. Given omni-modal (i.e., textual, visual and speech) inputs, EMOVA can generate both textual and speech responses with vivid emotional controls by utilizing the speech decoder and a style controller. ✨ EMOVA Highlights ✅ State-of-the-art omni-modality: EMOVA achieves SoTA comparable results on both vision-language and speech benchmarks simultaneously. ✅ Device adaptation: our codebase supports training/inference on both NVIDIA GPUs (e.g., A800 &amp; H20) and Ascend NPUs (e.g., 910B3)! ✅ Modular design: we integrate multiple implementations of vision encoder, vision projector, and language model, even including the most recent DeepSeekMoE-tiny! 🔥 You are all welcome to try and star! - Project page: https://emova-...</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/KaiChen1998/260621109030490</guid></item><item><title>to the nvidia employee that won't respond to my emails: hear me now.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/nroggendorff/181073331446889</link><description>to the nvidia employee that won't respond to my emails: hear me now. you have made a semi-powerful to irrelevant enemy. you have been warned See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/nroggendorff/181073331446889</guid></item><item><title>Hello community,</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/hanzla/186651630886849</link><description>Hello community, I want to share my work of creating a reasoning mamba model I used GRPO over Falcon3 Mamba Instruct to make this model. It generates blazing fast response while building good logic to answer challenging questions. Give it a try: Model repo: hanzla/Falcon3-Mamba-R1-v0 Space: hanzla/Falcon3MambaReasoner Looking forward to community feedback. See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/hanzla/186651630886849</guid></item><item><title>🔥MedAgentBench Amazing Work🚀</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/vansin/329603150202451</link><description>🔥MedAgentBench Amazing Work🚀 Just explored #MedAgentBench from @ Yale researchers and it's mind-blowing! They've created a cutting-edge benchmark that finally exposes the true capabilities of LLMs in complex medical reasoning. ⚡ Key discoveries: DeepSeek R1 &amp; OpenAI O3 dominate clinical reasoning tasks Agent-based frameworks deliver exceptional performance-cost balance Open-source alternatives are closing the gap at fraction of the cost This work shatters previous benchmarks that failed to challenge today's advanced models. The future of medical AI is here: https://github.com/gersteinlab/medagents-benchmark #MedicalAI #MachineLearning #AIinHealthcare 🔥 See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/vansin/329603150202451</guid></item><item><title>Think building custom digital twins for AI training is hard? Let us show you how to make it easy!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/310882641508042</link><description>Think building custom digital twins for AI training is hard? Let us show you how to make it easy! Next week, Duality AI is offering a free "Creating Your Own 4-Wheeled Vehicle Digital Twins for AI Training with Falcon Editor" live class. Sign up here: https://forms.gle/2U5xugMjvSkZdeaR8 What we'll cover: 🚗 Import &amp; Configure a rigged 4-wheeled vehicle and transform it into a controllable system twin using Blueprints. 🚗 Enable Dynamic Control by exposing Python variables for real-time adjustments. 🚗 Attach Sensors to capture valuable simulation data. 🚗 Assemble &amp; Run a Simulation Scenario to generate training data for AI &amp; robotics applications. See how Falcon creates synthetic data for faster, easier, and more targeted AI training by creating a FREE account here: https://www.duality.ai/edu See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/310882641508042</guid></item><item><title>This is the most exciting of this week’s release for me: Gemini Robotics - A SOTA generalist Vision-Language-Action model that brings intelligence to the physical world. It comes with a verifiable real-world knowledge Embodied Reasoning QA benchmark. Cool part is that the model can be specialized with fast adaptation to new tasks and have such adaptations transferred to new robot embodiment like humanoids. Looking forward to the model and data on hf, it’s about time I go full physical:)</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Jaward/782050409908004</link><description>This is the most exciting of this week’s release for me: Gemini Robotics - A SOTA generalist Vision-Language-Action model that brings intelligence to the physical world. It comes with a verifiable real-world knowledge Embodied Reasoning QA benchmark. Cool part is that the model can be specialized with fast adaptation to new tasks and have such adaptations transferred to new robot embodiment like humanoids. Looking forward to the model and data on hf, it’s about time I go full physical:) Technical Report: https://storage.googleapis.com/deepmind-media/gemini-robotics/gemini_robotics_report.pdf See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Jaward/782050409908004</guid></item><item><title>15 types of attention mechanisms</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/624548696865407</link><description>15 types of attention mechanisms Attention mechanisms allow models to dynamically focus on specific parts of their input when performing tasks. In our recent article, we discussed Multi-Head Latent Attention (MLA) in detail and now it's time to summarize other existing types of attention. Here is a list of 15 types of attention mechanisms used in AI models: 1. Soft attention (Deterministic attention) -&gt; Neural Machine Translation by Jointly Learning to Align and Translate (1409.0473) Assigns a continuous weight distribution over all parts of the input. It produces a weighted sum of the input using attention weights that sum to 1. 2. Hard attention (Stochastic attention) -&gt; Effective Approaches to Attention-based Neural Machine Translation (1508.04025) Makes a discrete selection of some part of the input to focus on at each step, rather than attending to everything. 3. Self-attention -&gt; Attention Is All You Need (1706.03762) Each element in the sequence "looks" at other elements and...</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/624548696865407</guid></item><item><title>smolagents now support vLLM! 🥳</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/m-ric/783111989290994</link><description>smolagents now support vLLM! 🥳 As one of the most popular local inference solutions, the community had been asking us to integrate vLLM: after a heavy refactoring of our LLM classes, we've just released smolagents 1.11.0, with a brand new VLLMModel class. Go try it and tell us what you think! https://github.com/huggingface/smolagents/blob/45b2c86857b7f7657daaa74e4d17d347e9e2c4a4/src/smolagents/models.py#L497 See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:17:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/m-ric/783111989290994</guid></item></channel></rss>