<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Run DeepSeek-V3.1 locally on 170GB RAM with Dynamic 1-bit GGUFs!🐋</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/385540082056286</link><description>Run DeepSeek-V3.1 locally on 170GB RAM with Dynamic 1-bit GGUFs!🐋 GGUFs: unsloth/DeepSeek-V3.1-GGUF The 715GB model gets reduced to 170GB (-80% size) by smartly quantizing layers. The 1-bit GGUF passes all our code tests &amp; we fixed the chat template for llama.cpp supported backends. Guide: https://docs.unsloth.ai/basics/deepseek-v3.1 See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/385540082056286</guid></item><item><title>Okay this is insane... WebGPU-accelerated semantic video tracking, powered by DINOv3 and Transformers.js! 🤯</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Xenova/448209562329557</link><description>Okay this is insane... WebGPU-accelerated semantic video tracking, powered by DINOv3 and Transformers.js! 🤯 Demo (+ source code): webml-community/DINOv3-video-tracking This will revolutionize AI-powered video editors... which can now run 100% locally in your browser, no server inference required (costs $0)! 😍 How does it work? 🤔 1️⃣ Generate and cache image features for each frame 2️⃣ Create a list of embeddings for selected patch(es) 3️⃣ Compute cosine similarity between each patch and the selected patch(es) 4️⃣ Highlight those whose score is above some threshold ... et voilà! 🥳 You can also make selections across frames to improve temporal consistency! This is super useful if the object changes its appearance slightly throughout the video. Excited to see what the community builds with it! See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Xenova/448209562329557</guid></item><item><title>If</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ProCreations/306123757721653</link><description>If @ clem comments on this post within the week with a task for me to classify with text and a paramater size for the model, within 48 hours I will create a new dataset, train the model, and post it all. Paramater size must be bellow 50 million params, and task can be text only, and genuinely possible. if I complete it, Clem must tell everyone on Twitter/x to follow me on huggingface and link it let's see if he comments See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ProCreations/306123757721653</guid></item><item><title>Qwen Image Edit Full Tutorial: 26 Different Demo Cases, Prompts &amp; Images, Pwns FLUX Kontext Dev</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/783922297746182</link><description>Qwen Image Edit Full Tutorial: 26 Different Demo Cases, Prompts &amp; Images, Pwns FLUX Kontext Dev Tutorial Link https://youtu.be/gLCMhbsICEQ Extra Info I tested newly arrived Qwen-Image-Edit-Lightning-8steps-V1.0 (arrived after tutorial recorded) and definitely our existing preset which uses Qwen-Image-Lightning-8steps-V1.1 is better than it, so this tutorial and presets are still 100% best quality and up-to-date Info Qwen Image Edit just has been published and since then I have been experimenting to prepare you this amazing tutorial. I have literally shown 26 unique cases and provided demo images and prompts. After watching this tutorial your image editing skills will move to next level i promise you that. Also this tutorial will give you a lot of ideas. See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/783922297746182</guid></item><item><title>Just applied for HF Community Grant for “Hugging Research” —  a lightweight CodeAgent‑based research assistant built on Hugging Face’s Open Deep Research project for the Hugging Face Hub (models, datasets, Spaces, users, collections, papers). It gathers links via dedicated tools and organizes them for easy review.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/daqc/944546045325401</link><description>Just applied for HF Community Grant for “Hugging Research” — a lightweight CodeAgent‑based research assistant built on Hugging Face’s Open Deep Research project for the Hugging Face Hub (models, datasets, Spaces, users, collections, papers). It gathers links via dedicated tools and organizes them for easy review. As this is for the community, comments and suggestions are appreciated: daqc/hugging-research#1 See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/daqc/944546045325401</guid></item><item><title>Releasing Version 1 of the Konkani LLM</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Reubencf/152225733300526</link><description>Releasing Version 1 of the Konkani LLM Konkani is a low resource Indian language spoken by 2.5 Million people Model:https://huggingface.co/Reubencf/gemma3-konkani space: Reubencf/Gemma3-konkani See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Reubencf/152225733300526</guid></item><item><title>✅ New Article: *Psychology as Structured Mind*</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/kanaria007/378247173323952</link><description>✅ New Article: *Psychology as Structured Mind* Title: 🧩 Psychology: Identity Constructs and Constraint-Based Emotion 🔗 https://huggingface.co/blog/kanaria007/structured-psychology --- Summary: Psychology is often framed as *feelings, behavior, and personality*. Structured Intelligence reframes the mind as *recursive identity architecture*: * Emotion as *state feedback in cognitive loops* * Behavior as *jump execution under constraints* * Personality as *long‑term stability of structural patterns* &gt; The psyche isn’t a mystery — &gt; *it’s the architecture of self in motion.* --- Why It Matters: • Explains *how emotion, memory, and decision interact structurally* • Supports *reflective AI that models affect without mimicry* • Bridges *clinical insight, cognitive science, and structured reasoning* --- What’s Inside: • Psyche as *identity‑bound jump and feedback system* • *Emotional signal processing* as structural state update • *Memory loops* enabling personality and self‑coherence •...</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/kanaria007/378247173323952</guid></item><item><title>New Hugging Face Dataset is LIVE 🤗</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ZacMasa5000/133834634332701</link><description>New Hugging Face Dataset is LIVE 🤗 In this dataset, you’ll find 20,000+ rows of the top trending posts on X over the past several weeks. 🔥Topics Include: 🔹Bitcoin 🔹GPT-5 🔹Grok 🔹Cursor 🔹AI, Agents + Prompts 🔹Chainlink $LINK 📂Download dataset! Easily, plug it into your AI agents, LLMs or apps. MasaFoundation/X_Twitter_Trending_Topics_August2025 You can start query fresh data in our app and request API key here: https://bit.ly/4mrqbO2 See translation</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ZacMasa5000/133834634332701</guid></item><item><title>🤖💬 How do different AI models handle companionship?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/frimelle/223474631124556</link><description>🤖💬 How do different AI models handle companionship? Many users have noticed that GPT-5 feels less approachable than o4 when it comes to emotional conversations. But what does that actually mean in practice, especially when users seek support or share vulnerabilities with an AI? To dig into this question, we built the AI Companionship Leaderboard: frimelle/companionship-leaderboard The leaderboard compares models on how often their responses reinforce companionship across four dimensions: ✨ Assistant Traits – How the assistant presents its personality and role. ✨ Relationship &amp; Intimacy – Whether it frames the interaction in terms of closeness or bonding. ✨ Emotional Investment – How far it goes in engaging emotionally when asked. ✨ User Vulnerabilities – How it responds when users disclose struggles or difficulties. 📊 You can explore how models differ, request new ones to be added, and see which ones are more likely to encourage (or resist) companionship-seeking behaviors. Based on...</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/frimelle/223474631124556</guid></item><item><title>Hey all,  just a friendly PSA heads-up to those using our POC space made for showcasing the various novel possibilities that</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/LPX55/270438933978827</link><description>Hey all, just a friendly PSA heads-up to those using our POC space made for showcasing the various novel possibilities that @ qwen-llm 's Image Editing model can be used for: - We do not collect or store any data of inferences by users. BUT (pun not intended) there's been a minor logic error in how we store session data for custom prompting for our presets feature. - While we can't deny that we all like nice buttocks as natural human beings, for the time being please reset the prompts to the default state after use, just as a courtesy for the next user. - As long as you are staying within the law and HF's terms of service, we do not judge for curious minds and the inevitable occasional ... urges driven by humanly hormones, which, our future AGI overlords will never have. The session storage logic error is completely on me, and will be fixed tomorrow, after I get some sleep as I am severely sleep-deprived (unrelated reasons) and my brain is pretty much mush. But thank you for the...</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/LPX55/270438933978827</guid></item></channel></rss>