<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>UniversalRAG: Retrieval-Augmented Generation over Multiple Corpora with
  Diverse Modalities and Granularities</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20734</link><description>Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has shown substantial promise in improving factual accuracy by grounding model responses with external knowledge relevant to queries. However, most existing RAG approaches are limited to a text-only corpus, and while recent efforts have extended RAG to other modalities such as images and videos, they typically operate over a single modality-specific corpus. In contrast, real-world queries vary widely in the type of knowledge they require, which a single type of knowledge source cannot address. To address this, we introduce UniversalRAG, a novel RAG framework designed to retrieve and integrate knowledge from heterogeneous sources with diverse modalities and granularities. Specifically, motivated by the observation that forcing all modalities into a unified representation space derived from a single combined corpus causes a modality gap, where the retrieval tends to favor items from the same modality as the query, we propose a modality-aware routing mechanism that dynamically identifies the most appropriate modality-specific corpus and performs targeted retrieval within it. Also, beyond modality, we organize each modality into multiple granularity levels, enabling fine-tuned retrieval tailored to the complexity and scope of the query. We validate UniversalRAG on 8 benchmarks spanning multiple modalities, showing its superiority over modality-specific and unified baselines.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 03:20:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20734</guid></item><item><title>ReasonIR: Training Retrievers for Reasoning Tasks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20595</link><description>We present ReasonIR-8B, the first retriever specifically trained for general reasoning tasks. Existing retrievers have shown limited gains on reasoning tasks, in part because existing training datasets focus on short factual queries tied to documents that straightforwardly answer them. We develop a synthetic data generation pipeline that, for each document, our pipeline creates a challenging and relevant query, along with a plausibly related but ultimately unhelpful hard negative. By training on a mixture of our synthetic data and existing public data, ReasonIR-8B achieves a new state-of-the-art of 29.9 nDCG@10 without reranker and 36.9 nDCG@10 with reranker on BRIGHT, a widely-used reasoning-intensive information retrieval (IR) benchmark. When applied to RAG tasks, ReasonIR-8B improves MMLU and GPQA performance by 6.4% and 22.6% respectively, relative to the closed-book baseline, outperforming other retrievers and search engines. In addition, ReasonIR-8B uses test-time compute more effectively: on BRIGHT, its performance consistently increases with longer and more information-rich rewritten queries; it continues to outperform other retrievers when combined with an LLM reranker. Our training recipe is general and can be easily extended to future LLMs; to this end, we open-source our code, data, and model.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 02:28:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20595</guid></item><item><title>Reinforcement Learning for Reasoning in Large Language Models with One
  Training Example</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20571</link><description>We show that reinforcement learning with verifiable reward using one training example (1-shot RLVR) is effective in incentivizing the math reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs). Applying RLVR to the base model Qwen2.5-Math-1.5B, we identify a single example that elevates model performance on MATH500 from 36.0% to 73.6%, and improves the average performance across six common mathematical reasoning benchmarks from 17.6% to 35.7%. This result matches the performance obtained using the 1.2k DeepScaleR subset (MATH500: 73.6%, average: 35.9%), which includes the aforementioned example. Similar substantial improvements are observed across various models (Qwen2.5-Math-7B, Llama3.2-3B-Instruct, DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-1.5B), RL algorithms (GRPO and PPO), and different math examples (many of which yield approximately 30% or greater improvement on MATH500 when employed as a single training example). In addition, we identify some interesting phenomena during 1-shot RLVR, including cross-domain generalization, increased frequency of self-reflection, and sustained test performance improvement even after the training accuracy has saturated, a phenomenon we term post-saturation generalization. Moreover, we verify that the effectiveness of 1-shot RLVR primarily arises from the policy gradient loss, distinguishing it from the "grokking" phenomenon. We also show the critical role of promoting exploration (e.g., by adding entropy loss with an appropriate coefficient) in 1-shot RLVR training. As a bonus, we observe that applying entropy loss alone, without any outcome reward, significantly enhances Qwen2.5-Math-1.5B's performance on MATH500 by 27.4%. These findings can inspire future work on RLVR data efficiency and encourage a re-examination of both recent progress and the underlying mechanisms in RLVR. Our code, model, and data are open source at https://github.com/ypwang61/One-Shot-RLVR</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 02:16:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20571</guid></item><item><title>Toward Evaluative Thinking: Meta Policy Optimization with Evolving
  Reward Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20157</link><description>Reward-based alignment methods for large language models (LLMs) face two key limitations: vulnerability to reward hacking, where models exploit flaws in the reward signal; and reliance on brittle, labor-intensive prompt engineering when LLMs are used as reward models. We introduce Meta Policy Optimization (MPO), a framework that addresses these challenges by integrating a meta-reward model that dynamically refines the reward model's prompt throughout training. In MPO, the meta-reward model monitors the evolving training context and continuously adjusts the reward model's prompt to maintain high alignment, providing an adaptive reward signal that resists exploitation by the policy. This meta-learning approach promotes a more stable policy optimization, and greatly reduces the need for manual reward prompt design. It yields performance on par with or better than models guided by extensively hand-crafted reward prompts. Furthermore, we show that MPO maintains its effectiveness across diverse tasks, such as question answering and mathematical reasoning, without requiring specialized reward designs. Beyond standard RLAIF, MPO's meta-learning formulation is readily extensible to higher-level alignment frameworks. Overall, this method addresses theoretical and practical challenges in reward-based RL alignment for LLMs, paving the way for more robust and adaptable alignment strategies. The code and models will be publicly shared.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 03:34:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20157</guid></item><item><title>TesserAct: Learning 4D Embodied World Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20995</link><description>This paper presents an effective approach for learning novel 4D embodied world models, which predict the dynamic evolution of 3D scenes over time in response to an embodied agent's actions, providing both spatial and temporal consistency. We propose to learn a 4D world model by training on RGB-DN (RGB, Depth, and Normal) videos. This not only surpasses traditional 2D models by incorporating detailed shape, configuration, and temporal changes into their predictions, but also allows us to effectively learn accurate inverse dynamic models for an embodied agent. Specifically, we first extend existing robotic manipulation video datasets with depth and normal information leveraging off-the-shelf models. Next, we fine-tune a video generation model on this annotated dataset, which jointly predicts RGB-DN (RGB, Depth, and Normal) for each frame. We then present an algorithm to directly convert generated RGB, Depth, and Normal videos into a high-quality 4D scene of the world. Our method ensures temporal and spatial coherence in 4D scene predictions from embodied scenarios, enables novel view synthesis for embodied environments, and facilitates policy learning that significantly outperforms those derived from prior video-based world models.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 02:35:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20995</guid></item><item><title>Certified Mitigation of Worst-Case LLM Copyright Infringement</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16046</link><description>The exposure of large language models (LLMs) to copyrighted material during pre-training raises concerns about unintentional copyright infringement post deployment. This has driven the development of "copyright takedown" methods, post-training approaches aimed at preventing models from generating content substantially similar to copyrighted ones. While current mitigation approaches are somewhat effective for average-case risks, we demonstrate that they overlook worst-case copyright risks exhibits by the existence of long, verbatim quotes from copyrighted sources. We propose BloomScrub, a remarkably simple yet highly effective inference-time approach that provides certified copyright takedown. Our method repeatedly interleaves quote detection with rewriting techniques to transform potentially infringing segments. By leveraging efficient data sketches (Bloom filters), our approach enables scalable copyright screening even for large-scale real-world corpora. When quotes beyond a length threshold cannot be removed, the system can abstain from responding, offering certified risk reduction. Experimental results show that BloomScrub reduces infringement risk, preserves utility, and accommodates different levels of enforcement stringency with adaptive abstention. Our results suggest that lightweight, inference-time methods can be surprisingly effective for copyright prevention.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 03:45:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16046</guid></item><item><title>YoChameleon: Personalized Vision and Language Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20998</link><description>Large Multimodal Models (e.g., GPT-4, Gemini, Chameleon) have evolved into powerful tools with millions of users. However, they remain generic models and lack personalized knowledge of specific user concepts. Previous work has explored personalization for text generation, yet it remains unclear how these methods can be adapted to new modalities, such as image generation. In this paper, we introduce Yo'Chameleon, the first attempt to study personalization for large multimodal models. Given 3-5 images of a particular concept, Yo'Chameleon leverages soft-prompt tuning to embed subject-specific information to (i) answer questions about the subject and (ii) recreate pixel-level details to produce images of the subject in new contexts. Yo'Chameleon is trained with (i) a self-prompting optimization mechanism to balance performance across multiple modalities, and (ii) a ``soft-positive" image generation approach to enhance image quality in a few-shot setting.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 02:24:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20998</guid></item><item><title>The Leaderboard Illusion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20879</link><description>Measuring progress is fundamental to the advancement of any scientific field. As benchmarks play an increasingly central role, they also grow more susceptible to distortion. Chatbot Arena has emerged as the go-to leaderboard for ranking the most capable AI systems. Yet, in this work we identify systematic issues that have resulted in a distorted playing field. We find that undisclosed private testing practices benefit a handful of providers who are able to test multiple variants before public release and retract scores if desired. We establish that the ability of these providers to choose the best score leads to biased Arena scores due to selective disclosure of performance results. At an extreme, we identify 27 private LLM variants tested by Meta in the lead-up to the Llama-4 release. We also establish that proprietary closed models are sampled at higher rates (number of battles) and have fewer models removed from the arena than open-weight and open-source alternatives. Both these policies lead to large data access asymmetries over time. Providers like Google and OpenAI have received an estimated 19.2% and 20.4% of all data on the arena, respectively. In contrast, a combined 83 open-weight models have only received an estimated 29.7% of the total data. We show that access to Chatbot Arena data yields substantial benefits; even limited additional data can result in relative performance gains of up to 112% on the arena distribution, based on our conservative estimates. Together, these dynamics result in overfitting to Arena-specific dynamics rather than general model quality. The Arena builds on the substantial efforts of both the organizers and an open community that maintains this valuable evaluation platform. We offer actionable recommendations to reform the Chatbot Arena's evaluation framework and promote fairer, more transparent benchmarking for the field</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 05:06:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20879</guid></item></channel></rss>