<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Entropy-Adaptive Fine-Tuning: Resolving Confident Conflicts to Mitigate Forgetting</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.02151</link><description>Entropy-Adaptive Fine-Tuning addresses catastrophic forgetting in supervised fine-tuning by using token-level entropy to distinguish uncertainty from knowledge conflict, enabling better preservation of general capabilities.  					AI-generated summary 				 Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) is the standard paradigm for domain adaptation, yet it frequently incurs the cost of catastrophic forgetting. In sharp contrast, on-policy Reinforcement Learning (RL) effectively preserves general capabilities. We investigate this discrepancy and identify a fundamental distributional gap: while RL aligns with the model's internal belief, SFT forces the model to fit external supervision. This mismatch often manifests as "Confident Conflicts" tokens characterized by low probability but low entropy. In these instances, the model is highly confident in its own prediction but is forced to learn a divergent ground truth, triggering destructive gradient updates. To address this, we propose Entropy-Adaptive Fine-Tuning (EAFT). Unlike methods relying solely on prediction probability, EAFT utilizes token-level entropy as a gating mechanism to distinguish between epistemic uncertainty and knowledge conflict. This allows the model to learn from uncertain samples while suppressing gradients on conflicting data. Extensive experiments on Qwen and GLM series (ranging from 4B to 32B parameters) across mathematical, medical, and agentic domains confirm our hypothesis. EAFT consistently matches the downstream performance of standard SFT while significantly mitigating the degradation of general capabilities.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:12:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.02151</guid></item><item><title>Benchmark^2: Systematic Evaluation of LLM Benchmarks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03986</link><description>Researchers developed Benchmark^2, a framework with three metrics to evaluate benchmark quality for large language models, revealing significant variations in existing benchmarks and enabling more efficient evaluation through selective benchmark construction.  					AI-generated summary 				 The rapid proliferation of benchmarks for evaluating large language models (LLMs) has created an urgent need for systematic methods to assess benchmark quality itself. We propose Benchmark^2, a comprehensive framework comprising three complementary metrics: (1) Cross-Benchmark Ranking Consistency, measuring whether a benchmark produces model rankings aligned with peer benchmarks; (2) Discriminability Score, quantifying a benchmark's ability to differentiate between models; and (3) Capability Alignment Deviation, identifying problematic instances where stronger models fail but weaker models succeed within the same model family. We conduct extensive experiments across 15 benchmarks spanning mathematics, reasoning, and knowledge domains, evaluating 11 LLMs across four model families. Our analysis reveals significant quality variations among existing benchmarks and demonstrates that selective benchmark construction based on our metrics can achieve comparable evaluation performance with substantially reduced test sets.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:29:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03986</guid></item><item><title>Choreographing a World of Dynamic Objects</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.04194</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:30:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.04194</guid></item><item><title>E-GRPO: High Entropy Steps Drive Effective Reinforcement Learning for Flow Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.00423</link><description>Entropy-aware policy optimization method for reinforcement learning in flow matching models that improves exploration through SDE and ODE sampling strategies.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent reinforcement learning has enhanced the flow matching models on human preference alignment. While stochastic sampling enables the exploration of denoising directions, existing methods which optimize over multiple denoising steps suffer from sparse and ambiguous reward signals. We observe that the high entropy steps enable more efficient and effective exploration while the low entropy steps result in undistinguished roll-outs. To this end, we propose E-GRPO, an entropy aware Group Relative Policy Optimization to increase the entropy of SDE sampling steps. Since the integration of stochastic differential equations suffer from ambiguous reward signals due to stochasticity from multiple steps, we specifically merge consecutive low entropy steps to formulate one high entropy step for SDE sampling, while applying ODE sampling on other steps. Building upon this, we introduce multi-step group normalized advantage, which computes group-relative advantages within samples sharing the same consolidated SDE denoising step. Experimental results on different reward settings have demonstrated the effectiveness of our methods.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:20:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.00423</guid></item><item><title>Klear: Unified Multi-Task Audio-Video Joint Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.04151</link><description>Klear addresses audio-video joint generation challenges through a unified model architecture, progressive multitask training, and large-scale dense-caption data construction, achieving superior alignment and generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Audio-video joint generation has progressed rapidly, yet substantial challenges still remain. Non-commercial approaches still suffer audio-visual asynchrony, poor lip-speech alignment, and unimodal degradation, which can be stemmed from weak audio-visual correspondence modeling, limited generalization, and scarce high-quality dense-caption data. To address these issues, we introduce Klear and delve into three axes--model architecture, training strategy, and data curation. Architecturally, we adopt a single-tower design with unified DiT blocks and an Omni-Full Attention mechanism, achieving tight audio-visual alignment and strong scalability. Training-wise, we adopt a progressive multitask regime--random modality masking to joint optimization across tasks, and a multistage curriculum, yielding robust representations, strengthening A-V aligned world knowledge, and preventing unimodal collapse. For datasets, we present the first large-scale audio-video dataset with dense captions, and introduce a novel automated data-construction pipeline which annotates and filters millions of diverse, high-quality, strictly aligned audio-video-caption triplets. Building on this, Klear scales to large datasets, delivering high-fidelity, semantically and temporally aligned, instruction-following generation in both joint and unimodal settings while generalizing robustly to out-of-distribution scenarios. Across tasks, it substantially outperforms prior methods by a large margin and achieves performance comparable to Veo 3, offering a unified, scalable path toward next-generation audio-video synthesis.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:37:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.04151</guid></item><item><title>RedBench: A Universal Dataset for Comprehensive Red Teaming of Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03699</link><description>RedBench presents a unified dataset with standardized risk categorization for evaluating LLM vulnerabilities across multiple domains and attack types.  					AI-generated summary 				 As large language models (LLMs) become integral to safety-critical applications, ensuring their robustness against adversarial prompts is paramount. However, existing red teaming datasets suffer from inconsistent risk categorizations, limited domain coverage, and outdated evaluations, hindering systematic vulnerability assessments. To address these challenges, we introduce RedBench, a universal dataset aggregating 37 benchmark datasets from leading conferences and repositories, comprising 29,362 samples across attack and refusal prompts. RedBench employs a standardized taxonomy with 22 risk categories and 19 domains, enabling consistent and comprehensive evaluations of LLM vulnerabilities. We provide a detailed analysis of existing datasets, establish baselines for modern LLMs, and open-source the dataset and evaluation code. Our contributions facilitate robust comparisons, foster future research, and promote the development of secure and reliable LLMs for real-world deployment. Code: https://github.com/knoveleng/redeval</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:27:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03699</guid></item><item><title>EpiQAL: Benchmarking Large Language Models in Epidemiological Question Answering for Enhanced Alignment and Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03471</link><description>EpiQAL presents a novel benchmark for evaluating epidemiological reasoning in language models through three distinct subsets measuring factual recall, multi-step inference, and conclusion reconstruction from scientific literature.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reliable epidemiological reasoning requires synthesizing study evidence to infer disease burden, transmission dynamics, and intervention effects at the population level. Existing medical question answering benchmarks primarily emphasize clinical knowledge or patient-level reasoning, yet few systematically evaluate evidence-grounded epidemiological inference. We present EpiQAL, the first diagnostic benchmark for epidemiological question answering across diverse diseases, comprising three subsets built from open-access literature. The subsets respectively evaluate text-grounded factual recall, multi-step inference linking document evidence with epidemiological principles, and conclusion reconstruction with the Discussion section withheld. Construction combines expert-designed taxonomy guidance, multi-model verification, and retrieval-based difficulty control. Experiments on ten open models reveal that current LLMs show limited performance on epidemiological reasoning, with multi-step inference posing the greatest challenge. Model rankings shift across subsets, and scale alone does not predict success. Chain-of-Thought prompting benefits multi-step inference but yields mixed results elsewhere. EpiQAL provides fine-grained diagnostic signals for evidence grounding, inferential reasoning, and conclusion reconstruction.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:42:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03471</guid></item><item><title>Agentic Rubrics as Contextual Verifiers for SWE Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.04171</link><description>Agentic Rubrics enable efficient and scalable verification for software engineering agents by creating context-aware checklists that outperform traditional methods while maintaining interpretability.  					AI-generated summary 				 Verification is critical for improving agents: it provides the reward signal for Reinforcement Learning and enables inference-time gains through Test-Time Scaling (TTS). Despite its importance, verification in software engineering (SWE) agent settings often relies on code execution, which can be difficult to scale due to environment setup overhead. Scalable alternatives such as patch classifiers and heuristic methods exist, but they are less grounded in codebase context and harder to interpret. To this end, we explore Agentic Rubrics: an expert agent interacts with the repository to create a context-grounded rubric checklist, and candidate patches are then scored against it without requiring test execution. On SWE-Bench Verified under parallel TTS evaluation, Agentic Rubrics achieve a score of 54.2% on Qwen3-Coder-30B-A3B and 40.6% on Qwen3-32B, with at least a +3.5 percentage-point gain over the strongest baseline in our comparison set. We further analyze rubric behavior, showing that rubric scores are consistent with ground-truth tests while also flagging issues that tests do not capture. Our ablations show that agentic context gathering is essential for producing codebase-specific, unambiguous criteria. Together, these results suggest that Agentic Rubrics provide an efficient, scalable, and granular verification signal for SWE agents.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:41:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.04171</guid></item><item><title>MDAgent2: Large Language Model for Code Generation and Knowledge Q&amp;A in Molecular Dynamics</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.02075</link><description>MDAgent2 enables automated molecular dynamics code generation and question answering through domain-adapted language models and a multi-agent runtime system.  					AI-generated summary 				 Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations are essential for understanding atomic-scale behaviors in materials science, yet writing LAMMPS scripts remains highly specialized and time-consuming tasks. Although LLMs show promise in code generation and domain-specific question answering, their performance in MD scenarios is limited by scarce domain data, the high deployment cost of state-of-the-art LLMs, and low code executability. Building upon our prior MDAgent, we present MDAgent2, the first end-to-end framework capable of performing both knowledge Q&amp;A and code generation within the MD domain. We construct a domain-specific data-construction pipeline that yields three high-quality datasets spanning MD knowledge, question answering, and code generation. Based on these datasets, we adopt a three stage post-training strategy--continued pre-training (CPT), supervised fine-tuning (SFT), and reinforcement learning (RL)--to train two domain-adapted models, MD-Instruct and MD-Code. Furthermore, we introduce MD-GRPO, a closed-loop RL method that leverages simulation outcomes as reward signals and recycles low-reward trajectories for continual refinement. We further build MDAgent2-RUNTIME, a deployable multi-agent system that integrates code generation, execution, evaluation, and self-correction. Together with MD-EvalBench proposed in this work, the first benchmark for LAMMPS code generation and question answering, our models and system achieve performance surpassing several strong baselines.This work systematically demonstrates the adaptability and generalization capability of large language models in industrial simulation tasks, laying a methodological foundation for automatic code generation in AI for Science and industrial-scale simulations. URL: https://github.com/FredericVAN/PKU_MDAgent2</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:46:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.02075</guid></item><item><title>ThinkRL-Edit: Thinking in Reinforcement Learning for Reasoning-Centric Image Editing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03467</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:30:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03467</guid></item></channel></rss>