<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>A.S.E: A Repository-Level Benchmark for Evaluating Security in
  AI-Generated Code</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.18106</link><description>A.S.E is a benchmark for evaluating the security of code generated by large language models using real-world repositories and expert-defined rules, revealing insights into model performance and decoding strategies.  					AI-generated summary 				 The increasing adoption of large language models (LLMs) in software engineering necessitates rigorous security evaluation of their generated code. However, existing benchmarks are inadequate, as they focus on isolated code snippets, employ unstable evaluation methods that lack reproducibility, and fail to connect the quality of input context with the security of the output. To address these gaps, we introduce A.S.E (AI Code Generation Security Evaluation), a benchmark for repository-level secure code generation. A.S.E constructs tasks from real-world repositories with documented CVEs, preserving full repository context like build systems and cross-file dependencies. Its reproducible, containerized evaluation framework uses expert-defined rules to provide stable, auditable assessments of security, build quality, and generation stability. Our evaluation of leading LLMs on A.S.E reveals three key findings: (1) Claude-3.7-Sonnet achieves the best overall performance. (2) The security gap between proprietary and open-source models is narrow; Qwen3-235B-A22B-Instruct attains the top security score. (3) Concise, ``fast-thinking'' decoding strategies consistently outperform complex, ``slow-thinking'' reasoning for security patching.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 03:03:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.18106</guid></item><item><title>EmbodiedOneVision: Interleaved Vision-Text-Action Pretraining for
  General Robot Control</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21112</link><description>EO-Robotics, comprising EO-1 model and EO-Data1.5M dataset, advances multimodal embodied reasoning and robot control through interleaved vision-text-action pre-training.  					AI-generated summary 				 The human ability to seamlessly perform multimodal reasoning and physical interaction in the open world is a core goal for general-purpose embodied intelligent systems. Recent vision-language-action (VLA) models, which are co-trained on large-scale robot and visual-text data, have demonstrated notable progress in general robot control. However, they still fail to achieve human-level flexibility in interleaved reasoning and interaction. In this work, introduce EO-Robotics, consists of EO-1 model and EO-Data1.5M dataset. EO-1 is a unified embodied foundation model that achieves superior performance in multimodal embodied reasoning and robot control through interleaved vision-text-action pre-training. The development of EO-1 is based on two key pillars: (i) a unified architecture that processes multimodal inputs indiscriminately (image, text, video, and action), and (ii) a massive, high-quality multimodal embodied reasoning dataset, EO-Data1.5M, which contains over 1.5 million samples with emphasis on interleaved vision-text-action comprehension. EO-1 is trained through synergies between auto-regressive decoding and flow matching denoising on EO-Data1.5M, enabling seamless robot action generation and multimodal embodied reasoning. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of interleaved vision-text-action learning for open-world understanding and generalization, validated through a variety of long-horizon, dexterous manipulation tasks across multiple embodiments. This paper details the architecture of EO-1, the data construction strategy of EO-Data1.5M, and the training methodology, offering valuable insights for developing advanced embodied foundation models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 01:34:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21112</guid></item><item><title>R-4B: Incentivizing General-Purpose Auto-Thinking Capability in MLLMs
  via Bi-Mode Annealing and Reinforce Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21113</link><description>R-4B, an auto-thinking multimodal large language model, uses bi-mode annealing and Bi-mode Policy Optimization to adaptively decide on problem-solving strategies, achieving state-of-the-art performance with lower computational cost.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) equipped with step-by-step thinking capabilities have demonstrated remarkable performance on complex reasoning problems. However, this thinking process is redundant for simple problems solvable without complex reasoning. To address this inefficiency, we propose R-4B, an auto-thinking MLLM, which can adaptively decide when to think based on problem complexity. The central idea of R-4B is to empower the model with both thinking and non-thinking capabilities using bi-mode annealing, and apply Bi-mode Policy Optimization~(BPO) to improve the model's accuracy in determining whether to activate the thinking process. Specifically, we first train the model on a carefully curated dataset spanning various topics, which contains samples from both thinking and non-thinking modes. Then it undergoes a second phase of training under an improved GRPO framework, where the policy model is forced to generate responses from both modes for each input query. Experimental results show that R-4B achieves state-of-the-art performance across 25 challenging benchmarks. It outperforms Qwen2.5-VL-7B in most tasks and achieves performance comparable to larger models such as Kimi-VL-A3B-Thinking-2506 (16B) on reasoning-intensive benchmarks with lower computational cost.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 01:40:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21113</guid></item><item><title>TalkVid: A Large-Scale Diversified Dataset for Audio-Driven Talking Head
  Synthesis</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.13618</link><description>TalkVid, a large-scale, high-quality, and diverse dataset, improves audio-driven talking head synthesis by enhancing generalization across human diversity and revealing subgroup performance disparities.  					AI-generated summary 				 Audio-driven talking head synthesis has achieved remarkable photorealism, yet state-of-the-art (SOTA) models exhibit a critical failure: they lack generalization to the full spectrum of human diversity in ethnicity, language, and age groups. We argue that this generalization gap is a direct symptom of limitations in existing training data, which lack the necessary scale, quality, and diversity. To address this challenge, we introduce TalkVid, a new large-scale, high-quality, and diverse dataset containing 1244 hours of video from 7729 unique speakers. TalkVid is curated through a principled, multi-stage automated pipeline that rigorously filters for motion stability, aesthetic quality, and facial detail, and is validated against human judgments to ensure its reliability. Furthermore, we construct and release TalkVid-Bench, a stratified evaluation set of 500 clips meticulously balanced across key demographic and linguistic axes. Our experiments demonstrate that a model trained on TalkVid outperforms counterparts trained on previous datasets, exhibiting superior cross-dataset generalization. Crucially, our analysis on TalkVid-Bench reveals performance disparities across subgroups that are obscured by traditional aggregate metrics, underscoring its necessity for future research. Code and data can be found in https://github.com/FreedomIntelligence/TalkVid</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 03:23:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.13618</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Code Embeddings from Code Generation Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21290</link><description>Jina-code-embeddings uses an autoregressive backbone pre-trained on text and code to generate embeddings for code retrieval, question-answering, and similarity identification.  					AI-generated summary 				 jina-code-embeddings is a novel code embedding model suite designed to retrieve code from natural language queries, perform technical question-answering, and identify semantically similar code snippets across programming languages. It makes innovative use of an autoregressive backbone pre-trained on both text and code, generating embeddings via last-token pooling. We outline the training recipe and demonstrate state-of-the-art performance despite the relatively small size of the models, validating this approach to code embedding model construction.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 04:33:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21290</guid></item><item><title>TiKMiX: Take Data Influence into Dynamic Mixture for Language Model
  Pre-training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.17677</link><description>Dynamic adjustment of data mixture based on Group Influence metric improves language model performance by adapting to evolving learning preferences.  					AI-generated summary 				 The data mixture used in the pre-training of a language model is a cornerstone of its final performance. However, a static mixing strategy is suboptimal, as the model's learning preferences for various data domains shift dynamically throughout training. Crucially, observing these evolving preferences in a computationally efficient manner remains a significant challenge. To address this, we propose TiKMiX, a method that dynamically adjusts the data mixture according to the model's evolving preferences. TiKMiX introduces Group Influence, an efficient metric for evaluating the impact of data domains on the model. This metric enables the formulation of the data mixing problem as a search for an optimal, influence-maximizing distribution. We solve this via two approaches: TiKMiX-D for direct optimization, and TiKMiX-M, which uses a regression model to predict a superior mixture. We trained models with different numbers of parameters, on up to 1 trillion tokens. TiKMiX-D exceeds the performance of state-of-the-art methods like REGMIX while using just 20% of the computational resources. TiKMiX-M leads to an average performance gain of 2% across 9 downstream benchmarks. Our experiments reveal that a model's data preferences evolve with training progress and scale, and we demonstrate that dynamically adjusting the data mixture based on Group Influence, a direct measure of these preferences, significantly improves performance by mitigating the underdigestion of data seen with static ratios.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 03:39:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.17677</guid></item><item><title>UItron: Foundational GUI Agent with Advanced Perception and Planning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21767</link><description>UItron, an open-source foundational model for GUI agents, enhances visual understanding and task planning through advanced perception, grounding, and planning capabilities, achieving superior performance in Chinese app scenarios.  					AI-generated summary 				 GUI agent aims to enable automated operations on Mobile/PC devices, which is an important task toward achieving artificial general intelligence. The rapid advancement of VLMs accelerates the development of GUI agents, owing to their powerful capabilities in visual understanding and task planning. However, building a GUI agent remains a challenging task due to the scarcity of operation trajectories, the availability of interactive infrastructure, and the limitation of initial capabilities in foundation models. In this work, we introduce UItron, an open-source foundational model for automatic GUI agents, featuring advanced GUI perception, grounding, and planning capabilities. UItron highlights the necessity of systemic data engineering and interactive infrastructure as foundational components for advancing GUI agent development. It not only systematically studies a series of data engineering strategies to enhance training effects, but also establishes an interactive environment connecting both Mobile and PC devices. In training, UItron adopts supervised finetuning over perception and planning tasks in various GUI scenarios, and then develop a curriculum reinforcement learning framework to enable complex reasoning and exploration for online environments. As a result, UItron achieves superior performance in benchmarks of GUI perception, grounding, and planning. In particular, UItron highlights the interaction proficiency with top-tier Chinese mobile APPs, as we identified a general lack of Chinese capabilities even in state-of-the-art solutions. To this end, we manually collect over one million steps of operation trajectories across the top 100 most popular apps, and build the offline and online agent evaluation environments. Experimental results demonstrate that UItron achieves significant progress in Chinese app scenarios, propelling GUI agents one step closer to real-world application.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 03:17:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21767</guid></item><item><title>Morae: Proactively Pausing UI Agents for User Choices</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21456</link><description>Morae, a UI agent, enhances accessibility for BLV users by involving them in decision-making processes during task execution, using large multimodal models to interpret user queries and UI elements.  					AI-generated summary 				 User interface (UI) agents promise to make inaccessible or complex UIs easier to access for blind and low-vision (BLV) users. However, current UI agents typically perform tasks end-to-end without involving users in critical choices or making them aware of important contextual information, thus reducing user agency. For example, in our field study, a BLV participant asked to buy the cheapest available sparkling water, and the agent automatically chose one from several equally priced options, without mentioning alternative products with different flavors or better ratings. To address this problem, we introduce Morae, a UI agent that automatically identifies decision points during task execution and pauses so that users can make choices. Morae uses large multimodal models to interpret user queries alongside UI code and screenshots, and prompt users for clarification when there is a choice to be made. In a study over real-world web tasks with BLV participants, Morae helped users complete more tasks and select options that better matched their preferences, as compared to baseline agents, including OpenAI Operator. More broadly, this work exemplifies a mixed-initiative approach in which users benefit from the automation of UI agents while being able to express their preferences.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 03:15:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21456</guid></item><item><title>AHELM: A Holistic Evaluation of Audio-Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21376</link><description>AHELM is a comprehensive benchmark for audio-language models that evaluates multiple aspects including fairness, safety, and reasoning across various datasets and models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Evaluations of audio-language models (ALMs) -- multimodal models that take interleaved audio and text as input and output text -- are hindered by the lack of standardized benchmarks; most benchmarks measure only one or two capabilities and omit evaluative aspects such as fairness or safety. Furthermore, comparison across models is difficult as separate evaluations test a limited number of models and use different prompting methods and inference parameters. To address these shortfalls, we introduce AHELM, a benchmark that aggregates various datasets -- including 2 new synthetic audio-text datasets called PARADE, which evaluates the ALMs on avoiding stereotypes, and CoRe-Bench, which measures reasoning over conversational audio through inferential multi-turn question answering -- to holistically measure the performance of ALMs across 10 aspects we have identified as important to the development and usage of ALMs: audio perception, knowledge, reasoning, emotion detection, bias, fairness, multilinguality, robustness, toxicity, and safety. We also standardize the prompts, inference parameters, and evaluation metrics to ensure equitable comparisons across models. We test 14 open-weight and closed-API ALMs from 3 developers and 3 additional simple baseline systems each consisting of an automatic speech recognizer and a language model. Our results show that while Gemini 2.5 Pro ranks top in 5 out of 10 aspects, it exhibits group unfairness (p=0.01) on ASR tasks whereas most of the other models do not. We also find that the baseline systems perform reasonably well on AHELM, with one ranking 5th overall despite having only speech-to-text capabilities. For transparency, all raw prompts, model generations, and outputs are available on our website at https://crfm.stanford.edu/helm/audio/v1.0.0. AHELM is intended to be a living benchmark and new datasets and models will be added over time.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 03:25:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21376</guid></item><item><title>Think in Games: Learning to Reason in Games via Reinforcement Learning
  with Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21365</link><description>Think in Games (TiG) framework enables large language models to develop procedural knowledge through interactive game environments, achieving competitive performance with reduced data and computational demands while providing transparent explanations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) excel at complex reasoning tasks such as mathematics and coding, yet they frequently struggle with simple interactive tasks that young children perform effortlessly. This discrepancy highlights a critical gap between declarative knowledge (knowing about something) and procedural knowledge (knowing how to do something). Although traditional reinforcement learning (RL) agents can acquire procedural knowledge through environmental interaction, they often operate as black boxes and require substantial training data. In contrast, LLMs possess extensive world knowledge and reasoning capabilities, but are unable to effectively convert this static knowledge into dynamic decision-making in interactive settings. To address this challenge, we propose Think in Games (TiG), a novel framework that empowers LLMs to develop procedural understanding through direct interaction with game environments, while retaining their inherent reasoning and explanatory abilities. Specifically, TiG reformulates RL-based decision-making as a language modeling task: LLMs generate language-guided policies, which are refined iteratively through online reinforcement learning based on environmental feedback. Our experimental results show that TiG successfully bridges the gap between declarative and procedural knowledge, achieving competitive performance with dramatically lower data and computational demands compared to conventional RL methods. Moreover, TiG provides step-by-step natural language explanations for its decisions, greatly improving transparency and interpretability in complex interactive tasks.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 03:50:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.21365</guid></item><item><title>HERMES: Human-to-Robot Embodied Learning from Multi-Source Motion Data
  for Mobile Dexterous Manipulation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.20085</link><description>HERMES is a human-to-robot learning framework that translates human hand motions into robotic behaviors, using reinforcement learning and sim2real transfer for versatile manipulation in diverse environments.  					AI-generated summary 				 Leveraging human motion data to impart robots with versatile manipulation skills has emerged as a promising paradigm in robotic manipulation. Nevertheless, translating multi-source human hand motions into feasible robot behaviors remains challenging, particularly for robots equipped with multi-fingered dexterous hands characterized by complex, high-dimensional action spaces. Moreover, existing approaches often struggle to produce policies capable of adapting to diverse environmental conditions. In this paper, we introduce HERMES, a human-to-robot learning framework for mobile bimanual dexterous manipulation. First, HERMES formulates a unified reinforcement learning approach capable of seamlessly transforming heterogeneous human hand motions from multiple sources into physically plausible robotic behaviors. Subsequently, to mitigate the sim2real gap, we devise an end-to-end, depth image-based sim2real transfer method for improved generalization to real-world scenarios. Furthermore, to enable autonomous operation in varied and unstructured environments, we augment the navigation foundation model with a closed-loop Perspective-n-Point (PnP) localization mechanism, ensuring precise alignment of visual goals and effectively bridging autonomous navigation and dexterous manipulation. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that HERMES consistently exhibits generalizable behaviors across diverse, in-the-wild scenarios, successfully performing numerous complex mobile bimanual dexterous manipulation tasks. Project Page:https://gemcollector.github.io/HERMES/.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 04:44:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.20085</guid></item></channel></rss>