<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Genius: A Generalizable and Purely Unsupervised Self-Training Framework
  For Advanced Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.08672</link><description>Advancing LLM reasoning skills has captivated wide interest. However, current post-training techniques rely heavily on supervisory signals, such as outcome supervision or auxiliary reward models, which face the problem of scalability and high annotation costs. This motivates us to enhance LLM reasoning without the need for external supervision. We introduce a generalizable and purely unsupervised self-training framework, named Genius. Without external auxiliary, Genius requires to seek the optimal response sequence in a stepwise manner and optimize the LLM. To explore the potential steps and exploit the optimal ones, Genius introduces a stepwise foresight re-sampling strategy to sample and estimate the step value by simulating future outcomes. Further, we recognize that the unsupervised setting inevitably induces the intrinsic noise and uncertainty. To provide a robust optimization, we propose an advantage-calibrated optimization (ACO) loss function to mitigate estimation inconsistencies. Combining these techniques together, Genius provides an advanced initial step towards self-improve LLM reasoning with general queries and without supervision, revolutionizing reasoning scaling laws given the vast availability of general queries. The code will be released at https://github.com/xufangzhi/Genius.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:16:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.08672</guid></item><item><title>xVerify: Efficient Answer Verifier for Reasoning Model Evaluations</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10481</link><description>With the release of the o1 model by OpenAI, reasoning models adopting slow thinking strategies have gradually emerged. As the responses generated by such models often include complex reasoning, intermediate steps, and self-reflection, existing evaluation methods are often inadequate. They struggle to determine whether the LLM output is truly equivalent to the reference answer, and also have difficulty identifying and extracting the final answer from long, complex responses. To address this issue, we propose xVerify, an efficient answer verifier for reasoning model evaluations. xVerify demonstrates strong capability in equivalence judgment, enabling it to effectively determine whether the answers produced by reasoning models are equivalent to reference answers across various types of objective questions. To train and evaluate xVerify, we construct the VAR dataset by collecting question-answer pairs generated by multiple LLMs across various datasets, leveraging multiple reasoning models and challenging evaluation sets designed specifically for reasoning model assessment. A multi-round annotation process is employed to ensure label accuracy. Based on the VAR dataset, we train multiple xVerify models of different scales. In evaluation experiments conducted on both the test set and generalization set, all xVerify models achieve overall F1 scores and accuracy exceeding 95\%. Notably, the smallest variant, xVerify-0.5B-I, outperforms all evaluation methods except GPT-4o, while xVerify-3B-Ib surpasses GPT-4o in overall performance. These results validate the effectiveness and generalizability of xVerify.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 02:23:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10481</guid></item><item><title>Heimdall: test-time scaling on the generative verification</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10337</link><description>An AI system can create and maintain knowledge only to the extent that it can verify that knowledge itself. Recent work on long Chain-of-Thought reasoning has demonstrated great potential of LLMs on solving competitive problems, but their verification ability remains to be weak and not sufficiently investigated. In this paper, we propose Heimdall, the long CoT verification LLM that can accurately judge the correctness of solutions. With pure reinforcement learning, we boost the verification accuracy from 62.5% to 94.5% on competitive math problems. By scaling with repeated sampling, the accuracy further increases to 97.5%. Through human evaluation, Heimdall demonstrates impressive generalization capabilities, successfully detecting most issues in challenging math proofs, the type of which is not included during training. Furthermore, we propose Pessimistic Verification to extend the functionality of Heimdall to scaling up the problem solving. It calls Heimdall to judge the solutions from a solver model and based on the pessimistic principle, selects the most likely correct solution with the least uncertainty. Taking DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-32B as the solver model, Pessimistic Verification improves the solution accuracy on AIME2025 from 54.2% to 70.0% with 16x compute budget and to 83.3% with more compute budget. With the stronger solver Gemini 2.5 Pro, the score reaches 93.0%. Finally, we prototype an automatic knowledge discovery system, a ternary system where one poses questions, another provides solutions, and the third verifies the solutions. Using the data synthesis work NuminaMath for the first two components, Heimdall effectively identifies problematic records within the dataset and reveals that nearly half of the data is flawed, which interestingly aligns with the recent ablation studies from NuminaMath.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 02:22:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10337</guid></item><item><title>Pixel-SAIL: Single Transformer For Pixel-Grounded Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10465</link><description>Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) achieve remarkable performance for fine-grained pixel-level understanding tasks. However, all the works rely heavily on extra components, such as vision encoder (CLIP), segmentation experts, leading to high system complexity and limiting model scaling. In this work, our goal is to explore a highly simplified MLLM without introducing extra components. Our work is motivated by the recent works on Single trAnsformer as a unified vIsion-Language Model (SAIL) design, where these works jointly learn vision tokens and text tokens in transformers. We present Pixel-SAIL, a single transformer for pixel-wise MLLM tasks. In particular, we present three technical improvements on the plain baseline. First, we design a learnable upsampling module to refine visual token features. Secondly, we propose a novel visual prompt injection strategy to enable the single transformer to understand visual prompt inputs and benefit from the early fusion of visual prompt embeddings and vision tokens. Thirdly, we introduce a vision expert distillation strategy to efficiently enhance the single transformer's fine-grained feature extraction capability. In addition, we have collected a comprehensive pixel understanding benchmark (PerBench), using a manual check. It includes three tasks: detailed object description, visual prompt-based question answering, and visual-text referring segmentation. Extensive experiments on four referring segmentation benchmarks, one visual prompt benchmark, and our PerBench show that our Pixel-SAIL achieves comparable or even better results with a much simpler pipeline. Code and model will be released at https://github.com/magic-research/Sa2VA.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 03:41:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10465</guid></item><item><title>Seedream 3.0 Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11346</link><description>We present Seedream 3.0, a high-performance Chinese-English bilingual image generation foundation model. We develop several technical improvements to address existing challenges in Seedream 2.0, including alignment with complicated prompts, fine-grained typography generation, suboptimal visual aesthetics and fidelity, and limited image resolutions. Specifically, the advancements of Seedream 3.0 stem from improvements across the entire pipeline, from data construction to model deployment. At the data stratum, we double the dataset using a defect-aware training paradigm and a dual-axis collaborative data-sampling framework. Furthermore, we adopt several effective techniques such as mixed-resolution training, cross-modality RoPE, representation alignment loss, and resolution-aware timestep sampling in the pre-training phase. During the post-training stage, we utilize diversified aesthetic captions in SFT, and a VLM-based reward model with scaling, thereby achieving outputs that well align with human preferences. Furthermore, Seedream 3.0 pioneers a novel acceleration paradigm. By employing consistent noise expectation and importance-aware timestep sampling, we achieve a 4 to 8 times speedup while maintaining image quality. Seedream 3.0 demonstrates significant improvements over Seedream 2.0: it enhances overall capabilities, in particular for text-rendering in complicated Chinese characters which is important to professional typography generation. In addition, it provides native high-resolution output (up to 2K), allowing it to generate images with high visual quality.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 02:40:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11346</guid></item><item><title>TextArena</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11442</link><description>TextArena is an open-source collection of competitive text-based games for training and evaluation of agentic behavior in Large Language Models (LLMs). It spans 57+ unique environments (including single-player, two-player, and multi-player setups) and allows for easy evaluation of model capabilities via an online-play system (against humans and other submitted models) with real-time TrueSkill scores. Traditional benchmarks rarely assess dynamic social skills such as negotiation, theory of mind, and deception, creating a gap that TextArena addresses. Designed with research, community and extensibility in mind, TextArena emphasizes ease of adding new games, adapting the framework, testing models, playing against the models, and training models. Detailed documentation of environments, games, leaderboard, and examples are available on https://github.com/LeonGuertler/TextArena and https://www.textarena.ai/.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 02:21:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11442</guid></item><item><title>How Instruction and Reasoning Data shape Post-Training: Data Quality
  through the Lens of Layer-wise Gradients</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10766</link><description>As the post-training of large language models (LLMs) advances from instruction-following to complex reasoning tasks, understanding how different data affect finetuning dynamics remains largely unexplored. In this paper, we present a spectral analysis of layer-wise gradients induced by low/high-quality instruction and reasoning data for LLM post-training. Our analysis reveals that widely-studied metrics for data evaluation, e.g., IFD, InsTag, Difficulty, and Reward, can be explained and unified by spectral properties computed from gradients' singular value decomposition (SVD). Specifically, higher-quality data are usually associated with lower nuclear norms and higher effective ranks. Notably, effective rank exhibits better robustness and resolution than nuclear norm in capturing subtle quality differences. For example, reasoning data achieves substantially higher effective ranks than instruction data, implying richer gradient structures on more complex tasks. Our experiments also highlight that models within the same family share similar gradient patterns regardless of their sizes, whereas different model families diverge significantly. Providing a unified view on the effects of data quality across instruction and reasoning data, this work illuminates the interplay between data quality and training stability, shedding novel insights into developing better data exploration strategies for post-training.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 02:10:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10766</guid></item><item><title>The Scalability of Simplicity: Empirical Analysis of Vision-Language
  Learning with a Single Transformer</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10462</link><description>This paper introduces SAIL, a single transformer unified multimodal large language model (MLLM) that integrates raw pixel encoding and language decoding within a singular architecture. Unlike existing modular MLLMs, which rely on a pre-trained vision transformer (ViT), SAIL eliminates the need for a separate vision encoder, presenting a more minimalist architecture design. Instead of introducing novel architectural components, SAIL adapts mix-attention mechanisms and multimodal positional encodings to better align with the distinct characteristics of visual and textual modalities. We systematically compare SAIL's properties-including scalability, cross-modal information flow patterns, and visual representation capabilities-with those of modular MLLMs. By scaling both training data and model size, SAIL achieves performance comparable to modular MLLMs. Notably, the removal of pretrained ViT components enhances SAIL's scalability and results in significantly different cross-modal information flow patterns. Moreover, SAIL demonstrates strong visual representation capabilities, achieving results on par with ViT-22B in vision tasks such as semantic segmentation. Code and models are available at https://github.com/bytedance/SAIL.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 03:57:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10462</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Process Reward Model Training via Active Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10559</link><description>Process Reward Models (PRMs) provide step-level supervision to large language models (LLMs), but scaling up training data annotation remains challenging for both humans and LLMs. To address this limitation, we propose an active learning approach, ActPRM, which proactively selects the most uncertain samples for training, substantially reducing labeling costs. During training, we use the PRM to estimate uncertainty after the forward pass, retaining only highly uncertain data. A capable yet costly reasoning model then labels this data. Then we compute the loss with respect to the labels and update the PRM's weights. We compare ActPRM vs. vanilla fine-tuning, on a pool-based active learning setting, demonstrating that ActPRM reduces 50% annotation, but achieving the comparable or even better performance. Beyond annotation efficiency, we further advance the actively trained PRM by filtering over 1M+ math reasoning trajectories with ActPRM, retaining 60% of the data. A subsequent training on this selected dataset yields a new state-of-the-art (SOTA) PRM on ProcessBench (75.0%) and PRMBench (65.5%) compared with same sized models.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 03:04:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10559</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Reasoning Models: A Survey</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10903</link><description>Reasoning models have demonstrated remarkable progress in solving complex and logic-intensive tasks by generating extended Chain-of-Thoughts (CoTs) prior to arriving at a final answer. Yet, the emergence of this "slow-thinking" paradigm, with numerous tokens generated in sequence, inevitably introduces substantial computational overhead. To this end, it highlights an urgent need for effective acceleration. This survey aims to provide a comprehensive overview of recent advances in efficient reasoning. It categorizes existing works into three key directions: (1) shorter - compressing lengthy CoTs into concise yet effective reasoning chains; (2) smaller - developing compact language models with strong reasoning capabilities through techniques such as knowledge distillation, other model compression techniques, and reinforcement learning; and (3) faster - designing efficient decoding strategies to accelerate inference. A curated collection of papers discussed in this survey is available in our GitHub repository.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:43:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10903</guid></item><item><title>A Minimalist Approach to LLM Reasoning: from Rejection Sampling to
  Reinforce</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11343</link><description>Reinforcement learning (RL) has become a prevailing approach for fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) on complex reasoning tasks. Among recent methods, GRPO stands out for its empirical success in training models such as DeepSeek-R1, yet the sources of its effectiveness remain poorly understood. In this work, we revisit GRPO from a reinforce-like algorithm perspective and analyze its core components. Surprisingly, we find that a simple rejection sampling baseline, RAFT, which trains only on positively rewarded samples, yields competitive performance than GRPO and PPO. Our ablation studies reveal that GRPO's main advantage arises from discarding prompts with entirely incorrect responses, rather than from its reward normalization. Motivated by this insight, we propose Reinforce-Rej, a minimal extension of policy gradient that filters both entirely incorrect and entirely correct samples. Reinforce-Rej improves KL efficiency and stability, serving as a lightweight yet effective alternative to more complex RL algorithms. We advocate RAFT as a robust and interpretable baseline, and suggest that future advances should focus on more principled designs for incorporating negative samples, rather than relying on them indiscriminately. Our findings provide guidance for future work in reward-based LLM post-training.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 04:09:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11343</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Generative Model Training via Embedded Representation Warmup</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10188</link><description>Diffusion models excel at generating high-dimensional data but fall short in training efficiency and representation quality compared to self-supervised methods. We identify a key bottleneck: the underutilization of high-quality, semantically rich representations during training notably slows down convergence. Our systematic analysis reveals a critical representation processing region -- primarily in the early layers -- where semantic and structural pattern learning takes place before generation can occur. To address this, we propose Embedded Representation Warmup (ERW), a plug-and-play framework where in the first stage we get the ERW module serves as a warmup that initializes the early layers of the diffusion model with high-quality, pretrained representations. This warmup minimizes the burden of learning representations from scratch, thereby accelerating convergence and boosting performance. Our theoretical analysis demonstrates that ERW's efficacy depends on its precise integration into specific neural network layers -- termed the representation processing region -- where the model primarily processes and transforms feature representations for later generation. We further establish that ERW not only accelerates training convergence but also enhances representation quality: empirically, our method achieves a 40times acceleration in training speed compared to REPA, the current state-of-the-art methods. Code is available at https://github.com/LINs-lab/ERW.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 04:33:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10188</guid></item><item><title>NormalCrafter: Learning Temporally Consistent Normals from Video
  Diffusion Priors</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11427</link><description>Surface normal estimation serves as a cornerstone for a spectrum of computer vision applications. While numerous efforts have been devoted to static image scenarios, ensuring temporal coherence in video-based normal estimation remains a formidable challenge. Instead of merely augmenting existing methods with temporal components, we present NormalCrafter to leverage the inherent temporal priors of video diffusion models. To secure high-fidelity normal estimation across sequences, we propose Semantic Feature Regularization (SFR), which aligns diffusion features with semantic cues, encouraging the model to concentrate on the intrinsic semantics of the scene. Moreover, we introduce a two-stage training protocol that leverages both latent and pixel space learning to preserve spatial accuracy while maintaining long temporal context. Extensive evaluations demonstrate the efficacy of our method, showcasing a superior performance in generating temporally consistent normal sequences with intricate details from diverse videos.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 02:58:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11427</guid></item><item><title>PVUW 2025 Challenge Report: Advances in Pixel-level Understanding of
  Complex Videos in the Wild</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11326</link><description>This report provides a comprehensive overview of the 4th Pixel-level Video Understanding in the Wild (PVUW) Challenge, held in conjunction with CVPR 2025. It summarizes the challenge outcomes, participating methodologies, and future research directions. The challenge features two tracks: MOSE, which focuses on complex scene video object segmentation, and MeViS, which targets motion-guided, language-based video segmentation. Both tracks introduce new, more challenging datasets designed to better reflect real-world scenarios. Through detailed evaluation and analysis, the challenge offers valuable insights into the current state-of-the-art and emerging trends in complex video segmentation. More information can be found on the workshop website: https://pvuw.github.io/.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 03:56:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11326</guid></item><item><title>ReZero: Enhancing LLM search ability by trying one-more-time</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11001</link><description>Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) improves Large Language Model (LLM) performance on knowledge-intensive tasks but depends heavily on initial search query quality. Current methods, often using Reinforcement Learning (RL), typically focus on query formulation or reasoning over results, without explicitly encouraging persistence after a failed search. We introduce ReZero (Retry-Zero), a novel RL framework that directly rewards the act of retrying a search query following an initial unsuccessful attempt. This incentivizes the LLM to explore alternative queries rather than prematurely halting. ReZero demonstrates significant improvement, achieving 46.88% accuracy compared to a 25% baseline. By rewarding persistence, ReZero enhances LLM robustness in complex information-seeking scenarios where initial queries may prove insufficient.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 06:19:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11001</guid></item><item><title>DeepMath-103K: A Large-Scale, Challenging, Decontaminated, and
  Verifiable Mathematical Dataset for Advancing Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11456</link><description>The capacity for complex mathematical reasoning is a key benchmark for artificial intelligence. While reinforcement learning (RL) applied to LLMs shows promise, progress is significantly hindered by the lack of large-scale training data that is sufficiently challenging, possesses verifiable answer formats suitable for RL, and is free from contamination with evaluation benchmarks. To address these limitations, we introduce DeepMath-103K, a new, large-scale dataset comprising approximately 103K mathematical problems, specifically designed to train advanced reasoning models via RL. DeepMath-103K is curated through a rigorous pipeline involving source analysis, stringent decontamination against numerous benchmarks, and filtering for high difficulty (primarily Levels 5-9), significantly exceeding existing open resources in challenge. Each problem includes a verifiable final answer, enabling rule-based RL, and three distinct R1-generated solutions suitable for diverse training paradigms like supervised fine-tuning or distillation. Spanning a wide range of mathematical topics, DeepMath-103K promotes the development of generalizable reasoning. We demonstrate that models trained on DeepMath-103K achieve significant improvements on challenging mathematical benchmarks, validating its effectiveness. We release DeepMath-103K publicly to facilitate community progress in building more capable AI reasoning systems: https://github.com/zwhe99/DeepMath.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 09:39:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11456</guid></item><item><title>Diffusion Distillation With Direct Preference Optimization For Efficient
  3D LiDAR Scene Completion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11447</link><description>The application of diffusion models in 3D LiDAR scene completion is limited due to diffusion's slow sampling speed. Score distillation accelerates diffusion sampling but with performance degradation, while post-training with direct policy optimization (DPO) boosts performance using preference data. This paper proposes Distillation-DPO, a novel diffusion distillation framework for LiDAR scene completion with preference aligment. First, the student model generates paired completion scenes with different initial noises. Second, using LiDAR scene evaluation metrics as preference, we construct winning and losing sample pairs. Such construction is reasonable, since most LiDAR scene metrics are informative but non-differentiable to be optimized directly. Third, Distillation-DPO optimizes the student model by exploiting the difference in score functions between the teacher and student models on the paired completion scenes. Such procedure is repeated until convergence. Extensive experiments demonstrate that, compared to state-of-the-art LiDAR scene completion diffusion models, Distillation-DPO achieves higher-quality scene completion while accelerating the completion speed by more than 5-fold. Our method is the first to explore adopting preference learning in distillation to the best of our knowledge and provide insights into preference-aligned distillation. Our code is public available on https://github.com/happyw1nd/DistillationDPO.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 02:05:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11447</guid></item><item><title>AI-University: An LLM-based platform for instructional alignment to
  scientific classrooms</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.08846</link><description>We introduce AI University (AI-U), a flexible framework for AI-driven course content delivery that adapts to instructors' teaching styles. At its core, AI-U fine-tunes a large language model (LLM) with retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) to generate instructor-aligned responses from lecture videos, notes, and textbooks. Using a graduate-level finite-element-method (FEM) course as a case study, we present a scalable pipeline to systematically construct training data, fine-tune an open-source LLM with Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA), and optimize its responses through RAG-based synthesis. Our evaluation - combining cosine similarity, LLM-based assessment, and expert review - demonstrates strong alignment with course materials. We also have developed a prototype web application, available at https://my-ai-university.com, that enhances traceability by linking AI-generated responses to specific sections of the relevant course material and time-stamped instances of the open-access video lectures. Our expert model is found to have greater cosine similarity with a reference on 86% of test cases. An LLM judge also found our expert model to outperform the base Llama 3.2 model approximately four times out of five. AI-U offers a scalable approach to AI-assisted education, paving the way for broader adoption in higher education. Here, our framework has been presented in the setting of a class on FEM - a subject that is central to training PhD and Master students in engineering science. However, this setting is a particular instance of a broader context: fine-tuning LLMs to research content in science.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 08:51:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.08846</guid></item><item><title>Adaptive Computation Pruning for the Forgetting Transformer</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.06949</link><description>The recently proposed Forgetting Transformer (FoX) incorporates a forget gate into softmax attention and has shown consistently better or on-par performance compared to the standard RoPE-based Transformer. Notably, many attention heads in FoX tend to forget quickly, causing their output at each timestep to rely primarily on the local context. Based on this observation, we propose Adaptive Computation Pruning (ACP) for FoX, a method that dynamically prunes computations involving input-output dependencies that are strongly decayed by the forget gate. This is achieved using a dynamically set pruning threshold that ensures that the pruned attention weights remain negligible. We apply ACP to language model pretraining with FoX and show it consistently reduces the number of FLOPs in softmax attention by around 70% across different model sizes and context lengths, resulting in a roughly 10% to 35% improvement in training throughput. Furthermore, longer context lengths yield greater computational savings. All these speed improvements are achieved without any performance degradation. We also perform several analyses to provide deeper insights into our method, such as examining the pruning patterns and analyzing the distribution of FLOP savings across different attention heads. Our code is available at https://github.com/zhixuan-lin/arctic-fox.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 02:58:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.06949</guid></item><item><title>SimpleAR: Pushing the Frontier of Autoregressive Visual Generation
  through Pretraining, SFT, and RL</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11455</link><description></description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:31:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11455</guid></item><item><title>Multimodal Long Video Modeling Based on Temporal Dynamic Context</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10443</link><description>Recent advances in Large Language Models (LLMs) have led to significant breakthroughs in video understanding. However, existing models still struggle with long video processing due to the context length constraint of LLMs and the vast amount of information within the video. Although some recent methods are designed for long video understanding, they often lose crucial information during token compression and struggle with additional modality like audio. In this work, we propose a dynamic long video encoding method utilizing the temporal relationship between frames, named Temporal Dynamic Context (TDC). Firstly, we segment the video into semantically consistent scenes based on inter-frame similarities, then encode each frame into tokens using visual-audio encoders. Secondly, we propose a novel temporal context compressor to reduce the number of tokens within each segment. Specifically, we employ a query-based Transformer to aggregate video, audio, and instruction text tokens into a limited set of temporal context tokens. Finally, we feed the static frame tokens and the temporal context tokens into the LLM for video understanding. Furthermore, to handle extremely long videos, we propose a training-free chain-of-thought strategy that progressively extracts answers from multiple video segments. These intermediate answers serve as part of the reasoning process and contribute to the final answer. We conduct extensive experiments on general video understanding and audio-video understanding benchmarks, where our method demonstrates strong performance. The code and models are available at https://github.com/Hoar012/TDC-Video.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 11:25:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10443</guid></item><item><title>Summarization of Multimodal Presentations with Vision-Language Models:
  Study of the Effect of Modalities and Structure</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10049</link><description>Vision-Language Models (VLMs) can process visual and textual information in multiple formats: texts, images, interleaved texts and images, or even hour-long videos. In this work, we conduct fine-grained quantitative and qualitative analyses of automatic summarization of multimodal presentations using VLMs with various representations as input. From these experiments, we suggest cost-effective strategies for generating summaries from text-heavy multimodal documents under different input-length budgets using VLMs. We show that slides extracted from the video stream can be beneficially used as input against the raw video, and that a structured representation from interleaved slides and transcript provides the best performance. Finally, we reflect and comment on the nature of cross-modal interactions in multimodal presentations and share suggestions to improve the capabilities of VLMs to understand documents of this nature.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:25:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10049</guid></item><item><title>D^2iT: Dynamic Diffusion Transformer for Accurate Image Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.09454</link><description>Diffusion models are widely recognized for their ability to generate high-fidelity images. Despite the excellent performance and scalability of the Diffusion Transformer (DiT) architecture, it applies fixed compression across different image regions during the diffusion process, disregarding the naturally varying information densities present in these regions. However, large compression leads to limited local realism, while small compression increases computational complexity and compromises global consistency, ultimately impacting the quality of generated images. To address these limitations, we propose dynamically compressing different image regions by recognizing the importance of different regions, and introduce a novel two-stage framework designed to enhance the effectiveness and efficiency of image generation: (1) Dynamic VAE (DVAE) at first stage employs a hierarchical encoder to encode different image regions at different downsampling rates, tailored to their specific information densities, thereby providing more accurate and natural latent codes for the diffusion process. (2) Dynamic Diffusion Transformer (D^2iT) at second stage generates images by predicting multi-grained noise, consisting of coarse-grained (less latent code in smooth regions) and fine-grained (more latent codes in detailed regions), through an novel combination of the Dynamic Grain Transformer and the Dynamic Content Transformer. The strategy of combining rough prediction of noise with detailed regions correction achieves a unification of global consistency and local realism. Comprehensive experiments on various generation tasks validate the effectiveness of our approach. Code will be released at https://github.com/jiawn-creator/Dynamic-DiT.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 08:51:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.09454</guid></item><item><title>VisualPuzzles: Decoupling Multimodal Reasoning Evaluation from Domain
  Knowledge</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10342</link><description>Current multimodal benchmarks often conflate reasoning with domain-specific knowledge, making it difficult to isolate and evaluate general reasoning abilities in non-expert settings. To address this, we introduce VisualPuzzles, a benchmark that targets visual reasoning while deliberately minimizing reliance on specialized knowledge. VisualPuzzles consists of diverse questions spanning five categories: algorithmic, analogical, deductive, inductive, and spatial reasoning. One major source of our questions is manually translated logical reasoning questions from the Chinese Civil Service Examination. Experiments show that VisualPuzzles requires significantly less intensive domain-specific knowledge and more complex reasoning compared to benchmarks like MMMU, enabling us to better evaluate genuine multimodal reasoning. Evaluations show that state-of-the-art multimodal large language models consistently lag behind human performance on VisualPuzzles, and that strong performance on knowledge-intensive benchmarks does not necessarily translate to success on reasoning-focused, knowledge-light tasks. Additionally, reasoning enhancements such as scaling up inference compute (with "thinking" modes) yield inconsistent gains across models and task types, and we observe no clear correlation between model size and performance. We also found that models exhibit different reasoning and answering patterns on VisualPuzzles compared to benchmarks with heavier emphasis on knowledge. VisualPuzzles offers a clearer lens through which to evaluate reasoning capabilities beyond factual recall and domain knowledge.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:03:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.10342</guid></item><item><title>Change State Space Models for Remote Sensing Change Detection</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11080</link><description>Despite their frequent use for change detection, both ConvNets and Vision transformers (ViT) exhibit well-known limitations, namely the former struggle to model long-range dependencies while the latter are computationally inefficient, rendering them challenging to train on large-scale datasets. Vision Mamba, an architecture based on State Space Models has emerged as an alternative addressing the aforementioned deficiencies and has been already applied to remote sensing change detection, though mostly as a feature extracting backbone. In this article the Change State Space Model is introduced, that has been specifically designed for change detection by focusing on the relevant changes between bi-temporal images, effectively filtering out irrelevant information. By concentrating solely on the changed features, the number of network parameters is reduced, enhancing significantly computational efficiency while maintaining high detection performance and robustness against input degradation. The proposed model has been evaluated via three benchmark datasets, where it outperformed ConvNets, ViTs, and Mamba-based counterparts at a fraction of their computational complexity. The implementation will be made available at https://github.com/Elman295/CSSM upon acceptance.</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 11:44:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11080</guid></item><item><title>LazyReview A Dataset for Uncovering Lazy Thinking in NLP Peer Reviews</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11042</link><description>Peer review is a cornerstone of quality control in scientific publishing. With the increasing workload, the unintended use of `quick' heuristics, referred to as lazy thinking, has emerged as a recurring issue compromising review quality. Automated methods to detect such heuristics can help improve the peer-reviewing process. However, there is limited NLP research on this issue, and no real-world dataset exists to support the development of detection tools. This work introduces LazyReview, a dataset of peer-review sentences annotated with fine-grained lazy thinking categories. Our analysis reveals that Large Language Models (LLMs) struggle to detect these instances in a zero-shot setting. However, instruction-based fine-tuning on our dataset significantly boosts performance by 10-20 performance points, highlighting the importance of high-quality training data. Furthermore, a controlled experiment demonstrates that reviews revised with lazy thinking feedback are more comprehensive and actionable than those written without such feedback. We will release our dataset and the enhanced guidelines that can be used to train junior reviewers in the community. (Code available here: https://github.com/UKPLab/arxiv2025-lazy-review)</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 11:12:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.11042</guid></item></channel></rss>