<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>🐦‍🔥 I've just published Sentence Transformers v5.2.0! It introduces multi-processing for CrossEncoder (rerankers), multilingual NanoBEIR evaluators, similarity score outputs in mine_hard_negatives, Transformers v5 support and more. Details:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/tomaarsen/853653818134091</link><description>🐦‍🔥 I've just published Sentence Transformers v5.2.0! It introduces multi-processing for CrossEncoder (rerankers), multilingual NanoBEIR evaluators, similarity score outputs in mine_hard_negatives, Transformers v5 support and more. Details: - CrossEncoder multi-processing: Similar to SentenceTransformer and SparseEncoder, you can now use multi-processing with CrossEncoder rerankers. Useful for multi-GPU and CPU settings, and simple to configure: just device=["cuda:0", "cuda:1"] or device=["cpu"]*4 on the model.predict or model.rank calls. - Multilingual NanoBEIR Support: You can now use community translations of the tiny NanoBEIR retrieval benchmark instead of only the English one, by passing dataset_id , e.g. dataset_id="lightonai/NanoBEIR-de" for the German benchmark. - Similarity scores in Hard Negatives Mining: When mining for hard negatives to create a strong training dataset, you can now pass output_scores=True to get similarity scores returned. This can be useful for some...</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/tomaarsen/853653818134091</guid></item><item><title>ICYMI, you can fine-tune open LLMs using Claude Code</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/384415208092213</link><description>ICYMI, you can fine-tune open LLMs using Claude Code just tell it: “Fine-tune Qwen3-0.6B on open-r1/codeforces-cots” and Claude submits a real training job on HF GPUs using TRL. it handles everything: &gt; dataset validation &gt; GPU selection &gt; training + Trackio monitoring &gt; job submission + cost estimation when it’s done, your model is on the Hub, ready to use read more about the process: https://huggingface.co/blog/hf-skills-training See translation</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/384415208092213</guid></item><item><title>We just released TRL v0.26.0!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/627155943228357</link><description>We just released TRL v0.26.0! It comes packed with updates: &gt; Agent training with tools in GRPO &gt; New CISPO &amp; SAPO losses + reasoning rewards &gt; vLLM quantization in colocate mode &gt; Dataset shuffling in SFT &gt; Lots of NEW examples &gt; Tons of fixes and documentation improvements See translation</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/627155943228357</guid></item><item><title>Z-Image Turbo + LoRA ⚡</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ovi054/902660269971069</link><description>Z-Image Turbo + LoRA ⚡ ovi054/Z-Image-LORA Z-Image Turbo is the No. 1 trending Text-to-Image model right now. You can add a custom LoRA and generate images with this Space. 👉 Try it now: ovi054/Z-Image-LORA See translation</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ovi054/902660269971069</guid></item><item><title>Muon vs MuonClip vs Muon+Adamw</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/KingNish/784885155042758</link><description>Muon vs MuonClip vs Muon+Adamw Muon has gone from an experiment to a mainstream optimizer, but does it hold up for fine‑tuning? We ran head‑to‑head tests on Qwen3‑4B (10k+ high‑quality instruction rows) to find out. Short story: Pure Muon converged fastest at the start, but its gradient‑norm spikes made training unstable. MuonClip (Kimi K2’s clipping) stabilizes long pretraining runs, yet in our small‑scale fine‑tune it underperformed, lower token accuracy and slower convergence. The winner was the hybrid: Muon for 2D layers + AdamW for 1D layers. It delivered the best balance of stability and final performance and even beat vanilla AdamW. Takeaway: for small-scale fine-tuning, hybrid = practical and reliable. Next Step: scale to larger models/datasets to see if Muon’s spikes become catastrophic or if clipping wins out. Full Blog Link: https://huggingface.co/blog/KingNish/optimizer-part1 See translation</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/KingNish/784885155042758</guid></item><item><title>Introducing 🇨🇭WindowSeat🇨🇭 –– our new method for removing reflections from photos taken through windows, on planes, in malls, offices, and other glass-filled environments.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/toshas/756417426105326</link><description>Introducing 🇨🇭WindowSeat🇨🇭 –– our new method for removing reflections from photos taken through windows, on planes, in malls, offices, and other glass-filled environments. Finetuning a foundation diffusion transformer for reflection removal quickly runs up against the limits of what existing datasets and techniques can offer. To fill that gap, we generate physically accurate examples in Blender that simulate realistic glass and reflection effects. This data enables strong performance on both established benchmarks and previously unseen images. To make this practical, the open-source Apache-2 model builds on Qwen-Image-Edit-2509, a 20B image-editing diffusion transformer that runs on a single GPU and can be fine-tuned in about a day. WindowSeat keeps its use of the underlying DiT cleanly separated from the data and training recipe, allowing future advances in base models to be incorporated with minimal friction. Try it out with your own photos in this interactive demo: 🤗...</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/toshas/756417426105326</guid></item><item><title>installama.sh at the TigerBeetle 1000x World Tour !</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/angt/186034800220690</link><description>installama.sh at the TigerBeetle 1000x World Tour ! Last week I had the chance to give a short talk during the TigerBeetle 1000x World Tour (organized by @ jedisct1 👏 ) a fantastic event celebrating high-performance engineering and the people who love pushing systems to their limits! In the talk, I focused on the CPU and Linux side of things, with a simple goal in mind: making the installation of llama.cpp instant, automatic, and optimal, no matter your OS or hardware setup. For the curious, here are the links worth checking out: Event page: https://tigerbeetle.com/event/1000x GitHub repo: https://github.com/angt/installama.sh Talk: https://youtu.be/pg5NOeJZf0o?si=9Dkcfi2TqjnT_30e More improvements are coming soon. Stay tuned! See translation</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/angt/186034800220690</guid></item><item><title>🏆 BEHAVIOR Challenge 1st Place – Solution Summary</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/IliaLarchenko/908879505364910</link><description>🏆 BEHAVIOR Challenge 1st Place – Solution Summary My team recently won 1st place in the BEHAVIOR Challenge at NeurIPS. The competition focused on training a single policy to complete 50 long-horizon household tasks in simulation. We built an end-to-end policy based on Pi0.5 with a bunch of custom modifications. Everything is open-sourced, and it should be useful for anyone exploring VLAs or adapting them to specific tasks. Key Architecture Changes: - Replaced language model with 50 trainable task embeddings (no text at all) - Correlated noise for Flow Matching: ϵ ∼ N(0, 0.5I + 0.5Σ) using dataset action covariance - Learnable mixed-layer attention: each action expert layer attends to a trainable mix of all VLM layers - System 2 stage tracking: model predicts task stage, we smooth it with voting and feed it back as context Training: - Multi-sample Flow Matching: 15 FM samples per VLM pass to reduce gradient variance - Delta action space + per-timestamp normalization - FAST auxiliary...</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/IliaLarchenko/908879505364910</guid></item><item><title>Got to 1199.8 tokens/sec with Devstral Small -2 on my desktop GPU workstation. vLLM nightly.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mitkox/706030667212965</link><description>Got to 1199.8 tokens/sec with Devstral Small -2 on my desktop GPU workstation. vLLM nightly. Works out of the box with Mistral Vibe. Next is time to test the big one. See translation</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mitkox/706030667212965</guid></item><item><title>We just released our latest Shisa V2.1 Japanese multi-lingual models:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/leonardlin/280604558183575</link><description>We just released our latest Shisa V2.1 Japanese multi-lingual models: https://huggingface.co/collections/shisa-ai/shisa-v21 Besides updates to our 14B, and 70B, we have a new LFM2-based 1.2B, Llama 3.2-based 3B, and Qwen 3-based 8B, all with class-leading Japanese language capabilities. Per usual, lots of details in the Model Cards for those interested. See translation</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:29:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/leonardlin/280604558183575</guid></item></channel></rss>