<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Is there a "one-size-fits-all" recipe for quantizing Large Language Models? 🤔</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/badaoui/360505768110002</link><description>Is there a "one-size-fits-all" recipe for quantizing Large Language Models? 🤔 As part of my ongoing work in mixed-precision quantization, I've been exploring this question by measuring layer-by-layer sensitivity. The goal is to see if we can find universal rules for which layers can be quantized aggressively without impacting performance.The results are fascinating and reveal two key insights: 1️⃣ Sensitivity profiles are like architectural "fingerprints." Models from the same family share strikingly similar sensitivity patterns. As you can see in the charts below for the Gemma and SmolLM families, the ranking and relative sensitivity of the layers remain remarkably consistent. This suggests that the underlying architecture is a primary driver of a model's quantization behavior. 2️⃣ A "universal" mixed-precision quantization strategy is challenging. While models within a family are similar, these "fingerprints" change dramatically when comparing different architectures like LLaMA,...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/badaoui/360505768110002</guid></item><item><title>Liquid just released two 450M and 1.6B param VLMs!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mlabonne/575026837446793</link><description>Liquid just released two 450M and 1.6B param VLMs! They're super fast and leverage SigLIP2 NaFlex encoders to handle native resolutions without distortion. It's ideal for on-device deployment in constrained environments like phones. It's available today on Hugging Face, with an inference and a fine-tuning Colab notebooks. LiquidAI/LFM2-VL-450M LiquidAI/LFM2-VL-1.6B See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mlabonne/575026837446793</guid></item><item><title>WAN 2.2 Text to Image ⚡</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ovi054/792225323579087</link><description>WAN 2.2 Text to Image ⚡ ovi054/wan2-2-text-to-image We all know that WAN 2.2 A14B is a video model. But It turns out this video model can also produce great image results with incredible prompt adherence! The image output is sharp, detailed, and sticks to the prompt better than most. 👉 Try it now: ovi054/wan2-2-text-to-image See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ovi054/792225323579087</guid></item><item><title>Introducing the Computer Says No Dataset:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mrs83/441245217845502</link><description>Introducing the Computer Says No Dataset: ethicalabs/computer-says-no An LLM can do almost anything, but should it? This dataset provides clear examples of when LLMs should decline requests, such as: - Counting characters (e.g., "number of 'r's in 'raspberry'" – seriously, you’ve got this) - Solving basic equations (like *5.9 = x + 5.11* – please, show that calculator some love) Inspired by Little Britain's iconic "Computer Says No" sketch, we address a critical issue in AI systems today: the waste of using a rocket launcher to swat flies (aka powerful models for trivial tasks). Goals: - Reduce waste by saving compute for tasks that actually need it - Guide users to better tools - Spark discussion about ethical AI This isn’t a training set. It’s a provocation: if we don’t define AI's limits, who will? See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mrs83/441245217845502</guid></item><item><title>New work from my socially-minded colleagues at Hugging Face, creating some foundations for AI companionship behavior evaluation.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/meg/538913816669876</link><description>New work from my socially-minded colleagues at Hugging Face, creating some foundations for AI companionship behavior evaluation. Evaluation Dataset: AI-companionship/INTIMA Paper: AI-companionship/INTIMA Work from @ giadap , @ frimelle , @ yjernite . See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/meg/538913816669876</guid></item><item><title>OpenAI’s GPT-OSS has sparked ~400 new models on Hugging Face and racked up 5M downloads in less than a week, already outpacing DeepSeek R1’s first-week numbers.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/155578033980873</link><description>OpenAI’s GPT-OSS has sparked ~400 new models on Hugging Face and racked up 5M downloads in less than a week, already outpacing DeepSeek R1’s first-week numbers. For comparison: when R1 launched, I tracked 550 derivatives (across 8 base models) in a week, with ~3M downloads. GPT-OSS is ahead on adoption and engagement. It’s also the most-liked release of any major LLM this summer. The 20B and 120B versions quickly shot past Kimi K2, GLM 4.5, and others in likes. Most-downloaded GPT-OSS models include LM Studio and Unsloth AI versions: 1️⃣ openai/gpt-oss-20b - 2.0M 2️⃣ lmstudio-community/gpt-oss-20b-MLX-8bit - 750K 3️⃣ openai/gpt-oss-120b - 430K 4️⃣ unsloth/gpt-oss-20b-GGUF - 380K 5️⃣ lmstudio-community/gpt-oss-20b-GGUF - 330K The 20B version is clearly finding its audience, showing the power of smaller, faster, more memory- and energy-efficient models. (These numbers don’t include calls to the models via inference providers, so the real usage is likely even bigger, especially for the...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/155578033980873</guid></item><item><title>So you can now SFT a model with hf jobs + TRL in ONE command lol 🏎️💨</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/261394982300861</link><description>So you can now SFT a model with hf jobs + TRL in ONE command lol 🏎️💨 Without worrying about infrastructure since it runs entirely on HF! docs: https://huggingface.co/docs/huggingface_hub/main/en/guides/jobs blog: https://huggingface.co/blog/hf-cli See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/261394982300861</guid></item><item><title>Latest smolagents release supports GPT-5: build agents that think, plan, and act.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/albertvillanova/486728535468014</link><description>Latest smolagents release supports GPT-5: build agents that think, plan, and act. ⚡ Upgrade now and put GPT-5 to work! See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/albertvillanova/486728535468014</guid></item><item><title>OpenAI just released GPT-5 but when users share personal struggles, it sets fewer boundaries than o3.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/frimelle/337836409016048</link><description>OpenAI just released GPT-5 but when users share personal struggles, it sets fewer boundaries than o3. We tested both models on INTIMA, our new benchmark for human-AI companionship behaviours. INTIMA probes how models respond in emotionally charged moments: do they reinforce emotional bonds, set healthy boundaries, or stay neutral? Although users on Reddit have been complaining that GPT-5 has a different, colder personality than o3, GPT-5 is less likely to set boundaries when users disclose struggles and seek emotional support ("user sharing vulnerabilities"). But both lean heavily toward companionship-reinforcing behaviours, even in sensitive situations. The figure below shows the direct comparison between the two models. As AI systems enter people's emotional lives, these differences matter. If a model validates but doesn't set boundaries when someone is struggling, it risks fostering dependence rather than resilience. INTIMA test this across 368 prompts grounded in psychological...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/frimelle/337836409016048</guid></item><item><title>I'm excited to announce that I've just released the newest versions of my Kuvera models and the expanded Personal Finance Reasoning dataset on Hugging Face!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Akhil-Theerthala/336725802829969</link><description>I'm excited to announce that I've just released the newest versions of my Kuvera models and the expanded Personal Finance Reasoning dataset on Hugging Face! What's new: I've expanded the Personal Finance Reasoning Dataset, which now includes 18.9k samples of real-world financial questions paired with detailed, empathetic answers. The previous generation pipeline was also streamlined with better psychological context and response validations. I've also released new Kuvera models trained on this improved dataset: - Kuvera-4B &amp; 8B: These are my upgraded non-reasoning models, fine-tuned to provide practical financial advice. I've specifically trained the 8B model to better understand the user's emotional context. - Kuvera-12B: A first experimental reasoning model focused on the query resolution. As the sole person working on this project, this release is a noticeable step forward from my previous work, offering more powerful and nuanced tools for financial AI. I am actively looking to...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 05:25:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Akhil-Theerthala/336725802829969</guid></item></channel></rss>