<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>WebThinker: Empowering Large Reasoning Models with Deep Research
  Capability</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21776</link><description>Large reasoning models (LRMs), such as OpenAI-o1 and DeepSeek-R1, demonstrate impressive long-horizon reasoning capabilities. However, their reliance on static internal knowledge limits their performance on complex, knowledge-intensive tasks and hinders their ability to produce comprehensive research reports requiring synthesis of diverse web information. To address this, we propose WebThinker, a deep research agent that empowers LRMs to autonomously search the web, navigate web pages, and draft research reports during the reasoning process. WebThinker integrates a Deep Web Explorer module, enabling LRMs to dynamically search, navigate, and extract information from the web when encountering knowledge gaps. It also employs an Autonomous Think-Search-and-Draft strategy, allowing the model to seamlessly interleave reasoning, information gathering, and report writing in real time. To further enhance research tool utilization, we introduce an RL-based training strategy via iterative online Direct Preference Optimization (DPO). Extensive experiments on complex reasoning benchmarks (GPQA, GAIA, WebWalkerQA, HLE) and scientific report generation tasks (Glaive) demonstrate that WebThinker significantly outperforms existing methods and strong proprietary systems. Our approach enhances LRM reliability and applicability in complex scenarios, paving the way for more capable and versatile deep research systems. The code is available at https://github.com/RUC-NLPIR/WebThinker.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:03:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21776</guid></item><item><title>Phi-4-Mini-Reasoning: Exploring the Limits of Small Reasoning Language
  Models in Math</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21233</link><description>Chain-of-Thought (CoT) significantly enhances formal reasoning capabilities in Large Language Models (LLMs) by training them to explicitly generate intermediate reasoning steps. While LLMs readily benefit from such techniques, improving reasoning in Small Language Models (SLMs) remains challenging due to their limited model capacity. Recent work by Deepseek-R1 demonstrates that distillation from LLM-generated synthetic data can substantially improve the reasoning ability of SLM. However, the detailed modeling recipe is not disclosed. In this work, we present a systematic training recipe for SLMs that consists of four steps: (1) large-scale mid-training on diverse distilled long-CoT data, (2) supervised fine-tuning on high-quality long-CoT data, (3) Rollout DPO leveraging a carefully curated preference dataset, and (4) Reinforcement Learning (RL) with Verifiable Reward. We apply our method on Phi-4-Mini, a compact 3.8B-parameter model. The resulting Phi-4-Mini-Reasoning model exceeds, on math reasoning tasks, much larger reasoning models, e.g., outperforming DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-7B by 3.2 points and DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-8B by 7.7 points on Math-500. Our results validate that a carefully designed training recipe, with large-scale high-quality CoT data, is effective to unlock strong reasoning capabilities even in resource-constrained small models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:02:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21233</guid></item><item><title>Softpick: No Attention Sink, No Massive Activations with Rectified
  Softmax</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20966</link><description>We introduce softpick, a rectified, not sum-to-one, drop-in replacement for softmax in transformer attention mechanisms that eliminates attention sink and massive activations. Our experiments with 340M parameter models demonstrate that softpick maintains performance parity with softmax on standard benchmarks while achieving 0% sink rate. The softpick transformer produces hidden states with significantly lower kurtosis (340 vs 33,510) and creates sparse attention maps (46.97% sparsity). Models using softpick consistently outperform softmax when quantized, with particularly pronounced advantages at lower bit precisions. Our analysis and discussion shows how softpick has the potential to open new possibilities for quantization, low-precision training, sparsity optimization, pruning, and interpretability. Our code is available at https://github.com/zaydzuhri/softpick-attention.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 03:08:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.20966</guid></item><item><title>Phi-4-reasoning Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21318</link><description>We introduce Phi-4-reasoning, a 14-billion parameter reasoning model that achieves strong performance on complex reasoning tasks. Trained via supervised fine-tuning of Phi-4 on carefully curated set of "teachable" prompts-selected for the right level of complexity and diversity-and reasoning demonstrations generated using o3-mini, Phi-4-reasoning generates detailed reasoning chains that effectively leverage inference-time compute. We further develop Phi-4-reasoning-plus, a variant enhanced through a short phase of outcome-based reinforcement learning that offers higher performance by generating longer reasoning traces. Across a wide range of reasoning tasks, both models outperform significantly larger open-weight models such as DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-70B model and approach the performance levels of full DeepSeek-R1 model. Our comprehensive evaluations span benchmarks in math and scientific reasoning, coding, algorithmic problem solving, planning, and spatial understanding. Interestingly, we observe a non-trivial transfer of improvements to general-purpose benchmarks as well. In this report, we provide insights into our training data, our training methodologies, and our evaluations. We show that the benefit of careful data curation for supervised fine-tuning (SFT) extends to reasoning language models, and can be further amplified by reinforcement learning (RL). Finally, our evaluation points to opportunities for improving how we assess the performance and robustness of reasoning models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 01:52:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21318</guid></item><item><title>Taming the Titans: A Survey of Efficient LLM Inference Serving</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19720</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) for Generative AI have achieved remarkable progress, evolving into sophisticated and versatile tools widely adopted across various domains and applications. However, the substantial memory overhead caused by their vast number of parameters, combined with the high computational demands of the attention mechanism, poses significant challenges in achieving low latency and high throughput for LLM inference services. Recent advancements, driven by groundbreaking research, have significantly accelerated progress in this field. This paper provides a comprehensive survey of these methods, covering fundamental instance-level approaches, in-depth cluster-level strategies, emerging scenario directions, and other miscellaneous but important areas. At the instance level, we review model placement, request scheduling, decoding length prediction, storage management, and the disaggregation paradigm. At the cluster level, we explore GPU cluster deployment, multi-instance load balancing, and cloud service solutions. For emerging scenarios, we organize the discussion around specific tasks, modules, and auxiliary methods. To ensure a holistic overview, we also highlight several niche yet critical areas. Finally, we outline potential research directions to further advance the field of LLM inference serving.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 03:38:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19720</guid></item><item><title>RoboVerse: Towards a Unified Platform, Dataset and Benchmark for
  Scalable and Generalizable Robot Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.18904</link><description>Data scaling and standardized evaluation benchmarks have driven significant advances in natural language processing and computer vision. However, robotics faces unique challenges in scaling data and establishing evaluation protocols. Collecting real-world data is resource-intensive and inefficient, while benchmarking in real-world scenarios remains highly complex. Synthetic data and simulation offer promising alternatives, yet existing efforts often fall short in data quality, diversity, and benchmark standardization. To address these challenges, we introduce RoboVerse, a comprehensive framework comprising a simulation platform, a synthetic dataset, and unified benchmarks. Our simulation platform supports multiple simulators and robotic embodiments, enabling seamless transitions between different environments. The synthetic dataset, featuring high-fidelity physics and photorealistic rendering, is constructed through multiple approaches. Additionally, we propose unified benchmarks for imitation learning and reinforcement learning, enabling evaluation across different levels of generalization. At the core of the simulation platform is MetaSim, an infrastructure that abstracts diverse simulation environments into a universal interface. It restructures existing simulation environments into a simulator-agnostic configuration system, as well as an API aligning different simulator functionalities, such as launching simulation environments, loading assets with initial states, stepping the physics engine, etc. This abstraction ensures interoperability and extensibility. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that RoboVerse enhances the performance of imitation learning, reinforcement learning, world model learning, and sim-to-real transfer. These results validate the reliability of our dataset and benchmarks, establishing RoboVerse as a robust solution for advancing robot learning.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 01:51:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.18904</guid></item><item><title>COMPACT: COMPositional Atomic-to-Complex Visual Capability Tuning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21850</link><description>Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) excel at simple vision-language tasks but struggle when faced with complex tasks that require multiple capabilities, such as simultaneously recognizing objects, counting them, and understanding their spatial relationships. This might be partially the result of the fact that Visual Instruction Tuning (VIT), a critical training step for MLLMs, has traditionally focused on scaling data volume, but not the compositional complexity of training examples. We propose COMPACT (COMPositional Atomic-to-complex visual Capability Tuning), which generates a training dataset explicitly controlling for the compositional complexity of the training examples. The data from COMPACT allows MLLMs to train on combinations of atomic capabilities to learn complex capabilities more efficiently. Across all benchmarks, COMPACT achieves comparable performance to the LLaVA-665k VIT while using less than 10% of its data budget, and even outperforms it on several, especially those involving complex multi-capability tasks. For example, COMPACT achieves substantial 83.3% improvement on MMStar and 94.0% improvement on MM-Vet compared to the full-scale VIT on particularly complex questions that require four or more atomic capabilities. COMPACT offers a scalable, data-efficient, visual compositional tuning recipe to improve on complex visual-language tasks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:02:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21850</guid></item><item><title>ReVision: High-Quality, Low-Cost Video Generation with Explicit 3D
  Physics Modeling for Complex Motion and Interaction</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21855</link><description>In recent years, video generation has seen significant advancements. However, challenges still persist in generating complex motions and interactions. To address these challenges, we introduce ReVision, a plug-and-play framework that explicitly integrates parameterized 3D physical knowledge into a pretrained conditional video generation model, significantly enhancing its ability to generate high-quality videos with complex motion and interactions. Specifically, ReVision consists of three stages. First, a video diffusion model is used to generate a coarse video. Next, we extract a set of 2D and 3D features from the coarse video to construct a 3D object-centric representation, which is then refined by our proposed parameterized physical prior model to produce an accurate 3D motion sequence. Finally, this refined motion sequence is fed back into the same video diffusion model as additional conditioning, enabling the generation of motion-consistent videos, even in scenarios involving complex actions and interactions. We validate the effectiveness of our approach on Stable Video Diffusion, where ReVision significantly improves motion fidelity and coherence. Remarkably, with only 1.5B parameters, it even outperforms a state-of-the-art video generation model with over 13B parameters on complex video generation by a substantial margin. Our results suggest that, by incorporating 3D physical knowledge, even a relatively small video diffusion model can generate complex motions and interactions with greater realism and controllability, offering a promising solution for physically plausible video generation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:26:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21855</guid></item><item><title>Llama-3.1-FoundationAI-SecurityLLM-Base-8B Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21039</link><description>As transformer-based large language models (LLMs) increasingly permeate society, they have revolutionized domains such as software engineering, creative writing, and digital arts. However, their adoption in cybersecurity remains limited due to challenges like scarcity of specialized training data and complexity of representing cybersecurity-specific knowledge. To address these gaps, we present Foundation-Sec-8B, a cybersecurity-focused LLM built on the Llama 3.1 architecture and enhanced through continued pretraining on a carefully curated cybersecurity corpus. We evaluate Foundation-Sec-8B across both established and new cybersecurity benchmarks, showing that it matches Llama 3.1-70B and GPT-4o-mini in certain cybersecurity-specific tasks. By releasing our model to the public, we aim to accelerate progress and adoption of AI-driven tools in both public and private cybersecurity contexts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 04:37:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.21039</guid></item></channel></rss>