<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>LangScene-X: Reconstruct Generalizable 3D Language-Embedded Scenes with
  TriMap Video Diffusion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02813</link><description>Recovering 3D structures with open-vocabulary scene understanding from 2D images is a fundamental but daunting task. Recent developments have achieved this by performing per-scene optimization with embedded language information. However, they heavily rely on the calibrated dense-view reconstruction paradigm, thereby suffering from severe rendering artifacts and implausible semantic synthesis when limited views are available. In this paper, we introduce a novel generative framework, coined LangScene-X, to unify and generate 3D consistent multi-modality information for reconstruction and understanding. Powered by the generative capability of creating more consistent novel observations, we can build generalizable 3D language-embedded scenes from only sparse views. Specifically, we first train a TriMap video diffusion model that can generate appearance (RGBs), geometry (normals), and semantics (segmentation maps) from sparse inputs through progressive knowledge integration. Furthermore, we propose a Language Quantized Compressor (LQC), trained on large-scale image datasets, to efficiently encode language embeddings, enabling cross-scene generalization without per-scene retraining. Finally, we reconstruct the language surface fields by aligning language information onto the surface of 3D scenes, enabling open-ended language queries. Extensive experiments on real-world data demonstrate the superiority of our LangScene-X over state-of-the-art methods in terms of quality and generalizability. Project Page: https://liuff19.github.io/LangScene-X.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 02:05:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02813</guid></item><item><title>Skywork-Reward-V2: Scaling Preference Data Curation via Human-AI Synergy</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01352</link><description>Despite the critical role of reward models (RMs) in reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF), current state-of-the-art open RMs perform poorly on most existing evaluation benchmarks, failing to capture the spectrum of nuanced and sophisticated human preferences. Even approaches that incorporate advanced training techniques have not yielded meaningful performance improvements. We hypothesize that this brittleness stems primarily from limitations in preference datasets, which are often narrowly scoped, synthetically labeled, or lack rigorous quality control. To address these challenges, we present a large-scale preference dataset comprising 40 million preference pairs, named SynPref-40M. To enable data curation at scale, we design a human-AI synergistic two-stage pipeline that leverages the complementary strengths of human annotation quality and AI scalability. In this pipeline, humans provide verified annotations, while large language models perform automatic curation based on human guidance. Training on this preference mixture, we introduce Skywork-Reward-V2, a suite of eight reward models ranging from 0.6B to 8B parameters, trained on a carefully curated subset of 26 million preference pairs from SynPref-40M. We demonstrate that Skywork-Reward-V2 is versatile across a wide range of capabilities, including alignment with human preferences, objective correctness, safety, resistance to stylistic biases, and best-of-N scaling, achieving state-of-the-art performance across seven major reward model benchmarks. Ablation studies confirm that the effectiveness of our approach stems not only from data scale but also from high-quality curation. The Skywork-Reward-V2 series represents substantial progress in open reward models, highlighting the untapped potential of existing preference datasets and demonstrating how human-AI curation synergy can unlock significantly higher data quality.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 01:02:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01352</guid></item><item><title>Decoupled Planning and Execution: A Hierarchical Reasoning Framework for
  Deep Search</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02652</link><description>Complex information needs in real-world search scenarios demand deep reasoning and knowledge synthesis across diverse sources, which traditional retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) pipelines struggle to address effectively. Current reasoning-based approaches suffer from a fundamental limitation: they use a single model to handle both high-level planning and detailed execution, leading to inefficient reasoning and limited scalability. In this paper, we introduce HiRA, a hierarchical framework that separates strategic planning from specialized execution. Our approach decomposes complex search tasks into focused subtasks, assigns each subtask to domain-specific agents equipped with external tools and reasoning capabilities, and coordinates the results through a structured integration mechanism. This separation prevents execution details from disrupting high-level reasoning while enabling the system to leverage specialized expertise for different types of information processing. Experiments on four complex, cross-modal deep search benchmarks demonstrate that HiRA significantly outperforms state-of-the-art RAG and agent-based systems. Our results show improvements in both answer quality and system efficiency, highlighting the effectiveness of decoupled planning and execution for multi-step information seeking tasks. Our code is available at https://github.com/ignorejjj/HiRA.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 01:37:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02652</guid></item><item><title>WebSailor: Navigating Super-human Reasoning for Web Agent</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02592</link><description>Transcending human cognitive limitations represents a critical frontier in LLM training. Proprietary agentic systems like DeepResearch have demonstrated superhuman capabilities on extremely complex information-seeking benchmarks such as BrowseComp, a feat previously unattainable. We posit that their success hinges on a sophisticated reasoning pattern absent in open-source models: the ability to systematically reduce extreme uncertainty when navigating vast information landscapes. Based on this insight, we introduce WebSailor, a complete post-training methodology designed to instill this crucial capability. Our approach involves generating novel, high-uncertainty tasks through structured sampling and information obfuscation, RFT cold start, and an efficient agentic RL training algorithm, Duplicating Sampling Policy Optimization (DUPO). With this integrated pipeline, WebSailor significantly outperforms all opensource agents in complex information-seeking tasks, matching proprietary agents' performance and closing the capability gap.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 01:50:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02592</guid></item><item><title>Thinking with Images for Multimodal Reasoning: Foundations, Methods, and
  Future Frontiers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.23918</link><description>Recent progress in multimodal reasoning has been significantly advanced by textual Chain-of-Thought (CoT), a paradigm where models conduct reasoning within language. This text-centric approach, however, treats vision as a static, initial context, creating a fundamental "semantic gap" between rich perceptual data and discrete symbolic thought. Human cognition often transcends language, utilizing vision as a dynamic mental sketchpad. A similar evolution is now unfolding in AI, marking a fundamental paradigm shift from models that merely think about images to those that can truly think with images. This emerging paradigm is characterized by models leveraging visual information as intermediate steps in their thought process, transforming vision from a passive input into a dynamic, manipulable cognitive workspace. In this survey, we chart this evolution of intelligence along a trajectory of increasing cognitive autonomy, which unfolds across three key stages: from external tool exploration, through programmatic manipulation, to intrinsic imagination. To structure this rapidly evolving field, our survey makes four key contributions. (1) We establish the foundational principles of the think with image paradigm and its three-stage framework. (2) We provide a comprehensive review of the core methods that characterize each stage of this roadmap. (3) We analyze the critical landscape of evaluation benchmarks and transformative applications. (4) We identify significant challenges and outline promising future directions. By providing this structured overview, we aim to offer a clear roadmap for future research towards more powerful and human-aligned multimodal AI.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 03:50:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.23918</guid></item><item><title>Can LLMs Identify Critical Limitations within Scientific Research? A
  Systematic Evaluation on AI Research Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02694</link><description>Peer review is fundamental to scientific research, but the growing volume of publications has intensified the challenges of this expertise-intensive process. While LLMs show promise in various scientific tasks, their potential to assist with peer review, particularly in identifying paper limitations, remains understudied. We first present a comprehensive taxonomy of limitation types in scientific research, with a focus on AI. Guided by this taxonomy, for studying limitations, we present LimitGen, the first comprehensive benchmark for evaluating LLMs' capability to support early-stage feedback and complement human peer review. Our benchmark consists of two subsets: LimitGen-Syn, a synthetic dataset carefully created through controlled perturbations of high-quality papers, and LimitGen-Human, a collection of real human-written limitations. To improve the ability of LLM systems to identify limitations, we augment them with literature retrieval, which is essential for grounding identifying limitations in prior scientific findings. Our approach enhances the capabilities of LLM systems to generate limitations in research papers, enabling them to provide more concrete and constructive feedback.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 05:13:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02694</guid></item><item><title>IntFold: A Controllable Foundation Model for General and Specialized
  Biomolecular Structure Prediction</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02025</link><description>We introduce IntFold, a controllable foundation model for both general and specialized biomolecular structure prediction. IntFold demonstrates predictive accuracy comparable to the state-of-the-art AlphaFold3, while utilizing a superior customized attention kernel. Beyond standard structure prediction, IntFold can be adapted to predict allosteric states, constrained structures, and binding affinity through the use of individual adapters. Furthermore, we introduce a novel confidence head to estimate docking quality, offering a more nuanced assessment for challenging targets such as antibody-antigen complexes. Finally, we share insights gained during the training process of this computationally intensive model.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 05:22:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02025</guid></item><item><title>Fast and Simplex: 2-Simplicial Attention in Triton</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02754</link><description>Recent work has shown that training loss scales as a power law with both model size and the number of tokens, and that achieving compute-optimal models requires scaling model size and token count together. However, these scaling laws assume an infinite supply of data and apply primarily in compute-bound settings. As modern large language models increasingly rely on massive internet-scale datasets, the assumption that they are compute-bound is becoming less valid. This shift highlights the need for architectures that prioritize token efficiency.   In this work, we investigate the use of the 2-simplicial Transformer, an architecture that generalizes standard dot-product attention to trilinear functions through an efficient Triton kernel implementation. We demonstrate that the 2-simplicial Transformer achieves better token efficiency than standard Transformers: for a fixed token budget, similarly sized models outperform their dot-product counterparts on tasks involving mathematics, coding, reasoning, and logic. We quantify these gains by demonstrating that 2-simplicial attention changes the exponent in the scaling laws for knowledge and reasoning tasks compared to dot product attention.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 01:49:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02754</guid></item><item><title>Bourbaki: Self-Generated and Goal-Conditioned MDPs for Theorem Proving</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02726</link><description>Reasoning remains a challenging task for large language models (LLMs), especially within the logically constrained environment of automated theorem proving (ATP), due to sparse rewards and the vast scale of proofs. These challenges are amplified in benchmarks like PutnamBench, which contains university-level problems requiring complex, multi-step reasoning. To address this, we introduce self-generated goal-conditioned MDPs (sG-MDPs), a new framework in which agents generate and pursue their subgoals based on the evolving proof state. Given this more structured generation of goals, the resulting problem becomes more amenable to search. We then apply Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS)-like algorithms to solve the sG-MDP, instantiating our approach in Bourbaki (7B), a modular system that can ensemble multiple 7B LLMs for subgoal generation and tactic synthesis. On PutnamBench, Bourbaki (7B) solves 26 problems, achieving new state-of-the-art results with models at this scale.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 02:39:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.02726</guid></item><item><title>AsyncFlow: An Asynchronous Streaming RL Framework for Efficient LLM
  Post-Training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01663</link><description>Reinforcement learning (RL) has become a pivotal technology in the post-training phase of large language models (LLMs). Traditional task-colocated RL frameworks suffer from significant scalability bottlenecks, while task-separated RL frameworks face challenges in complex dataflows and the corresponding resource idling and workload imbalance. Moreover, most existing frameworks are tightly coupled with LLM training or inference engines, making it difficult to support custom-designed engines. To address these challenges, we propose AsyncFlow, an asynchronous streaming RL framework for efficient post-training. Specifically, we introduce a distributed data storage and transfer module that provides a unified data management and fine-grained scheduling capability in a fully streamed manner. This architecture inherently facilitates automated pipeline overlapping among RL tasks and dynamic load balancing. Moreover, we propose a producer-consumer-based asynchronous workflow engineered to minimize computational idleness by strategically deferring parameter update process within staleness thresholds. Finally, the core capability of AsynFlow is architecturally decoupled from underlying training and inference engines and encapsulated by service-oriented user interfaces, offering a modular and customizable user experience. Extensive experiments demonstrate an average of 1.59 throughput improvement compared with state-of-the-art baseline. The presented architecture in this work provides actionable insights for next-generation RL training system designs.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 03:19:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01663</guid></item></channel></rss>