<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Block Diffusion: Interpolating Between Autoregressive and Diffusion
  Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.09573</link><description>Diffusion language models offer unique benefits over autoregressive models due to their potential for parallelized generation and controllability, yet they lag in likelihood modeling and are limited to fixed-length generation. In this work, we introduce a class of block diffusion language models that interpolate between discrete denoising diffusion and autoregressive models. Block diffusion overcomes key limitations of both approaches by supporting flexible-length generation and improving inference efficiency with KV caching and parallel token sampling. We propose a recipe for building effective block diffusion models that includes an efficient training algorithm, estimators of gradient variance, and data-driven noise schedules to minimize the variance. Block diffusion sets a new state-of-the-art performance among diffusion models on language modeling benchmarks and enables generation of arbitrary-length sequences. We provide the code, along with the model weights and blog post on the project page: https://m-arriola.com/bd3lms/</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 03:30:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.09573</guid></item><item><title>Multimodal Language Modeling for High-Accuracy Single Cell
  Transcriptomics Analysis and Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.09427</link><description>Pre-trained language models (PLMs) have revolutionized scientific research, yet their application to single-cell analysis remains limited. Text PLMs cannot process single-cell RNA sequencing data, while cell PLMs lack the ability to handle free text, restricting their use in multimodal tasks. Existing efforts to bridge these modalities often suffer from information loss or inadequate single-modal pre-training, leading to suboptimal performances. To address these challenges, we propose Single-Cell MultiModal Generative Pre-trained Transformer (scMMGPT), a unified PLM for joint cell and text modeling. scMMGPT effectively integrates the state-of-the-art cell and text PLMs, facilitating cross-modal knowledge sharing for improved performance. To bridge the text-cell modality gap, scMMGPT leverages dedicated cross-modal projectors, and undergoes extensive pre-training on 27 million cells -- the largest dataset for multimodal cell-text PLMs to date. This large-scale pre-training enables scMMGPT to excel in joint cell-text tasks, achieving an 84\% relative improvement of textual discrepancy for cell description generation, 20.5\% higher accuracy for cell type annotation, and 4\% improvement in k-NN accuracy for text-conditioned pseudo-cell generation, outperforming baselines.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 02:51:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.09427</guid></item></channel></rss>