<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>InfiGUI-G1: Advancing GUI Grounding with Adaptive Exploration Policy
  Optimization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.05731</link><description>Adaptive Exploration Policy Optimization (AEPO) enhances semantic alignment in Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) for GUI interaction, improving performance on benchmarks by up to 9.0% compared to RLVR.  					AI-generated summary 				 The emergence of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) has propelled the development of autonomous agents that operate on Graphical User Interfaces (GUIs) using pure visual input. A fundamental challenge is robustly grounding natural language instructions. This requires a precise spatial alignment, which accurately locates the coordinates of each element, and, more critically, a correct semantic alignment, which matches the instructions to the functionally appropriate UI element. Although Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) has proven to be effective at improving spatial alignment for these MLLMs, we find that inefficient exploration bottlenecks semantic alignment, which prevent models from learning difficult semantic associations. To address this exploration problem, we present Adaptive Exploration Policy Optimization (AEPO), a new policy optimization framework. AEPO employs a multi-answer generation strategy to enforce broader exploration, which is then guided by a theoretically grounded Adaptive Exploration Reward (AER) function derived from first principles of efficiency eta=U/C. Our AEPO-trained models, InfiGUI-G1-3B and InfiGUI-G1-7B, establish new state-of-the-art results across multiple challenging GUI grounding benchmarks, achieving significant relative improvements of up to 9.0% against the naive RLVR baseline on benchmarks designed to test generalization and semantic understanding. Resources are available at https://github.com/InfiXAI/InfiGUI-G1.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 02:04:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.05731</guid></item><item><title>Voost: A Unified and Scalable Diffusion Transformer for Bidirectional
  Virtual Try-On and Try-Off</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04825</link><description>Voost, a unified diffusion transformer framework, jointly learns virtual try-on and try-off, enhancing garment-body correspondence and achieving state-of-the-art results across benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Virtual try-on aims to synthesize a realistic image of a person wearing a target garment, but accurately modeling garment-body correspondence remains a persistent challenge, especially under pose and appearance variation. In this paper, we propose Voost - a unified and scalable framework that jointly learns virtual try-on and try-off with a single diffusion transformer. By modeling both tasks jointly, Voost enables each garment-person pair to supervise both directions and supports flexible conditioning over generation direction and garment category, enhancing garment-body relational reasoning without task-specific networks, auxiliary losses, or additional labels. In addition, we introduce two inference-time techniques: attention temperature scaling for robustness to resolution or mask variation, and self-corrective sampling that leverages bidirectional consistency between tasks. Extensive experiments demonstrate that Voost achieves state-of-the-art results on both try-on and try-off benchmarks, consistently outperforming strong baselines in alignment accuracy, visual fidelity, and generalization.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 02:07:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04825</guid></item><item><title>GLM-4.5: Agentic, Reasoning, and Coding (ARC) Foundation Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.06471</link><description>GLM-4.5, a Mixture-of-Experts large language model with 355B parameters, achieves strong performance across agentic, reasoning, and coding tasks using multi-stage training and reinforcement learning.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present GLM-4.5, an open-source Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) large language model with 355B total parameters and 32B activated parameters, featuring a hybrid reasoning method that supports both thinking and direct response modes. Through multi-stage training on 23T tokens and comprehensive post-training with expert model iteration and reinforcement learning, GLM-4.5 achieves strong performance across agentic, reasoning, and coding (ARC) tasks, scoring 70.1% on TAU-Bench, 91.0% on AIME 24, and 64.2% on SWE-bench Verified. With much fewer parameters than several competitors, GLM-4.5 ranks 3rd overall among all evaluated models and 2nd on agentic benchmarks. We release both GLM-4.5 (355B parameters) and a compact version, GLM-4.5-Air (106B parameters), to advance research in reasoning and agentic AI systems. Code, models, and more information are available at https://github.com/zai-org/GLM-4.5.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 04:09:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.06471</guid></item><item><title>Pruning the Unsurprising: Efficient Code Reasoning via First-Token
  Surprisal</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.05988</link><description>ASAP, a novel coarse-to-fine framework, compresses Chain-of-Thought in code reasoning by preserving core structure and essential steps, reducing costs and improving efficiency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recently, Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in code reasoning by scaling up the length of Chain-of-Thought (CoT). However, excessively long reasoning traces introduce substantial challenges in terms of training cost, inference latency, and deployment feasibility. While various CoT compression approaches have emerged to address this challenge, they face inherent trade-offs: token-level methods often disrupt syntactic and logical coherence, while step-level methods based on perplexity fail to reliably capture the logically critical reasoning steps. In this paper, we propose ASAP (Anchor-guided, Surprisal-based Pruning), a novel coarse-to-fine framework for CoT compression. ASAP first performs anchor-guided pruning to preserve the core reasoning structure, which efficiently reduces the search space for subsequent processing. It then enables a logic-aware pruning by selecting logically essential reasoning steps based on a novel first-token surprisal metric. Finally, ASAP teaches models to autonomously generate and leverage these concise CoTs at inference time, enabling efficient reasoning in coding tasks. Experiments show that ASAP achieves state-of-the-art accuracy across multiple code generation benchmarks while substantially reducing training and inference costs. On the challenging LiveCodeBench v4_v5 benchmark, our approach reduces token generation by 23.5% and inference latency by 43.5% compared to the strongest baseline, while achieving a competitive accuracy of 36.19% in Pass@1. Our results highlight a promising direction for building powerful and efficient LRMs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 02:07:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.05988</guid></item><item><title>Adapting Vision-Language Models Without Labels: A Comprehensive Survey</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.05547</link><description>A comprehensive survey of unsupervised adaptation methods for Vision-Language Models (VLMs) categorizes approaches based on the availability of unlabeled visual data and discusses methodologies, benchmarks, and future research directions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have demonstrated remarkable generalization capabilities across a wide range of tasks. However, their performance often remains suboptimal when directly applied to specific downstream scenarios without task-specific adaptation. To enhance their utility while preserving data efficiency, recent research has increasingly focused on unsupervised adaptation methods that do not rely on labeled data. Despite the growing interest in this area, there remains a lack of a unified, task-oriented survey dedicated to unsupervised VLM adaptation. To bridge this gap, we present a comprehensive and structured overview of the field. We propose a taxonomy based on the availability and nature of unlabeled visual data, categorizing existing approaches into four key paradigms: Data-Free Transfer (no data), Unsupervised Domain Transfer (abundant data), Episodic Test-Time Adaptation (batch data), and Online Test-Time Adaptation (streaming data). Within this framework, we analyze core methodologies and adaptation strategies associated with each paradigm, aiming to establish a systematic understanding of the field. Additionally, we review representative benchmarks across diverse applications and highlight open challenges and promising directions for future research. An actively maintained repository of relevant literature is available at https://github.com/tim-learn/Awesome-LabelFree-VLMs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 05:05:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.05547</guid></item><item><title>UI-AGILE: Advancing GUI Agents with Effective Reinforcement Learning and
  Precise Inference-Time Grounding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.22025</link><description>UI-AGILE enhances GUI agents through improved training with a Continuous Reward function, Simple Thinking reward, and Cropping-based Resampling, and inference with Decomposed Grounding with Selection, achieving state-of-the-art performance on GUI benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 The emergence of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) has driven significant advances in Graphical User Interface (GUI) agent capabilities. Nevertheless, existing GUI agent training and inference techniques still suffer from a dilemma for reasoning designs, ineffective reward, and visual noise. To address these issues, we introduce UI-AGILE, a comprehensive framework enhancing GUI agents at both the training and inference stages. For training, we propose a suite of improvements to the Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) process: 1) a Continuous Reward function to incentivize high-precision grounding; 2) a "Simple Thinking" reward to balance planning with speed and grounding accuracy; and 3) a Cropping-based Resampling strategy to mitigate the sparse reward problem and improve learning on complex tasks. For inference, we present Decomposed Grounding with Selection, a novel method that dramatically improves grounding accuracy on high-resolution displays by breaking the image into smaller, manageable parts. Experiments show that UI-AGILE achieves the state-of-the-art performance on two benchmarks ScreenSpot-Pro and ScreenSpot-v2. For instance, using both our proposed training and inference enhancement methods brings 23% grounding accuracy improvement over the best baseline on ScreenSpot-Pro.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 05:09:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.22025</guid></item><item><title>MELLA: Bridging Linguistic Capability and Cultural Groundedness for
  Low-Resource Language MLLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.05502</link><description>MELLA, a multimodal, multilingual dataset, enhances MLLMs in low-resource languages by improving linguistic capability and cultural groundedness through native web alt-text and MLLM-generated captions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have shown remarkable performance in high-resource languages. However, their effectiveness diminishes significantly in the contexts of low-resource languages. Current multilingual enhancement methods are often limited to text modality or rely solely on machine translation. While such approaches help models acquire basic linguistic capabilities and produce "thin descriptions", they neglect the importance of multimodal informativeness and cultural groundedness, both of which are crucial for serving low-resource language users effectively. To bridge this gap, in this study, we identify two significant objectives for a truly effective MLLM in low-resource language settings, namely 1) linguistic capability and 2) cultural groundedness, placing special emphasis on cultural awareness. To achieve these dual objectives, we propose a dual-source strategy that guides the collection of data tailored to each goal, sourcing native web alt-text for culture and MLLM-generated captions for linguistics. As a concrete implementation, we introduce MELLA, a multimodal, multilingual dataset. Experiment results show that after fine-tuning on MELLA, there is a general performance improvement for the eight languages on various MLLM backbones, with models producing "thick descriptions". We verify that the performance gains are from both cultural knowledge enhancement and linguistic capability enhancement. Our dataset can be found at https://opendatalab.com/applyMultilingualCorpus.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 01:47:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.05502</guid></item><item><title>MeshLLM: Empowering Large Language Models to Progressively Understand
  and Generate 3D Mesh</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01242</link><description>MeshLLM uses large language models to generate and understand text-serialized 3D meshes by decomposing them into meaningful subunits and training with local mesh assembly strategies.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present MeshLLM, a novel framework that leverages large language models (LLMs) to understand and generate text-serialized 3D meshes. Our approach addresses key limitations in existing methods, including the limited dataset scale when catering to LLMs' token length and the loss of 3D structural information during mesh serialization. We introduce a Primitive-Mesh decomposition strategy, which divides 3D meshes into structurally meaningful subunits. This enables the creation of a large-scale dataset with 1500k+ samples, almost 50 times larger than previous methods, which aligns better with the LLM scaling law principles. Furthermore, we propose inferring face connectivity from vertices and local mesh assembly training strategies, significantly enhancing the LLMs' ability to capture mesh topology and spatial structures. Experiments show that MeshLLM outperforms the state-of-the-art LLaMA-Mesh in both mesh generation quality and shape understanding, highlighting its great potential in processing text-serialized 3D meshes.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 05:14:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01242</guid></item></channel></rss>