<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>ScaleCUA: Scaling Open-Source Computer Use Agents with Cross-Platform
  Data</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15221</link><description>ScaleCUA, a large-scale dataset and model for computer use agents, achieves state-of-the-art performance across multiple platforms and tasks by leveraging data-driven scaling.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have enabled computer use agents (CUAs) that operate GUIs autonomously, showing great potential, yet progress is limited by the lack of large-scale, open-source computer use data and foundation models. In this work, we introduce ScaleCUA, a step toward scaling open-source CUAs. It offers a large-scale dataset spanning 6 operating systems and 3 task domains, built via a closed-loop pipeline uniting automated agents with human experts. Trained on this scaled-up data, ScaleCUA can operate seamlessly across platforms. Specifically, it delivers strong gains over baselines (+26.6 on WebArena-Lite-v2, +10.7 on ScreenSpot-Pro) and sets new state-of-the-art results (94.4% on MMBench-GUI L1-Hard, 60.6% on OSWorld-G, 47.4% on WebArena-Lite-v2). These findings underscore the power of data-driven scaling for general-purpose computer use agents. We will release data, models, and code to advance future research: https://github.com/OpenGVLab/ScaleCUA.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:33:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15221</guid></item><item><title>FlowRL: Matching Reward Distributions for LLM Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15207</link><description>FlowRL enhances LLM reinforcement learning by matching the full reward distribution through flow balancing, improving diversity and performance over reward-maximizing methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 We propose FlowRL: matching the full reward distribution via flow balancing instead of maximizing rewards in large language model (LLM) reinforcement learning (RL). Recent advanced reasoning models adopt reward-maximizing methods (\eg, PPO and GRPO), which tend to over-optimize dominant reward signals while neglecting less frequent but valid reasoning paths, thus reducing diversity. In contrast, we transform scalar rewards into a normalized target distribution using a learnable partition function, and then minimize the reverse KL divergence between the policy and the target distribution. We implement this idea as a flow-balanced optimization method that promotes diverse exploration and generalizable reasoning trajectories. We conduct experiments on math and code reasoning tasks: FlowRL achieves a significant average improvement of 10.0% over GRPO and 5.1% over PPO on math benchmarks, and performs consistently better on code reasoning tasks. These results highlight reward distribution-matching as a key step toward efficient exploration and diverse reasoning in LLM reinforcement learning.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:54:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15207</guid></item><item><title>Reasoning over Boundaries: Enhancing Specification Alignment via
  Test-time Delibration</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14760</link><description>Align3, a lightweight method using Test-Time Deliberation, enhances specification alignment in large language models across diverse scenarios with minimal overhead.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly applied in diverse real-world scenarios, each governed by bespoke behavioral and safety specifications (spec) custom-tailored by users or organizations. These spec, categorized into safety-spec and behavioral-spec, vary across scenarios and evolve with changing preferences and requirements. We formalize this challenge as specification alignment, focusing on LLMs' ability to follow dynamic, scenario-specific spec from both behavioral and safety perspectives. To address this challenge, we propose Align3, a lightweight method that employs Test-Time Deliberation (TTD) with hierarchical reflection and revision to reason over the specification boundaries. We further present SpecBench, a unified benchmark for measuring specification alignment, covering 5 scenarios, 103 spec, and 1,500 prompts. Experiments on 15 reasoning and 18 instruct models with several TTD methods, including Self-Refine, TPO, and MoreThink, yield three key findings: (i) test-time deliberation enhances specification alignment; (ii) Align3 advances the safety-helpfulness trade-off frontier with minimal overhead; (iii) SpecBench effectively reveals alignment gaps. These results highlight the potential of test-time deliberation as an effective strategy for reasoning over the real-world specification boundaries.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 04:18:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14760</guid></item><item><title>Evolving Language Models without Labels: Majority Drives Selection,
  Novelty Promotes Variation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15194</link><description>EVOL-RL, a label-free reinforcement learning method, enhances large language models by balancing stability and variation, preventing entropy collapse and improving generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly trained with reinforcement learning from verifiable rewards (RLVR), yet real-world deployment demands models that can self-improve without labels or external judges. Existing label-free methods, confidence minimization, self-consistency, or majority-vote objectives, stabilize learning but steadily shrink exploration, causing an entropy collapse: generations become shorter, less diverse, and brittle. Unlike prior approaches such as Test-Time Reinforcement Learning (TTRL), which primarily adapt models to the immediate unlabeled dataset at hand, our goal is broader: to enable general improvements without sacrificing the model's inherent exploration capacity and generalization ability, i.e., evolving. We formalize this issue and propose EVolution-Oriented and Label-free Reinforcement Learning (EVOL-RL), a simple rule that couples stability with variation under a label-free setting. EVOL-RL keeps the majority-voted answer as a stable anchor (selection) while adding a novelty-aware reward that favors responses whose reasoning differs from what has already been produced (variation), measured in semantic space. Implemented with GRPO, EVOL-RL also uses asymmetric clipping to preserve strong signals and an entropy regularizer to sustain search. This majority-for-selection + novelty-for-variation design prevents collapse, maintains longer and more informative chains of thought, and improves both pass@1 and pass@n. EVOL-RL consistently outperforms the majority-only TTRL baseline; e.g., training on label-free AIME24 lifts Qwen3-4B-Base AIME25 pass@1 from TTRL's 4.6% to 16.4%, and pass@16 from 18.5% to 37.9%. EVOL-RL not only prevents diversity collapse but also unlocks stronger generalization across domains (e.g., GPQA). Furthermore, we demonstrate that EVOL-RL also boosts performance in the RLVR setting, highlighting its broad applicability.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:39:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15194</guid></item><item><title>Understand Before You Generate: Self-Guided Training for Autoregressive
  Image Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15185</link><description>Self-guided Training for AutoRegressive models (ST-AR) enhances image understanding and generation quality in autoregressive models by addressing key visual semantics challenges through self-supervised objectives.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent studies have demonstrated the importance of high-quality visual representations in image generation and have highlighted the limitations of generative models in image understanding. As a generative paradigm originally designed for natural language, autoregressive models face similar challenges. In this work, we present the first systematic investigation into the mechanisms of applying the next-token prediction paradigm to the visual domain. We identify three key properties that hinder the learning of high-level visual semantics: local and conditional dependence, inter-step semantic inconsistency, and spatial invariance deficiency. We show that these issues can be effectively addressed by introducing self-supervised objectives during training, leading to a novel training framework, Self-guided Training for AutoRegressive models (ST-AR). Without relying on pre-trained representation models, ST-AR significantly enhances the image understanding ability of autoregressive models and leads to improved generation quality. Specifically, ST-AR brings approximately 42% FID improvement for LlamaGen-L and 49% FID improvement for LlamaGen-XL, while maintaining the same sampling strategy.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:01:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15185</guid></item><item><title>FinSearchComp: Towards a Realistic, Expert-Level Evaluation of Financial
  Search and Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13160</link><description>FinSearchComp is an open-source benchmark for evaluating financial search and reasoning capabilities of end-to-end agents, featuring realistic tasks and professional annotations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Search has emerged as core infrastructure for LLM-based agents and is widely viewed as critical on the path toward more general intelligence. Finance is a particularly demanding proving ground: analysts routinely conduct complex, multi-step searches over time-sensitive, domain-specific data, making it ideal for assessing both search proficiency and knowledge-grounded reasoning. Yet no existing open financial datasets evaluate data searching capability of end-to-end agents, largely because constructing realistic, complicated tasks requires deep financial expertise and time-sensitive data is hard to evaluate. We present FinSearchComp, the first fully open-source agent benchmark for realistic, open-domain financial search and reasoning. FinSearchComp comprises three tasks -- Time-Sensitive Data Fetching, Simple Historical Lookup, and Complex Historical Investigation -- closely reproduce real-world financial analyst workflows. To ensure difficulty and reliability, we engage 70 professional financial experts for annotation and implement a rigorous multi-stage quality-assurance pipeline. The benchmark includes 635 questions spanning global and Greater China markets, and we evaluate 21 models (products) on it. Grok 4 (web) tops the global subset, approaching expert-level accuracy. DouBao (web) leads on the Greater China subset. Experimental analyses show that equipping agents with web search and financial plugins substantially improves results on FinSearchComp, and the country origin of models and tools impact performance significantly.By aligning with realistic analyst tasks and providing end-to-end evaluation, FinSearchComp offers a professional, high-difficulty testbed for complex financial search and reasoning.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:50:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13160</guid></item><item><title>RynnVLA-001: Using Human Demonstrations to Improve Robot Manipulation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15212</link><description>RynnVLA-001, a vision-language-action model, uses a two-stage pretraining approach and ActionVAE to achieve superior performance on robotics tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 This paper presents RynnVLA-001, a vision-language-action(VLA) model built upon large-scale video generative pretraining from human demonstrations. We propose a novel two-stage pretraining methodology. The first stage, Ego-Centric Video Generative Pretraining, trains an Image-to-Video model on 12M ego-centric manipulation videos to predict future frames conditioned on an initial frame and a language instruction. The second stage, Human-Centric Trajectory-Aware Modeling, extends this by jointly predicting future keypoint trajectories, thereby effectively bridging visual frame prediction with action prediction. Furthermore, to enhance action representation, we propose ActionVAE, a variational autoencoder that compresses sequences of actions into compact latent embeddings, reducing the complexity of the VLA output space. When finetuned on the same downstream robotics datasets, RynnVLA-001 achieves superior performance over state-of-the-art baselines, demonstrating that the proposed pretraining strategy provides a more effective initialization for VLA models.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:43:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15212</guid></item><item><title>AToken: A Unified Tokenizer for Vision</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14476</link><description>AToken, a unified visual tokenizer, achieves high-fidelity reconstruction and semantic understanding across images, videos, and 3D assets using a 4D transformer architecture with adversarial-free training.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present AToken, the first unified visual tokenizer that achieves both high-fidelity reconstruction and semantic understanding across images, videos, and 3D assets. Unlike existing tokenizers that specialize in either reconstruction or understanding for single modalities, AToken encodes these diverse visual inputs into a shared 4D latent space, unifying both tasks and modalities in a single framework. Specifically, we introduce a pure transformer architecture with 4D rotary position embeddings to process visual inputs of arbitrary resolutions and temporal durations. To ensure stable training, we introduce an adversarial-free training objective that combines perceptual and Gram matrix losses, achieving state-of-the-art reconstruction quality. By employing a progressive training curriculum, AToken gradually expands from single images, videos, and 3D, and supports both continuous and discrete latent tokens. AToken achieves 0.21 rFID with 82.2% ImageNet accuracy for images, 3.01 rFVD with 32.6% MSRVTT retrieval for videos, and 28.19 PSNR with 90.9% classification accuracy for 3D. In downstream applications, AToken enables both visual generation tasks (e.g., image generation with continuous and discrete tokens, text-to-video generation, image-to-3D synthesis) and understanding tasks (e.g., multimodal LLMs), achieving competitive performance across all benchmarks. These results shed light on the next-generation multimodal AI systems built upon unified visual tokenization.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:49:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14476</guid></item><item><title>WorldForge: Unlocking Emergent 3D/4D Generation in Video Diffusion Model
  via Training-Free Guidance</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15130</link><description>WorldForge, a training-free framework, enhances video diffusion models with precise motion control and photorealistic content generation through recursive refinement, flow-gated latent fusion, and dual-path self-corrective guidance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent video diffusion models demonstrate strong potential in spatial intelligence tasks due to their rich latent world priors. However, this potential is hindered by their limited controllability and geometric inconsistency, creating a gap between their strong priors and their practical use in 3D/4D tasks. As a result, current approaches often rely on retraining or fine-tuning, which risks degrading pretrained knowledge and incurs high computational costs. To address this, we propose WorldForge, a training-free, inference-time framework composed of three tightly coupled modules. Intra-Step Recursive Refinement introduces a recursive refinement mechanism during inference, which repeatedly optimizes network predictions within each denoising step to enable precise trajectory injection. Flow-Gated Latent Fusion leverages optical flow similarity to decouple motion from appearance in the latent space and selectively inject trajectory guidance into motion-related channels. Dual-Path Self-Corrective Guidance compares guided and unguided denoising paths to adaptively correct trajectory drift caused by noisy or misaligned structural signals. Together, these components inject fine-grained, trajectory-aligned guidance without training, achieving both accurate motion control and photorealistic content generation. Extensive experiments across diverse benchmarks validate our method's superiority in realism, trajectory consistency, and visual fidelity. This work introduces a novel plug-and-play paradigm for controllable video synthesis, offering a new perspective on leveraging generative priors for spatial intelligence.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:46:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15130</guid></item><item><title>MultiEdit: Advancing Instruction-based Image Editing on Diverse and
  Challenging Tasks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14638</link><description>MultiEdit, a comprehensive dataset with over 107K high-quality image editing samples, improves performance on sophisticated editing tasks using a novel pipeline with multi-modal large language models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Current instruction-based image editing (IBIE) methods struggle with challenging editing tasks, as both editing types and sample counts of existing datasets are limited. Moreover, traditional dataset construction often contains noisy image-caption pairs, which may introduce biases and limit model capabilities in complex editing scenarios. To address these limitations, we introduce MultiEdit, a comprehensive dataset featuring over 107K high-quality image editing samples. It encompasses 6 challenging editing tasks through a diverse collection of 18 non-style-transfer editing types and 38 style transfer operations, covering a spectrum from sophisticated style transfer to complex semantic operations like person reference editing and in-image text editing. We employ a novel dataset construction pipeline that utilizes two multi-modal large language models (MLLMs) to generate visual-adaptive editing instructions and produce high-fidelity edited images, respectively. Extensive experiments demonstrate that fine-tuning foundational open-source models with our MultiEdit-Train set substantially improves models' performance on sophisticated editing tasks in our proposed MultiEdit-Test benchmark, while effectively preserving their capabilities on the standard editing benchmark. We believe MultiEdit provides a valuable resource for advancing research into more diverse and challenging IBIE capabilities. Our dataset is available at https://huggingface.co/datasets/inclusionAI/MultiEdit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:43:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14638</guid></item><item><title>Unleashing the Potential of Multimodal LLMs for Zero-Shot
  Spatio-Temporal Video Grounding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15178</link><description>A zero-shot framework using multimodal large language models for spatio-temporal video grounding employs decomposed spatio-temporal highlighting and temporal-augmented assembling strategies to improve grounding accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Spatio-temporal video grounding (STVG) aims at localizing the spatio-temporal tube of a video, as specified by the input text query. In this paper, we utilize multimodal large language models (MLLMs) to explore a zero-shot solution in STVG. We reveal two key insights about MLLMs: (1) MLLMs tend to dynamically assign special tokens, referred to as grounding tokens, for grounding the text query; and (2) MLLMs often suffer from suboptimal grounding due to the inability to fully integrate the cues in the text query (e.g., attributes, actions) for inference. Based on these insights, we propose a MLLM-based zero-shot framework for STVG, which includes novel decomposed spatio-temporal highlighting (DSTH) and temporal-augmented assembling (TAS) strategies to unleash the reasoning ability of MLLMs. The DSTH strategy first decouples the original query into attribute and action sub-queries for inquiring the existence of the target both spatially and temporally. It then uses a novel logit-guided re-attention (LRA) module to learn latent variables as spatial and temporal prompts, by regularizing token predictions for each sub-query. These prompts highlight attribute and action cues, respectively, directing the model's attention to reliable spatial and temporal related visual regions. In addition, as the spatial grounding by the attribute sub-query should be temporally consistent, we introduce the TAS strategy to assemble the predictions using the original video frames and the temporal-augmented frames as inputs to help improve temporal consistency. We evaluate our method on various MLLMs, and show that it outperforms SOTA methods on three common STVG benchmarks.   The code will be available at https://github.com/zaiquanyang/LLaVA_Next_STVG.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:39:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.15178</guid></item><item><title>EchoVLM: Dynamic Mixture-of-Experts Vision-Language Model for Universal
  Ultrasound Intelligence</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14977</link><description>EchoVLM, a vision-language model with a Mixture of Experts architecture, improves ultrasound report generation and diagnosis by leveraging data from multiple anatomical regions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Ultrasound imaging has become the preferred imaging modality for early cancer screening due to its advantages of non-ionizing radiation, low cost, and real-time imaging capabilities. However, conventional ultrasound diagnosis heavily relies on physician expertise, presenting challenges of high subjectivity and low diagnostic efficiency. Vision-language models (VLMs) offer promising solutions for this issue, but existing general-purpose models demonstrate limited knowledge in ultrasound medical tasks, with poor generalization in multi-organ lesion recognition and low efficiency across multi-task diagnostics. To address these limitations, we propose EchoVLM, a vision-language model specifically designed for ultrasound medical imaging. The model employs a Mixture of Experts (MoE) architecture trained on data spanning seven anatomical regions. This design enables the model to perform multiple tasks, including ultrasound report generation, diagnosis and visual question-answering (VQA). The experimental results demonstrated that EchoVLM achieved significant improvements of 10.15 and 4.77 points in BLEU-1 scores and ROUGE-1 scores respectively compared to Qwen2-VL on the ultrasound report generation task. These findings suggest that EchoVLM has substantial potential to enhance diagnostic accuracy in ultrasound imaging, thereby providing a viable technical solution for future clinical applications. Source code and model weights are available at https://github.com/Asunatan/EchoVLM.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 06:52:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14977</guid></item><item><title>FSG-Net: Frequency-Spatial Synergistic Gated Network for High-Resolution
  Remote Sensing Change Detection</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.06482</link><description>FSG-Net addresses false alarms and semantic gaps in change detection by using a frequency-spatial synergistic approach with wavelet interaction, attention mechanisms, and gated fusion.  					AI-generated summary 				 Change detection from high-resolution remote sensing images lies as a cornerstone of Earth observation applications, yet its efficacy is often compromised by two critical challenges. First, false alarms are prevalent as models misinterpret radiometric variations from temporal shifts (e.g., illumination, season) as genuine changes. Second, a non-negligible semantic gap between deep abstract features and shallow detail-rich features tends to obstruct their effective fusion, culminating in poorly delineated boundaries. To step further in addressing these issues, we propose the Frequency-Spatial Synergistic Gated Network (FSG-Net), a novel paradigm that aims to systematically disentangle semantic changes from nuisance variations. Specifically, FSG-Net first operates in the frequency domain, where a Discrepancy-Aware Wavelet Interaction Module (DAWIM) adaptively mitigates pseudo-changes by discerningly processing different frequency components. Subsequently, the refined features are enhanced in the spatial domain by a Synergistic Temporal-Spatial Attention Module (STSAM), which amplifies the saliency of genuine change regions. To finally bridge the semantic gap, a Lightweight Gated Fusion Unit (LGFU) leverages high-level semantics to selectively gate and integrate crucial details from shallow layers. Comprehensive experiments on the CDD, GZ-CD, and LEVIR-CD benchmarks validate the superiority of FSG-Net, establishing a new state-of-the-art with F1-scores of 94.16%, 89.51%, and 91.27%, respectively. The code will be made available at https://github.com/zxXie-Air/FSG-Net after a possible publication.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:55:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.06482</guid></item></channel></rss>