<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Just completed the AI Agents course and wow, that capstone project really makes you understand how to build agents that can handle real-world complexity!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/719212082746895</link><description>Just completed the AI Agents course and wow, that capstone project really makes you understand how to build agents that can handle real-world complexity! The final project uses the GAIA dataset - your agent has to solve tasks like analyzing Excel files, processing audio recordings, answering questions about YouTube videos, and diving into research papers. This isn't toy examples, it's the messy, multimodal stuff agents need to handle in practice. Whether you’re just getting started with agents or want to go deeper with tools like LangChain, LlamaIndex, and SmolAgents, this course has tons of useful stuff. A few key insights: - Code agents are incredibly versatile once you get the architecture right - The sweet spot is finding the right balance of guidance vs autonomy for each use case - Once the logic clicks, the possibilities really are endless - it's like letting LLMs break free from the chatbox The course is free and the certification deadline is July 1st, 2025. The Hugging Face...</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/fdaudens/719212082746895</guid></item><item><title>It's just become easier to share your apps on the biggest AI app store (aka HF spaces) for unlimited storage, more visibility and community interactions.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/clem/541152505631903</link><description>It's just become easier to share your apps on the biggest AI app store (aka HF spaces) for unlimited storage, more visibility and community interactions. Just pick a React, Svelte, or Vue template when you create your space or add app_build_command: npm run build in your README's YAML and app_file: build/index.html in your README's YAML block. Or follow this link: https://huggingface.co/new-space?sdk=static Let's build! See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/clem/541152505631903</guid></item><item><title>Benchmark Update:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/660720952792703</link><description>Benchmark Update: @ google Veo3 (Text-to-Video) Two months ago, we benchmarked @ google ’s Veo2 model. It fell short, struggling with style consistency and temporal coherence, trailing behind Runway, Pika, @ tencent , and even @ alibaba-pai . That’s changed. We just wrapped up benchmarking Veo3, and the improvements are substantial. It outperformed every other model by a wide margin across all key metrics. Not just better, dominating across style, coherence, and prompt adherence. It's rare to see such a clear lead in today’s hyper-competitive T2V landscape. Dataset coming soon. Stay tuned. See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/660720952792703</guid></item><item><title>what happened in open AI past week? so many vision LM &amp; omni releases 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/349112163630055</link><description>what happened in open AI past week? so many vision LM &amp; omni releases 🔥 merve/releases-23-may-68343cb970bbc359f9b5fb05 multimodal 💬🖼️ &gt; new moondream (VLM) is out: it's 4-bit quantized (with QAT) version of moondream-2b, runs on 2.5GB VRAM at 184 tps with only 0.6% drop in accuracy (OS) 🌚 &gt; ByteDance released BAGEL-7B, an omni model that understands and generates both image + text. they also released Dolphin, a document parsing VLM 🐬 (OS) &gt; Google DeepMind dropped MedGemma in I/O, VLM that can interpret medical scans, and Gemma 3n, an omni model with competitive LLM performance &gt; MMaDa is a new 8B diffusion language model that can generate image and text LLMs &gt; Mistral released Devstral, a 24B coding assistant (OS) 👩🏻‍💻 &gt; Fairy R1-32B is a new reasoning model -- distilled version of DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-32B (OS) &gt; NVIDIA released ACEReason-Nemotron-14B, new 14B math and code reasoning model &gt; sarvam-m is a new Indic LM with hybrid thinking mode, based on Mistral Small (OS) &gt;...</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/349112163630055</guid></item><item><title>Orsta 🔥 vision language models trained with V-Triune, a unified reinforcement learning system by MiniMax AI</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/689443142454195</link><description>Orsta 🔥 vision language models trained with V-Triune, a unified reinforcement learning system by MiniMax AI One-RL-to-See-Them-All/one-rl-to-see-them-all-6833d27abce23898b2f9815a ✨ 7B &amp; 32B with MIT license ✨ Masters 8 visual tasks: math, science QA, charts, puzzles, object detection, grounding, OCR, and counting ✨ Uses Dynamic IoU rewards for better visual understanding ✨Strong performance in visual reasoning and perception See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/689443142454195</guid></item><item><title>Excited to share my latest project: an AI-powered Educational Content Creator Assistant! 📚✨ Built with Gradio and OpenAI, it transforms PDF/DOCX documents into engaging study materials like interactive flashcards, quizzes, summaries, and lesson plans. Features GPU acceleration and downloadable HTML outputs. Perfect for educators and students! 🚀 #EdTech #AI #Python #ML #LLM</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/shukdevdatta123/533287086907274</link><description>Excited to share my latest project: an AI-powered Educational Content Creator Assistant! 📚✨ Built with Gradio and OpenAI, it transforms PDF/DOCX documents into engaging study materials like interactive flashcards, quizzes, summaries, and lesson plans. Features GPU acceleration and downloadable HTML outputs. Perfect for educators and students! 🚀 #EdTech #AI #Python #ML #LLM Features Include: - ✅ AI-powered content generation - ✅ Document processing (PDF/DOCX) - ✅ Interactive flashcards with slider functionality - ✅ Comprehensive summaries - ✅ Structured study notes - ✅ Quiz generation with multiple choice, short answer, and essay questions - ✅ Mind map structure creation - ✅ Detailed lesson plans - ✅ In-depth concept explanations - ✅ Practice problems (beginner to challenge levels) - ✅ Downloadable HTML outputs with interactivity - ✅ Gradio-based user interface - ✅ OpenAI API integration via OpenRouter - ✅ GPU acceleration with ZeroGPU - ✅ Real-time status updates for API and...</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/shukdevdatta123/533287086907274</guid></item><item><title>Anyone using AI and ML to help neurodivergent people? I'd love to hear what you're doing.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/nomadicsynth/536715864633357</link><description>Anyone using AI and ML to help neurodivergent people? I'd love to hear what you're doing. See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/nomadicsynth/536715864633357</guid></item><item><title>12 Types of JEPA</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/646284586461230</link><description>12 Types of JEPA JEPA, or Joint Embedding Predictive Architecture, is an approach to building AI models introduced by Yann LeCun. It differs from transformers by predicting the representation of a missing or future part of the input, rather than the next token or pixel. This encourages conceptual understanding, not just low-level pattern matching. So JEPA allows teaching AI to reason abstractly. Here are 12 types of JEPA you should know about: 1. I-JEPA -&gt; Self-Supervised Learning from Images with a Joint-Embedding Predictive Architecture (2301.08243) A non-generative, self-supervised learning framework designed for processing images. It works by masking parts of the images and then trying to predict those masked parts 2. MC-JEPA -&gt; MC-JEPA: A Joint-Embedding Predictive Architecture for Self-Supervised Learning of Motion and Content Features (2307.12698) Simultaneously interprets video data - dynamic elements (motion) and static details (content) - using a shared encoder 3. V-JEPA...</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/646284586461230</guid></item><item><title>Eyyyy 50 followers 🤯</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ProCreations/321100188234240</link><description>Eyyyy 50 followers 🤯 See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ProCreations/321100188234240</guid></item><item><title>A new research paper from KAIST builds on smolagents to push boundaries of distillation 🥳</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/m-ric/682683815641001</link><description>A new research paper from KAIST builds on smolagents to push boundaries of distillation 🥳 ➡️ "Distilling LLM Agent into Small Models with Retrieval and Code Tools" teaches that, when trying to distil reasoning capability from a strong LLM ("teacher") into a smaller one ("student"), it's much better to use Agent traces than CoT traces. Advantages are: 1. Improved generalization Intuitively, this is because your agent can encounter more "surprising" results by interacting with its environment : for example, a web research called by the LLM teacher in agent mode can bring results that the LLM teacher would not have generated in CoT. 2. Reduce hallucinations The trace won't hallucinate tool call outputs! Thank you @ akseljoonas for mentioning this paper! See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:21:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/m-ric/682683815641001</guid></item></channel></rss>