<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Kwai Keye-VL Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01949</link><description>While Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) demonstrate remarkable capabilities on static images, they often fall short in comprehending dynamic, information-dense short-form videos, a dominant medium in today's digital landscape. To bridge this gap, we introduce Kwai Keye-VL, an 8-billion-parameter multimodal foundation model engineered for leading-edge performance in short-video understanding while maintaining robust general-purpose vision-language abilities. The development of Keye-VL rests on two core pillars: a massive, high-quality dataset exceeding 600 billion tokens with a strong emphasis on video, and an innovative training recipe. This recipe features a four-stage pre-training process for solid vision-language alignment, followed by a meticulous two-phase post-training process. The first post-training stage enhances foundational capabilities like instruction following, while the second phase focuses on stimulating advanced reasoning. In this second phase, a key innovation is our five-mode ``cold-start'' data mixture, which includes ``thinking'', ``non-thinking'', ``auto-think'', ``think with image'', and high-quality video data. This mixture teaches the model to decide when and how to reason. Subsequent reinforcement learning (RL) and alignment steps further enhance these reasoning capabilities and correct abnormal model behaviors, such as repetitive outputs. To validate our approach, we conduct extensive evaluations, showing that Keye-VL achieves state-of-the-art results on public video benchmarks and remains highly competitive on general image-based tasks (Figure 1). Furthermore, we develop and release the KC-MMBench, a new benchmark tailored for real-world short-video scenarios, where Keye-VL shows a significant advantage.</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 02:10:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01949</guid></item><item><title>LongAnimation: Long Animation Generation with Dynamic Global-Local
  Memory</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01945</link><description>Animation colorization is a crucial part of real animation industry production. Long animation colorization has high labor costs. Therefore, automated long animation colorization based on the video generation model has significant research value. Existing studies are limited to short-term colorization. These studies adopt a local paradigm, fusing overlapping features to achieve smooth transitions between local segments. However, the local paradigm neglects global information, failing to maintain long-term color consistency. In this study, we argue that ideal long-term color consistency can be achieved through a dynamic global-local paradigm, i.e., dynamically extracting global color-consistent features relevant to the current generation. Specifically, we propose LongAnimation, a novel framework, which mainly includes a SketchDiT, a Dynamic Global-Local Memory (DGLM), and a Color Consistency Reward. The SketchDiT captures hybrid reference features to support the DGLM module. The DGLM module employs a long video understanding model to dynamically compress global historical features and adaptively fuse them with the current generation features. To refine the color consistency, we introduce a Color Consistency Reward. During inference, we propose a color consistency fusion to smooth the video segment transition. Extensive experiments on both short-term (14 frames) and long-term (average 500 frames) animations show the effectiveness of LongAnimation in maintaining short-term and long-term color consistency for open-domain animation colorization task. The code can be found at https://cn-makers.github.io/long_animation_web/.</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 02:27:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01945</guid></item><item><title>Depth Anything at Any Condition</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01634</link><description>We present Depth Anything at Any Condition (DepthAnything-AC), a foundation monocular depth estimation (MDE) model capable of handling diverse environmental conditions. Previous foundation MDE models achieve impressive performance across general scenes but not perform well in complex open-world environments that involve challenging conditions, such as illumination variations, adverse weather, and sensor-induced distortions. To overcome the challenges of data scarcity and the inability of generating high-quality pseudo-labels from corrupted images, we propose an unsupervised consistency regularization finetuning paradigm that requires only a relatively small amount of unlabeled data. Furthermore, we propose the Spatial Distance Constraint to explicitly enforce the model to learn patch-level relative relationships, resulting in clearer semantic boundaries and more accurate details. Experimental results demonstrate the zero-shot capabilities of DepthAnything-AC across diverse benchmarks, including real-world adverse weather benchmarks, synthetic corruption benchmarks, and general benchmarks.   Project Page: https://ghost233lism.github.io/depthanything-AC-page   Code: https://github.com/HVision-NKU/DepthAnythingAC</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 01:46:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01634</guid></item><item><title>A Survey on Vision-Language-Action Models: An Action Tokenization
  Perspective</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01925</link><description>The remarkable advancements of vision and language foundation models in multimodal understanding, reasoning, and generation has sparked growing efforts to extend such intelligence to the physical world, fueling the flourishing of vision-language-action (VLA) models. Despite seemingly diverse approaches, we observe that current VLA models can be unified under a single framework: vision and language inputs are processed by a series of VLA modules, producing a chain of action tokens that progressively encode more grounded and actionable information, ultimately generating executable actions. We further determine that the primary design choice distinguishing VLA models lies in how action tokens are formulated, which can be categorized into language description, code, affordance, trajectory, goal state, latent representation, raw action, and reasoning. However, there remains a lack of comprehensive understanding regarding action tokens, significantly impeding effective VLA development and obscuring future directions. Therefore, this survey aims to categorize and interpret existing VLA research through the lens of action tokenization, distill the strengths and limitations of each token type, and identify areas for improvement. Through this systematic review and analysis, we offer a synthesized outlook on the broader evolution of VLA models, highlight underexplored yet promising directions, and contribute guidance for future research, hoping to bring the field closer to general-purpose intelligence.</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 05:09:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01925</guid></item><item><title>FreeMorph: Tuning-Free Generalized Image Morphing with Diffusion Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01953</link><description>We present FreeMorph, the first tuning-free method for image morphing that accommodates inputs with different semantics or layouts. Unlike existing methods that rely on finetuning pre-trained diffusion models and are limited by time constraints and semantic/layout discrepancies, FreeMorph delivers high-fidelity image morphing without requiring per-instance training. Despite their efficiency and potential, tuning-free methods face challenges in maintaining high-quality results due to the non-linear nature of the multi-step denoising process and biases inherited from the pre-trained diffusion model. In this paper, we introduce FreeMorph to address these challenges by integrating two key innovations. 1) We first propose a guidance-aware spherical interpolation design that incorporates explicit guidance from the input images by modifying the self-attention modules, thereby addressing identity loss and ensuring directional transitions throughout the generated sequence. 2) We further introduce a step-oriented variation trend that blends self-attention modules derived from each input image to achieve controlled and consistent transitions that respect both inputs. Our extensive evaluations demonstrate that FreeMorph outperforms existing methods, being 10x ~ 50x faster and establishing a new state-of-the-art for image morphing.</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 04:10:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.01953</guid></item><item><title>JAM-Flow: Joint Audio-Motion Synthesis with Flow Matching</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.23552</link><description>The intrinsic link between facial motion and speech is often overlooked in generative modeling, where talking head synthesis and text-to-speech (TTS) are typically addressed as separate tasks. This paper introduces JAM-Flow, a unified framework to simultaneously synthesize and condition on both facial motion and speech. Our approach leverages flow matching and a novel Multi-Modal Diffusion Transformer (MM-DiT) architecture, integrating specialized Motion-DiT and Audio-DiT modules. These are coupled via selective joint attention layers and incorporate key architectural choices, such as temporally aligned positional embeddings and localized joint attention masking, to enable effective cross-modal interaction while preserving modality-specific strengths. Trained with an inpainting-style objective, JAM-Flow supports a wide array of conditioning inputs-including text, reference audio, and reference motion-facilitating tasks such as synchronized talking head generation from text, audio-driven animation, and much more, within a single, coherent model. JAM-Flow significantly advances multi-modal generative modeling by providing a practical solution for holistic audio-visual synthesis. project page: https://joonghyuk.com/jamflow-web</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 01:45:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2506.23552</guid></item></channel></rss>