<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>QeRL: Beyond Efficiency -- Quantization-enhanced Reinforcement Learning
  for LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11696</link><description>QeRL, a quantization-enhanced reinforcement learning framework, accelerates RL training for large language models by combining NVFP4 quantization with Low-Rank Adaptation and an Adaptive Quantization Noise mechanism, achieving significant speedups and improved performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 We propose QeRL, a Quantization-enhanced Reinforcement Learning framework for large language models (LLMs). While RL is essential for LLMs' reasoning capabilities, it is resource-intensive, requiring substantial GPU memory and long rollout durations. QeRL addresses these issues by combining NVFP4 quantization with Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA), accelerating rollout phase of RL while reducing memory overhead. Beyond efficiency, our findings show that quantization noise increases policy entropy, enhancing exploration, and enabling the discovery of better strategies during RL. To further optimize exploration, QeRL introduces an Adaptive Quantization Noise (AQN) mechanism, which dynamically adjusts noise during training. Experiments demonstrate that QeRL delivers over 1.5 times speedup in the rollout phase. Moreover, this is the first framework to enable RL training of a 32B LLM on a single H100 80GB GPU, while delivering overall speedups for RL training. It also achieves faster reward growth and higher final accuracy than 16-bit LoRA and QLoRA, while matching the performance of full-parameter fine-tuning on mathematical benchmarks such as GSM8K (90.8%) and MATH 500 (77.4%) in the 7B model. These results establish QeRL as an efficient and effective framework for RL training in LLMs.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:47:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11696</guid></item><item><title>Diffusion Transformers with Representation Autoencoders</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11690</link><description>Replacing VAEs with pretrained representation encoders in Diffusion Transformers enhances generative quality and convergence speed without auxiliary losses.  					AI-generated summary 				 Latent generative modeling, where a pretrained autoencoder maps pixels into a latent space for the diffusion process, has become the standard strategy for Diffusion Transformers (DiT); however, the autoencoder component has barely evolved. Most DiTs continue to rely on the original VAE encoder, which introduces several limitations: outdated backbones that compromise architectural simplicity, low-dimensional latent spaces that restrict information capacity, and weak representations that result from purely reconstruction-based training and ultimately limit generative quality. In this work, we explore replacing the VAE with pretrained representation encoders (e.g., DINO, SigLIP, MAE) paired with trained decoders, forming what we term Representation Autoencoders (RAEs). These models provide both high-quality reconstructions and semantically rich latent spaces, while allowing for a scalable transformer-based architecture. Since these latent spaces are typically high-dimensional, a key challenge is enabling diffusion transformers to operate effectively within them. We analyze the sources of this difficulty, propose theoretically motivated solutions, and validate them empirically. Our approach achieves faster convergence without auxiliary representation alignment losses. Using a DiT variant equipped with a lightweight, wide DDT head, we achieve strong image generation results on ImageNet: 1.51 FID at 256x256 (no guidance) and 1.13 at both 256x256 and 512x512 (with guidance). RAE offers clear advantages and should be the new default for diffusion transformer training.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:13:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11690</guid></item><item><title>OmniVideoBench: Towards Audio-Visual Understanding Evaluation for Omni
  MLLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10689</link><description>OmniVideoBench is a comprehensive benchmark for evaluating audio-visual reasoning in multimodal large language models, addressing modality complementarity and logical consistency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have demonstrated substantial potential in video understanding. However, existing benchmarks fail to comprehensively evaluate synergistic reasoning capabilities across audio and visual modalities, often neglecting either one of the modalities or integrating them in a logically inconsistent manner. To bridge this gap, we introduce OmniVideoBench, a large-scale and rigorously designed benchmark dedicated to assessing synergistic audio-visual understanding, with a strong emphasis on modality complementarity and logical consistency. Specifically, OmniVideoBench comprises 1000 high-quality question-answer(QA) pairs, each annotated with step-by-step reasoning traces, derived from 628 diverse videos ranging from several seconds to 30 minutes, and manually verified to guarantee complete correctness and uniqueness. Moreover, OmniVideoBench encompasses 13 carefully designed question types, covering temporal reasoning, spatial localization, counting, causal inference, summarization, and beyond, thereby capturing the essential challenges of video understanding. Evaluation of multiple MLLMs on OmniVideoBench reveals a pronounced gap between model performance and human reasoning, with open-source models lagging significantly behind their closed-source counterparts, underscoring the inherent difficulty of genuine audio-visual reasoning. We will release OmniVideoBench to foster the development of MLLMs with stronger and more generalizable reasoning capabilities.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:31:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10689</guid></item><item><title>AVoCaDO: An Audiovisual Video Captioner Driven by Temporal Orchestration</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10395</link><description>AVoCaDO, an audiovisual video captioner, enhances temporal coherence and dialogue accuracy through a two-stage post-training pipeline, outperforming existing models across multiple benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Audiovisual video captioning aims to generate semantically rich descriptions with temporal alignment between visual and auditory events, thereby benefiting both video understanding and generation. In this paper, we present AVoCaDO, a powerful audiovisual video captioner driven by the temporal orchestration between audio and visual modalities. We propose a two-stage post-training pipeline: (1) AVoCaDO SFT, which fine-tunes the model on a newly curated dataset of 107K high-quality, temporally-aligned audiovisual captions; and (2) AVoCaDO GRPO, which leverages tailored reward functions to further enhance temporal coherence and dialogue accuracy while regularizing caption length and reducing collapse. Experimental results demonstrate that AVoCaDO significantly outperforms existing open-source models across four audiovisual video captioning benchmarks, and also achieves competitive performance on the VDC and DREAM-1K benchmark under visual-only settings.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:20:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10395</guid></item><item><title>Making Mathematical Reasoning Adaptive</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.04617</link><description>AdaR framework enhances LLMs' robustness and generalization in mathematical reasoning by synthesizing logically equivalent queries and using RLVR to penalize spurious logic.  					AI-generated summary 				 Mathematical reasoning is a primary indicator of large language models (LLMs) intelligence. However, existing LLMs exhibit failures of robustness and generalization. This paper attributes these deficiencies to spurious reasoning, i.e., producing answers from superficial features. To address this challenge, we propose the AdaR framework to enable adaptive reasoning, wherein models rely on problem-solving logic to produce answers. AdaR synthesizes logically equivalent queries by varying variable values, and trains models with RLVR on these data to penalize spurious logic while encouraging adaptive logic. To improve data quality, we extract the problem-solving logic from the original query and generate the corresponding answer by code execution, then apply a sanity check. Experimental results demonstrate that AdaR improves robustness and generalization, achieving substantial improvement in mathematical reasoning while maintaining high data efficiency. Analysis indicates that data synthesis and RLVR function in a coordinated manner to enable adaptive reasoning in LLMs. Subsequent analyses derive key design insights into the effect of critical factors and the applicability to instruct LLMs. Our project is available at https://github.com/LaiZhejian/AdaR</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:14:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.04617</guid></item><item><title>Demystifying Reinforcement Learning in Agentic Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11701</link><description>Agentic reinforcement learning enhances LLMs' reasoning ability through real datasets, exploration techniques, and a deliberative strategy, achieving strong performance with smaller models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recently, the emergence of agentic RL has showcased that RL could also effectively improve the agentic reasoning ability of LLMs, yet the key design principles and optimal practices remain unclear. In this work, we conduct a comprehensive and systematic investigation to demystify reinforcement learning in agentic reasoning from three key perspectives: data, algorithm, and reasoning mode. We highlight our key insights: (i) Replacing stitched synthetic trajectories with real end-to-end tool-use trajectories yields a far stronger SFT initialization; high-diversity, model-aware datasets sustain exploration and markedly improve RL performance. (ii) Exploration-friendly techniques are crucial for agentic RL, such as clip higher, overlong reward shaping, and maintaining adequate policy entropy could improve the training efficiency. (iii) A deliberative strategy with fewer tool calls outperforms frequent tool calls or verbose self-reasoning, improving tool efficiency and final accuracy. Together, these simple practices consistently enhance agentic reasoning and training efficiency, achieving strong results on challenging benchmarks with smaller models, and establishing a practical baseline for future agentic RL research. Beyond these empirical insights, we further contribute a high-quality, real end-to-end agentic SFT dataset along with a high-quality RL dataset, and demonstrate the effectiveness of our insights in boosting the agentic reasoning ability of LLMs across four challenging benchmarks, including AIME2024/AIME2025, GPQA-Diamond, and LiveCodeBench-v6. With our recipes, 4B-sized models could also achieve superior agentic reasoning performance compared to 32B-sized models. Code and models: https://github.com/Gen-Verse/Open-AgentRL</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:36:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11701</guid></item><item><title>RLFR: Extending Reinforcement Learning for LLMs with Flow Environment</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10201</link><description>RLFR uses flow rewards derived from latent space to improve reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards, demonstrating reliable reward shaping and efficient context comprehension.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) has recently emerged as a promising framework for improving reasoning abilities in Large Language Models (LLMs). However, policy optimized with binary verification prone to overlook potential valuable exploration in reasoning trajectory. In view of heavy annotation cost of golden Process Reward Models (PRMs), recent works attempt using auxiliary signals for reward shaping of process tokens, involving entropy and likelihood collected from logit space. In this work, we offer a novel perspective on shaping RLVR with flow rewards derived from latent space, and propose RLFR, where the flow fields of model latents are constructed from either off-policy high-quality data and on-policy rejection sampling data, and the velocity deviations of policy latents within it are quantified to serve as a reward signal. RLFR first demonstrates that a well-established flow field can be a sound environment for reward signal collection, highlighting the expressive latent space is much underexplored. Moreover, RLFR is able to compress any off-policy expert data as reference for constituting reward signals, and we show that the efficient context dependence compressed within the hidden states are utilized, rather than individual token-level denotation for context comprehending. Experiments on both language and multimodal reasoning benchmarks demonstrate the reliability of flow rewards, and suggesting a promising paradigm for reward shaping with auxiliary signals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:47:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10201</guid></item><item><title>GIR-Bench: Versatile Benchmark for Generating Images with Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11026</link><description>GIR-Bench evaluates unified multimodal models across understanding-generation consistency, reasoning-centric text-to-image generation, and multi-step reasoning in editing, highlighting gaps in their capabilities.  					AI-generated summary 				 Unified multimodal models integrate the reasoning capacity of large language models with both image understanding and generation, showing great promise for advanced multimodal intelligence. However, the community still lacks a rigorous reasoning-centric benchmark to systematically evaluate the alignment between understanding and generation, and their generalization potential in complex visual tasks. To this end, we introduce GIR-Bench, a comprehensive benchmark that evaluates unified models across three complementary perspectives. Firstly, we investigate understanding-generation consistency (GIR-Bench-UGC), asking whether models can consistently leverage the same knowledge in both understanding and generation tasks. Secondly, we investigate whether models can perform reasoning-centric text-to-image generation that requires applying logical constraints and implicit knowledge to generate faithful visual content (GIR-Bench-T2I). Thirdly, we evaluate whether models can handle multi-step reasoning in editing (GIR-Bench-Edit). For each subset, we carefully design different task-specific evaluation pipelines tailored for each task. This enables fine-grained and interpretable evaluation while mitigating biases from the prevalent MLLM-as-a-Judge paradigm. Extensive ablations over various unified models and generation-only systems have shown that: Although unified models are more capable of reasoning-driven visual tasks, they still exhibit a persistent gap between understanding and generation. The data and code for GIR-Bench are available at https://hkust-longgroup.github.io/GIR-Bench{https://hkust-longgroup.github.io/GIR-Bench}.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:32:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11026</guid></item><item><title>AdaViewPlanner: Adapting Video Diffusion Models for Viewpoint Planning
  in 4D Scenes</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10670</link><description>A two-stage paradigm adapts pre-trained Text-to-Video models for viewpoint prediction in 4D scenes by integrating an adaptive learning branch and a camera extrinsic diffusion branch.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent Text-to-Video (T2V) models have demonstrated powerful capability in visual simulation of real-world geometry and physical laws, indicating its potential as implicit world models. Inspired by this, we explore the feasibility of leveraging the video generation prior for viewpoint planning from given 4D scenes, since videos internally accompany dynamic scenes with natural viewpoints. To this end, we propose a two-stage paradigm to adapt pre-trained T2V models for viewpoint prediction, in a compatible manner. First, we inject the 4D scene representation into the pre-trained T2V model via an adaptive learning branch, where the 4D scene is viewpoint-agnostic and the conditional generated video embeds the viewpoints visually. Then, we formulate viewpoint extraction as a hybrid-condition guided camera extrinsic denoising process. Specifically, a camera extrinsic diffusion branch is further introduced onto the pre-trained T2V model, by taking the generated video and 4D scene as input. Experimental results show the superiority of our proposed method over existing competitors, and ablation studies validate the effectiveness of our key technical designs. To some extent, this work proves the potential of video generation models toward 4D interaction in real world.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:50:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10670</guid></item><item><title>DiT360: High-Fidelity Panoramic Image Generation via Hybrid Training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11712</link><description>DiT360 framework enhances panoramic image generation by hybrid training on perspective and panoramic data, incorporating cross-domain knowledge and hybrid supervision to improve boundary consistency and image fidelity.  					AI-generated summary 				 In this work, we propose DiT360, a DiT-based framework that performs hybrid training on perspective and panoramic data for panoramic image generation. For the issues of maintaining geometric fidelity and photorealism in generation quality, we attribute the main reason to the lack of large-scale, high-quality, real-world panoramic data, where such a data-centric view differs from prior methods that focus on model design. Basically, DiT360 has several key modules for inter-domain transformation and intra-domain augmentation, applied at both the pre-VAE image level and the post-VAE token level. At the image level, we incorporate cross-domain knowledge through perspective image guidance and panoramic refinement, which enhance perceptual quality while regularizing diversity and photorealism. At the token level, hybrid supervision is applied across multiple modules, which include circular padding for boundary continuity, yaw loss for rotational robustness, and cube loss for distortion awareness. Extensive experiments on text-to-panorama, inpainting, and outpainting tasks demonstrate that our method achieves better boundary consistency and image fidelity across eleven quantitative metrics. Our code is available at https://github.com/Insta360-Research-Team/DiT360.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:28:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11712</guid></item><item><title>Building a Foundational Guardrail for General Agentic Systems via
  Synthetic Data</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09781</link><description>AuraGen and Safiron address pre-execution safety gaps in LLM agents by synthesizing benign trajectories, injecting risks, and using a cross-planner adapter for robust risk detection and explanation.  					AI-generated summary 				 While LLM agents can plan multi-step tasks, intervening at the planning stage-before any action is executed-is often the safest way to prevent harm, since certain risks can lead to severe consequences once carried out. However, existing guardrails mostly operate post-execution, which is difficult to scale and leaves little room for controllable supervision at the plan level. To address this challenge, we highlight three critical gaps in current research: data gap, model gap, and evaluation gap. To close the data gap, we introduce AuraGen, a controllable engine that (i) synthesizes benign trajectories, (ii) injects category-labeled risks with calibrated difficulty, and (iii) filters outputs via an automated reward model, producing large and reliable corpora for pre-execution safety. To close the guardian model gap, we propose a foundational guardrail Safiron, combining a cross-planner adapter with a compact guardian model. The adapter unifies different input formats, while Safiron flags risky cases, assigns risk types, and generates rationales; trained in two stages with a broadly explored data recipe, Safiron achieves robust transfer across settings. To close the evaluation gap, we release Pre-Exec Bench, a realistic benchmark covering diverse tools and branching trajectories, which measures detection, fine-grained categorization, explanation, and cross-planner generalization in human-verified scenarios. Extensive experiments demonstrate consistent gains of the proposed guardrail over strong baselines on Pre-Exec Bench, and ablations further distill actionable practices, providing a practical template for safer agentic systems.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:06:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09781</guid></item><item><title>FinAuditing: A Financial Taxonomy-Structured Multi-Document Benchmark
  for Evaluating LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.08886</link><description>FinAuditing is a benchmark for evaluating LLMs on structured financial auditing tasks, revealing their limitations in handling taxonomy-driven, hierarchical financial documents.  					AI-generated summary 				 The complexity of the Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP) and the hierarchical structure of eXtensible Business Reporting Language (XBRL) filings make financial auditing increasingly difficult to automate and verify. While large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong capabilities in unstructured text understanding, their ability to reason over structured, interdependent, and taxonomy-driven financial documents remains largely unexplored. To fill this gap, we introduce FinAuditing, the first taxonomy-aligned, structure-aware, multi-document benchmark for evaluating LLMs on financial auditing tasks. Built from real US-GAAP-compliant XBRL filings, FinAuditing defines three complementary subtasks, FinSM for semantic consistency, FinRE for relational consistency, and FinMR for numerical consistency, each targeting a distinct aspect of structured auditing reasoning. We further propose a unified evaluation framework integrating retrieval, classification, and reasoning metrics across these subtasks. Extensive zero-shot experiments on 13 state-of-the-art LLMs reveal that current models perform inconsistently across semantic, relational, and mathematical dimensions, with accuracy drops of up to 60-90% when reasoning over hierarchical multi-document structures. Our findings expose the systematic limitations of modern LLMs in taxonomy-grounded financial reasoning and establish FinAuditing as a foundation for developing trustworthy, structure-aware, and regulation-aligned financial intelligence systems. The benchmark dataset is available at Hugging Face.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:53:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.08886</guid></item><item><title>Vlaser: Vision-Language-Action Model with Synergistic Embodied Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11027</link><description>Vlaser, a Vision-Language-Action Model, integrates high-level reasoning with low-level control for embodied agents, achieving state-of-the-art performance in embodied reasoning tasks and competitive results in robot benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 While significant research has focused on developing embodied reasoning capabilities using Vision-Language Models (VLMs) or integrating advanced VLMs into Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models for end-to-end robot control, few studies directly address the critical gap between upstream VLM-based reasoning and downstream VLA policy learning. In this work, we take an initial step toward bridging embodied reasoning with VLA policy learning by introducing Vlaser - a Vision-Language-Action Model with synergistic embodied reasoning capability, which is a foundational vision-language model designed to integrate high-level reasoning with low-level control for embodied agents. Built upon the high-quality Vlaser-6M dataset, Vlaser achieves state-of-the-art performance across a range of embodied reasoning benchmarks - including spatial reasoning, embodied grounding, embodied QA, and task planning. Furthermore, we systematically examine how different VLM initializations affect supervised VLA fine-tuning, offering novel insights into mitigating the domain shift between internet-scale pre-training data and embodied-specific policy learning data. Based on these insights, our approach achieves state-of-the-art results on the WidowX benchmark and competitive performance on the Google Robot benchmark.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:30:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11027</guid></item><item><title>SPG: Sandwiched Policy Gradient for Masked Diffusion Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09541</link><description>The Sandwiched Policy Gradient method improves reinforcement learning for diffusion large language models by using both upper and lower bounds of log-likelihood, outperforming ELBO-based methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 Diffusion large language models (dLLMs) are emerging as an efficient alternative to autoregressive models due to their ability to decode multiple tokens in parallel. However, aligning dLLMs with human preferences or task-specific rewards via reinforcement learning (RL) is challenging because their intractable log-likelihood precludes the direct application of standard policy gradient methods. While prior work uses surrogates like the evidence lower bound (ELBO), these one-sided approximations can introduce significant policy gradient bias. To address this, we propose the Sandwiched Policy Gradient (SPG) that leverages both an upper and a lower bound of the true log-likelihood. Experiments show that SPG significantly outperforms baselines based on ELBO or one-step estimation. Specifically, SPG improves the accuracy over state-of-the-art RL methods for dLLMs by 3.6% in GSM8K, 2.6% in MATH500, 18.4% in Countdown and 27.0% in Sudoku.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:26:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09541</guid></item><item><title>On Epistemic Uncertainty of Visual Tokens for Object Hallucinations in
  Large Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09008</link><description>A method to reduce object hallucinations in large vision-language models by identifying and masking uncertain visual tokens in the vision encoder.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large vision-language models (LVLMs), which integrate a vision encoder (VE) with a large language model, have achieved remarkable success across various tasks. However, there are still crucial challenges in LVLMs such as object hallucination, generating descriptions of objects that are not in the input image. Here, we argue that uncertain visual tokens within the VE is a key factor that contributes to object hallucination. Our statistical analysis found that there are positive correlations between visual tokens with high epistemic uncertainty and the occurrence of hallucinations. Furthermore, we show theoretically and empirically that visual tokens in early VE layers that exhibit large representation deviations under small adversarial perturbations indicate high epistemic uncertainty. Based on these findings, we propose a simple yet effective strategy to mitigate object hallucination by modifying the VE only. Our method comprises a proxy method with adversarial perturbations for identifying uncertain visual tokens efficiently and a method to mask these uncertain visual tokens during the self-attention process in the middle layers of the VE, suppressing their influence on visual encoding and thus alleviating hallucinations. Extensive experiments show that our method significantly reduces object hallucinations in LVLMs and can synergistically work with other prior arts.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:44:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09008</guid></item><item><title>CodePlot-CoT: Mathematical Visual Reasoning by Thinking with Code-Driven
  Images</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11718</link><description>CodePlot-CoT, a code-driven Chain-of-Thought model, enhances multimodal mathematical reasoning by generating both text and executable plotting code to solve problems requiring visual assistance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in Large Language Models (LLMs) and Vision Language Models (VLMs) have shown significant progress in mathematical reasoning, yet they still face a critical bottleneck with problems requiring visual assistance, such as drawing auxiliary lines or plotting functions to solve the problems. Most LLMs and VLMs are constrained to text-only reasoning chains, while multimodal unified models that can generate interleaved text and images lack the necessary precision and controllability for such tasks. To address this, we propose CodePlot-CoT, a code-driven Chain-of-Thought paradigm for "thinking with images" in mathematics. Our approach leverages the VLM to generate text reasoning as well as executable plotting code, which is then rendered into images as "visual thought", to solve mathematical problems. To achieve this, we first construct Math-VR, the first large-scale, bilingual dataset and benchmark for Mathematics problems with Visual Reasoning, comprising 178K samples. Second, to create high-quality training data, we develop a state-of-the-art image-to-code converter specialized for parsing complex mathematical figures into codes. Finally, using these training data, we train the CodePlot-CoT model for solving mathematical problems. Experimental results show that our model achieves up to 21% increase over base model on our new benchmark, fully validating the efficacy of our proposed code-driven reasoning paradigm. Our work opens a new direction for multimodal mathematical reasoning and provides the community with the first large-scale dataset, comprehensive benchmark, and strong approach for such problems. To facilitate future research, we make our datasets, code, and pretrained models publicly available at https://github.com/HKU-MMLab/Math-VR-CodePlot-CoT.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:10:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11718</guid></item><item><title>ReLook: Vision-Grounded RL with a Multimodal LLM Critic for Agentic Web
  Coding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11498</link><description>ReLook, a vision-grounded reinforcement learning framework, enhances front-end code generation by integrating a multimodal LLM for visual feedback and forced optimization, outperforming existing methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 While Large Language Models (LLMs) excel at algorithmic code generation, they struggle with front-end development, where correctness is judged on rendered pixels and interaction. We present ReLook, an agentic, vision-grounded reinforcement learning framework that empowers an agent to close a robust generate--diagnose--refine loop by invoking a multimodal LLM (MLLM) as a tool. During training, the agent uses the MLLM-in-the-loop both as a visual critic--scoring code with screenshots--and as a source of actionable, vision-grounded feedback; a strict zero-reward rule for invalid renders anchors renderability and prevents reward hacking. To prevent behavioral collapse, we introduce Forced Optimization, a strict acceptance rule that admits only improving revisions, yielding monotonically better trajectories. At inference, we decouple the critic and run a lightweight, critic-free self-edit cycle, keeping latency comparable to base decoding while retaining most of the gains. Across three widely used benchmarks, ReLook consistently outperforms strong baselines in vision-grounded front-end code generation, highlighting the benefits of agentic perception, visual rewards, and training-inference decoupling.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:42:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11498</guid></item><item><title>Skill-Targeted Adaptive Training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10023</link><description>A new fine-tuning strategy, STAT, uses a teacher model's metacognition to identify and address skill gaps in a student model, leading to improved performance on both in-distribution and out-of-distribution benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Language models often show little to no improvement (i.e., "saturation") when trained via vanilla supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on data similar to what they saw in their training set (e.g., MATH). We introduce a new fine-tuning strategy, STAT, to train such a student model by using the metacognition ability of a stronger large language model (LLM) as the teacher. The teacher uses the task dataset to create a list of skills needed for the task, and then labels each data point with its required skills (Didolkar et al., 2024). By monitoring the student's answers, the teacher creates a Missing-Skill-Profile for the student, tracking how often they failed to apply each skill in their responses. We use this idea to build a modified training set in one of two ways. In STAT-Sel, the teacher uses an existing set of training examples but adaptively reweights them according to the Missing-Skill-Profile. In STAT-Syn, the teacher synthesizes additional examples involving missing skills. Across extensive experiments on Llama and Qwen models, our methods yield improvements of up to 7.5% on MATH, whereas SFT provides only limited gains. Furthermore, STAT enhances performance on out-of-distribution benchmarks (e.g., AIME24/25, AMC23, etc.) by an average of 4.6%. Crucially, we find that STAT is complementary to RL via GRPO (Shao et al., 2024): after the model is improved using STAT to address skill gaps, GRPO continues to add further gains. We conclude that skill-targeted adaptive training should broadly improve current training pipelines. Our code is available at: https://github.com/princeton-pli/STAT.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:34:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10023</guid></item><item><title>PEAR: Phase Entropy Aware Reward for Efficient Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.08026</link><description>A reward mechanism called Phase Entropy Aware Reward (PEAR) controls the length of reasoning in large models by adjusting entropy at different stages, balancing conciseness and accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) have achieved impressive performance on complex reasoning tasks by generating detailed chain-of-thought (CoT) explanations. However, these responses are often excessively long, containing redundant reasoning steps that inflate inference cost and reduce usability. Controlling the length of generated reasoning without sacrificing accuracy remains an open challenge. Through a systematic empirical analysis, we reveal a consistent positive correlation between model entropy and response length at different reasoning stages across diverse LRMs: the thinking phase exhibits higher entropy, reflecting exploratory behavior of longer responses, while the final answer phase shows lower entropy, indicating a more deterministic solution. This observation suggests that entropy at different reasoning stages can serve as a control knob for balancing conciseness and performance. Based on this insight, this paper introduces Phase Entropy Aware Reward (PEAR), a reward mechanism that incorporating phase-dependent entropy into the reward design. Instead of treating all tokens uniformly, PEAR penalize excessive entropy during the thinking phase and allowing moderate exploration at the final answer phase, which encourages models to generate concise reasoning traces that retain sufficient flexibility to solve the task correctly. This enables adaptive control of response length without relying on explicit length targets or rigid truncation rules. Extensive experiments across four benchmarks demonstrate that PEAR consistently reduces response length while sustaining competitive accuracy across model scales. In addition, PEAR demonstrates strong out-of-distribution (OOD) robustness beyond the training distribution. Our code is available at: https://github.com/iNLP-Lab/PEAR.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:33:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.08026</guid></item><item><title>Self-Improving LLM Agents at Test-Time</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.07841</link><description>A test-time self-improvement method enhances language models by generating additional training examples from uncertain cases, leading to better performance with fewer samples.  					AI-generated summary 				 One paradigm of language model (LM) fine-tuning relies on creating large training datasets, under the assumption that high quantity and diversity will enable models to generalize to novel tasks after post-training. In practice, gathering large sets of data is inefficient, and training on them is prohibitively expensive; worse, there is no guarantee that the resulting model will handle complex scenarios or generalize better. Moreover, existing techniques rarely assess whether a training sample provides novel information or is redundant with the knowledge already acquired by the model, resulting in unnecessary costs. In this work, we explore a new test-time self-improvement method to create more effective and generalizable agentic LMs on-the-fly. The proposed algorithm can be summarized in three steps: (i) first it identifies the samples that model struggles with (self-awareness), (ii) then generates similar examples from detected uncertain samples (self-data augmentation), and (iii) uses these newly generated samples at test-time fine-tuning (self-improvement). We study two variants of this approach: Test-Time Self-Improvement (TT-SI), where the same model generates additional training examples from its own uncertain cases and then learns from them, and contrast this approach with Test-Time Distillation (TT-D), where a stronger model generates similar examples for uncertain cases, enabling student to adapt using distilled supervision. Empirical evaluations across different agent benchmarks demonstrate that TT-SI improves the performance with +5.48% absolute accuracy gain on average across all benchmarks and surpasses other standard learning methods, yet using 68x less training samples. Our findings highlight the promise of TT-SI, demonstrating the potential of self-improvement algorithms at test-time as a new paradigm for building more capable agents toward self-evolution.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:46:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.07841</guid></item><item><title>BrowserAgent: Building Web Agents with Human-Inspired Web Browsing
  Actions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10666</link><description>BrowserAgent, an interactive web agent using human-like browser actions and a two-stage training process, achieves competitive results in Open-QA tasks with less training data and improved reasoning for multi-hop QA.  					AI-generated summary 				 Efficiently solving real-world problems with LLMs increasingly hinges on their ability to interact with dynamic web environments and autonomously acquire external information. While recent research like Search-R1 and WebDancer demonstrates strong performance in solving web tasks, they heavily rely on additional tools to convert the interactive web environment into static text content. This is in contrast to human browsing behaviors, which involve diverse interactions with the browser, such as scrolling, clicking, and typing. In this paper, we propose BrowserAgent, a more interactive agent that solves complex tasks through human-inspired browser actions. BrowserAgent operates directly on raw web pages via Playwright through a set of predefined browser actions. We adopt a two-stage training (Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) and Rejection Fine-Tuning (RFT)) to improve the model's generalization abilities. Despite using significantly less training data than Search-R1, BrowserAgent achieves more competitive results across different Open-QA tasks. Additionally, we introduce an explicit memory mechanism to store key conclusions across steps, further enhancing the model's reasoning capabilities for long-horizon tasks. Notably, BrowserAgent-7B can achieve around 20\% improvement over Search-R1 on multi-hop QA tasks like HotpotQA, 2Wiki, and Bamboogle. These results indicate that BrowserAgent can serve as a more advanced framework for more interactive and scalable web agents.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:18:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10666</guid></item><item><title>The Personalization Trap: How User Memory Alters Emotional Reasoning in
  LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09905</link><description>LLMs exhibit systematic biases in emotional interpretation and support based on user profiles, potentially reinforcing social hierarchies.  					AI-generated summary 				 When an AI assistant remembers that Sarah is a single mother working two jobs, does it interpret her stress differently than if she were a wealthy executive? As personalized AI systems increasingly incorporate long-term user memory, understanding how this memory shapes emotional reasoning is critical. We investigate how user memory affects emotional intelligence in large language models (LLMs) by evaluating 15 models on human validated emotional intelligence tests. We find that identical scenarios paired with different user profiles produce systematically divergent emotional interpretations. Across validated user independent emotional scenarios and diverse user profiles, systematic biases emerged in several high-performing LLMs where advantaged profiles received more accurate emotional interpretations. Moreover, LLMs demonstrate significant disparities across demographic factors in emotion understanding and supportive recommendations tasks, indicating that personalization mechanisms can embed social hierarchies into models emotional reasoning. These results highlight a key challenge for memory enhanced AI: systems designed for personalization may inadvertently reinforce social inequalities.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:54:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09905</guid></item><item><title>DocReward: A Document Reward Model for Structuring and Stylizing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11391</link><description>DocReward, a document reward model, evaluates and enhances the structural and stylistic quality of generated documents, outperforming GPT-4o and GPT-5 in both accuracy and human-preferred document generation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in agentic workflows have enabled the automation of tasks such as professional document generation. However, they primarily focus on textual quality, neglecting visual structure and style, which are crucial for readability and engagement. This gap arises mainly from the absence of suitable reward models to guide agentic workflows toward producing documents with stronger structural and stylistic quality. To address this, we propose DocReward, a document reward model that evaluates documents based on their structure and style. We construct a multi-domain dataset DocPair of 117K paired documents, covering 32 domains and 267 document types, each including a high- and low-professionalism document with identical content but different structure and style. This enables the model to evaluate professionalism comprehensively, and in a textual-quality-agnostic way. DocReward is trained using the Bradley-Terry loss to score documents, penalizing predictions that contradict the annotated ranking. To assess the performance of reward models, we create a test dataset containing document bundles ranked by well-educated human evaluators. Notably, DocReward outperforms GPT-4o and GPT-5 in accuracy by 30.6 and 19.4 percentage points, respectively, demonstrating its superiority over baselines. In an extrinsic evaluation of document generation, DocReward achieves a significantly higher win rate of 60.8%, compared to GPT-5's 37.7% win rate, demonstrating its utility in guiding generation agents toward producing human-preferred documents.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:21:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11391</guid></item><item><title>FastHMR: Accelerating Human Mesh Recovery via Token and Layer Merging
  with Diffusion Decoding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10868</link><description>Two merging strategies and a diffusion-based decoder improve 3D Human Mesh Recovery by reducing computational cost and slightly enhancing performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent transformer-based models for 3D Human Mesh Recovery (HMR) have achieved strong performance but often suffer from high computational cost and complexity due to deep transformer architectures and redundant tokens. In this paper, we introduce two HMR-specific merging strategies: Error-Constrained Layer Merging (ECLM) and Mask-guided Token Merging (Mask-ToMe). ECLM selectively merges transformer layers that have minimal impact on the Mean Per Joint Position Error (MPJPE), while Mask-ToMe focuses on merging background tokens that contribute little to the final prediction. To further address the potential performance drop caused by merging, we propose a diffusion-based decoder that incorporates temporal context and leverages pose priors learned from large-scale motion capture datasets. Experiments across multiple benchmarks demonstrate that our method achieves up to 2.3x speed-up while slightly improving performance over the baseline.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:07:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10868</guid></item><item><title>Don't Just Fine-tune the Agent, Tune the Environment</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10197</link><description>Environment Tuning enables LLM agents to learn complex behaviors from problem instances using a structured curriculum, environment augmentation, and progress rewards, achieving competitive in-distribution performance and superior out-of-distribution generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Model (LLM) agents show great promise for complex, multi-turn tool-use tasks, but their development is often hampered by the extreme scarcity of high-quality training data. Supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on synthetic data leads to overfitting, whereas standard reinforcement learning (RL) struggles with a critical cold-start problem and training instability. To address these challenges, we introduce Environment Tuning, a novel training paradigm that enables agents to learn complex behaviors directly from problem instances without relying on pre-collected expert trajectories. Environment Tuning orchestrates this learning process through a structured curriculum, actionable environment augmentation that provides corrective feedback, and fine-grained progress rewards to ensure stable and efficient exploration. Using only 400 problem instances from Berkeley Function-Calling Leaderboard (BFCL) benchmark, our method not only achieves competitive in-distribution performance against strong baselines but also demonstrates superior out-of-distribution generalization, overcoming the performance collapse common to SFT-based approaches. Our work presents a paradigm shift from supervised fine-tuning on static trajectories to dynamic, environment-based exploration, paving the way for training more robust and data-efficient agents.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:19:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10197</guid></item><item><title>InfiniHuman: Infinite 3D Human Creation with Precise Control</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11650</link><description>InfiniHuman framework distills existing models to generate large-scale, richly annotated 3D human data using a diffusion-based generative pipeline, achieving high visual quality, speed, and controllability.  					AI-generated summary 				 Generating realistic and controllable 3D human avatars is a long-standing challenge, particularly when covering broad attribute ranges such as ethnicity, age, clothing styles, and detailed body shapes. Capturing and annotating large-scale human datasets for training generative models is prohibitively expensive and limited in scale and diversity. The central question we address in this paper is: Can existing foundation models be distilled to generate theoretically unbounded, richly annotated 3D human data? We introduce InfiniHuman, a framework that synergistically distills these models to produce richly annotated human data at minimal cost and with theoretically unlimited scalability. We propose InfiniHumanData, a fully automatic pipeline that leverages vision-language and image generation models to create a large-scale multi-modal dataset. User study shows our automatically generated identities are undistinguishable from scan renderings. InfiniHumanData contains 111K identities spanning unprecedented diversity. Each identity is annotated with multi-granularity text descriptions, multi-view RGB images, detailed clothing images, and SMPL body-shape parameters. Building on this dataset, we propose InfiniHumanGen, a diffusion-based generative pipeline conditioned on text, body shape, and clothing assets. InfiniHumanGen enables fast, realistic, and precisely controllable avatar generation. Extensive experiments demonstrate significant improvements over state-of-the-art methods in visual quality, generation speed, and controllability. Our approach enables high-quality avatar generation with fine-grained control at effectively unbounded scale through a practical and affordable solution. We will publicly release the automatic data generation pipeline, the comprehensive InfiniHumanData dataset, and the InfiniHumanGen models at https://yuxuan-xue.com/infini-human.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:17:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11650</guid></item><item><title>RePro: Training Language Models to Faithfully Recycle the Web for
  Pretraining</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10681</link><description>RePro, a reinforcement learning-based method, generates high-quality rephrasings of pretraining data to enhance the efficiency and accuracy of large language models.  					AI-generated summary 				 High-quality pretraining data is the fossil fuel of large language models (LLMs), yet its reserves are running low for frontier models. In this paper, we introduce RePro, a novel web recycling method that trains a relatively small LM with reinforcement learning to generate effective and faithful rephrasings of pretraining data. Specifically, we design one quality reward and three faithfulness rewards, optimizing the LM rephraser to convert organic data into high-quality rephrasings while maintaining its core semantics and structure. In our experiment, we train a 4B rephraser to recycle 72B tokens sampled from DCLM-RefinedWeb. Pretraining results on 400M and 1.4B models demonstrate that RePro delivers 4.7%-14.0% relative accuracy gains over organic-only baseline on 22 downstream tasks. RePro also outperforms ReWire, the state-of-the-art web recycling method that prompts a 70B rephraser, as well as the organic baseline with a 4x larger data pool. Experiments with different amounts of recycled data highlight that RePro improves organic data efficiency by 2-3x. Individual and distributional analyses validate that RePro preserves more critical information and faithfully reflects the characteristics of organic data compared to prompting-based methods. Together, these results show that RePro provides an efficient and controllable path to effectively harness the fossil fuel of LLM pretraining. We open-source our code, rephraser, and recycled data at https://github.com/cxcscmu/RePro.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:54:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10681</guid></item><item><title>High-Fidelity Simulated Data Generation for Real-World Zero-Shot Robotic
  Manipulation Learning with Gaussian Splatting</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10637</link><description>RoboSimGS, a Real2Sim2Real framework, uses 3D Gaussian Splatting and mesh primitives to create scalable, high-fidelity, and physically interactive simulation environments, enabling successful zero-shot sim-to-real transfer for robotic manipulation tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 The scalability of robotic learning is fundamentally bottlenecked by the significant cost and labor of real-world data collection. While simulated data offers a scalable alternative, it often fails to generalize to the real world due to significant gaps in visual appearance, physical properties, and object interactions. To address this, we propose RoboSimGS, a novel Real2Sim2Real framework that converts multi-view real-world images into scalable, high-fidelity, and physically interactive simulation environments for robotic manipulation. Our approach reconstructs scenes using a hybrid representation: 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) captures the photorealistic appearance of the environment, while mesh primitives for interactive objects ensure accurate physics simulation. Crucially, we pioneer the use of a Multi-modal Large Language Model (MLLM) to automate the creation of physically plausible, articulated assets. The MLLM analyzes visual data to infer not only physical properties (e.g., density, stiffness) but also complex kinematic structures (e.g., hinges, sliding rails) of objects. We demonstrate that policies trained entirely on data generated by RoboSimGS achieve successful zero-shot sim-to-real transfer across a diverse set of real-world manipulation tasks. Furthermore, data from RoboSimGS significantly enhances the performance and generalization capabilities of SOTA methods. Our results validate RoboSimGS as a powerful and scalable solution for bridging the sim-to-real gap.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:41:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10637</guid></item><item><title>LLaMAX2: Your Translation-Enhanced Model also Performs Well in Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09189</link><description>A novel translation-enhanced recipe using layer-selective tuning on parallel data improves translation performance in both high- and low-resource languages while maintaining reasoning proficiency.  					AI-generated summary 				 General Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in reasoning, but those enhanced for translation struggle with reasoning tasks. To address this, we propose a novel translationenhanced recipe that begins with instruct models and applies layer-selective tuning only on parallel data. Following this pipeline, we introduce the Qwen3-XPlus models, which demonstrate significant improvements in translation performance across both high- and lowresource languages, achieving 15+ spBLEU and 40+ xComet in low-resource languages, like Swahili. Interestingly, training only with small parallel datasets, Qwen3-XPlus achieves an average improvement of 1+ points on 7 multilingual tasks while maintaining proficiency comparable to the Qwen3 instruct model in 15 popular reasoning datasets. This work offers a promising approach to multilingual enhancement, significantly reducing complexity and enhancing accessibility for a wider range of languages. The code and model are publicly available.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:45:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.09189</guid></item><item><title>Graph Diffusion Transformers are In-Context Molecular Designers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.08744</link><description>DemoDiff, a demonstration-conditioned diffusion model, uses molecule-score examples to guide a denoising Transformer for molecular design, outperforming larger language models and domain-specific approaches.  					AI-generated summary 				 In-context learning allows large models to adapt to new tasks from a few demonstrations, but it has shown limited success in molecular design. Existing databases such as ChEMBL contain molecular properties spanning millions of biological assays, yet labeled data for each property remain scarce. To address this limitation, we introduce demonstration-conditioned diffusion models (DemoDiff), which define task contexts using a small set of molecule-score examples instead of text descriptions. These demonstrations guide a denoising Transformer to generate molecules aligned with target properties. For scalable pretraining, we develop a new molecular tokenizer with Node Pair Encoding that represents molecules at the motif level, requiring 5.5times fewer nodes. We curate a dataset containing millions of context tasks from multiple sources covering both drugs and materials, and pretrain a 0.7-billion-parameter model on it. Across 33 design tasks in six categories, DemoDiff matches or surpasses language models 100-1000times larger and achieves an average rank of 3.63 compared to 5.25-10.20 for domain-specific approaches. These results position DemoDiff as a molecular foundation model for in-context molecular design. Our code is available at https://github.com/liugangcode/DemoDiff.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:34:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.08744</guid></item><item><title>Are Large Reasoning Models Interruptible?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11713</link><description>Large Reasoning Models evaluated in dynamic scenarios with interruptions and changing context show significant performance drops compared to static evaluations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) excel at complex reasoning but are traditionally evaluated in static, "frozen world" settings: model responses are assumed to be instantaneous, and the context of a request is presumed to be immutable over the duration of the response. While generally true for short-term tasks, the "frozen world" assumption breaks down in modern reasoning tasks such as assistive programming, where models may take hours to think through problems and code may change dramatically from the time the model starts thinking to the model's final output. In this work, we challenge the frozen world assumption and evaluate LRM robustness under two realistic dynamic scenarios: interruptions, which test the quality of the model's partial outputs on a limited budget, and dynamic context, which tests model adaptation to in-flight changes. Across mathematics and programming benchmarks that require long-form reasoning, static evaluations consistently overestimate robustness: even state-of-the-art LRMs, which achieve high accuracy in static settings, can fail unpredictably when interrupted or exposed to changing context, with performance dropping by up to 60% when updates are introduced late in the reasoning process. Our analysis further reveals several novel failure modes, including reasoning leakage, where models fold the reasoning into their final answer when interrupted; panic, where under time pressure models abandon reasoning entirely and return incorrect answers; and self-doubt, where performance degrades while incorporating updated information.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:55:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11713</guid></item><item><title>IVEBench: Modern Benchmark Suite for Instruction-Guided Video Editing
  Assessment</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11647</link><description>IVEBench is a benchmark suite for instruction-guided video editing that addresses limitations in existing benchmarks through diverse video sources, comprehensive task coverage, and a multi-dimensional evaluation protocol.  					AI-generated summary 				 Instruction-guided video editing has emerged as a rapidly advancing research direction, offering new opportunities for intuitive content transformation while also posing significant challenges for systematic evaluation. Existing video editing benchmarks fail to support the evaluation of instruction-guided video editing adequately and further suffer from limited source diversity, narrow task coverage and incomplete evaluation metrics. To address the above limitations, we introduce IVEBench, a modern benchmark suite specifically designed for instruction-guided video editing assessment. IVEBench comprises a diverse database of 600 high-quality source videos, spanning seven semantic dimensions, and covering video lengths ranging from 32 to 1,024 frames. It further includes 8 categories of editing tasks with 35 subcategories, whose prompts are generated and refined through large language models and expert review. Crucially, IVEBench establishes a three-dimensional evaluation protocol encompassing video quality, instruction compliance and video fidelity, integrating both traditional metrics and multimodal large language model-based assessments. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of IVEBench in benchmarking state-of-the-art instruction-guided video editing methods, showing its ability to provide comprehensive and human-aligned evaluation outcomes.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:19:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11647</guid></item><item><title>LikePhys: Evaluating Intuitive Physics Understanding in Video Diffusion
  Models via Likelihood Preference</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11512</link><description>LikePhys evaluates intuitive physics in video diffusion models using a denoising objective-based metric, demonstrating better alignment with human preference than existing methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 Intuitive physics understanding in video diffusion models plays an essential role in building general-purpose physically plausible world simulators, yet accurately evaluating such capacity remains a challenging task due to the difficulty in disentangling physics correctness from visual appearance in generation. To the end, we introduce LikePhys, a training-free method that evaluates intuitive physics in video diffusion models by distinguishing physically valid and impossible videos using the denoising objective as an ELBO-based likelihood surrogate on a curated dataset of valid-invalid pairs. By testing on our constructed benchmark of twelve scenarios spanning over four physics domains, we show that our evaluation metric, Plausibility Preference Error (PPE), demonstrates strong alignment with human preference, outperforming state-of-the-art evaluator baselines. We then systematically benchmark intuitive physics understanding in current video diffusion models. Our study further analyses how model design and inference settings affect intuitive physics understanding and highlights domain-specific capacity variations across physical laws. Empirical results show that, despite current models struggling with complex and chaotic dynamics, there is a clear trend of improvement in physics understanding as model capacity and inference settings scale.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:23:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11512</guid></item><item><title>The Hidden DNA of LLM-Generated JavaScript: Structural Patterns Enable
  High-Accuracy Authorship Attribution</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10493</link><description>A study on authorship attribution of JavaScript code generated by large language models using a custom dataset and advanced machine learning classifiers demonstrates high accuracy even after code transformations.  					AI-generated summary 				 In this paper, we present the first large-scale study exploring whether JavaScript code generated by Large Language Models (LLMs) can reveal which model produced it, enabling reliable authorship attribution and model fingerprinting. With the rapid rise of AI-generated code, attribution is playing a critical role in detecting vulnerabilities, flagging malicious content, and ensuring accountability. While AI-vs-human detection usually treats AI as a single category we show that individual LLMs leave unique stylistic signatures, even among models belonging to the same family or parameter size. To this end, we introduce LLM-NodeJS, a dataset of 50,000 Node.js back-end programs from 20 large language models. Each has four transformed variants, yielding 250,000 unique JavaScript samples and two additional representations (JSIR and AST) for diverse research applications. Using this dataset, we benchmark traditional machine learning classifiers against fine-tuned Transformer encoders and introduce CodeT5-JSA, a custom architecture derived from the 770M-parameter CodeT5 model with its decoder removed and a modified classification head. It achieves 95.8% accuracy on five-class attribution, 94.6% on ten-class, and 88.5% on twenty-class tasks, surpassing other tested models such as BERT, CodeBERT, and Longformer. We demonstrate that classifiers capture deeper stylistic regularities in program dataflow and structure, rather than relying on surface-level features. As a result, attribution remains effective even after mangling, comment removal, and heavy code transformations. To support open science and reproducibility, we release the LLM-NodeJS dataset, Google Colab training scripts, and all related materials on GitHub: https://github.com/LLM-NodeJS-dataset.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:31:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10493</guid></item><item><title>Pathology-CoT: Learning Visual Chain-of-Thought Agent from Expert Whole
  Slide Image Diagnosis Behavior</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.04587</link><description>A framework records and utilizes expert navigation behavior in whole-slide imaging to build an agentic system for pathology diagnosis, achieving high precision and recall in metastasis detection.  					AI-generated summary 				 Diagnosing a whole-slide image is an interactive, multi-stage process involving changes in magnification and movement between fields. Although recent pathology foundation models are strong, practical agentic systems that decide what field to examine next, adjust magnification, and deliver explainable diagnoses are still lacking. The blocker is data: scalable, clinically aligned supervision of expert viewing behavior that is tacit and experience-based, not written in textbooks or online, and therefore absent from large language model training. We introduce the AI Session Recorder, which works with standard WSI viewers to unobtrusively record routine navigation and convert the viewer logs into standardized behavioral commands (inspect or peek at discrete magnifications) and bounding boxes. A lightweight human-in-the-loop review turns AI-drafted rationales into the Pathology-CoT dataset, a form of paired "where to look" and "why it matters" supervision produced at roughly six times lower labeling time. Using this behavioral data, we build Pathologist-o3, a two-stage agent that first proposes regions of interest and then performs behavior-guided reasoning. On gastrointestinal lymph-node metastasis detection, it achieved 84.5% precision, 100.0% recall, and 75.4% accuracy, exceeding the state-of-the-art OpenAI o3 model and generalizing across backbones. To our knowledge, this constitutes one of the first behavior-grounded agentic systems in pathology. Turning everyday viewer logs into scalable, expert-validated supervision, our framework makes agentic pathology practical and establishes a path to human-aligned, upgradeable clinical AI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:58:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.04587</guid></item></channel></rss>