<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>When Reasoning Meets Its Laws</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17901</link><description>A framework called Laws of Reasoning (LoRe) is introduced to theoretically define desired reasoning behaviors in Large Reasoning Models, with a focus on compute and accuracy laws, and a benchmark (LoRe-Bench) to measure these properties.  					AI-generated summary 				 Despite the superior performance of Large Reasoning Models (LRMs), their reasoning behaviors are often counterintuitive, leading to suboptimal reasoning capabilities. To theoretically formalize the desired reasoning behaviors, this paper presents the Laws of Reasoning (LoRe), a unified framework that characterizes intrinsic reasoning patterns in LRMs. We first propose compute law with the hypothesis that the reasoning compute should scale linearly with question complexity. Beyond compute, we extend LoRe with a supplementary accuracy law. Since the question complexity is difficult to quantify in practice, we examine these hypotheses by two properties of the laws, monotonicity and compositionality. We therefore introduce LoRe-Bench, a benchmark that systematically measures these two tractable properties for large reasoning models. Evaluation shows that most reasoning models exhibit reasonable monotonicity but lack compositionality. In response, we develop an effective finetuning approach that enforces compute-law compositionality. Extensive empirical studies demonstrate that better compliance with compute laws yields consistently improved reasoning performance on multiple benchmarks, and uncovers synergistic effects across properties and laws. Project page: https://lore-project.github.io/</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:40:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17901</guid></item><item><title>Seed-Prover 1.5: Mastering Undergraduate-Level Theorem Proving via Learning from Experience</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17260</link><description>Seed-Prover 1.5, a formal theorem-proving model using large-scale agentic reinforcement learning and an efficient test-time scaling workflow, demonstrates superior performance in solving mathematical problems across various levels with reduced computational resources.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models have recently made significant progress to generate rigorous mathematical proofs. In contrast, utilizing LLMs for theorem proving in formal languages (such as Lean) remains challenging and computationally expensive, particularly when addressing problems at the undergraduate level and beyond. In this work, we present Seed-Prover 1.5, a formal theorem-proving model trained via large-scale agentic reinforcement learning, alongside an efficient test-time scaling (TTS) workflow. Through extensive interactions with Lean and other tools, the model continuously accumulates experience during the RL process, substantially enhancing the capability and efficiency of formal theorem proving. Furthermore, leveraging recent advancements in natural language proving, our TTS workflow efficiently bridges the gap between natural and formal languages. Compared to state-of-the-art methods, Seed-Prover 1.5 achieves superior performance with a smaller compute budget. It solves 88\% of PutnamBench (undergraduate-level), 80\% of Fate-H (graduate-level), and 33\% of Fate-X (PhD-level) problems. Notably, using our system, we solved 11 out of 12 problems from Putnam 2025 within 9 hours. Our findings suggest that scaling learning from experience, driven by high-quality formal feedback, holds immense potential for the future of formal mathematical reasoning.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:41:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17260</guid></item><item><title>4D-RGPT: Toward Region-level 4D Understanding via Perceptual Distillation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17012</link><description>4D-RGPT, a specialized multimodal LLM, enhances 4D perception in video inputs through Perceptual 4D Distillation and is evaluated on R4D-Bench, a new benchmark for depth-aware dynamic scenes.  					AI-generated summary 				 Despite advances in Multimodal LLMs (MLLMs), their ability to reason over 3D structures and temporal dynamics remains limited, constrained by weak 4D perception and temporal understanding. Existing 3D and 4D Video Question Answering (VQA) benchmarks also emphasize static scenes and lack region-level prompting. We tackle these issues by introducing: (a) 4D-RGPT, a specialized MLLM designed to capture 4D representations from video inputs with enhanced temporal perception; (b) Perceptual 4D Distillation (P4D), a training framework that transfers 4D representations from a frozen expert model into 4D-RGPT for comprehensive 4D perception; and (c) R4D-Bench, a benchmark for depth-aware dynamic scenes with region-level prompting, built via a hybrid automated and human-verified pipeline. Our 4D-RGPT achieves notable improvements on both existing 4D VQA benchmarks and the proposed R4D-Bench benchmark.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:38:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17012</guid></item><item><title>PhysBrain: Human Egocentric Data as a Bridge from Vision Language Models to Physical Intelligence</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.16793</link><description>Proposed Egocentric2Embodiment pipeline translates human egocentric videos into structured training data for robots, enhancing their egocentric understanding and task performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Robotic generalization relies on physical intelligence: the ability to reason about state changes, contact-rich interactions, and long-horizon planning under egocentric perception and action. However, most VLMs are trained primarily on third-person data, creating a fundamental viewpoint mismatch for humanoid robots. Scaling robot egocentric data collection remains impractical due to high cost and limited diversity, whereas large-scale human egocentric videos offer a scalable alternative that naturally capture rich interaction context and causal structure. The key challenge is to convert raw egocentric videos into structured and reliable embodiment training supervision. Accordingly, we propose an Egocentric2Embodiment translation pipeline that transforms first-person videos into multi-level, schema-driven VQA supervision with enforced evidence grounding and temporal consistency, enabling the construction of the Egocentric2Embodiment dataset (E2E-3M) at scale. An egocentric-aware embodied brain, termed PhysBrain, is obtained by training on the E2E-3M dataset. PhysBrain exhibits substantially improved egocentric understanding, particularly for planning on EgoThink. It provides an egocentric-aware initialization that enables more sample-efficient VLA fine-tuning and higher SimplerEnv success rates (53.9\%), demonstrating effective transfer from human egocentric supervision to downstream robot control.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:29:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.16793</guid></item><item><title>Are We on the Right Way to Assessing LLM-as-a-Judge?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.16041</link><description>Sage is a human-free evaluation suite for LLM-as-a-Judge, using rational choice theory to assess local and global consistency, revealing significant reliability issues with current LLM judges.  					AI-generated summary 				 LLM-as-a-Judge has been widely adopted as an evaluation method and served as supervised rewards in model training. However, existing benchmarks for LLM-as-a-Judge are mainly relying on human-annotated ground truth, which introduces human bias that undermines the assessment of reliability and imposes scalability constraints. To overcome these limitations, we introduce Sage, a novel evaluation suite that assesses the quality of LLM judges without necessitating any human annotation. Inspired by axioms of rational choice theory, Sage introduces two new lenses for measuring LLM-as-a-Judge: local self-consistency (pair-wise preference stability) and global logical consistency (transitivity across a full set of preferences). We curate a dataset of 650 questions by combining structured benchmark problems with real-world user queries. Our experiments demonstrate both the stability of our metrics and their high correlation with supervised benchmarks like LLMBar and RewardBench2, confirming Sage's reliability as an evaluation suite for the robustness and accuracy of LLM-as-a-Judge. Based on Sage, we reveal that current state-of-the-art LLMs exhibit significant reliability problems when acting as judges in both scoring and pairwise settings; even the top-performing models, Gemini-2.5-Pro and GPT-5, fail to maintain consistent preferences in nearly a quarter of difficult cases. We attribute this to a new phenomenon called situational preference, which explains why explicit rubrics or criteria can help the model judge consistently across answer pairs. Our further analysis shows that finetuned LLM-as-a-Judge is a feasible method to boost performance, and the panel-based judge as well as deep reasoning can enhance the judging consistency. We also find substantial inconsistency in human judgments, which indicates that human annotation may not be a reliable gold standard.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:47:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.16041</guid></item><item><title>Turn-PPO: Turn-Level Advantage Estimation with PPO for Improved Multi-Turn RL in Agentic LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17008</link><description>Turn-PPO, a variant of PPO tailored for multi-turn RL tasks, improves advantage estimation and performance over GRPO in environments requiring long-horizon reasoning.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement learning (RL) has re-emerged as a natural approach for training interactive LLM agents in real-world environments. However, directly applying the widely used Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) algorithm to multi-turn tasks exposes notable limitations, particularly in scenarios requiring long-horizon reasoning. To address these challenges, we investigate more stable and effective advantage estimation strategies, especially for multi-turn settings. We first explore Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO) as an alternative and find it to be more robust than GRPO. To further enhance PPO in multi-turn scenarios, we introduce turn-PPO, a variant that operates on a turn-level MDP formulation, as opposed to the commonly used token-level MDP. Our results on the WebShop and Sokoban datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of turn-PPO, both with and without long reasoning components.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:49:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17008</guid></item><item><title>SWE-Bench++: A Framework for the Scalable Generation of Software Engineering Benchmarks from Open-Source Repositories</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17419</link><description>SWE-Bench++ is an automated framework generating repository-level coding tasks from live GitHub pull requests, offering a scalable, multilingual benchmark for evaluating and improving code generation models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Benchmarks like SWE-bench have standardized the evaluation of Large Language Models (LLMs) on repository-level software engineering tasks. However, these efforts remain limited by manual curation, static datasets, and a focus on Python-based bug fixes. We introduce SWE-Bench++, an automated framework that generates repository-level coding tasks from open-source GitHub projects. Unlike synthetic approaches, our pipeline harvests live pull requests to cover both bug fixes and feature requests across 11 languages. SWE-Bench++ turns GitHub pull requests (PRs) into reproducible, execution-based tasks via four stages: programmatic sourcing, environment synthesis, test oracle extraction, and quality assurance. A final hint-guided trajectory synthesis step converts instances that strong models fail on into training trajectories. Our initial benchmark consists of 11,133 instances from 3,971 repositories across 11 languages. On a subset of 1,782 instances of this benchmark, today's strongest models perform as follows: claude-sonnet-4.5 achieves 36.20% pass@10, gpt-5-2025-08-07 34.57%, gemini/gemini-2.5-pro 24.92%, and gpt-4o 16.89%. We further demonstrate the utility of our dataset by showing that fine-tuning on SWE-Bench++ instances yields measurable improvements on the SWE-bench Multilingual benchmark. SWE-Bench++ provides a scalable, multilingual benchmark for evaluating and improving repository-level code generation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:43:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17419</guid></item><item><title>Physics of Language Models: Part 4.1, Architecture Design and the Magic of Canon Layers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17351</link><description>Canon layers, lightweight architectural components, enhance reasoning depth and breadth in language models, improving performance in synthetic and real-world pretraining tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Understanding architectural differences in language models is challenging, especially at academic-scale pretraining (e.g., 1.3B parameters, 100B tokens), where results are often dominated by noise and randomness. To overcome this, we introduce controlled synthetic pretraining tasks that isolate and evaluate core model capabilities. Within this framework, we discover CANON LAYERS: lightweight architectural components -- named after the musical term "canon" -- that promote horizontal information flow across neighboring tokens. Canon layers compute weighted sums of nearby token representations and integrate seamlessly into Transformers, linear attention, state-space models, or any sequence architecture.   We present 12 key results. This includes how Canon layers enhance reasoning depth (e.g., by 2times), reasoning breadth, knowledge manipulation, etc. They lift weak architectures like NoPE to match RoPE, and linear attention to rival SOTA linear models like Mamba2/GDN -- validated both through synthetic tasks and real-world academic-scale pretraining. This synthetic playground offers an economical, principled path to isolate core model capabilities often obscured at academic scales. Equipped with infinite high-quality data, it may even PREDICT how future architectures will behave as training pipelines improve -- e.g., through better data curation or RL-based post-training -- unlocking deeper reasoning and hierarchical inference.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:34:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17351</guid></item><item><title>Probing Scientific General Intelligence of LLMs with Scientist-Aligned Workflows</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.16969</link><description>A framework for Scientific General Intelligence (SGI) is presented, evaluated using SGI-Bench, and improved with Test-Time Reinforcement Learning, highlighting gaps in existing models' scientific capabilities.  					AI-generated summary 				 Despite advances in scientific AI, a coherent framework for Scientific General Intelligence (SGI)-the ability to autonomously conceive, investigate, and reason across scientific domains-remains lacking. We present an operational SGI definition grounded in the Practical Inquiry Model (PIM: Deliberation, Conception, Action, Perception) and operationalize it via four scientist-aligned tasks: deep research, idea generation, dry/wet experiments, and experimental reasoning. SGI-Bench comprises over 1,000 expert-curated, cross-disciplinary samples inspired by Science's 125 Big Questions, enabling systematic evaluation of state-of-the-art LLMs. Results reveal gaps: low exact match (10--20%) in deep research despite step-level alignment; ideas lacking feasibility and detail; high code executability but low execution result accuracy in dry experiments; low sequence fidelity in wet protocols; and persistent multimodal comparative-reasoning challenges. We further introduce Test-Time Reinforcement Learning (TTRL), which optimizes retrieval-augmented novelty rewards at inference, enhancing hypothesis novelty without reference answer. Together, our PIM-grounded definition, workflow-centric benchmark, and empirical insights establish a foundation for AI systems that genuinely participate in scientific discovery.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:44:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.16969</guid></item><item><title>Robust-R1: Degradation-Aware Reasoning for Robust Visual Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17532</link><description>A novel framework, Robust-R1, enhances multimodal large language models' robustness to visual degradations through explicit modeling, supervised fine-tuning, reward-driven alignment, and dynamic reasoning depth scaling, achieving state-of-the-art performance on real-world degradation benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multimodal Large Language Models struggle to maintain reliable performance under extreme real-world visual degradations, which impede their practical robustness. Existing robust MLLMs predominantly rely on implicit training/adaptation that focuses solely on visual encoder generalization, suffering from limited interpretability and isolated optimization. To overcome these limitations, we propose Robust-R1, a novel framework that explicitly models visual degradations through structured reasoning chains. Our approach integrates: (i) supervised fine-tuning for degradation-aware reasoning foundations, (ii) reward-driven alignment for accurately perceiving degradation parameters, and (iii) dynamic reasoning depth scaling adapted to degradation intensity. To facilitate this approach, we introduce a specialized 11K dataset featuring realistic degradations synthesized across four critical real-world visual processing stages, each annotated with structured chains connecting degradation parameters, perceptual influence, pristine semantic reasoning chain, and conclusion. Comprehensive evaluations demonstrate state-of-the-art robustness: Robust-R1 outperforms all general and robust baselines on the real-world degradation benchmark R-Bench, while maintaining superior anti-degradation performance under multi-intensity adversarial degradations on MMMB, MMStar, and RealWorldQA.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:16:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17532</guid></item><item><title>StageVAR: Stage-Aware Acceleration for Visual Autoregressive Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.16483</link><description>StageVAR accelerates visual autoregressive models by selectively pruning or approximating less critical later stages, achieving significant speedup with minimal quality loss.  					AI-generated summary 				 Visual Autoregressive (VAR) modeling departs from the next-token prediction paradigm of traditional Autoregressive (AR) models through next-scale prediction, enabling high-quality image generation. However, the VAR paradigm suffers from sharply increased computational complexity and running time at large-scale steps. Although existing acceleration methods reduce runtime for large-scale steps, but rely on manual step selection and overlook the varying importance of different stages in the generation process. To address this challenge, we present StageVAR, a systematic study and stage-aware acceleration framework for VAR models. Our analysis shows that early steps are critical for preserving semantic and structural consistency and should remain intact, while later steps mainly refine details and can be pruned or approximated for acceleration. Building on these insights, StageVAR introduces a plug-and-play acceleration strategy that exploits semantic irrelevance and low-rank properties in late-stage computations, without requiring additional training. Our proposed StageVAR achieves up to 3.4x speedup with only a 0.01 drop on GenEval and a 0.26 decrease on DPG, consistently outperforming existing acceleration baselines. These results highlight stage-aware design as a powerful principle for efficient visual autoregressive image generation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 04:08:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.16483</guid></item><item><title>Animate Any Character in Any World</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17796</link><description>AniX synthesizes temporally coherent videos by extending controllable-entity models to support diverse, user-defined character interactions in static 3D environments using conditional autoregressive video generation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in world models have greatly enhanced interactive environment simulation. Existing methods mainly fall into two categories: (1) static world generation models, which construct 3D environments without active agents, and (2) controllable-entity models, which allow a single entity to perform limited actions in an otherwise uncontrollable environment. In this work, we introduce AniX, leveraging the realism and structural grounding of static world generation while extending controllable-entity models to support user-specified characters capable of performing open-ended actions. Users can provide a 3DGS scene and a character, then direct the character through natural language to perform diverse behaviors from basic locomotion to object-centric interactions while freely exploring the environment. AniX synthesizes temporally coherent video clips that preserve visual fidelity with the provided scene and character, formulated as a conditional autoregressive video generation problem. Built upon a pre-trained video generator, our training strategy significantly enhances motion dynamics while maintaining generalization across actions and characters. Our evaluation covers a broad range of aspects, including visual quality, character consistency, action controllability, and long-horizon coherence.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:54:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2512.17796</guid></item></channel></rss>