<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>RepText: Rendering Visual Text via Replicating</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19724</link><description>Although contemporary text-to-image generation models have achieved remarkable breakthroughs in producing visually appealing images, their capacity to generate precise and flexible typographic elements, especially non-Latin alphabets, remains constrained. To address these limitations, we start from an naive assumption that text understanding is only a sufficient condition for text rendering, but not a necessary condition. Based on this, we present RepText, which aims to empower pre-trained monolingual text-to-image generation models with the ability to accurately render, or more precisely, replicate, multilingual visual text in user-specified fonts, without the need to really understand them. Specifically, we adopt the setting from ControlNet and additionally integrate language agnostic glyph and position of rendered text to enable generating harmonized visual text, allowing users to customize text content, font and position on their needs. To improve accuracy, a text perceptual loss is employed along with the diffusion loss. Furthermore, to stabilize rendering process, at the inference phase, we directly initialize with noisy glyph latent instead of random initialization, and adopt region masks to restrict the feature injection to only the text region to avoid distortion of the background. We conducted extensive experiments to verify the effectiveness of our RepText relative to existing works, our approach outperforms existing open-source methods and achieves comparable results to native multi-language closed-source models. To be more fair, we also exhaustively discuss its limitations in the end.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 03:57:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19724</guid></item><item><title>LLM-Powered GUI Agents in Phone Automation: Surveying Progress and
  Prospects</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19838</link><description>With the rapid rise of large language models (LLMs), phone automation has undergone transformative changes. This paper systematically reviews LLM-driven phone GUI agents, highlighting their evolution from script-based automation to intelligent, adaptive systems. We first contextualize key challenges, (i) limited generality, (ii) high maintenance overhead, and (iii) weak intent comprehension, and show how LLMs address these issues through advanced language understanding, multimodal perception, and robust decision-making. We then propose a taxonomy covering fundamental agent frameworks (single-agent, multi-agent, plan-then-act), modeling approaches (prompt engineering, training-based), and essential datasets and benchmarks. Furthermore, we detail task-specific architectures, supervised fine-tuning, and reinforcement learning strategies that bridge user intent and GUI operations. Finally, we discuss open challenges such as dataset diversity, on-device deployment efficiency, user-centric adaptation, and security concerns, offering forward-looking insights into this rapidly evolving field. By providing a structured overview and identifying pressing research gaps, this paper serves as a definitive reference for researchers and practitioners seeking to harness LLMs in designing scalable, user-friendly phone GUI agents.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 02:00:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19838</guid></item><item><title>Clinical knowledge in LLMs does not translate to human interactions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.18919</link><description>Global healthcare providers are exploring use of large language models (LLMs) to provide medical advice to the public. LLMs now achieve nearly perfect scores on medical licensing exams, but this does not necessarily translate to accurate performance in real-world settings. We tested if LLMs can assist members of the public in identifying underlying conditions and choosing a course of action (disposition) in ten medical scenarios in a controlled study with 1,298 participants. Participants were randomly assigned to receive assistance from an LLM (GPT-4o, Llama 3, Command R+) or a source of their choice (control). Tested alone, LLMs complete the scenarios accurately, correctly identifying conditions in 94.9% of cases and disposition in 56.3% on average. However, participants using the same LLMs identified relevant conditions in less than 34.5% of cases and disposition in less than 44.2%, both no better than the control group. We identify user interactions as a challenge to the deployment of LLMs for medical advice. Standard benchmarks for medical knowledge and simulated patient interactions do not predict the failures we find with human participants. Moving forward, we recommend systematic human user testing to evaluate interactive capabilities prior to public deployments in healthcare.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 02:31:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.18919</guid></item><item><title>CipherBank: Exploring the Boundary of LLM Reasoning Capabilities through
  Cryptography Challenges</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19093</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities, especially the recent advancements in reasoning, such as o1 and o3, pushing the boundaries of AI. Despite these impressive achievements in mathematics and coding, the reasoning abilities of LLMs in domains requiring cryptographic expertise remain underexplored. In this paper, we introduce CipherBank, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate the reasoning capabilities of LLMs in cryptographic decryption tasks. CipherBank comprises 2,358 meticulously crafted problems, covering 262 unique plaintexts across 5 domains and 14 subdomains, with a focus on privacy-sensitive and real-world scenarios that necessitate encryption. From a cryptographic perspective, CipherBank incorporates 3 major categories of encryption methods, spanning 9 distinct algorithms, ranging from classical ciphers to custom cryptographic techniques. We evaluate state-of-the-art LLMs on CipherBank, e.g., GPT-4o, DeepSeek-V3, and cutting-edge reasoning-focused models such as o1 and DeepSeek-R1. Our results reveal significant gaps in reasoning abilities not only between general-purpose chat LLMs and reasoning-focused LLMs but also in the performance of current reasoning-focused models when applied to classical cryptographic decryption tasks, highlighting the challenges these models face in understanding and manipulating encrypted data. Through detailed analysis and error investigations, we provide several key observations that shed light on the limitations and potential improvement areas for LLMs in cryptographic reasoning. These findings underscore the need for continuous advancements in LLM reasoning capabilities.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 02:29:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19093</guid></item><item><title>SPC: Evolving Self-Play Critic via Adversarial Games for LLM Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19162</link><description>Evaluating the step-by-step reliability of large language model (LLM) reasoning, such as Chain-of-Thought, remains challenging due to the difficulty and cost of obtaining high-quality step-level supervision. In this paper, we introduce Self-Play Critic (SPC), a novel approach where a critic model evolves its ability to assess reasoning steps through adversarial self-play games, eliminating the need for manual step-level annotation. SPC involves fine-tuning two copies of a base model to play two roles, namely a "sneaky generator" that deliberately produces erroneous steps designed to be difficult to detect, and a "critic" that analyzes the correctness of reasoning steps. These two models engage in an adversarial game in which the generator aims to fool the critic, while the critic model seeks to identify the generator's errors. Using reinforcement learning based on the game outcomes, the models iteratively improve; the winner of each confrontation receives a positive reward and the loser receives a negative reward, driving continuous self-evolution. Experiments on three reasoning process benchmarks (ProcessBench, PRM800K, DeltaBench) demonstrate that our SPC progressively enhances its error detection capabilities (e.g., accuracy increases from 70.8% to 77.7% on ProcessBench) and surpasses strong baselines, including distilled R1 model. Furthermore, applying SPC to guide the test-time search of diverse LLMs significantly improves their mathematical reasoning performance on MATH500 and AIME2024, outperforming state-of-the-art process reward models.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 08:16:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19162</guid></item><item><title>MMInference: Accelerating Pre-filling for Long-Context VLMs via
  Modality-Aware Permutation Sparse Attention</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16083</link><description>The integration of long-context capabilities with visual understanding unlocks unprecedented potential for Vision Language Models (VLMs). However, the quadratic attention complexity during the pre-filling phase remains a significant obstacle to real-world deployment. To overcome this limitation, we introduce MMInference (Multimodality Million tokens Inference), a dynamic sparse attention method that accelerates the prefilling stage for long-context multi-modal inputs. First, our analysis reveals that the temporal and spatial locality of video input leads to a unique sparse pattern, the Grid pattern. Simultaneously, VLMs exhibit markedly different sparse distributions across different modalities. We introduce a permutation-based method to leverage the unique Grid pattern and handle modality boundary issues. By offline search the optimal sparse patterns for each head, MMInference constructs the sparse distribution dynamically based on the input. We also provide optimized GPU kernels for efficient sparse computations. Notably, MMInference integrates seamlessly into existing VLM pipelines without any model modifications or fine-tuning. Experiments on multi-modal benchmarks-including Video QA, Captioning, VisionNIAH, and Mixed-Modality NIAH-with state-of-the-art long-context VLMs (LongVila, LlavaVideo, VideoChat-Flash, Qwen2.5-VL) show that MMInference accelerates the pre-filling stage by up to 8.3x at 1M tokens while maintaining accuracy. Our code is available at https://aka.ms/MMInference.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 05:04:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.16083</guid></item><item><title>Benchmarking Multimodal Mathematical Reasoning with Explicit Visual
  Dependency</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.18589</link><description>Recent advancements in Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) have significantly enhanced their ability to integrate visual and linguistic information, achieving near-human proficiency in tasks like object recognition, captioning, and visual question answering. However, current benchmarks typically focus on knowledge-centric evaluations that assess domain-specific expertise, often neglecting the core ability to reason about fundamental mathematical elements and visual concepts. We identify a gap in evaluating elementary-level math problems, which rely on explicit visual dependencies-requiring models to discern, integrate, and reason across multiple images while incorporating commonsense knowledge, all of which are crucial for advancing toward broader AGI capabilities. To address this gap, we introduce VCBENCH, a comprehensive benchmark for multimodal mathematical reasoning with explicit visual dependencies. VCBENCH includes 1,720 problems across six cognitive domains, featuring 6,697 images (averaging 3.9 per question) to ensure multi-image reasoning. We evaluate 26 state-of-the-art LVLMs on VCBENCH, revealing substantial performance disparities, with even the top models unable to exceed 50% accuracy. Our findings highlight the ongoing challenges in visual-mathematical integration and suggest avenues for future LVLM advancements.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 08:23:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.18589</guid></item><item><title>Group Downsampling with Equivariant Anti-aliasing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.17258</link><description>Downsampling layers are crucial building blocks in CNN architectures, which help to increase the receptive field for learning high-level features and reduce the amount of memory/computation in the model. In this work, we study the generalization of the uniform downsampling layer for group equivariant architectures, e.g., G-CNNs. That is, we aim to downsample signals (feature maps) on general finite groups with anti-aliasing. This involves the following: (a) Given a finite group and a downsampling rate, we present an algorithm to form a suitable choice of subgroup. (b) Given a group and a subgroup, we study the notion of bandlimited-ness and propose how to perform anti-aliasing. Notably, our method generalizes the notion of downsampling based on classical sampling theory. When the signal is on a cyclic group, i.e., periodic, our method recovers the standard downsampling of an ideal low-pass filter followed by a subsampling operation. Finally, we conducted experiments on image classification tasks demonstrating that the proposed downsampling operation improves accuracy, better preserves equivariance, and reduces model size when incorporated into G-equivariant networks</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 04:11:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.17258</guid></item><item><title>TrustGeoGen: Scalable and Formal-Verified Data Engine for Trustworthy
  Multi-modal Geometric Problem Solving</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15780</link><description>Mathematical geometric problem solving (GPS) often requires effective integration of multimodal information and verifiable logical coherence. Despite the fast development of large language models in general problem solving, it remains unresolved regarding with both methodology and benchmarks, especially given the fact that exiting synthetic GPS benchmarks are often not self-verified and contain noise and self-contradicted information due to the illusion of LLMs. In this paper, we propose a scalable data engine called TrustGeoGen for problem generation, with formal verification to provide a principled benchmark, which we believe lays the foundation for the further development of methods for GPS. The engine synthesizes geometric data through four key innovations: 1) multimodal-aligned generation of diagrams, textual descriptions, and stepwise solutions; 2) formal verification ensuring rule-compliant reasoning paths; 3) a bootstrapping mechanism enabling complexity escalation via recursive state generation and 4) our devised GeoExplore series algorithms simultaneously produce multi-solution variants and self-reflective backtracking traces. By formal logical verification, TrustGeoGen produces GeoTrust-200K dataset with guaranteed modality integrity, along with GeoTrust-test testset. Experiments reveal the state-of-the-art models achieve only 49.17\% accuracy on GeoTrust-test, demonstrating its evaluation stringency. Crucially, models trained on GeoTrust achieve OOD generalization on GeoQA, significantly reducing logical inconsistencies relative to pseudo-label annotated by OpenAI-o1. Our code is available at https://github.com/Alpha-Innovator/TrustGeoGen</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 04:06:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15780</guid></item><item><title>ChiseLLM: Unleashing the Power of Reasoning LLMs for Chisel Agile
  Hardware Development</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19144</link><description>The growing demand for Domain-Specific Architecture (DSA) has driven the development of Agile Hardware Development Methodology (AHDM). Hardware Construction Language (HCL) like Chisel offers high-level abstraction features, making it an ideal language for HCL-Based AHDM. While Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in code generation tasks, they still face challenges with Chisel generation, particularly regarding syntax correctness and design variability. Recent reasoning models have significantly enhanced code generation capabilities through test-time scaling techniques. However, we found that reasoning models without domain adaptation cannot bring substantial benefits to Chisel code generation tasks. This paper presents ChiseLLM, a solution comprising data processing and transformation, prompt-guided reasoning trace synthesis, and domain-adapted model training. We constructed high-quality datasets from public RTL code resources and guided the model to adopt structured thinking patterns through prompt enhancement methods. Experiments demonstrate that our ChiseLLM-7B and ChiseLLM-32B models improved syntax correctness by 18.85% and 26.32% respectively over base models, while increasing variability design ability by 47.58% compared to baseline reasoning models. Our datasets and models are publicly available, providing high-performance, cost-effective models for HCL-Based AHDM, and offering an effective baseline for future research. Github repository: https://github.com/observerw/ChiseLLM</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 12:07:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19144</guid></item><item><title>ICL CIPHERS: Quantifying "Learning'' in In-Context Learning via
  Substitution Ciphers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19395</link><description>Recent works have suggested that In-Context Learning (ICL) operates in dual modes, i.e. task retrieval (remember learned patterns from pre-training) and task learning (inference-time ``learning'' from demonstrations). However, disentangling these the two modes remains a challenging goal. We introduce ICL CIPHERS, a class of task reformulations based on substitution ciphers borrowed from classic cryptography. In this approach, a subset of tokens in the in-context inputs are substituted with other (irrelevant) tokens, rendering English sentences less comprehensible to human eye. However, by design, there is a latent, fixed pattern to this substitution, making it reversible. This bijective (reversible) cipher ensures that the task remains a well-defined task in some abstract sense, despite the transformations. It is a curious question if LLMs can solve ICL CIPHERS with a BIJECTIVE mapping, which requires deciphering the latent cipher. We show that LLMs are better at solving ICL CIPHERS with BIJECTIVE mappings than the NON-BIJECTIVE (irreversible) baseline, providing a novel approach to quantify ``learning'' in ICL. While this gap is small, it is consistent across the board on four datasets and six models. Finally, we examine LLMs' internal representations and identify evidence in their ability to decode the ciphered inputs.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 06:52:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19395</guid></item><item><title>Versatile Framework for Song Generation with Prompt-based Control</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19062</link><description>Song generation focuses on producing controllable high-quality songs based on various prompts. However, existing methods struggle to generate vocals and accompaniments with prompt-based control and proper alignment. Additionally, they fall short in supporting various tasks. To address these challenges, we introduce VersBand, a multi-task song generation framework for synthesizing high-quality, aligned songs with prompt-based control. VersBand comprises these primary models: 1) VocalBand, a decoupled model, leverages the flow-matching method for generating singing styles, pitches, and mel-spectrograms, allowing fast, high-quality vocal generation with style control. 2) AccompBand, a flow-based transformer model, incorporates the Band-MOE, selecting suitable experts for enhanced quality, alignment, and control. This model allows for generating controllable, high-quality accompaniments aligned with vocals. 3) Two generation models, LyricBand for lyrics and MelodyBand for melodies, contribute to the comprehensive multi-task song generation system, allowing for extensive control based on multiple prompts. Experimental results demonstrate that VersBand performs better over baseline models across multiple song generation tasks using objective and subjective metrics. Audio samples are available at https://VersBand.github.io.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:54:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.19062</guid></item></channel></rss>