<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>VeriGUI: Verifiable Long-Chain GUI Dataset</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04026</link><description>VeriGUI is a novel dataset for evaluating GUI agents in long-horizon tasks, emphasizing long-chain complexity and subtask-level verifiability.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent studies have delved into constructing autonomous agents capable of performing complex Graphical User Interface (GUI)-based computer tasks, with the potential to revolutionize human-computer interaction. Despite encouraging results, existing efforts mainly focus on short-term interactions and rely on outcome-only verification, thereby limiting their scalability in real-world GUI applications that demand long-horizon task decomposition and execution. In this work, we introduce VeriGUI, a novel verifiable long-chain GUI dataset designed to facilitate the development and evaluation of generalist GUI agents operating in realistic computer environments. Our dataset emphasizes two critical dimensions: (1) long-chain complexity, with tasks decomposed into a sequence of interdependent subtasks spanning hundreds of steps, explicitly designed to allow any subtask to serve as a valid starting point; and (2) subtask-level verifiability, which enables diverse exploration strategies within each subtask, while ensuring that each subtask-level goal remains verifiable and consistent. The dataset consists of GUI task trajectories across both desktop and web, annotated by human experts. Extensive experiments on VeriGUI using various agents with different foundation models reveal significant performance gaps in handling long-horizon tasks, highlighting the need for more robust planning and decision-making capabilities in GUI agents.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 03:36:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04026</guid></item><item><title>SEAgent: Self-Evolving Computer Use Agent with Autonomous Learning from
  Experience</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04700</link><description>SEAgent, an agentic self-evolving framework, enables computer-use agents to autonomously master novel software through experiential learning and a curriculum of tasks, achieving superior performance compared to existing methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 Repurposing large vision-language models (LVLMs) as computer use agents (CUAs) has led to substantial breakthroughs, primarily driven by human-labeled data. However, these models often struggle with novel and specialized software, particularly in scenarios lacking human annotations. To address this challenge, we propose SEAgent, an agentic self-evolving framework enabling CUAs to autonomously evolve through interactions with unfamiliar software. Specifically, SEAgent empowers computer-use agents to autonomously master novel software environments via experiential learning, where agents explore new software, learn through iterative trial-and-error, and progressively tackle auto-generated tasks organized from simple to complex. To achieve this goal, we design a World State Model for step-wise trajectory assessment, along with a Curriculum Generator that generates increasingly diverse and challenging tasks. The agent's policy is updated through experiential learning, comprised of adversarial imitation of failure actions and Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) on successful ones. Furthermore, we introduce a specialist-to-generalist training strategy that integrates individual experiential insights from specialist agents, facilitating the development of a stronger generalist CUA capable of continuous autonomous evolution. This unified agent ultimately achieves performance surpassing ensembles of individual specialist agents on their specialized software. We validate the effectiveness of SEAgent across five novel software environments within OS-World. Our approach achieves a significant improvement of 23.2% in success rate, from 11.3% to 34.5%, over a competitive open-source CUA, i.e., UI-TARS.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 03:39:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04700</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Agents: Building Effective Agents While Reducing Cost</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.02694</link><description>A study on the efficiency-effectiveness trade-off in LLM-driven agent systems identifies optimal agent framework design to reduce costs while maintaining performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 The remarkable capabilities of Large Language Model (LLM)-driven agents have enabled sophisticated systems to tackle complex, multi-step tasks, but their escalating costs threaten scalability and accessibility. This work presents the first systematic study of the efficiency-effectiveness trade-off in modern agent systems, addressing the critical need for cost-effective designs without sacrificing performance. We investigate three key questions: (1) How much complexity do agentic tasks inherently require? (2) When do additional modules yield diminishing returns? (3) How much efficiency can be gained through the design of efficient agent frameworks? Through an empirical analysis on the GAIA benchmark, we evaluate the impact of LLM backbone selection, agent framework designs, and test-time scaling strategies. Using the cost-of-pass metric, we quantify the efficiency-performance trade-off across these dimensions. Our findings inform the development of Efficient Agents , a novel agent framework that has an optimal complexity to task requirements. Efficient Agents retains 96.7% of the performance of OWL, one leading open-source agent framework, while reducing operational costs from 0.398 to 0.228, resulting in a 28.4% improvement in cost-of-pass. Our work provides actionable insights for designing efficient, high-performing agent systems, advancing the accessibility and sustainability of AI-driven solutions.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 05:09:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.02694</guid></item><item><title>Is Chain-of-Thought Reasoning of LLMs a Mirage? A Data Distribution Lens</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01191</link><description>CoT reasoning in LLMs is found to be limited by the distribution discrepancy between training and test data, suggesting it is not a robust form of reasoning.  					AI-generated summary 				 Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has been shown to improve Large Language Model (LLM) performance on various tasks. With this approach, LLMs appear to produce human-like reasoning steps before providing answers (a.k.a., CoT reasoning), which often leads to the perception that they engage in deliberate inferential processes. However, some initial findings suggest that CoT reasoning may be more superficial than it appears, motivating us to explore further. In this paper, we study CoT reasoning via a data distribution lens and investigate if CoT reasoning reflects a structured inductive bias learned from in-distribution data, allowing the model to conditionally generate reasoning paths that approximate those seen during training. Thus, its effectiveness is fundamentally bounded by the degree of distribution discrepancy between the training data and the test queries. With this lens, we dissect CoT reasoning via three dimensions: task, length, and format. To investigate each dimension, we design DataAlchemy, an isolated and controlled environment to train LLMs from scratch and systematically probe them under various distribution conditions. Our results reveal that CoT reasoning is a brittle mirage that vanishes when it is pushed beyond training distributions. This work offers a deeper understanding of why and when CoT reasoning fails, emphasizing the ongoing challenge of achieving genuine and generalizable reasoning.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 02:59:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01191</guid></item><item><title>Agent Lightning: Train ANY AI Agents with Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03680</link><description>Agent Lightning is a flexible RL framework for training LLMs in various agents, using a hierarchical RL algorithm and decoupling execution from training to handle complex interactions.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present Agent Lightning, a flexible and extensible framework that enables Reinforcement Learning (RL)-based training of Large Language Models (LLMs) for any AI agent. Unlike existing methods that tightly couple RL training with agent or rely on sequence concatenation with masking, Agent Lightning achieves complete decoupling between agent execution and training, allowing seamless integration with existing agents developed via diverse ways (e.g., using frameworks like LangChain, OpenAI Agents SDK, AutoGen, and building from scratch) with almost ZERO code modifications. By formulating agent execution as Markov decision process, we define an unified data interface and propose a hierarchical RL algorithm, LightningRL, which contains a credit assignment module, allowing us to decompose trajectories generated by ANY agents into training transition. This enables RL to handle complex interaction logic, such as multi-agent scenarios and dynamic workflows. For the system design, we introduce a Training-Agent Disaggregation architecture, and brings agent observability frameworks into agent runtime, providing a standardized agent finetuning interface. Experiments across text-to-SQL, retrieval-augmented generation, and math tool-use tasks demonstrate stable, continuous improvements, showcasing the framework's potential for real-world agent training and deployment.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 04:00:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03680</guid></item><item><title>CoTox: Chain-of-Thought-Based Molecular Toxicity Reasoning and
  Prediction</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03159</link><description>CoTox, a framework integrating LLMs with chain-of-thought reasoning, enhances multi-toxicity prediction by incorporating chemical structure data, biological pathways, and gene ontology terms, improving interpretability and predictive performance in drug development.  					AI-generated summary 				 Drug toxicity remains a major challenge in pharmaceutical development. Recent machine learning models have improved in silico toxicity prediction, but their reliance on annotated data and lack of interpretability limit their applicability. This limits their ability to capture organ-specific toxicities driven by complex biological mechanisms. Large language models (LLMs) offer a promising alternative through step-by-step reasoning and integration of textual data, yet prior approaches lack biological context and transparent rationale. To address this issue, we propose CoTox, a novel framework that integrates LLM with chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning for multi-toxicity prediction. CoTox combines chemical structure data, biological pathways, and gene ontology (GO) terms to generate interpretable toxicity predictions through step-by-step reasoning. Using GPT-4o, we show that CoTox outperforms both traditional machine learning and deep learning model. We further examine its performance across various LLMs to identify where CoTox is most effective. Additionally, we find that representing chemical structures with IUPAC names, which are easier for LLMs to understand than SMILES, enhances the model's reasoning ability and improves predictive performance. To demonstrate its practical utility in drug development, we simulate the treatment of relevant cell types with drug and incorporated the resulting biological context into the CoTox framework. This approach allow CoTox to generate toxicity predictions aligned with physiological responses, as shown in case study. This result highlights the potential of LLM-based frameworks to improve interpretability and support early-stage drug safety assessment. The code and prompt used in this work are available at https://github.com/dmis-lab/CoTox.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 04:48:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03159</guid></item><item><title>Sotopia-RL: Reward Design for Social Intelligence</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03905</link><description>Sotopia-RL, a novel reinforcement learning framework, enhances social intelligence in large language models by refining feedback into utterance-level, multi-dimensional rewards, improving performance in social tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Social intelligence has become a critical capability for large language models (LLMs), enabling them to engage effectively in real-world social tasks such as accommodation, persuasion, collaboration, and negotiation. Reinforcement learning (RL) is a natural fit for training socially intelligent agents because it allows models to learn sophisticated strategies directly through social interactions. However, social interactions have two key characteristics that set barriers for RL training: (1) partial observability, where utterances have indirect and delayed effects that complicate credit assignment, and (2) multi-dimensionality, where behaviors such as rapport-building or knowledge-seeking contribute indirectly to goal achievement. These characteristics make Markov decision process (MDP)-based RL with single-dimensional episode-level rewards inefficient and unstable. To address these challenges, we propose Sotopia-RL, a novel framework that refines coarse episode-level feedback into utterance-level, multi-dimensional rewards. Utterance-level credit assignment mitigates partial observability by attributing outcomes to individual utterances, while multi-dimensional rewards capture the full richness of social interactions and reduce reward hacking. Experiments in Sotopia, an open-ended social learning environment, demonstrate that Sotopia-RL achieves state-of-the-art social goal completion scores (7.17 on Sotopia-hard and 8.31 on Sotopia-full), significantly outperforming existing approaches. Ablation studies confirm the necessity of both utterance-level credit assignment and multi-dimensional reward design for RL training. Our implementation is publicly available at: https://github.com/sotopia-lab/sotopia-rl.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 03:00:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03905</guid></item><item><title>LaTCoder: Converting Webpage Design to Code with Layout-as-Thought</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03560</link><description>LaTCoder enhances layout preservation in design-to-code tasks by dividing webpage designs into blocks and using Chain-of-Thought reasoning with MLLMs, achieving significant improvements in metrics and human preference.  					AI-generated summary 				 Converting webpage designs into code (design-to-code) plays a vital role in User Interface (UI) development for front-end developers, bridging the gap between visual design and functional implementation. While recent Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have shown significant potential in design-to-code tasks, they often fail to accurately preserve the layout during code generation. To this end, we draw inspiration from the Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning in human cognition and propose LaTCoder, a novel approach that enhances layout preservation in webpage design during code generation with Layout-as-Thought (LaT). Specifically, we first introduce a simple yet efficient algorithm to divide the webpage design into image blocks. Next, we prompt MLLMs using a CoTbased approach to generate code for each block. Finally, we apply two assembly strategies-absolute positioning and an MLLM-based method-followed by dynamic selection to determine the optimal output. We evaluate the effectiveness of LaTCoder using multiple backbone MLLMs (i.e., DeepSeek-VL2, Gemini, and GPT-4o) on both a public benchmark and a newly introduced, more challenging benchmark (CC-HARD) that features complex layouts. The experimental results on automatic metrics demonstrate significant improvements. Specifically, TreeBLEU scores increased by 66.67% and MAE decreased by 38% when using DeepSeek-VL2, compared to direct prompting. Moreover, the human preference evaluation results indicate that annotators favor the webpages generated by LaTCoder in over 60% of cases, providing strong evidence of the effectiveness of our method.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 04:32:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03560</guid></item><item><title>Web-CogReasoner: Towards Knowledge-Induced Cognitive Reasoning for Web
  Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01858</link><description>A framework for web agents decomposes their capabilities into knowledge content learning and cognitive processes, using a structured dataset and a novel reasoning framework to enhance generalization and performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multimodal large-scale models have significantly advanced the development of web agents, enabling perception and interaction with digital environments akin to human cognition. In this paper, we argue that web agents must first acquire sufficient knowledge to effectively engage in cognitive reasoning. Therefore, we decompose a web agent's capabilities into two essential stages: knowledge content learning and cognitive processes. To formalize this, we propose Web-CogKnowledge Framework, categorizing knowledge as Factual, Conceptual, and Procedural. In this framework, knowledge content learning corresponds to the agent's processes of Memorizing and Understanding, which rely on the first two knowledge types, representing the "what" of learning. Conversely, cognitive processes correspond to Exploring, grounded in Procedural knowledge, defining the "how" of reasoning and action. To facilitate knowledge acquisition, we construct the Web-CogDataset, a structured resource curated from 14 real-world websites, designed to systematically instill core knowledge necessary for web agent. This dataset serves as the agent's conceptual grounding-the "nouns" upon which comprehension is built-as well as the basis for learning how to reason and act. Building on this foundation, we operationalize these processes through a novel knowledge-driven Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning framework, developing and training our proposed agent, the Web-CogReasoner. Extensive experimentation reveals its significant superiority over existing models, especially in generalizing to unseen tasks where structured knowledge is decisive. To enable rigorous evaluation, we introduce the Web-CogBench, a comprehensive evaluation suite designed to assess and compare agent performance across the delineated knowledge domains and cognitive capabilities. Our code and data is open sourced at https://github.com/Gnonymous/Web-CogReasoner</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 03:10:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01858</guid></item><item><title>HPSv3: Towards Wide-Spectrum Human Preference Score</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03789</link><description>HPSv3, a human preference score using a wide-spectrum dataset and uncertainty-aware ranking loss, enhances text-to-image generation quality through iterative refinement.  					AI-generated summary 				 Evaluating text-to-image generation models requires alignment with human perception, yet existing human-centric metrics are constrained by limited data coverage, suboptimal feature extraction, and inefficient loss functions. To address these challenges, we introduce Human Preference Score v3 (HPSv3). (1) We release HPDv3, the first wide-spectrum human preference dataset integrating 1.08M text-image pairs and 1.17M annotated pairwise comparisons from state-of-the-art generative models and low to high-quality real-world images. (2) We introduce a VLM-based preference model trained using an uncertainty-aware ranking loss for fine-grained ranking. Besides, we propose Chain-of-Human-Preference (CoHP), an iterative image refinement method that enhances quality without extra data, using HPSv3 to select the best image at each step. Extensive experiments demonstrate that HPSv3 serves as a robust metric for wide-spectrum image evaluation, and CoHP offers an efficient and human-aligned approach to improve image generation quality. The code and dataset are available at the HPSv3 Homepage.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 02:50:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03789</guid></item><item><title>Gaussian Variation Field Diffusion for High-fidelity Video-to-4D
  Synthesis</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.23785</link><description>A novel framework uses a Direct 4DMesh-to-GS Variation Field VAE and Gaussian Variation Field diffusion model to generate high-quality dynamic 3D content from single video inputs, demonstrating superior quality and generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 In this paper, we present a novel framework for video-to-4D generation that creates high-quality dynamic 3D content from single video inputs. Direct 4D diffusion modeling is extremely challenging due to costly data construction and the high-dimensional nature of jointly representing 3D shape, appearance, and motion. We address these challenges by introducing a Direct 4DMesh-to-GS Variation Field VAE that directly encodes canonical Gaussian Splats (GS) and their temporal variations from 3D animation data without per-instance fitting, and compresses high-dimensional animations into a compact latent space. Building upon this efficient representation, we train a Gaussian Variation Field diffusion model with temporal-aware Diffusion Transformer conditioned on input videos and canonical GS. Trained on carefully-curated animatable 3D objects from the Objaverse dataset, our model demonstrates superior generation quality compared to existing methods. It also exhibits remarkable generalization to in-the-wild video inputs despite being trained exclusively on synthetic data, paving the way for generating high-quality animated 3D content. Project page: https://gvfdiffusion.github.io/.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 02:56:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.23785</guid></item><item><title>LeanK: Learnable K Cache Channel Pruning for Efficient Decoding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.02215</link><description>LeanK, a learning-based method, prunes unimportant key cache channels in large language models to reduce memory usage and accelerate decoding without sacrificing accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) enable long-context tasks but face efficiency challenges due to the growing key-value (KV) cache. We propose LeanK, a learning-based method that prunes unimportant key (K) cache channels by leveraging static channel sparsity. With a novel two-stage training process, LeanK learns channel-wise static mask that could satisfy specific sparsity ratio and hardware alignment requirement. LeanK reduces GPU memory and accelerates decoding without sacrificing accuracy. Experiments demonstrate up to 70% K cache and 16%-18% V cache memory reduction. Custom decoding kernel enables 1.3x speedup for attention computation. We also provide insights into model channels and attention heads during long-context inference by analyzing the learned importance distribution. Our code is available at https://aka.ms/LeanK.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 02:48:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.02215</guid></item><item><title>Sculptor: Empowering LLMs with Cognitive Agency via Active Context
  Management</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04664</link><description>Sculptor, a framework for Active Context Management, enhances LLM performance on long contexts by enabling proactive attention and memory control, reducing proactive interference and improving reasoning reliability.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Models (LLMs) suffer from significant performance degradation when processing long contexts due to proactive interference, where irrelevant information in earlier parts of the context disrupts reasoning and memory recall. While most research focuses on external memory systems to augment LLMs' capabilities, we propose a complementary approach: empowering LLMs with Active Context Management (ACM) tools to actively sculpt their internal working memory. We introduce Sculptor, a framework that equips LLMs with three categories of tools: (1) context fragmentation, (2) summary, hide, and restore, and (3) intelligent search. Our approach enables LLMs to proactively manage their attention and working memory, analogous to how humans selectively focus on relevant information while filtering out distractions. Experimental evaluation on information-sparse benchmarks-PI-LLM (proactive interference) and NeedleBench Multi-Needle Reasoning-demonstrates that Sculptor significantly improves performance even without specific training, leveraging LLMs' inherent tool calling generalization capabilities. By enabling Active Context Management, Sculptor not only mitigates proactive interference but also provides a cognitive foundation for more reliable reasoning across diverse long-context tasks-highlighting that explicit context-control strategies, rather than merely larger token windows, are key to robustness at scale.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 03:07:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04664</guid></item><item><title>Position: The Current AI Conference Model is Unsustainable! Diagnosing
  the Crisis of Centralized AI Conference</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04586</link><description>The paper diagnoses structural issues in AI conferences, including publication rates, carbon footprint, negative community sentiment, and logistical challenges, and proposes a Community-Federated Conference model to address these issues.  					AI-generated summary 				 Artificial Intelligence (AI) conferences are essential for advancing research, sharing knowledge, and fostering academic community. However, their rapid expansion has rendered the centralized conference model increasingly unsustainable. This paper offers a data-driven diagnosis of a structural crisis that threatens the foundational goals of scientific dissemination, equity, and community well-being. We identify four key areas of strain: (1) scientifically, with per-author publication rates more than doubling over the past decade to over 4.5 papers annually; (2) environmentally, with the carbon footprint of a single conference exceeding the daily emissions of its host city; (3) psychologically, with 71% of online community discourse reflecting negative sentiment and 35% referencing mental health concerns; and (4) logistically, with attendance at top conferences such as NeurIPS 2024 beginning to outpace venue capacity. These pressures point to a system that is misaligned with its core mission. In response, we propose the Community-Federated Conference (CFC) model, which separates peer review, presentation, and networking into globally coordinated but locally organized components, offering a more sustainable, inclusive, and resilient path forward for AI research.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 02:44:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04586</guid></item><item><title>EVOC2RUST: A Skeleton-guided Framework for Project-Level C-to-Rust
  Translation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04295</link><description>EvoC2Rust is an automated framework that translates entire C projects to Rust using a skeleton-guided approach, combining rule-based and LLM-based methods to improve syntax, semantics, and safety.  					AI-generated summary 				 Rust's compile-time safety guarantees make it ideal for safety-critical systems, creating demand for translating legacy C codebases to Rust. While various approaches have emerged for this task, they face inherent trade-offs: rule-based solutions face challenges in meeting code safety and idiomaticity requirements, while LLM-based solutions often fail to generate semantically equivalent Rust code, due to the heavy dependencies of modules across the entire codebase. Recent studies have revealed that both solutions are limited to small-scale programs. In this paper, we propose EvoC2Rust, an automated framework for converting entire C projects to equivalent Rust ones. EvoC2Rust employs a skeleton-guided translation strategy for project-level translation. The pipeline consists of three evolutionary stages: 1) it first decomposes the C project into functional modules, employs a feature-mapping-enhanced LLM to transform definitions and macros and generates type-checked function stubs, which form a compilable Rust skeleton; 2) it then incrementally translates the function, replacing the corresponding stub placeholder; 3) finally, it repairs compilation errors by integrating LLM and static analysis. Through evolutionary augmentation, EvoC2Rust combines the advantages of both rule-based and LLM-based solutions. Our evaluation on open-source benchmarks and six industrial projects demonstrates EvoC2Rust's superior performance in project-level C-to-Rust translation. On average, it achieves 17.24% and 14.32% improvements in syntax and semantic accuracy over the LLM-based approaches, along with a 96.79% higher code safety rate than the rule-based tools. At the module level, EvoC2Rust reaches 92.25% compilation and 89.53% test pass rates on industrial projects, even for complex codebases and long functions.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 04:27:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.04295</guid></item><item><title>DreamVVT: Mastering Realistic Video Virtual Try-On in the Wild via a
  Stage-Wise Diffusion Transformer Framework</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.02807</link><description>DreamVVT, a two-stage framework using Diffusion Transformers and LoRA adapters, enhances video virtual try-on by leveraging unpaired human-centric data and pretrained models to preserve garment details and temporal consistency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Video virtual try-on (VVT) technology has garnered considerable academic interest owing to its promising applications in e-commerce advertising and entertainment. However, most existing end-to-end methods rely heavily on scarce paired garment-centric datasets and fail to effectively leverage priors of advanced visual models and test-time inputs, making it challenging to accurately preserve fine-grained garment details and maintain temporal consistency in unconstrained scenarios. To address these challenges, we propose DreamVVT, a carefully designed two-stage framework built upon Diffusion Transformers (DiTs), which is inherently capable of leveraging diverse unpaired human-centric data to enhance adaptability in real-world scenarios. To further leverage prior knowledge from pretrained models and test-time inputs, in the first stage, we sample representative frames from the input video and utilize a multi-frame try-on model integrated with a vision-language model (VLM), to synthesize high-fidelity and semantically consistent keyframe try-on images. These images serve as complementary appearance guidance for subsequent video generation. In the second stage, skeleton maps together with fine-grained motion and appearance descriptions are extracted from the input content, and these along with the keyframe try-on images are then fed into a pretrained video generation model enhanced with LoRA adapters. This ensures long-term temporal coherence for unseen regions and enables highly plausible dynamic motions. Extensive quantitative and qualitative experiments demonstrate that DreamVVT surpasses existing methods in preserving detailed garment content and temporal stability in real-world scenarios. Our project page https://virtu-lab.github.io/</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 06:46:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.02807</guid></item><item><title>A Coarse-to-Fine Approach to Multi-Modality 3D Occupancy Grounding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01197</link><description>A benchmark and model for 3D occupancy grounding using natural language and voxel-level annotations improve object perception in autonomous driving.  					AI-generated summary 				 Visual grounding aims to identify objects or regions in a scene based on natural language descriptions, essential for spatially aware perception in autonomous driving. However, existing visual grounding tasks typically depend on bounding boxes that often fail to capture fine-grained details. Not all voxels within a bounding box are occupied, resulting in inaccurate object representations. To address this, we introduce a benchmark for 3D occupancy grounding in challenging outdoor scenes. Built on the nuScenes dataset, it integrates natural language with voxel-level occupancy annotations, offering more precise object perception compared to the traditional grounding task. Moreover, we propose GroundingOcc, an end-to-end model designed for 3D occupancy grounding through multi-modal learning. It combines visual, textual, and point cloud features to predict object location and occupancy information from coarse to fine. Specifically, GroundingOcc comprises a multimodal encoder for feature extraction, an occupancy head for voxel-wise predictions, and a grounding head to refine localization. Additionally, a 2D grounding module and a depth estimation module enhance geometric understanding, thereby boosting model performance. Extensive experiments on the benchmark demonstrate that our method outperforms existing baselines on 3D occupancy grounding. The dataset is available at https://github.com/RONINGOD/GroundingOcc.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 02:55:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01197</guid></item><item><title>RL-PLUS: Countering Capability Boundary Collapse of LLMs in
  Reinforcement Learning with Hybrid-policy Optimization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.00222</link><description>RL-PLUS, a hybrid-policy optimization approach, enhances LLM reasoning capabilities by integrating Multiple Importance Sampling and Exploration-Based Advantage Function, outperforming RLVR on various benchmarks and resolving capability boundary collapse.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Reward (RLVR) has significantly advanced the complex reasoning abilities of Large Language Models (LLMs). However, it struggles to break through the inherent capability boundaries of the base LLM, due to its essentially on-policy strategy coupled with LLM's immense action space and sparse reward. Critically, RLVR can lead to the capability boundary collapse, narrowing the LLM's problem-solving scope. To address this problem, we propose RL-PLUS, a novel hybrid-policy optimization approach for LLMs that synergizes internal exploitation with external data to achieve stronger reasoning capabilities and surpass the boundaries of base models. RL-PLUS integrates two core components, i.e., Multiple Importance Sampling to address distributional mismatch from external data, and Exploration-Based Advantage Function to guide the model towards high-value, unexplored reasoning paths. We provide both theoretical analysis and extensive experiments to demonstrate the superiority and generalizability of our approach. Compared with existing RLVR methods, RL-PLUS achieves 1) state-of-the-art performance on six math reasoning benchmarks; 2) superior performance on six out-of-distribution reasoning tasks; 3) consistent and significant gains across diverse model families, with average relative improvements up to 69.2\%. Moreover, the analysis of Pass@k curves indicates that RL-PLUS effectively resolves the capability boundary collapse problem.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 06:40:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.00222</guid></item><item><title>OpenMed NER: Open-Source, Domain-Adapted State-of-the-Art Transformers
  for Biomedical NER Across 12 Public Datasets</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01630</link><description>OpenMed NER, a suite of open-source transformer models using DAPT and LoRA, achieves state-of-the-art performance on diverse biomedical NER benchmarks with high efficiency and low computational cost.  					AI-generated summary 				 Named-entity recognition (NER) is fundamental to extracting structured information from the &gt;80% of healthcare data that resides in unstructured clinical notes and biomedical literature. Despite recent advances with large language models, achieving state-of-the-art performance across diverse entity types while maintaining computational efficiency remains a significant challenge. We introduce OpenMed NER, a suite of open-source, domain-adapted transformer models that combine lightweight domain-adaptive pre-training (DAPT) with parameter-efficient Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA). Our approach performs cost-effective DAPT on a 350k-passage corpus compiled from ethically sourced, publicly available research repositories and de-identified clinical notes (PubMed, arXiv, and MIMIC-III) using DeBERTa-v3, PubMedBERT, and BioELECTRA backbones. This is followed by task-specific fine-tuning with LoRA, which updates less than 1.5% of model parameters. We evaluate our models on 12 established biomedical NER benchmarks spanning chemicals, diseases, genes, and species. OpenMed NER achieves new state-of-the-art micro-F1 scores on 10 of these 12 datasets, with substantial gains across diverse entity types. Our models advance the state-of-the-art on foundational disease and chemical benchmarks (e.g., BC5CDR-Disease, +2.70 pp), while delivering even larger improvements of over 5.3 and 9.7 percentage points on more specialized gene and clinical cell line corpora. This work demonstrates that strategically adapted open-source models can surpass closed-source solutions. This performance is achieved with remarkable efficiency: training completes in under 12 hours on a single GPU with a low carbon footprint (&lt; 1.2 kg CO2e), producing permissively licensed, open-source checkpoints designed to help practitioners facilitate compliance with emerging data protection and AI regulations, such as the EU AI Act.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 09:37:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01630</guid></item><item><title>SonicMaster: Towards Controllable All-in-One Music Restoration and
  Mastering</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03448</link><description>SonicMaster, a unified generative model, improves music audio quality by addressing various artifacts using text-based control and a flow-matching generative training paradigm.  					AI-generated summary 				 Music recordings often suffer from audio quality issues such as excessive reverberation, distortion, clipping, tonal imbalances, and a narrowed stereo image, especially when created in non-professional settings without specialized equipment or expertise. These problems are typically corrected using separate specialized tools and manual adjustments. In this paper, we introduce SonicMaster, the first unified generative model for music restoration and mastering that addresses a broad spectrum of audio artifacts with text-based control. SonicMaster is conditioned on natural language instructions to apply targeted enhancements, or can operate in an automatic mode for general restoration. To train this model, we construct the SonicMaster dataset, a large dataset of paired degraded and high-quality tracks by simulating common degradation types with nineteen degradation functions belonging to five enhancements groups: equalization, dynamics, reverb, amplitude, and stereo. Our approach leverages a flow-matching generative training paradigm to learn an audio transformation that maps degraded inputs to their cleaned, mastered versions guided by text prompts. Objective audio quality metrics demonstrate that SonicMaster significantly improves sound quality across all artifact categories. Furthermore, subjective listening tests confirm that listeners prefer SonicMaster's enhanced outputs over the original degraded audio, highlighting the effectiveness of our unified approach.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 05:29:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.03448</guid></item><item><title>IAUNet: Instance-Aware U-Net</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01928</link><description>IAUNet, a query-based U-Net architecture with a lightweight convolutional Pixel decoder and Transformer decoder, outperforms state-of-the-art models in biomedical instance segmentation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Instance segmentation is critical in biomedical imaging to accurately distinguish individual objects like cells, which often overlap and vary in size. Recent query-based methods, where object queries guide segmentation, have shown strong performance. While U-Net has been a go-to architecture in medical image segmentation, its potential in query-based approaches remains largely unexplored. In this work, we present IAUNet, a novel query-based U-Net architecture. The core design features a full U-Net architecture, enhanced by a novel lightweight convolutional Pixel decoder, making the model more efficient and reducing the number of parameters. Additionally, we propose a Transformer decoder that refines object-specific features across multiple scales. Finally, we introduce the 2025 Revvity Full Cell Segmentation Dataset, a unique resource with detailed annotations of overlapping cell cytoplasm in brightfield images, setting a new benchmark for biomedical instance segmentation. Experiments on multiple public datasets and our own show that IAUNet outperforms most state-of-the-art fully convolutional, transformer-based, and query-based models and cell segmentation-specific models, setting a strong baseline for cell instance segmentation tasks. Code is available at https://github.com/SlavkoPrytula/IAUNet</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 08:36:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2508.01928</guid></item><item><title>The Cow of Rembrandt - Analyzing Artistic Prompt Interpretation in
  Text-to-Image Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.23313</link><description>Transformer-based text-to-image diffusion models show varying degrees of content-style separation in generated artworks, as revealed by cross-attention heatmaps.  					AI-generated summary 				 Text-to-image diffusion models have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in generating artistic content by learning from billions of images, including popular artworks. However, the fundamental question of how these models internally represent concepts, such as content and style in paintings, remains unexplored. Traditional computer vision assumes content and style are orthogonal, but diffusion models receive no explicit guidance about this distinction during training. In this work, we investigate how transformer-based text-to-image diffusion models encode content and style concepts when generating artworks. We leverage cross-attention heatmaps to attribute pixels in generated images to specific prompt tokens, enabling us to isolate image regions influenced by content-describing versus style-describing tokens. Our findings reveal that diffusion models demonstrate varying degrees of content-style separation depending on the specific artistic prompt and style requested. In many cases, content tokens primarily influence object-related regions while style tokens affect background and texture areas, suggesting an emergent understanding of the content-style distinction. These insights contribute to our understanding of how large-scale generative models internally represent complex artistic concepts without explicit supervision. We share the code and dataset, together with an exploratory tool for visualizing attention maps at https://github.com/umilISLab/artistic-prompt-interpretation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 04:28:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.23313</guid></item></channel></rss>