<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>On the Entropy Dynamics in Reinforcement Fine-Tuning of Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.03392</link><description>The paper establishes a theoretical framework for analyzing entropy dynamics in reinforcement fine-tuning of large language models, deriving expressions for entropy change and proposing entropy control methods based on discriminant analysis.  					AI-generated summary 				 Entropy serves as a critical metric for measuring the diversity of outputs generated by large language models (LLMs), providing valuable insights into their exploration capabilities. While recent studies increasingly focus on monitoring and adjusting entropy to better balance exploration and exploitation in reinforcement fine-tuning (RFT), a principled understanding of entropy dynamics during this process is yet to be thoroughly investigated. In this paper, we establish a theoretical framework for analyzing the entropy dynamics during the RFT process, which begins with a discriminant expression that quantifies entropy change under a single logit update. This foundation enables the derivation of a first-order expression for entropy change, which can be further extended to the update formula of Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO). The corollaries and insights drawn from the theoretical analysis inspire the design of entropy control methods, and also offer a unified lens for interpreting various entropy-based methods in existing studies. We provide empirical evidence to support the main conclusions of our analysis and demonstrate the effectiveness of the derived entropy-discriminator clipping methods. This study yields novel insights into RFT training dynamics, providing theoretical support and practical strategies for optimizing the exploration-exploitation balance during LLM fine-tuning.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:38:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.03392</guid></item><item><title>Judging What We Cannot Solve: A Consequence-Based Approach for Oracle-Free Evaluation of Research-Level Math</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06291</link><description>Consequence-Based Utility evaluates mathematical solutions by testing their effectiveness as exemplars for related problems, outperforming reward models and LLM judges in ranking quality and correct-wrong separation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent progress in reasoning models suggests that generating plausible attempts for research-level mathematics may be within reach, but verification remains a bottleneck, consuming scarce expert time. We hypothesize that a meaningful solution should contain enough method-level information that, when applied to a neighborhood of related questions, it should yield better downstream performance than incorrect solutions. Building on this idea, we propose Consequence-Based Utility, an oracle-free evaluator that scores each candidate by testing its value as an in-context exemplar in solving related yet verifiable questions. Our approach is evaluated on an original set of research-level math problems, each paired with one expert-written solution and nine LLM-generated solutions. Notably, Consequence-Based Utility consistently outperforms reward models, generative reward models, and LLM judges on ranking quality. Specifically, for GPT-OSS-120B, it improves Acc@1 from 67.2 to 76.3 and AUC from 71.4 to 79.6, with similarly large AUC gains on GPT-OSS-20B (69.0 to 79.2). Furthermore, compared to LLM-Judges, it also exhibits a larger solver-evaluator gap, maintaining a stronger correct-wrong separation even on instances where the underlying solver often fails to solve.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 04:38:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06291</guid></item><item><title>Baichuan-M3: Modeling Clinical Inquiry for Reliable Medical Decision-Making</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06570</link><description>Baichuan-M3 is a medical-enhanced large language model designed for clinical decision support with capabilities in proactive information gathering, long-horizon reasoning, and hallucination suppression.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Baichuan-M3, a medical-enhanced large language model engineered to shift the paradigm from passive question-answering to active, clinical-grade decision support. Addressing the limitations of existing systems in open-ended consultations, Baichuan-M3 utilizes a specialized training pipeline to model the systematic workflow of a physician. Key capabilities include: (i) proactive information acquisition to resolve ambiguity; (ii) long-horizon reasoning that unifies scattered evidence into coherent diagnoses; and (iii) adaptive hallucination suppression to ensure factual reliability. Empirical evaluations demonstrate that Baichuan-M3 achieves state-of-the-art results on HealthBench, the newly introduced HealthBench-Hallu and ScanBench, significantly outperforming GPT-5.2 in clinical inquiry, advisory and safety. The models are publicly available at https://huggingface.co/collections/baichuan-inc/baichuan-m3.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 05:30:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06570</guid></item><item><title>Self-Improving Multilingual Long Reasoning via Translation-Reasoning Integrated Training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05940</link><description>TRIT framework improves multilingual reasoning by jointly training translation and reasoning components, enhancing question understanding and response generation across languages.  					AI-generated summary 				 Long reasoning models often struggle in multilingual settings: they tend to reason in English for non-English questions; when constrained to reasoning in the question language, accuracies drop substantially. The struggle is caused by the limited abilities for both multilingual question understanding and multilingual reasoning. To address both problems, we propose TRIT (Translation-Reasoning Integrated Training), a self-improving framework that integrates the training of translation into multilingual reasoning. Without external feedback or additional multilingual data, our method jointly enhances multilingual question understanding and response generation. On MMATH, our method outperforms multiple baselines by an average of 7 percentage points, improving both answer correctness and language consistency. Further analysis reveals that integrating translation training improves cross-lingual question alignment by over 10 percentage points and enhances translation quality for both mathematical questions and general-domain text, with gains up to 8.4 COMET points on FLORES-200.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:44:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05940</guid></item><item><title>OdysseyArena: Benchmarking Large Language Models For Long-Horizon, Active and Inductive Interactions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05843</link><description>OdysseyArena presents a new framework for evaluating large language models on long-horizon, inductive agent tasks that emphasize autonomous discovery of environmental transition laws.  					AI-generated summary 				 The rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs) has catalyzed the development of autonomous agents capable of navigating complex environments. However, existing evaluations primarily adopt a deductive paradigm, where agents execute tasks based on explicitly provided rules and static goals, often within limited planning horizons. Crucially, this neglects the inductive necessity for agents to discover latent transition laws from experience autonomously, which is the cornerstone for enabling agentic foresight and sustaining strategic coherence. To bridge this gap, we introduce OdysseyArena, which re-centers agent evaluation on long-horizon, active, and inductive interactions. We formalize and instantiate four primitives, translating abstract transition dynamics into concrete interactive environments. Building upon this, we establish OdysseyArena-Lite for standardized benchmarking, providing a set of 120 tasks to measure an agent's inductive efficiency and long-horizon discovery. Pushing further, we introduce OdysseyArena-Challenge to stress-test agent stability across extreme interaction horizons (e.g., &gt; 200 steps). Extensive experiments on 15+ leading LLMs reveal that even frontier models exhibit a deficiency in inductive scenarios, identifying a critical bottleneck in the pursuit of autonomous discovery in complex environments. Our code and data are available at https://github.com/xufangzhi/Odyssey-Arena</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 05:44:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05843</guid></item><item><title>POINTS-GUI-G: GUI-Grounding Journey</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06391</link><description>GUI agents for automated digital tasks rely on vision-language models with enhanced grounding capabilities, achieved through refined data engineering, improved training strategies, and reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards.  					AI-generated summary 				 The rapid advancement of vision-language models has catalyzed the emergence of GUI agents, which hold immense potential for automating complex tasks, from online shopping to flight booking, thereby alleviating the burden of repetitive digital workflows. As a foundational capability, GUI grounding is typically established as a prerequisite for end-to-end task execution. It enables models to precisely locate interface elements, such as text and icons, to perform accurate operations like clicking and typing. Unlike prior works that fine-tune models already possessing strong spatial awareness (e.g., Qwen3-VL), we aim to master the full technical pipeline by starting from a base model with minimal grounding ability, such as POINTS-1.5. We introduce POINTS-GUI-G-8B, which achieves state-of-the-art performance with scores of 59.9 on ScreenSpot-Pro, 66.0 on OSWorld-G, 95.7 on ScreenSpot-v2, and 49.9 on UI-Vision. Our model's success is driven by three key factors: (1) Refined Data Engineering, involving the unification of diverse open-source datasets format alongside sophisticated strategies for augmentation, filtering, and difficulty grading; (2) Improved Training Strategies, including continuous fine-tuning of the vision encoder to enhance perceptual accuracy and maintaining resolution consistency between training and inference; and (3) Reinforcement Learning (RL) with Verifiable Rewards. While RL is traditionally used to bolster reasoning, we demonstrate that it significantly improves precision in the perception-intensive GUI grounding task. Furthermore, GUI grounding provides a natural advantage for RL, as rewards are easily verifiable and highly accurate.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 04:48:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06391</guid></item><item><title>MemGUI-Bench: Benchmarking Memory of Mobile GUI Agents in Dynamic Environments</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06075</link><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:08:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06075</guid></item><item><title>Back to Basics: Revisiting Exploration in Reinforcement Learning for LLM Reasoning via Generative Probabilities</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05281</link><description>A novel reinforcement learning approach called ARM addresses entropy collapse in LLM reasoning by equilibrating confidence levels across correct responses through dynamic reward shaping.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) has emerged as an indispensable paradigm for enhancing reasoning in Large Language Models (LLMs). However, standard policy optimization methods, such as Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO), often converge to low-entropy policies, leading to severe mode collapse and limited output diversity. We analyze this issue from the perspective of sampling probability dynamics, identifying that the standard objective disproportionately reinforces the highest-likelihood paths, thereby suppressing valid alternative reasoning chains. To address this, we propose a novel Advantage Re-weighting Mechanism (ARM) designed to equilibrate the confidence levels across all correct responses. By incorporating Prompt Perplexity and Answer Confidence into the advantage estimation, our method dynamically reshapes the reward signal to attenuate the gradient updates of over-confident reasoning paths, while redistributing probability mass toward under-explored correct solutions. Empirical results demonstrate that our approach significantly enhances generative diversity and response entropy while maintaining competitive accuracy, effectively achieving a superior trade-off between exploration and exploitation in reasoning tasks. Empirical results on Qwen2.5 and DeepSeek models across mathematical and coding benchmarks show that ProGRPO significantly mitigates entropy collapse. Specifically, on Qwen2.5-7B, our method outperforms GRPO by 5.7% in Pass@1 and, notably, by 13.9% in Pass@32, highlighting its superior capability in generating diverse correct reasoning paths.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:55:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05281</guid></item><item><title>MSign: An Optimizer Preventing Training Instability in Large Language Models via Stable Rank Restoration</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.01734</link><description>Training instability in large language models is linked to weight matrix stable rank decline and Jacobian alignment, which MSign addresses through matrix sign operations to prevent gradient explosions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Training instability remains a critical challenge in large language model (LLM) pretraining, often manifesting as sudden gradient explosions that waste significant computational resources. We study training failures in a 5M-parameter NanoGPT model scaled via μP, identifying two key phenomena preceding collapse: (1) rapid decline in weight matrix stable rank (ratio of squared Frobenius norm to squared spectral norm), and (2) increasing alignment between adjacent layer Jacobians. We prove theoretically that these two conditions jointly cause exponential gradient norm growth with network depth. To break this instability mechanism, we propose MSign, a new optimizer that periodically applies matrix sign operations to restore stable rank. Experiments on models from 5M to 3B parameters demonstrate that MSign effectively prevents training failures with a computational overhead of less than 7.0%.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 04:47:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.01734</guid></item><item><title>InftyThink+: Effective and Efficient Infinite-Horizon Reasoning via Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06960</link><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:08:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06960</guid></item><item><title>DreamDojo: A Generalist Robot World Model from Large-Scale Human Videos</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06949</link><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:08:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06949</guid></item><item><title>PlanViz: Evaluating Planning-Oriented Image Generation and Editing for Computer-Use Tasks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06663</link><description>PlanViz benchmark evaluates unified multimodal models' capabilities in computer-use planning tasks through route planning, work diagramming, and web&amp;UI displaying sub-tasks with a task-adaptive scoring system.  					AI-generated summary 				 Unified multimodal models (UMMs) have shown impressive capabilities in generating natural images and supporting multimodal reasoning. However, their potential in supporting computer-use planning tasks, which are closely related to our lives, remain underexplored. Image generation and editing in computer-use tasks require capabilities like spatial reasoning and procedural understanding, and it is still unknown whether UMMs have these capabilities to finish these tasks or not. Therefore, we propose PlanViz, a new benchmark designed to evaluate image generation and editing for computer-use tasks. To achieve the goal of our evaluation, we focus on sub-tasks which frequently involve in daily life and require planning steps. Specifically, three new sub-tasks are designed: route planning, work diagramming, and web&amp;UI displaying. We address challenges in data quality ensuring by curating human-annotated questions and reference images, and a quality control process. For challenges of comprehensive and exact evaluation, a task-adaptive score, PlanScore, is proposed. The score helps understanding the correctness, visual quality and efficiency of generated images. Through experiments, we highlight key limitations and opportunities for future research on this topic.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:54:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06663</guid></item><item><title>RaBiT: Residual-Aware Binarization Training for Accurate and Efficient LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05367</link><description>Residual binarization framework RaBiT addresses feature co-adaptation in quantized LLMs through hierarchical path derivation and robust initialization, achieving superior accuracy-efficiency trade-offs.  					AI-generated summary 				 Efficient deployment of large language models (LLMs) requires extreme quantization, forcing a critical trade-off between low-bit efficiency and performance. Residual binarization enables hardware-friendly, matmul-free inference by stacking binary (pm1) layers, but is plagued by pathological feature co-adaptation. We identify a key failure mode, which we term inter-path adaptation: during quantization-aware training (QAT), parallel residual binary paths learn redundant features, degrading the error-compensation structure and limiting the expressive capacity of the model. While prior work relies on heuristic workarounds (e.g., path freezing) that constrain the solution space, we propose RaBiT, a novel quantization framework that resolves co-adaptation by algorithmically enforcing a residual hierarchy. Its core mechanism sequentially derives each binary path from a single shared full-precision weight, which ensures that every path corrects the error of the preceding one. This process is stabilized by a robust initialization that prioritizes functional preservation over mere weight approximation. RaBiT redefines the 2-bit accuracy-efficiency frontier: it achieves state-of-the-art performance, rivals even hardware-intensive Vector Quantization (VQ) methods, and delivers a 4.49times inference speed-up over full-precision models on an RTX 4090.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 05:24:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05367</guid></item><item><title>SEMA: Simple yet Effective Learning for Multi-Turn Jailbreak Attacks</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06854</link><description>A novel framework called SEMA is introduced that effectively trains multi-turn attackers for large language models without relying on existing strategies or external data, achieving state-of-the-art attack success rates while being compact, reproducible, and transferable across different models and datasets.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multi-turn jailbreaks capture the real threat model for safety-aligned chatbots, where single-turn attacks are merely a special case. Yet existing approaches break under exploration complexity and intent drift. We propose SEMA, a simple yet effective framework that trains a multi-turn attacker without relying on any existing strategies or external data. SEMA comprises two stages. Prefilling self-tuning enables usable rollouts by fine-tuning on non-refusal, well-structured, multi-turn adversarial prompts that are self-generated with a minimal prefix, thereby stabilizing subsequent learning. Reinforcement learning with intent-drift-aware reward trains the attacker to elicit valid multi-turn adversarial prompts while maintaining the same harmful objective. We anchor harmful intent in multi-turn jailbreaks via an intent-drift-aware reward that combines intent alignment, compliance risk, and level of detail. Our open-loop attack regime avoids dependence on victim feedback, unifies single- and multi-turn settings, and reduces exploration complexity. Across multiple datasets, victim models, and jailbreak judges, our method achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) attack success rates (ASR), outperforming all single-turn baselines, manually scripted and template-driven multi-turn baselines, as well as our SFT (Supervised Fine-Tuning) and DPO (Direct Preference Optimization) variants. For instance, SEMA performs an average 80.1% ASR@1 across three closed-source and open-source victim models on AdvBench, 33.9% over SOTA. The approach is compact, reproducible, and transfers across targets, providing a stronger and more realistic stress test for large language model (LLM) safety and enabling automatic redteaming to expose and localize failure modes. Our code is available at: https://github.com/fmmarkmq/SEMA.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 05:08:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06854</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting the Shape Convention of Transformer Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06471</link><description>Replacing conventional feed-forward networks with hourglass-shaped MLPs in Transformers improves model efficiency and performance by enabling better parameter utilization and competitive scaling.  					AI-generated summary 				 Dense Transformer language models have largely adhered to one consistent architectural shape: each layer consists of an attention module followed by a feed-forward network (FFN) with a narrow-wide-narrow MLP, allocating most parameters to the MLP at expansion ratios between 2 and 4. Motivated by recent results that residual wide-narrow-wide (hourglass) MLPs offer superior function approximation capabilities, we revisit the long-standing MLP shape convention in Transformer, challenging the necessity of the narrow-wide-narrow design. To study this, we develop a Transformer variant that replaces the conventional FFN with a deeper hourglass-shaped FFN, comprising a stack of hourglass sub-MLPs connected by residual pathways. We posit that a deeper but lighter hourglass FFN can serve as a competitive alternative to the conventional FFN, and that parameters saved by using a lighter hourglass FFN can be more effectively utilized, such as by enlarging model hidden dimensions under fixed budgets. We confirm these through empirical validations across model scales: hourglass FFNs outperform conventional FFNs up to 400M and achieve comparable performance at larger scales to 1B parameters; hourglass FFN variants with reduced FFN and increased attention parameters show consistent improvements over conventional configurations at matched budgets. Together, these findings shed new light on recent work and prompt a rethinking of the narrow-wide-narrow MLP convention and the balance between attention and FFN towards efficient and expressive modern language models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 02:41:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06471</guid></item><item><title>EgoAVU: Egocentric Audio-Visual Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06139</link><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:08:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06139</guid></item><item><title>OmniMoE: An Efficient MoE by Orchestrating Atomic Experts at Scale</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05711</link><description>OmniMoE presents a system-algorithm co-designed framework that achieves fine-grained expert specialization in Mixture-of-Experts architectures through vector-level atomic experts and optimized routing and scheduling mechanisms.  					AI-generated summary 				 Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) architectures are evolving towards finer granularity to improve parameter efficiency. However, existing MoE designs face an inherent trade-off between the granularity of expert specialization and hardware execution efficiency. We propose OmniMoE, a system-algorithm co-designed framework that pushes expert granularity to its logical extreme. OmniMoE introduces vector-level Atomic Experts, enabling scalable routing and execution within a single MoE layer, while retaining a shared dense MLP branch for general-purpose processing. Although this atomic design maximizes capacity, it poses severe challenges for routing complexity and memory access. To address these, OmniMoE adopts a system-algorithm co-design: (i) a Cartesian Product Router that decomposes the massive index space to reduce routing complexity from O(N) to O(sqrt(N)); and (ii) Expert-Centric Scheduling that inverts the execution order to turn scattered, memory-bound lookups into efficient dense matrix operations. Validated on seven benchmarks, OmniMoE (with 1.7B active parameters) achieves 50.9% zero-shot accuracy across seven benchmarks, outperforming coarse-grained (e.g., DeepSeekMoE) and fine-grained (e.g., PEER) baselines. Crucially, OmniMoE reduces inference latency from 73ms to 6.7ms (a 10.9-fold speedup) compared to PEER, demonstrating that massive-scale fine-grained MoE can be fast and accurate. Our code is open-sourced at https://github.com/flash-algo/omni-moe.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.05711</guid></item><item><title>Avoiding Premature Collapse: Adaptive Annealing for Entropy-Regularized Structural Inference</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.23039</link><description>Researchers identify and address premature mode collapse in optimal transport-based structural prediction models through an adaptive stability control algorithm that prevents gradient explosions during large-scale training.  					AI-generated summary 				 Differentiable matching layers and residual connection paradigms, often implemented via entropy-regularized Optimal Transport (OT), serve as critical mechanisms in structural prediction and architectural scaling. However, recovering discrete permutations or maintaining identity mappings via annealing εto 0 is notoriously unstable. In this work, we identify a fundamental mechanism for this failure: Premature Mode Collapse. By analyzing the non-normal dynamics of the Sinkhorn fixed-point map, we reveal a theoretical thermodynamic speed limit: standard exponential cooling outpaces the contraction rate of the inference operator, which degrades as O(1/ε). To address this, we propose Efficient Piecewise Hybrid Adaptive Stability Control (EPH-ASC), an adaptive scheduling algorithm that monitors the stability of the inference process. We demonstrate that EPH-ASC is essential for stabilizing Manifold-Constrained Hyper-Connections (mHC) during large-scale training on the FineWeb-Edu dataset, effectively preventing late-stage gradient explosions by enforcing a linear stability law.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 05:47:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.23039</guid></item><item><title>SeeUPO: Sequence-Level Agentic-RL with Convergence Guarantees</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06554</link><description>SeeUPO is a critic-free reinforcement learning method that ensures convergence guarantees in multi-turn agent interactions by modeling sequential decision-making as multi-agent bandit problems and using backward induction for policy updates.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as the predominant paradigm for training large language model (LLM)-based AI agents. However, existing backbone RL algorithms lack verified convergence guarantees in agentic scenarios, especially in multi-turn settings, which can lead to training instability and failure to converge to optimal policies.   In this paper, we systematically analyze how different combinations of policy update mechanisms and advantage estimation methods affect convergence properties in single/multi-turn scenarios. We find that REINFORCE with Group Relative Advantage Estimation (GRAE) can converge to the globally optimal under undiscounted conditions, but the combination of PPO &amp; GRAE breaks PPO's original monotonic improvement property. Furthermore, we demonstrate that mainstream backbone RL algorithms cannot simultaneously achieve both critic-free and convergence guarantees in multi-turn scenarios.   To address this, we propose SeeUPO (Sequence-level Sequential Update Policy Optimization), a critic-free approach with convergence guarantees for multi-turn interactions. SeeUPO models multi-turn interaction as sequentially executed multi-agent bandit problems. Through turn-by-turn sequential policy updates in reverse execution order, it ensures monotonic improvement and convergence to global optimal solution via backward induction.   Experiments on AppWorld and BFCL v4 demonstrate SeeUPO's substantial improvements over existing backbone algorithms: relative gains of 43.3%-54.6% on Qwen3-14B and 24.1%-41.9% on Qwen2.5-14B (averaged across benchmarks), along with superior training stability.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 05:22:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.06554</guid></item><item><title>Exploring Knowledge Purification in Multi-Teacher Knowledge Distillation for LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.01064</link><description>Knowledge purification techniques consolidate rationales from multiple teacher LLMs to reduce conflicts and improve efficiency in distillation processes.  					AI-generated summary 				 Knowledge distillation has emerged as a pivotal technique for transferring knowledge from stronger large language models (LLMs) to smaller, more efficient models. However, traditional distillation approaches face challenges related to knowledge conflicts and high resource demands, particularly when leveraging multiple teacher models. In this paper, we introduce the concept of Knowledge Purification, which consolidates the rationales from multiple teacher LLMs into a single rationale, thereby mitigating conflicts and enhancing efficiency. To investigate the effectiveness of knowledge purification, we further propose five purification methods from various perspectives. Our experiments demonstrate that these methods not only improve the performance of the distilled model but also effectively alleviate knowledge conflicts. Moreover, router-based methods exhibit robust generalization capabilities, underscoring the potential of innovative purification techniques in optimizing multi-teacher distillation and facilitating the practical deployment of powerful yet lightweight models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:59:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2602.01064</guid></item></channel></rss>