<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Hello everyone, happy to share with you my experimentation of a Deep Research Assistant, using 7 agents and a quality assurance pipeline :</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mallocode200/873699618032778</link><description>Hello everyone, happy to share with you my experimentation of a Deep Research Assistant, using 7 agents and a quality assurance pipeline : 🤖 What makes this special: ✅ Agent-Based Architecture - 7 specialised AI agents working together: - Planner Agent - Strategic search planning - Search Agent - Multi-source web research - Writer Agent - Comprehensive report generation - Evaluator Agent - Automatic quality assessment - Optimiser Agent - Iterative improvement when needed - Email Agent - Professional report delivery - Clarifier Agent - Interactive query refinement ✅ Quality Assurance Pipeline - Every report is scored (1-10) and automatically improved if it scores below 7/10 ✅ Multiple Research Modes - From quick queries to deep, clarification-driven analysis ✅ Production-Ready - Deployed on Hugging Face Spaces with comprehensive documentation 🔧 Technical Stack: - Frontend: Gradio with theme-adaptive UI - Backend: OpenAI Agents framework - Integration: SendGrid for email delivery -...</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mallocode200/873699618032778</guid></item><item><title>10 Techniques for Boosting LLM Reasoning in 2025</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/930317125764918</link><description>10 Techniques for Boosting LLM Reasoning in 2025 Everyone’s chasing top reasoning, but sometimes it's still the bottleneck for many real-world tasks. This week, let's spotlight some powerful techniques that have shown promise in helping LLMs achieve more consistent logic, planning, and depth: 1. Retrieval-Augmented CoT Chaining (RAG+CoT) -&gt; CoT-RAG: Integrating Chain of Thought and Retrieval-Augmented Generation to Enhance Reasoning in Large Language Models (2504.13534) Combines Chain-of-Thought prompting with retrieval augmentation at intermediate steps. Relevant documents are fetched after each reasoning subgoal, updating context dynamically. Great for open-domain QA, math, logic and multi-hop fact-checking 2. Tool-use by example injection -&gt; Self-Training Large Language Models for Tool-Use Without Demonstrations (2502.05867) Injects few-shot tool interaction examples during training to implicitly teach calling patterns. Helps in plug-and-play tool use without training new...</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/930317125764918</guid></item><item><title>fav open-source multimodal reasoning model just got an update 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/432717492221522</link><description>fav open-source multimodal reasoning model just got an update 🔥 moonshotai/Kimi-VL-A3B-Thinking-2506 has &gt; smarter with less tokens, small size (only 3B active params!!!) &gt; better accuracy &gt; video reasoning &gt; higher resolution 🤯 Read their blog https://huggingface.co/blog/moonshotai/kimi-vl-a3b-thinking-2506 See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/432717492221522</guid></item><item><title>💫 Next-Level On-Device AI Showdown</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/yeonseok-zeticai/882369268235109</link><description>💫 Next-Level On-Device AI Showdown 🪽 See It to Believe It, How QWEN4b works at On-device environment without expensive GPU Cloud server? We’ve crafted a side-by-side demo video showcasing both Jan-Nano and QWEN 4B in action—no more wondering which model reigns supreme. Click play, compare their speeds, accuracy, and memory footprints, and decide which one fits your needs best! 👋 Why You Can’t Miss This We are actively creating runnable sLLM environments for On-device AI. You can just build On-device AI apps within few hours. Including Jan-Nano, QWEN4b, there are several sLLM models ready to be used on your AI application!. 🤑 Please feel free to use, because it is free to use!. Ready to Compare? Watch now, draw your own conclusions, and let us know which model you’d deploy in your next edge-AI project! 🌍💡 #OnDeviceAI #EdgeAI #AIShowdown #MLOptimization #DemoVideo #AIComparison See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/yeonseok-zeticai/882369268235109</guid></item><item><title>Trinity-Synthesis: A Multi-Agent Architecture for AI Agents That Think Before They Speak</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/brainhome/128948549150065</link><description>Trinity-Synthesis: A Multi-Agent Architecture for AI Agents That Think Before They Speak Ever felt your AI agent is "shooting from the hip"? It latches onto a single line of thought and fails to produce a robust, well-rounded plan. This is a common struggle I've called the "AI Reasoning Paradox." To tackle this, I developed Trinity-Synthesis, a multi-agent architecture designed to force reflection and synthesis before delivering a final answer. The philosophy is simple: constructive conflict between different perspectives leads to better solutions. Here’s the core idea: Instead of one agent, it uses four agents running on the same base model but with different "personalities" defined by their system prompts and temperature settings: 🧠 The Visionary: Thinks outside the box (high temp: 1.0). 📊 The Analyst: Focuses on logic, data, and structure (low temp: 0.3). 🛠️ The Pragmatist: Evaluates feasibility, costs, and risks (mid temp: 0.5). These three "thinkers" work in parallel on the...</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/brainhome/128948549150065</guid></item><item><title>y'all have been asking my opinion on how OCR models compare to each other 👀</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/300457326273979</link><description>y'all have been asking my opinion on how OCR models compare to each other 👀 I will leave three apps to compare newest models by @ prithivMLmods instead ⤵️ &gt; compare Nanonets-OCR-s, Qwen2-VL-OCR-2B-Instruct, RolmOCR, Aya-Vision prithivMLmods/Multimodal-OCR &gt; SmolDocling, Nanonets-OCR-s, MonkeyOCR, Typhoon-OCR-7B prithivMLmods/Multimodal-OCR2 &gt; docscopeOCR, MonkeyOCR, coreOCR prithivMLmods/core-OCR See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/300457326273979</guid></item><item><title>Adaptive Classifier: Dynamic Text Classification with Strategic Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/825512802076392</link><description>Adaptive Classifier: Dynamic Text Classification with Strategic Learning New text classification system that learns continuously without catastrophic forgetting. Achieved 22.2% robustness improvement on adversarial datasets while maintaining clean data performance. 🎯 THE PROBLEM Traditional classifiers require complete retraining when adding new classes. Expensive and time-consuming, especially with adversarial users trying to game the system. 🚀 KEY INNOVATIONS • Hybrid memory-neural architecture (prototype-based + neural adaptation) • Strategic classification using game theory to predict and defend against manipulation • Elastic Weight Consolidation prevents catastrophic forgetting 📊 RESULTS Tested on AI-Secure/adv_glue dataset: • Clean data: 80.0% → 82.2% (+2.2%) • Manipulated data: 60.0% → 82.2% (+22.2%) • Zero performance drop under adversarial attacks 🔬 APPLICATIONS • Hallucination detection: 80.7% recall for RAG safety • LLM routing: 26.6% cost optimization improvement •...</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/825512802076392</guid></item><item><title>Hi everyone, I have updated the space from its original version.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mallocode200/392195427390890</link><description>Hi everyone, I have updated the space from its original version. mallocode200/Deep_Research_Assistant The main changes are: - The possibility for users to insert their own OpenAI API Key - The possibility for users to select the model they want from OpenAI - An improved UI to see the process going on when the research is running - A better Gradio interface for both light and dark themes Why use only OpenAI models? For this research assistant, I've chosen to focus exclusively on OpenAI models for several key reasons: - Reliability &amp; Consistency: OpenAI's models provide consistent, high-quality responses that are crucial for research tasks requiring accuracy and depth. - Advanced Reasoning: Models like GPT-4o and o1-preview excel at complex analytical thinking, making them ideal for comprehensive research synthesis and evaluation. - Proven Performance: The research pipeline has been extensively tested and optimised specifically for OpenAI's model behaviours and capabilities. - API...</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mallocode200/392195427390890</guid></item><item><title>🚀 VEO3 Real-Time: Real-time AI Video Generation with Self-Forcing</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/seawolf2357/835684207699630</link><description>🚀 VEO3 Real-Time: Real-time AI Video Generation with Self-Forcing 🎯 Core Innovation: Self-Forcing Technology VEO3 Real-Time, an open-source project challenging Google's VEO3, achieves real-time video generation through revolutionary Self-Forcing technology. Heartsync/VEO3-RealTime ⚡ What is Self-Forcing? While traditional methods require 50-100 steps, Self-Forcing achieves the same quality in just 1-2 steps. Through self-correction and rapid convergence, this Distribution Matching Distillation (DMD) technique maintains quality while delivering 50x speed improvement. 💡 Technical Advantages of Self-Forcing 1. Extreme Speed Generates 4-second videos in under 30 seconds, with first frame streaming in just 3 seconds. This represents 50x faster performance than traditional diffusion methods. 2. Consistent Quality Maintains cinematic quality despite fewer steps, ensures temporal consistency, and minimizes artifacts. 3. Efficient Resource Usage Reduces GPU memory usage by 70% and heat...</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/seawolf2357/835684207699630</guid></item><item><title># Machine Learning and societal impact: The Next Frontier</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ghostai1/318401982758206</link><description># Machine Learning and societal impact: The Next Frontier The advent of artificial intelligence and machine learning has been nothing short of transformative for society. These revolutionary technologies have taken society by storm, making a lasting impact on virtually every aspect of our lives. From the way we communicate to how we work, play, and learn, AI-driven machine learning has made its presence felt in countless ways. One of the most significant impacts of AI-driven machine learning has been in the realm of healthcare. With the help of AI, doctors and researchers can now process vast amounts of medical data at lightning speed. This enables them to come up with personalized treatment plans, leading to better outcomes for patients. AI-driven machine learning is also being used to develop more effective drugs, making treatments more accessible and affordable. In terms of applications, AI-driven machine learning has taken the world by storm. From virtual assistants like Siri...</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:38:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ghostai1/318401982758206</guid></item></channel></rss>