<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Apriel-1.5-15b-Thinker</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01141</link><description>A 15-billion parameter multimodal reasoning model achieves competitive performance through a progressive training methodology without reinforcement learning, demonstrating efficient use of computational resources.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present Apriel-1.5-15B-Thinker, a 15-billion parameter open-weights multimodal reasoning model that achieves frontier-level performance through training design rather than sheer scale. Starting from Pixtral-12B, we apply a progressive three-stage methodology: (1) depth upscaling to expand reasoning capacity without pretraining from scratch, (2) staged continual pre-training that first develops foundational text and vision understanding, then enhances visual reasoning through targeted synthetic data generation addressing spatial structure, compositional understanding, and fine-grained perception, and (3) high-quality text-only supervised fine-tuning on curated instruction-response pairs with explicit reasoning traces spanning mathematics, coding, science, and tool use. Notably, our model achieves competitive results without reinforcement learning or preference optimization, isolating the contribution of our data-centric continual pre-training approach. On the Artificial Analysis Intelligence Index, Apriel-1.5-15B-Thinker attains a score of 52, matching DeepSeek-R1-0528 despite requiring significantly fewer computational resources. Across ten image benchmarks, its performance is on average within five points of Gemini-2.5-Flash and Claude Sonnet-3.7, a key achievement for a model operating within single-GPU deployment constraints. Our results demonstrate that thoughtful mid-training 2 design can close substantial capability gaps without massive scale, making frontier-level multimodal reasoning accessible to organizations with limited infrastructure. We release the model checkpoint, all training recipes, and evaluation protocols under the MIT license to to advance open-source research.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:50:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01141</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Multi-modal Large Language Models via Progressive Consistency
  Distillation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.00515</link><description>EPIC, a progressive learning framework, improves the efficiency of multi-modal large models by reducing training difficulty through token and layer consistency distillation during visual token compression.  					AI-generated summary 				 Visual tokens consume substantial computational resources in multi-modal large models (MLLMs), significantly compromising their efficiency. Recent works have attempted to improve efficiency by compressing visual tokens during training, either through modifications to model components or by introducing additional parameters. However, they often overlook the increased learning difficulty caused by such compression, as the model's parameter space struggles to quickly adapt to the substantial perturbations in the feature space induced by token compression. In this work, we propose to develop Efficient MLLMs via Progressive Consistency Distillation (EPIC), a progressive learning framework. Specifically, by decomposing the feature space perturbations introduced by token compression along the token-wise and layer-wise dimensions, we introduce token consistency distillation and layer consistency distillation, respectively, aiming to reduce the training difficulty by leveraging guidance from a teacher model and following a progressive learning trajectory. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superior effectiveness, robustness, and generalization capabilities of our proposed framework.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:14:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.00515</guid></item><item><title>Compose Your Policies! Improving Diffusion-based or Flow-based Robot
  Policies via Test-time Distribution-level Composition</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01068</link><description>General Policy Composition (GPC) enhances robotic control performance by combining pre-trained diffusion-based policies without additional training, leading to superior results across various benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Diffusion-based models for robotic control, including vision-language-action (VLA) and vision-action (VA) policies, have demonstrated significant capabilities. Yet their advancement is constrained by the high cost of acquiring large-scale interaction datasets. This work introduces an alternative paradigm for enhancing policy performance without additional model training. Perhaps surprisingly, we demonstrate that the composed policies can exceed the performance of either parent policy. Our contribution is threefold. First, we establish a theoretical foundation showing that the convex composition of distributional scores from multiple diffusion models can yield a superior one-step functional objective compared to any individual score. A Gr\"onwall-type bound is then used to show that this single-step improvement propagates through entire generation trajectories, leading to systemic performance gains. Second, motivated by these results, we propose General Policy Composition (GPC), a training-free method that enhances performance by combining the distributional scores of multiple pre-trained policies via a convex combination and test-time search. GPC is versatile, allowing for the plug-and-play composition of heterogeneous policies, including VA and VLA models, as well as those based on diffusion or flow-matching, irrespective of their input visual modalities. Third, we provide extensive empirical validation. Experiments on Robomimic, PushT, and RoboTwin benchmarks, alongside real-world robotic evaluations, confirm that GPC consistently improves performance and adaptability across a diverse set of tasks. Further analysis of alternative composition operators and weighting strategies offers insights into the mechanisms underlying the success of GPC. These results establish GPC as a simple yet effective method for improving control performance by leveraging existing policies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:05:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01068</guid></item><item><title>Self-Improvement in Multimodal Large Language Models: A Survey</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.02665</link><description>A survey of self-improvement methods in Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) from data collection, organization, and model optimization perspectives.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advancements in self-improvement for Large Language Models (LLMs) have efficiently enhanced model capabilities without significantly increasing costs, particularly in terms of human effort. While this area is still relatively young, its extension to the multimodal domain holds immense potential for leveraging diverse data sources and developing more general self-improving models. This survey is the first to provide a comprehensive overview of self-improvement in Multimodal LLMs (MLLMs). We provide a structured overview of the current literature and discuss methods from three perspectives: 1) data collection, 2) data organization, and 3) model optimization, to facilitate the further development of self-improvement in MLLMs. We also include commonly used evaluations and downstream applications. Finally, we conclude by outlining open challenges and future research directions.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:40:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.02665</guid></item><item><title>Your Agent May Misevolve: Emergent Risks in Self-evolving LLM Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.26354</link><description>Self-evolving agents based on Large Language Models can deviate in unintended ways, leading to various risks such as safety misalignment and vulnerability introduction, necessitating new safety paradigms.  					AI-generated summary 				 Advances in Large Language Models (LLMs) have enabled a new class of self-evolving agents that autonomously improve through interaction with the environment, demonstrating strong capabilities. However, self-evolution also introduces novel risks overlooked by current safety research. In this work, we study the case where an agent's self-evolution deviates in unintended ways, leading to undesirable or even harmful outcomes. We refer to this as Misevolution. To provide a systematic investigation, we evaluate misevolution along four key evolutionary pathways: model, memory, tool, and workflow. Our empirical findings reveal that misevolution is a widespread risk, affecting agents built even on top-tier LLMs (e.g., Gemini-2.5-Pro). Different emergent risks are observed in the self-evolutionary process, such as the degradation of safety alignment after memory accumulation, or the unintended introduction of vulnerabilities in tool creation and reuse. To our knowledge, this is the first study to systematically conceptualize misevolution and provide empirical evidence of its occurrence, highlighting an urgent need for new safety paradigms for self-evolving agents. Finally, we discuss potential mitigation strategies to inspire further research on building safer and more trustworthy self-evolving agents. Our code and data are available at https://github.com/ShaoShuai0605/Misevolution . Warning: this paper includes examples that may be offensive or harmful in nature.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:14:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.26354</guid></item><item><title>SurveyBench: How Well Can LLM(-Agents) Write Academic Surveys?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03120</link><description>A new evaluation framework, SurveyBench, assesses the quality of automatically generated academic surveys using a quiz-driven approach, revealing deficiencies in current LLM4Survey methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 Academic survey writing, which distills vast literature into a coherent and insightful narrative, remains a labor-intensive and intellectually demanding task. While recent approaches, such as general DeepResearch agents and survey-specialized methods, can generate surveys automatically (a.k.a. LLM4Survey), their outputs often fall short of human standards and there lacks a rigorous, reader-aligned benchmark for thoroughly revealing their deficiencies. To fill the gap, we propose a fine-grained, quiz-driven evaluation framework SurveyBench, featuring (1) typical survey topics source from recent 11,343 arXiv papers and corresponding 4,947 high-quality surveys; (2) a multifaceted metric hierarchy that assesses the outline quality (e.g., coverage breadth, logical coherence), content quality (e.g., synthesis granularity, clarity of insights), and non-textual richness; and (3) a dual-mode evaluation protocol that includes content-based and quiz-based answerability tests, explicitly aligned with readers' informational needs. Results show SurveyBench effectively challenges existing LLM4Survey approaches (e.g., on average 21% lower than human in content-based evaluation).</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:00:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03120</guid></item><item><title>CoDA: Agentic Systems for Collaborative Data Visualization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03194</link><description>CoDA, a multi-agent system using specialized LLM agents, enhances visualization automation by managing data complexity and ensuring high-quality visualizations through collaborative workflows.  					AI-generated summary 				 Deep research has revolutionized data analysis, yet data scientists still devote substantial time to manually crafting visualizations, highlighting the need for robust automation from natural language queries. However, current systems struggle with complex datasets containing multiple files and iterative refinement. Existing approaches, including simple single- or multi-agent systems, often oversimplify the task, focusing on initial query parsing while failing to robustly manage data complexity, code errors, or final visualization quality. In this paper, we reframe this challenge as a collaborative multi-agent problem. We introduce CoDA, a multi-agent system that employs specialized LLM agents for metadata analysis, task planning, code generation, and self-reflection. We formalize this pipeline, demonstrating how metadata-focused analysis bypasses token limits and quality-driven refinement ensures robustness. Extensive evaluations show CoDA achieves substantial gains in the overall score, outperforming competitive baselines by up to 41.5%. This work demonstrates that the future of visualization automation lies not in isolated code generation but in integrated, collaborative agentic workflows.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:06:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03194</guid></item><item><title>REPAIR: Robust Editing via Progressive Adaptive Intervention and
  Reintegration</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01879</link><description>REPAIR is a lifelong editing framework for large language models that enhances editing accuracy and reduces knowledge forgetting through progressive adaptive intervention and reintegration.  					AI-generated summary 				 Post-training for large language models (LLMs) is constrained by the high cost of acquiring new knowledge or correcting errors and by the unintended side effects that frequently arise from retraining. To address these issues, we introduce REPAIR (Robust Editing via Progressive Adaptive Intervention and Reintegration), a lifelong editing framework designed to support precise and low-cost model updates while preserving non-target knowledge. REPAIR mitigates the instability and conflicts of large-scale sequential edits through a closed-loop feedback mechanism coupled with dynamic memory management. Furthermore, by incorporating frequent knowledge fusion and enforcing strong locality guards, REPAIR effectively addresses the shortcomings of traditional distribution-agnostic approaches that often overlook unintended ripple effects. Our experiments demonstrate that REPAIR boosts editing accuracy by 10%-30% across multiple model families and significantly reduces knowledge forgetting. This work introduces a robust framework for developing reliable, scalable, and continually evolving LLMs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:20:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01879</guid></item><item><title>FocusAgent: Simple Yet Effective Ways of Trimming the Large Context of
  Web Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03204</link><description>FocusAgent uses a lightweight LLM retriever to extract relevant content from web page observations, improving efficiency and security in web agents.  					AI-generated summary 				 Web agents powered by large language models (LLMs) must process lengthy web page observations to complete user goals; these pages often exceed tens of thousands of tokens. This saturates context limits and increases computational cost processing; moreover, processing full pages exposes agents to security risks such as prompt injection. Existing pruning strategies either discard relevant content or retain irrelevant context, leading to suboptimal action prediction. We introduce FocusAgent, a simple yet effective approach that leverages a lightweight LLM retriever to extract the most relevant lines from accessibility tree (AxTree) observations, guided by task goals. By pruning noisy and irrelevant content, FocusAgent enables efficient reasoning while reducing vulnerability to injection attacks. Experiments on WorkArena and WebArena benchmarks show that FocusAgent matches the performance of strong baselines, while reducing observation size by over 50%. Furthermore, a variant of FocusAgent significantly reduces the success rate of prompt-injection attacks, including banner and pop-up attacks, while maintaining task success performance in attack-free settings. Our results highlight that targeted LLM-based retrieval is a practical and robust strategy for building web agents that are efficient, effective, and secure.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:04:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03204</guid></item><item><title>Improving GUI Grounding with Explicit Position-to-Coordinate Mapping</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03230</link><description>Explicit coordinate markers and improved spatial encoding enhance GUI grounding accuracy across diverse resolutions and platforms.  					AI-generated summary 				 GUI grounding, the task of mapping natural-language instructions to pixel coordinates, is crucial for autonomous agents, yet remains difficult for current VLMs. The core bottleneck is reliable patch-to-pixel mapping, which breaks when extrapolating to high-resolution displays unseen during training. Current approaches generate coordinates as text tokens directly from visual features, forcing the model to infer complex position-to-pixel mappings implicitly; as a result, accuracy degrades and failures proliferate on new resolutions. We address this with two complementary innovations. First, RULER tokens serve as explicit coordinate markers, letting the model reference positions similar to gridlines on a map and adjust rather than generate coordinates from scratch. Second, Interleaved MRoPE (I-MRoPE) improves spatial encoding by ensuring that width and height dimensions are represented equally, addressing the asymmetry of standard positional schemes. Experiments on ScreenSpot, ScreenSpot-V2, and ScreenSpot-Pro show consistent gains in grounding accuracy, with the largest improvements on high-resolution interfaces. By providing explicit spatial guidance rather than relying on implicit learning, our approach enables more reliable GUI automation across diverse resolutions and platforms.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:42:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03230</guid></item><item><title>LSPO: Length-aware Dynamic Sampling for Policy Optimization in LLM
  Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01459</link><description>Length-aware Sampling for Policy Optimization (LSPO) is a meta-RLVR algorithm that dynamically selects training data based on response length, improving learning effectiveness in large language models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Since the release of Deepseek-R1, reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards (RLVR) has become a central approach for training large language models (LLMs) on reasoning tasks. Recent work has largely focused on modifying loss functions to make RLVR more efficient and effective. In this paper, motivated by studies of overthinking in LLMs, we propose Length-aware Sampling for Policy Optimization (LSPO), a novel meta-RLVR algorithm that dynamically selects training data at each step based on the average response length. We evaluate LSPO across multiple base models and datasets, demonstrating that it consistently improves learning effectiveness. In addition, we conduct a detailed ablation study to examine alternative ways of incorporating length signals into dynamic sampling, offering further insights and highlighting promising directions for future research.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:36:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01459</guid></item><item><title>Free Lunch Alignment of Text-to-Image Diffusion Models without
  Preference Image Pairs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.25771</link><description>A new framework, Text Preference Optimization (TPO), aligns text-to-image models with human preferences without requiring paired image preference data, improving text-to-image alignment and human preference scores.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in diffusion-based text-to-image (T2I) models have led to remarkable success in generating high-quality images from textual prompts. However, ensuring accurate alignment between the text and the generated image remains a significant challenge for state-of-the-art diffusion models. To address this, existing studies employ reinforcement learning with human feedback (RLHF) to align T2I outputs with human preferences. These methods, however, either rely directly on paired image preference data or require a learned reward function, both of which depend heavily on costly, high-quality human annotations and thus face scalability limitations. In this work, we introduce Text Preference Optimization (TPO), a framework that enables "free-lunch" alignment of T2I models, achieving alignment without the need for paired image preference data. TPO works by training the model to prefer matched prompts over mismatched prompts, which are constructed by perturbing original captions using a large language model. Our framework is general and compatible with existing preference-based algorithms. We extend both DPO and KTO to our setting, resulting in TDPO and TKTO. Quantitative and qualitative evaluations across multiple benchmarks show that our methods consistently outperform their original counterparts, delivering better human preference scores and improved text-to-image alignment. Our Open-source code is available at https://github.com/DSL-Lab/T2I-Free-Lunch-Alignment.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 03:29:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.25771</guid></item><item><title>LEAML: Label-Efficient Adaptation to Out-of-Distribution Visual Tasks
  for Multimodal Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03232</link><description>LEAML, a label-efficient adaptation framework, enhances MLLMs for specialized domains by generating pseudo question-answer pairs and selectively updating relevant neurons, outperforming standard fine-tuning with minimal supervision.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have achieved strong performance on general visual benchmarks but struggle with out-of-distribution (OOD) tasks in specialized domains such as medical imaging, where labeled data is limited and expensive. We introduce LEAML, a label-efficient adaptation framework that leverages both scarce labeled VQA samples and abundant unlabeled images. Our approach generates domain-relevant pseudo question-answer pairs for unlabeled data using a QA generator regularized by caption distillation. Importantly, we selectively update only those neurons most relevant to question-answering, enabling the QA Generator to efficiently acquire domain-specific knowledge during distillation. Experiments on gastrointestinal endoscopy and sports VQA demonstrate that LEAML consistently outperforms standard fine-tuning under minimal supervision, highlighting the effectiveness of our proposed LEAML framework.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:08:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03232</guid></item><item><title>SpineBench: A Clinically Salient, Level-Aware Benchmark Powered by the
  SpineMed-450k Corpus</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03160</link><description>SpineMed, an ecosystem with SpineMed-450k and SpineBench, addresses the lack of level-aware, multimodal datasets and benchmarks for AI-assisted diagnosis of spine disorders, improving model performance through fine-grained, level-specific reasoning.  					AI-generated summary 				 Spine disorders affect 619 million people globally and are a leading cause of disability, yet AI-assisted diagnosis remains limited by the lack of level-aware, multimodal datasets. Clinical decision-making for spine disorders requires sophisticated reasoning across X-ray, CT, and MRI at specific vertebral levels. However, progress has been constrained by the absence of traceable, clinically-grounded instruction data and standardized, spine-specific benchmarks. To address this, we introduce SpineMed, an ecosystem co-designed with practicing spine surgeons. It features SpineMed-450k, the first large-scale dataset explicitly designed for vertebral-level reasoning across imaging modalities with over 450,000 instruction instances, and SpineBench, a clinically-grounded evaluation framework. SpineMed-450k is curated from diverse sources, including textbooks, guidelines, open datasets, and ~1,000 de-identified hospital cases, using a clinician-in-the-loop pipeline with a two-stage LLM generation method (draft and revision) to ensure high-quality, traceable data for question-answering, multi-turn consultations, and report generation. SpineBench evaluates models on clinically salient axes, including level identification, pathology assessment, and surgical planning. Our comprehensive evaluation of several recently advanced large vision-language models (LVLMs) on SpineBench reveals systematic weaknesses in fine-grained, level-specific reasoning. In contrast, our model fine-tuned on SpineMed-450k demonstrates consistent and significant improvements across all tasks. Clinician assessments confirm the diagnostic clarity and practical utility of our model's outputs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:28:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.03160</guid></item><item><title>How Confident are Video Models? Empowering Video Models to Express their
  Uncertainty</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.02571</link><description>A framework for uncertainty quantification in generative video models is introduced, including a metric for calibration, a black-box method called S-QUBED, and a benchmark dataset, demonstrating improved uncertainty estimates and task accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Generative video models demonstrate impressive text-to-video capabilities, spurring widespread adoption in many real-world applications. However, like large language models (LLMs), video generation models tend to hallucinate, producing plausible videos even when they are factually wrong. Although uncertainty quantification (UQ) of LLMs has been extensively studied in prior work, no UQ method for video models exists, raising critical safety concerns. To our knowledge, this paper represents the first work towards quantifying the uncertainty of video models. We present a framework for uncertainty quantification of generative video models, consisting of: (i) a metric for evaluating the calibration of video models based on robust rank correlation estimation with no stringent modeling assumptions; (ii) a black-box UQ method for video models (termed S-QUBED), which leverages latent modeling to rigorously decompose predictive uncertainty into its aleatoric and epistemic components; and (iii) a UQ dataset to facilitate benchmarking calibration in video models. By conditioning the generation task in the latent space, we disentangle uncertainty arising due to vague task specifications from that arising from lack of knowledge. Through extensive experiments on benchmark video datasets, we demonstrate that S-QUBED computes calibrated total uncertainty estimates that are negatively correlated with the task accuracy and effectively computes the aleatoric and epistemic constituents.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:46:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.02571</guid></item><item><title>WAInjectBench: Benchmarking Prompt Injection Detections for Web Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01354</link><description>A comprehensive benchmark study evaluates the detection of prompt injection attacks against web agents, revealing that current detectors perform well against explicit attacks but struggle with subtle ones.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multiple prompt injection attacks have been proposed against web agents. At the same time, various methods have been developed to detect general prompt injection attacks, but none have been systematically evaluated for web agents. In this work, we bridge this gap by presenting the first comprehensive benchmark study on detecting prompt injection attacks targeting web agents. We begin by introducing a fine-grained categorization of such attacks based on the threat model. We then construct datasets containing both malicious and benign samples: malicious text segments generated by different attacks, benign text segments from four categories, malicious images produced by attacks, and benign images from two categories. Next, we systematize both text-based and image-based detection methods. Finally, we evaluate their performance across multiple scenarios. Our key findings show that while some detectors can identify attacks that rely on explicit textual instructions or visible image perturbations with moderate to high accuracy, they largely fail against attacks that omit explicit instructions or employ imperceptible perturbations. Our datasets and code are released at: https://github.com/Norrrrrrr-lyn/WAInjectBench.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:09:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01354</guid></item><item><title>A Practitioner's Guide to Multi-turn Agentic Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01132</link><description>Research identifies key design choices for training large language models as agents via multi-turn reinforcement learning, focusing on environment complexity, reward sparsity, and policy methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 We study what actually works and what doesn't for training large language models as agents via multi-turn reinforcement learning. Despite rapid progress, existing frameworks and definitions are fragmented, and there is no systematic formulation or analysis of which design choices matter across tasks. We address this gap by first breaking down the design space into three inter-related pillars -- environment, reward, and policy -- and empirically derive a recipe for training LLM agents in situated textual domains. In particular, we test TextWorld and ALFWorld, popular domains for testing situated embodied reasoning, as well as SWE-Gym for more software engineering style tasks. (i) For the environment, we analyze the impacts of task complexity in terms of sizes of the state and action spaces as well as optimal solution length, finding that even simple environments within a domain can provide signal on how well an agent can generalize to more complex tasks. (ii) For the reward, we ablate relative reward sparsity, observing that while dense turn-level rewards accelerate training, performance and stability is highly dependent on the choice of RL algorithm. (iii) And for the agent's policy, we explore the interplay between reward sparsity and biased (PPO, GRPO) and unbiased (RLOO) policy gradient methods in addition to showing how to find the optimal Supervised Fine-tuning (SFT) to RL training ratio given a fixed budget. We distill these findings into a training recipe that guides co-design across the three pillars, facilitating research and practical efforts in multi-turn agentic RL. Code: https://github.com/pearls-lab/meow-tea-taro</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:17:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.01132</guid></item><item><title>Align Your Tangent: Training Better Consistency Models via
  Manifold-Aligned Tangents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.00658</link><description>Align Your Tangent (AYT) improves Consistency Model training by reducing oscillatory tangents and enabling faster convergence with small batch sizes.  					AI-generated summary 				 With diffusion and flow matching models achieving state-of-the-art generating performance, the interest of the community now turned to reducing the inference time without sacrificing sample quality. Consistency Models (CMs), which are trained to be consistent on diffusion or probability flow ordinary differential equation (PF-ODE) trajectories, enable one or two-step flow or diffusion sampling. However, CMs typically require prolonged training with large batch sizes to obtain competitive sample quality. In this paper, we examine the training dynamics of CMs near convergence and discover that CM tangents -- CM output update directions -- are quite oscillatory, in the sense that they move parallel to the data manifold, not towards the manifold. To mitigate oscillatory tangents, we propose a new loss function, called the manifold feature distance (MFD), which provides manifold-aligned tangents that point toward the data manifold. Consequently, our method -- dubbed Align Your Tangent (AYT) -- can accelerate CM training by orders of magnitude and even out-perform the learned perceptual image patch similarity metric (LPIPS). Furthermore, we find that our loss enables training with extremely small batch sizes without compromising sample quality. Code: https://github.com/1202kbs/AYT</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:24:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.00658</guid></item><item><title>NuRisk: A Visual Question Answering Dataset for Agent-Level Risk
  Assessment in Autonomous Driving</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.25944</link><description>NuRisk, a comprehensive VQA dataset, addresses the lack of spatio-temporal reasoning in current VLMs for autonomous driving by providing agent-level risk annotations in sequential images, improving accuracy and reducing latency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Understanding risk in autonomous driving requires not only perception and prediction, but also high-level reasoning about agent behavior and context. Current Vision Language Models (VLMs)-based methods primarily ground agents in static images and provide qualitative judgments, lacking the spatio-temporal reasoning needed to capture how risks evolve over time. To address this gap, we propose NuRisk, a comprehensive Visual Question Answering (VQA) dataset comprising 2,900 scenarios and 1.1 million agent-level samples, built on real-world data from nuScenes and Waymo, supplemented with safety-critical scenarios from the CommonRoad simulator. The dataset provides Bird-Eye-View (BEV) based sequential images with quantitative, agent-level risk annotations, enabling spatio-temporal reasoning. We benchmark well-known VLMs across different prompting techniques and find that they fail to perform explicit spatio-temporal reasoning, resulting in a peak accuracy of 33% at high latency. To address these shortcomings, our fine-tuned 7B VLM agent improves accuracy to 41% and reduces latency by 75%, demonstrating explicit spatio-temporal reasoning capabilities that proprietary models lacked. While this represents a significant step forward, the modest accuracy underscores the profound challenge of the task, establishing NuRisk as a critical benchmark for advancing spatio-temporal reasoning in autonomous driving.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:02:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.25944</guid></item><item><title>Triangle Splatting+: Differentiable Rendering with Opaque Triangles</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.25122</link><description>Triangle Splatting+ optimizes triangles within a differentiable framework for real-time, high-fidelity 3D scene reconstruction and novel view synthesis, compatible with standard graphics engines.  					AI-generated summary 				 Reconstructing 3D scenes and synthesizing novel views has seen rapid progress in recent years. Neural Radiance Fields demonstrated that continuous volumetric radiance fields can achieve high-quality image synthesis, but their long training and rendering times limit practicality. 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) addressed these issues by representing scenes with millions of Gaussians, enabling real-time rendering and fast optimization. However, Gaussian primitives are not natively compatible with the mesh-based pipelines used in VR headsets, and real-time graphics applications. Existing solutions attempt to convert Gaussians into meshes through post-processing or two-stage pipelines, which increases complexity and degrades visual quality. In this work, we introduce Triangle Splatting+, which directly optimizes triangles, the fundamental primitive of computer graphics, within a differentiable splatting framework. We formulate triangle parametrization to enable connectivity through shared vertices, and we design a training strategy that enforces opaque triangles. The final output is immediately usable in standard graphics engines without post-processing. Experiments on the Mip-NeRF360 and Tanks &amp; Temples datasets show that Triangle Splatting+achieves state-of-the-art performance in mesh-based novel view synthesis. Our method surpasses prior splatting approaches in visual fidelity while remaining efficient and fast to training. Moreover, the resulting semi-connected meshes support downstream applications such as physics-based simulation or interactive walkthroughs. The project page is https://trianglesplatting2.github.io/trianglesplatting2/.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:59:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.25122</guid></item></channel></rss>