<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Kanana: Compute-efficient Bilingual Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18934</link><description>We introduce Kanana, a series of bilingual language models that demonstrate exceeding performance in Korean and competitive performance in English. The computational cost of Kanana is significantly lower than that of state-of-the-art models of similar size. The report details the techniques employed during pre-training to achieve compute-efficient yet competitive models, including high quality data filtering, staged pre-training, depth up-scaling, and pruning and distillation. Furthermore, the report outlines the methodologies utilized during the post-training of the Kanana models, encompassing supervised fine-tuning and preference optimization, aimed at enhancing their capability for seamless interaction with users. Lastly, the report elaborates on plausible approaches used for language model adaptation to specific scenarios, such as embedding, retrieval augmented generation, and function calling. The Kanana model series spans from 2.1B to 32.5B parameters with 2.1B models (base, instruct, embedding) publicly released to promote research on Korean language models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 04:05:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18934</guid></item><item><title>TheoremExplainAgent: Towards Multimodal Explanations for LLM Theorem Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19400</link><description>Understanding domain-specific theorems often requires more than just text-based reasoning; effective communication through structured visual explanations is crucial for deeper comprehension. While large language models (LLMs) demonstrate strong performance in text-based theorem reasoning, their ability to generate coherent and pedagogically meaningful visual explanations remains an open challenge. In this work, we introduce TheoremExplainAgent, an agentic approach for generating long-form theorem explanation videos (over 5 minutes) using Manim animations. To systematically evaluate multimodal theorem explanations, we propose TheoremExplainBench, a benchmark covering 240 theorems across multiple STEM disciplines, along with 5 automated evaluation metrics. Our results reveal that agentic planning is essential for generating detailed long-form videos, and the o3-mini agent achieves a success rate of 93.8% and an overall score of 0.77. However, our quantitative and qualitative studies show that most of the videos produced exhibit minor issues with visual element layout. Furthermore, multimodal explanations expose deeper reasoning flaws that text-based explanations fail to reveal, highlighting the importance of multimodal explanations.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 03:07:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19400</guid></item><item><title>Can Large Language Models Detect Errors in Long Chain-of-Thought Reasoning?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19361</link><description>Recently, o1-like models have drawn significant attention, where these models produce the long Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning steps to improve the reasoning abilities of existing Large Language Models (LLMs). In this paper, to understand the qualities of these long CoTs and measure the critique abilities of existing LLMs on these long CoTs, we introduce the DeltaBench, including the generated long CoTs from different o1-like models (e.g., QwQ, DeepSeek-R1) for different reasoning tasks (e.g., Math, Code, General Reasoning), to measure the ability to detect errors in long CoT reasoning. Based on DeltaBench, we first perform fine-grained analysis of the generated long CoTs to discover the effectiveness and efficiency of different o1-like models. Then, we conduct extensive evaluations of existing process reward models (PRMs) and critic models to detect the errors of each annotated process, which aims to investigate the boundaries and limitations of existing PRMs and critic models. Finally, we hope that DeltaBench could guide developers to better understand the long CoT reasoning abilities of their models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 04:04:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19361</guid></item><item><title>Agentic Reward Modeling: Integrating Human Preferences with Verifiable Correctness Signals for Reliable Reward Systems</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19328</link><description>Reward models (RMs) are crucial for the training and inference-time scaling up of large language models (LLMs). However, existing reward models primarily focus on human preferences, neglecting verifiable correctness signals which have shown strong potential in training LLMs. In this paper, we propose agentic reward modeling, a reward system that combines reward models with verifiable correctness signals from different aspects to provide reliable rewards. We empirically implement a reward agent, named RewardAgent, that combines human preference rewards with two verifiable signals: factuality and instruction following, to provide more reliable rewards. We conduct comprehensive experiments on existing reward model benchmarks and inference time best-of-n searches on real-world downstream tasks. RewardAgent significantly outperforms vanilla reward models, demonstrating its effectiveness. We further construct training preference pairs using RewardAgent and train an LLM with the DPO objective, achieving superior performance on various NLP benchmarks compared to conventional reward models. Our codes are publicly released to facilitate further research (https://github.com/THU-KEG/Agentic-Reward-Modeling).</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 03:05:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19328</guid></item><item><title>Language Models' Factuality Depends on the Language of Inquiry</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.17955</link><description>Multilingual language models (LMs) are expected to recall factual knowledge consistently across languages, yet they often fail to transfer knowledge between languages even when they possess the correct information in one of the languages. For example, we find that an LM may correctly identify Rashed Al Shashai as being from Saudi Arabia when asked in Arabic, but consistently fails to do so when asked in English or Swahili. To systematically investigate this limitation, we introduce a benchmark of 10,000 country-related facts across 13 languages and propose three novel metrics: Factual Recall Score, Knowledge Transferability Score, and Cross-Lingual Factual Knowledge Transferability Score-to quantify factual recall and knowledge transferability in LMs across different languages. Our results reveal fundamental weaknesses in today's state-of-the-art LMs, particularly in cross-lingual generalization where models fail to transfer knowledge effectively across different languages, leading to inconsistent performance sensitive to the language used. Our findings emphasize the need for LMs to recognize language-specific factual reliability and leverage the most trustworthy information across languages. We release our benchmark and evaluation framework to drive future research in multilingual knowledge transfer.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:17:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.17955</guid></item><item><title>Towards an AI co-scientist</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18864</link><description>Scientific discovery relies on scientists generating novel hypotheses that undergo rigorous experimental validation. To augment this process, we introduce an AI co-scientist, a multi-agent system built on Gemini 2.0. The AI co-scientist is intended to help uncover new, original knowledge and to formulate demonstrably novel research hypotheses and proposals, building upon prior evidence and aligned to scientist-provided research objectives and guidance. The system's design incorporates a generate, debate, and evolve approach to hypothesis generation, inspired by the scientific method and accelerated by scaling test-time compute. Key contributions include: (1) a multi-agent architecture with an asynchronous task execution framework for flexible compute scaling; (2) a tournament evolution process for self-improving hypotheses generation. Automated evaluations show continued benefits of test-time compute, improving hypothesis quality. While general purpose, we focus development and validation in three biomedical areas: drug repurposing, novel target discovery, and explaining mechanisms of bacterial evolution and anti-microbial resistance. For drug repurposing, the system proposes candidates with promising validation findings, including candidates for acute myeloid leukemia that show tumor inhibition in vitro at clinically applicable concentrations. For novel target discovery, the AI co-scientist proposed new epigenetic targets for liver fibrosis, validated by anti-fibrotic activity and liver cell regeneration in human hepatic organoids. Finally, the AI co-scientist recapitulated unpublished experimental results via a parallel in silico discovery of a novel gene transfer mechanism in bacterial evolution. These results, detailed in separate, co-timed reports, demonstrate the potential to augment biomedical and scientific discovery and usher an era of AI empowered scientists.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 03:18:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18864</guid></item><item><title>Can Language Models Falsify? Evaluating Algorithmic Reasoning with Counterexample Creation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19414</link><description>There is growing excitement about the potential of Language Models (LMs) to accelerate scientific discovery. Falsifying hypotheses is key to scientific progress, as it allows claims to be iteratively refined over time. This process requires significant researcher effort, reasoning, and ingenuity. Yet current benchmarks for LMs predominantly assess their ability to generate solutions rather than challenge them. We advocate for developing benchmarks that evaluate this inverse capability - creating counterexamples for subtly incorrect solutions. To demonstrate this approach, we start with the domain of algorithmic problem solving, where counterexamples can be evaluated automatically using code execution. Specifically, we introduce REFUTE, a dynamically updating benchmark that includes recent problems and incorrect submissions from programming competitions, where human experts successfully identified counterexamples. Our analysis finds that the best reasoning agents, even OpenAI o3-mini (high) with code execution feedback, can create counterexamples for only &lt;9% of incorrect solutions in REFUTE, even though ratings indicate its ability to solve up to 48% of these problems from scratch. We hope our work spurs progress in evaluating and enhancing LMs' ability to falsify incorrect solutions - a capability that is crucial for both accelerating research and making models self-improve through reliable reflective reasoning.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 07:36:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19414</guid></item><item><title>AISafetyLab: A Comprehensive Framework for AI Safety Evaluation and Improvement</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.16776</link><description>As AI models are increasingly deployed across diverse real-world scenarios, ensuring their safety remains a critical yet underexplored challenge. While substantial efforts have been made to evaluate and enhance AI safety, the lack of a standardized framework and comprehensive toolkit poses significant obstacles to systematic research and practical adoption. To bridge this gap, we introduce AISafetyLab, a unified framework and toolkit that integrates representative attack, defense, and evaluation methodologies for AI safety. AISafetyLab features an intuitive interface that enables developers to seamlessly apply various techniques while maintaining a well-structured and extensible codebase for future advancements. Additionally, we conduct empirical studies on Vicuna, analyzing different attack and defense strategies to provide valuable insights into their comparative effectiveness. To facilitate ongoing research and development in AI safety, AISafetyLab is publicly available at https://github.com/thu-coai/AISafetyLab, and we are committed to its continuous maintenance and improvement.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 03:16:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.16776</guid></item><item><title>VEM: Environment-Free Exploration for Training GUI Agent with Value Environment Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18906</link><description>Training Vision-Language Models (VLMs) for Graphical User Interfaces (GUI) agents via Reinforcement Learning (RL) faces critical challenges: environment-based RL requires costly interactions, while environment-free methods struggle with distribution shift and reward generalization. We propose an environment-free RL framework that decouples value estimation from policy optimization by leveraging a pretrained Value Environment Model (VEM). VEM predicts state-action values directly from offline data, distilling human-like priors about GUI interaction outcomes without requiring next-state prediction or environmental feedback. This avoids compounding errors and enhances resilience to UI changes by focusing on semantic reasoning (e.g., Does this action advance the user's goal?). The framework operates in two stages: (1) pretraining VEM to estimate long-term action utilities and (2) guiding policy exploration with frozen VEM signals, enabling layout-agnostic GUI automation. Evaluated on Android-in-the-Wild benchmarks, VEM achieves state-of-the-art performance in both offline and online settings, outperforming environment-free baselines significantly and matching environment-based approaches without interaction costs. Importantly, VEM demonstrates that semantic-aware value estimation can achieve comparable performance with online-trained methods.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 03:02:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18906</guid></item><item><title>Plutus: Benchmarking Large Language Models in Low-Resource Greek Finance</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18772</link><description>Despite Greece's pivotal role in the global economy, large language models (LLMs) remain underexplored for Greek financial context due to the linguistic complexity of Greek and the scarcity of domain-specific datasets. Previous efforts in multilingual financial natural language processing (NLP) have exposed considerable performance disparities, yet no dedicated Greek financial benchmarks or Greek-specific financial LLMs have been developed until now. To bridge this gap, we introduce Plutus-ben, the first Greek Financial Evaluation Benchmark, and Plutus-8B, the pioneering Greek Financial LLM, fine-tuned with Greek domain-specific data. Plutus-ben addresses five core financial NLP tasks in Greek: numeric and textual named entity recognition, question answering, abstractive summarization, and topic classification, thereby facilitating systematic and reproducible LLM assessments. To underpin these tasks, we present three novel, high-quality Greek financial datasets, thoroughly annotated by expert native Greek speakers, augmented by two existing resources. Our comprehensive evaluation of 22 LLMs on Plutus-ben reveals that Greek financial NLP remains challenging due to linguistic complexity, domain-specific terminology, and financial reasoning gaps. These findings underscore the limitations of cross-lingual transfer, the necessity for financial expertise in Greek-trained models, and the challenges of adapting financial LLMs to Greek text. We release Plutus-ben, Plutus-8B, and all associated datasets publicly to promote reproducible research and advance Greek financial NLP, fostering broader multilingual inclusivity in finance.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:08:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18772</guid></item><item><title>Distill Any Depth: Distillation Creates a Stronger Monocular Depth Estimator</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19204</link><description>Monocular depth estimation (MDE) aims to predict scene depth from a single RGB image and plays a crucial role in 3D scene understanding. Recent advances in zero-shot MDE leverage normalized depth representations and distillation-based learning to improve generalization across diverse scenes. However, current depth normalization methods for distillation, relying on global normalization, can amplify noisy pseudo-labels, reducing distillation effectiveness. In this paper, we systematically analyze the impact of different depth normalization strategies on pseudo-label distillation. Based on our findings, we propose Cross-Context Distillation, which integrates global and local depth cues to enhance pseudo-label quality. Additionally, we introduce a multi-teacher distillation framework that leverages complementary strengths of different depth estimation models, leading to more robust and accurate depth predictions. Extensive experiments on benchmark datasets demonstrate that our approach significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods, both quantitatively and qualitatively.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 03:10:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19204</guid></item><item><title>CritiQ: Mining Data Quality Criteria from Human Preferences</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19279</link><description>Language model heavily depends on high-quality data for optimal performance. Existing approaches rely on manually designed heuristics, the perplexity of existing models, training classifiers, or careful prompt engineering, which require significant expert experience and human annotation effort while introduce biases. We introduce CritiQ, a novel data selection method that automatically mines criteria from human preferences for data quality with only sim30 human-annotated pairs and performs efficient data selection. The main component, CritiQ Flow, employs a manager agent to evolve quality criteria and worker agents to make pairwise judgments. We build a knowledge base that extracts quality criteria from previous work to boost CritiQ Flow. Compared to perplexity- and classifier- based methods, verbal criteria are more interpretable and possess reusable value. After deriving the criteria, we train the CritiQ Scorer to give quality scores and perform efficient data selection. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our method in the code, math, and logic domains, achieving high accuracy on human-annotated test sets. To validate the quality of the selected data, we continually train Llama 3.1 models and observe improved performance on downstream tasks compared to uniform sampling. Ablation studies validate the benefits of the knowledge base and the reflection process. We analyze how criteria evolve and the effectiveness of majority voting.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:47:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19279</guid></item><item><title>GHOST 2.0: generative high-fidelity one shot transfer of heads</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18417</link><description>While the task of face swapping has recently gained attention in the research community, a related problem of head swapping remains largely unexplored. In addition to skin color transfer, head swap poses extra challenges, such as the need to preserve structural information of the whole head during synthesis and inpaint gaps between swapped head and background. In this paper, we address these concerns with GHOST 2.0, which consists of two problem-specific modules. First, we introduce enhanced Aligner model for head reenactment, which preserves identity information at multiple scales and is robust to extreme pose variations. Secondly, we use a Blender module that seamlessly integrates the reenacted head into the target background by transferring skin color and inpainting mismatched regions. Both modules outperform the baselines on the corresponding tasks, allowing to achieve state of the art results in head swapping. We also tackle complex cases, such as large difference in hair styles of source and target. Code is available at https://github.com/ai-forever/ghost-2.0</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 09:15:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.18417</guid></item><item><title>BIG-Bench Extra Hard</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19187</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in everyday applications, demanding robust general reasoning capabilities and diverse reasoning skillset. However, current LLM reasoning benchmarks predominantly focus on mathematical and coding abilities, leaving a gap in evaluating broader reasoning proficiencies. One particular exception is the BIG-Bench dataset, which has served as a crucial benchmark for evaluating the general reasoning capabilities of LLMs, thanks to its diverse set of challenging tasks that allowed for a comprehensive assessment of general reasoning across various skills within a unified framework. However, recent advances in LLMs have led to saturation on BIG-Bench, and its harder version BIG-Bench Hard (BBH). State-of-the-art models achieve near-perfect scores on many tasks in BBH, thus diminishing its utility. To address this limitation, we introduce BIG-Bench Extra Hard (BBEH), a new benchmark designed to push the boundaries of LLM reasoning evaluation. BBEH replaces each task in BBH with a novel task that probes a similar reasoning capability but exhibits significantly increased difficulty. We evaluate various models on BBEH and observe a (harmonic) average accuracy of 9.8\% for the best general-purpose model and 44.8\% for the best reasoning-specialized model, indicating substantial room for improvement and highlighting the ongoing challenge of achieving robust general reasoning in LLMs. We release BBEH publicly at: https://github.com/google-deepmind/bbeh.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 07:43:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19187</guid></item><item><title>PosterSum: A Multimodal Benchmark for Scientific Poster Summarization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.17540</link><description>Generating accurate and concise textual summaries from multimodal documents is challenging, especially when dealing with visually complex content like scientific posters. We introduce PosterSum, a novel benchmark to advance the development of vision-language models that can understand and summarize scientific posters into research paper abstracts. Our dataset contains 16,305 conference posters paired with their corresponding abstracts as summaries. Each poster is provided in image format and presents diverse visual understanding challenges, such as complex layouts, dense text regions, tables, and figures. We benchmark state-of-the-art Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) on PosterSum and demonstrate that they struggle to accurately interpret and summarize scientific posters. We propose Segment &amp; Summarize, a hierarchical method that outperforms current MLLMs on automated metrics, achieving a 3.14% gain in ROUGE-L. This will serve as a starting point for future research on poster summarization.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:37:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.17540</guid></item><item><title>MolSpectra: Pre-training 3D Molecular Representation with Multi-modal Energy Spectra</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.16284</link><description>Establishing the relationship between 3D structures and the energy states of molecular systems has proven to be a promising approach for learning 3D molecular representations. However, existing methods are limited to modeling the molecular energy states from classical mechanics. This limitation results in a significant oversight of quantum mechanical effects, such as quantized (discrete) energy level structures, which offer a more accurate estimation of molecular energy and can be experimentally measured through energy spectra. In this paper, we propose to utilize the energy spectra to enhance the pre-training of 3D molecular representations (MolSpectra), thereby infusing the knowledge of quantum mechanics into the molecular representations. Specifically, we propose SpecFormer, a multi-spectrum encoder for encoding molecular spectra via masked patch reconstruction. By further aligning outputs from the 3D encoder and spectrum encoder using a contrastive objective, we enhance the 3D encoder's understanding of molecules. Evaluations on public benchmarks reveal that our pre-trained representations surpass existing methods in predicting molecular properties and modeling dynamics.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 03:29:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.16284</guid></item><item><title>Project Alexandria: Towards Freeing Scientific Knowledge from Copyright Burdens via LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19413</link><description>Paywalls, licenses and copyright rules often restrict the broad dissemination and reuse of scientific knowledge. We take the position that it is both legally and technically feasible to extract the scientific knowledge in scholarly texts. Current methods, like text embeddings, fail to reliably preserve factual content, and simple paraphrasing may not be legally sound. We urge the community to adopt a new idea: convert scholarly documents into Knowledge Units using LLMs. These units use structured data capturing entities, attributes and relationships without stylistic content. We provide evidence that Knowledge Units: (1) form a legally defensible framework for sharing knowledge from copyrighted research texts, based on legal analyses of German copyright law and U.S. Fair Use doctrine, and (2) preserve most (~95%) factual knowledge from original text, measured by MCQ performance on facts from the original copyrighted text across four research domains. Freeing scientific knowledge from copyright promises transformative benefits for scientific research and education by allowing language models to reuse important facts from copyrighted text. To support this, we share open-source tools for converting research documents into Knowledge Units. Overall, our work posits the feasibility of democratizing access to scientific knowledge while respecting copyright.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 09:18:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2502.19413</guid></item></channel></rss>