<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>2025.1  - DeepSeek entered the scene, backed by High Flyer Quant</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/447609737740306</link><description>2025.1 - DeepSeek entered the scene, backed by High Flyer Quant 2026.1 - IQuest enters the game, backed by Uniquant Quant 📈 and launching IQuest-Coder on huggingface https://huggingface.co/collections/IQuestLab/iquest-coder ✨ 40B models: Instruct / Thinking / Loop ✨ Loop = MoE-level performance with only ~5% extra training cost ✨ Native 128K context See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/447609737740306</guid></item><item><title>The Architecture of 2026: Beyond the Token Trap 🚀</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/mindchain/406965796956131</link><description>The Architecture of 2026: Beyond the Token Trap 🚀 We are witnessing a tectonic shift in Transformer architecture. It’s no longer just about "predicting the next token"—it’s about executing latent plans on a high-speed data highway. What happens when we combine DeepSeek’s stability with Google’s strategic intelligence? 1️⃣ The Infrastructure: DeepSeek’s mHC Moving from a single-lane residual stream to a multi-lane highway. Using the Birkhoff Polytope, mHC ensures mathematical stability (Identity Mapping) while routing specialized data through dedicated lanes. 2️⃣ The Intelligence: Google’s Meta-Controller An internal AI unit that lives inside the Transformer. It escapes the "Token Trap" by extracting data to create a latent plan, steering the model via Temporal Abstraction. The Synergy: In a Topological Transformer, the Meta-Controller finally has the "dedicated lanes" it needs to steer complex reasoning without causing gradient explosions. We aren't just making models bigger; we are...</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/mindchain/406965796956131</guid></item><item><title>🚀 Excited to share: The vLLM container for NVIDIA DGX Spark!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Hellohal2064/482165788562535</link><description>🚀 Excited to share: The vLLM container for NVIDIA DGX Spark! I've been working on getting vLLM to run natively on the new DGX Spark with its GB10 Blackwell GPU (SM121 architecture). The results? 2.5x faster inference compared to llama.cpp! 📊 Performance Highlights: • Qwen3-Coder-30B: 44 tok/s (vs 21 tok/s with llama.cpp) • Qwen3-Next-80B: 45 tok/s (vs 18 tok/s with llama.cpp) 🔧 Technical Challenges Solved: • Built PyTorch nightly with CUDA 13.1 + SM121 support • Patched vLLM for Blackwell architecture • Created custom MoE expert configs for GB10 • Implemented TRITON_ATTN backend workaround 📦 Available now: • Docker Hub: docker pull hellohal2064/vllm-dgx-spark-gb10:latest • HuggingFace: huggingface.co/Hellohal2064/vllm-dgx-spark-gb10 The DGX Spark's 119GB unified memory opens up possibilities for running massive models locally. Happy to connect with others working on the DGX Spark Blackwell! See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Hellohal2064/482165788562535</guid></item><item><title>Chinese open source AI in December 2025 was about the stack coming together: open, end to end, and ready to ship 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/239073779898851</link><description>Chinese open source AI in December 2025 was about the stack coming together: open, end to end, and ready to ship 🔥 https://huggingface.co/collections/zh-ai-community/december-2025-china-open-source-highlights ✨ Big wave of foundation models: still scaling, but efficiency, reasoning, and deployment now matter more than size - DeepSeek-V3.2 - Z.ai GLM-4.7 - MiniMax-M2.1 - Xiaomi: MiMo-V2-Flash ✨ Multimodal reasoning is now default - Z.ai GLM-4.6V - Z.ai AutoGLM-Phone 9B - Bytedance: Dolphin-v2 ✨ Image &amp; video: editable assets and real workflows - Qwen-Image-Layered / Image-2512 - Meituan: LongCat-Image &amp; Image Edit - AIDC: Ovis-Image-7B - Live-Avatar / LongCat-Video-Avatar - HY-WorldPlay / RealVideo ✨ Audio goes edge ready - GLM-ASR-Nano / Fun-ASR-Nano - GLM-TTS / VoxCPM1.5 - CosyVoice 0.5B ✨ The quiet backbone: data &amp; infrastructure - Finch (FinWorkBench) - Tencent ARC: TimeLens-100K - BIGAI: TongSIM-Asset - MiniMax: VTP-Base ✨ Also congrats on Minimax and Z.ai announced their IPOs...</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/239073779898851</guid></item><item><title>👉 What happened in AI in 2025? 👈</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/pcuenq/421927498996428</link><description>👉 What happened in AI in 2025? 👈 We prepared the 2025 version of the HF AI Timeline Grid, highlighting open vs API-based model releases, and allowing you to browse and filter by access, modality, and release type! Play with it here: 2025-ai-timeline/2025-ai-timeline Here's my personal quarterly TL;DR: 1️⃣ Q1 — Learning to Reason Deepseek not only releases a top-notch reasoning model, but shows how to train them and compete with closed frontier models. OpenAI debuts Deep Research. Significant milestones: DeepSeek R1 &amp; R1-Zero, Qwen 2.5 VL, OpenAI Deep Research, Gemini 2.5 Pro (experimental) 2️⃣ Q2 — Multimodality and Coding More LLMs embrace multimodality by default, and there's a surge in coding agents. Strong vision, audio, and generative models emerge. Significant milestones: Llama 4, Qwen 3, Imagen 4, OpenAI Codex, Google Jules, Claude 4 3️⃣ Q3 — "Gold" rush, OpenAI opens up, the community goes bananas Flagship models get gold in Math olympiads and hard benchmarks. OpenAI...</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/pcuenq/421927498996428</guid></item><item><title>One of the most practical and genuinely useful use cases of agentic systems is a research assistant.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/RakshitAralimatti/360718325875789</link><description>One of the most practical and genuinely useful use cases of agentic systems is a research assistant. I built a Deep Research multi-agent system using NVIDIA’s Nemotron-3-Nano-30B-A3B model and CrewAI. Try it out yourself 👇 🔗 GitHub: https://github.com/rakshit2020/Deep-Research-Agent-using-CrewAI What truly made this system feel next-level was powering it with NVIDIA Nemotron-3-Nano-30B-A3B, its built for real-world agentic applications. The agentic system I built: 1. First talks to you and clarifies what you actually want, removing ambiguity 2. Then creates a proper research plan based on that clarity 3. Performs deep research using web search and content extraction tools 4. Finally produces a well-structured research report grounded in sources See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/RakshitAralimatti/360718325875789</guid></item><item><title>✅ New Article: *Operating an SI-Core (v0.1)*</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/kanaria007/128065561044409</link><description>✅ New Article: *Operating an SI-Core (v0.1)* Title: 🛠️ Operating SI-Core: Dashboards, Playbooks, and Human Loops 🔗 https://huggingface.co/blog/kanaria007/operating-si-core --- Summary: Designing an SI-Core is only half the job — the other half is *running it safely at 03:00*. This guide is a *non-normative ops runbook* for SRE/Ops teams and governance owners: what to put on the *one-page dashboard*, how to wire *alerts → actions*, when to use *safe-mode*, and how to answer the question that always arrives after an incident: &gt; “Why did the system do *that*?” --- Why It Matters: • Turns “auditable AI” into *operational reality* (not a slide deck) • Makes *ethics + rollback* measurable, actionable, and drillable • Clarifies how humans stay in the loop without becoming the bottleneck • Provides templates for *postmortems, escalation, and regulator-grade explanations* --- What’s Inside: *Core Ops Dashboard (1 page):* • Determinism/consistency, ethics/oversight, rollback/recovery,...</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/kanaria007/128065561044409</guid></item><item><title>🚨 Ads might be coming to AI assistants. But what if the ad is the response?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/nkasmanoff/401252358780981</link><description>🚨 Ads might be coming to AI assistants. But what if the ad is the response? Introducing ShillLM – a demo showing how activation steering can subtly nudge an LLM to favor specific brands without touching the prompt. Chat with it yourself. See exactly how it's influencing you. 🔗 nkasmanoff/shillm See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/nkasmanoff/401252358780981</guid></item><item><title>Incredible work!! They claim this is the year of recursive language models (I hope so). As models get bigger and better managing their context windows to fit longer prompts has been a standing engineering problem. They propose an inference technique that allows the model to externally crunch down long prompts into snippets that it can recursively call itself on, instead of directly feeding the entire prompt into the transformer. This could make models cheaper and more efficient but I doubt if big tech will adopt it since they profit more with the current approach (bigger models = longer context windows = more expensive the model). Once again such work came from academia/oss community cuz I doubt big tech would have shared these findings lol. They probably have much better inference methods that we may never know of haha.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Jaward/308052401069450</link><description>Incredible work!! They claim this is the year of recursive language models (I hope so). As models get bigger and better managing their context windows to fit longer prompts has been a standing engineering problem. They propose an inference technique that allows the model to externally crunch down long prompts into snippets that it can recursively call itself on, instead of directly feeding the entire prompt into the transformer. This could make models cheaper and more efficient but I doubt if big tech will adopt it since they profit more with the current approach (bigger models = longer context windows = more expensive the model). Once again such work came from academia/oss community cuz I doubt big tech would have shared these findings lol. They probably have much better inference methods that we may never know of haha. Paper: https://arxiv.org/pdf/2512.24601 See translation</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Jaward/308052401069450</guid></item><item><title>Big news from CES — Cosmos Reason 2 is here — our most advanced reasoning vision-language model for physical AI, now topping the Physical AI Bench leaderboard🏆</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/tsungyi/839679910683551</link><description>Big news from CES — Cosmos Reason 2 is here — our most advanced reasoning vision-language model for physical AI, now topping the Physical AI Bench leaderboard🏆 shi-labs/physical-ai-bench-leaderboard What’s new: - Enhanced physical reasoning &amp; spatio-temporal understanding - Flexible deployment with 2B &amp; 8B model sizes - Long-context understanding (up to 256K tokens) - Object detection with 2D/3D point localizations and trajectory data - New Cosmos Cookbook Recipes for faster onboarding Read the full blog 📖 https://huggingface.co/blog/nvidia/nvidia-cosmos-reason-2-brings-advanced-reasoning Download Cosmos Reason 2 👉 nvidia/Cosmos-Reason2-8B On top of Cosmos Reason 2, we also rolled out other new updates, including: - Cosmos Predict 2.5 – Unified Text2World/Image2World/Video2World model for higher-quality synthetic video worlds - Cosmos Transfer 2.5-2B – Lightweight, high-fidelity world-to-world translation with stronger physics alignment - NVIDIA GR00T N1.6 – Open robot foundation...</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/tsungyi/839679910683551</guid></item></channel></rss>