<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>DeepAgent: A General Reasoning Agent with Scalable Toolsets</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21618</link><description>DeepAgent, an end-to-end deep reasoning agent, autonomously performs thinking, tool discovery, and action execution using memory folding and reinforcement learning, outperforming baselines in various tool-use and application tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large reasoning models have demonstrated strong problem-solving abilities, yet real-world tasks often require external tools and long-horizon interactions. Existing agent frameworks typically follow predefined workflows, which limit autonomous and global task completion. In this paper, we introduce DeepAgent, an end-to-end deep reasoning agent that performs autonomous thinking, tool discovery, and action execution within a single, coherent reasoning process. To address the challenges of long-horizon interactions, particularly the context length explosion from multiple tool calls and the accumulation of interaction history, we introduce an autonomous memory folding mechanism that compresses past interactions into structured episodic, working, and tool memories, reducing error accumulation while preserving critical information. To teach general-purpose tool use efficiently and stably, we develop an end-to-end reinforcement learning strategy, namely ToolPO, that leverages LLM-simulated APIs and applies tool-call advantage attribution to assign fine-grained credit to the tool invocation tokens. Extensive experiments on eight benchmarks, including general tool-use tasks (ToolBench, API-Bank, TMDB, Spotify, ToolHop) and downstream applications (ALFWorld, WebShop, GAIA, HLE), demonstrate that DeepAgent consistently outperforms baselines across both labeled-tool and open-set tool retrieval scenarios. This work takes a step toward more general and capable agents for real-world applications. The code and demo are available at https://github.com/RUC-NLPIR/DeepAgent.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:07:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21618</guid></item><item><title>Video-As-Prompt: Unified Semantic Control for Video Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20888</link><description>Video-As-Prompt (VAP) uses a reference video to guide a frozen Video Diffusion Transformer via a Mixture-of-Transformers expert, achieving state-of-the-art results in semantic-controlled video generation with strong zero-shot generalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 Unified, generalizable semantic control in video generation remains a critical open challenge. Existing methods either introduce artifacts by enforcing inappropriate pixel-wise priors from structure-based controls, or rely on non-generalizable, condition-specific finetuning or task-specific architectures. We introduce Video-As-Prompt (VAP), a new paradigm that reframes this problem as in-context generation. VAP leverages a reference video as a direct semantic prompt, guiding a frozen Video Diffusion Transformer (DiT) via a plug-and-play Mixture-of-Transformers (MoT) expert. This architecture prevents catastrophic forgetting and is guided by a temporally biased position embedding that eliminates spurious mapping priors for robust context retrieval. To power this approach and catalyze future research, we built VAP-Data, the largest dataset for semantic-controlled video generation with over 100K paired videos across 100 semantic conditions. As a single unified model, VAP sets a new state-of-the-art for open-source methods, achieving a 38.7% user preference rate that rivals leading condition-specific commercial models. VAP's strong zero-shot generalization and support for various downstream applications mark a significant advance toward general-purpose, controllable video generation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:01:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20888</guid></item><item><title>From Denoising to Refining: A Corrective Framework for Vision-Language
  Diffusion Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.19871</link><description>ReDiff, a refining-enhanced diffusion framework, addresses train-inference discrepancies in discrete diffusion models by enabling the model to identify and correct its own errors, improving coherence and factual accuracy in generated content.  					AI-generated summary 				 Discrete diffusion models have emerged as a promising direction for vision-language tasks, offering bidirectional context modeling and theoretical parallelization. However, their practical application is severely hindered by a train-inference discrepancy, which leads to catastrophic error cascades: initial token errors during parallel decoding pollute the generation context, triggering a chain reaction of compounding errors and leading to syntactic errors and semantic hallucinations. To address this fundamental challenge, we reframe the generation process from passive denoising to active refining. We introduce ReDiff, a refining-enhanced diffusion framework that teaches the model to identify and correct its own errors. Our approach features a two-stage training process: first, we instill a foundational revision capability by training the model to revise synthetic errors; second, we implement a novel online self-correction loop where the model is explicitly trained to revise its own flawed drafts by learning from an expert's corrections. This mistake-driven learning endows the model with the crucial ability to revisit and refine its already generated output, effectively breaking the error cascade. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ReDiff significantly improves the coherence and factual accuracy of generated content, enabling stable and efficient parallel generation far superior to traditional denoising methods. Our codes and models are available at https://rediff-hku.github.io/.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:47:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.19871</guid></item><item><title>Sample By Step, Optimize By Chunk: Chunk-Level GRPO For Text-to-Image
  Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21583</link><description>Chunk-GRPO, a chunk-level optimization approach for text-to-image generation, improves preference alignment and image quality by addressing inaccurate advantage attribution and neglecting temporal dynamics.  					AI-generated summary 				 Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) has shown strong potential for flow-matching-based text-to-image (T2I) generation, but it faces two key limitations: inaccurate advantage attribution, and the neglect of temporal dynamics of generation. In this work, we argue that shifting the optimization paradigm from the step level to the chunk level can effectively alleviate these issues. Building on this idea, we propose Chunk-GRPO, the first chunk-level GRPO-based approach for T2I generation. The insight is to group consecutive steps into coherent 'chunk's that capture the intrinsic temporal dynamics of flow matching, and to optimize policies at the chunk level. In addition, we introduce an optional weighted sampling strategy to further enhance performance. Extensive experiments show that ChunkGRPO achieves superior results in both preference alignment and image quality, highlighting the promise of chunk-level optimization for GRPO-based methods.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 05:36:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21583</guid></item><item><title>UI-Ins: Enhancing GUI Grounding with Multi-Perspective
  Instruction-as-Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20286</link><description>The Instruction-as-Reasoning paradigm enhances GUI grounding by treating instructions as dynamic pathways, improving performance through multi-perspective reasoning and reinforcement learning.  					AI-generated summary 				 GUI grounding, which maps natural-language instructions to actionable UI elements, is a core capability of GUI agents. Prior works largely treats instructions as a static proxy for user intent, overlooking the impact of instruction diversity and quality on grounding performance. Through a careful investigation of existing grounding datasets, we find a 23.3% flaw rate in their instructions and show that inference-time exploitation of instruction diversity yields up to a substantial 76% relative performance improvement. In this paper, we introduce the Instruction-as-Reasoning paradigm, treating instructions as dynamic analytical pathways that offer distinct perspectives and enabling the model to select the most effective pathway during reasoning. To achieve this, we propose a two-stage training framework: supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on synthesized, diverse instructions to instill multi-perspective reasoning, followed by reinforcement learning (RL) to optimize pathway selection and composition. Our resulting models, UI-Ins-7B and UI-Ins-32B, achieve state-of-the-art results on five challenging grounding benchmarks and exhibit emergent reasoning, selectively composing and synthesizing novel instruction pathways at inference. In particular, UI-Ins-32B attains the best grounding accuracy, scoring 87.3% on UI-I2E-Bench, 57.0% on ScreenSpot-Pro, and 84.9% on MMBench-GUI L2. Furthermore, our model demonstrates strong agentic potential, achieving a 74.1% success rate on AndroidWorld using UI-Ins-7B as the executor. Our in-depth analysis reveals additional insights such as how reasoning can be formulated to enhance rather than hinder grounding performance, and how our method mitigates policy collapse in the SFT+RL framework. All code and model checkpoints will be publicly released in https://github.com/alibaba/UI-Ins.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:05:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20286</guid></item><item><title>A Definition of AGI</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.18212</link><description>A quantifiable framework based on Cattell-Horn-Carroll theory evaluates AI systems across ten cognitive domains, revealing significant gaps in foundational cognitive abilities like long-term memory.  					AI-generated summary 				 The lack of a concrete definition for Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) obscures the gap between today's specialized AI and human-level cognition. This paper introduces a quantifiable framework to address this, defining AGI as matching the cognitive versatility and proficiency of a well-educated adult. To operationalize this, we ground our methodology in Cattell-Horn-Carroll theory, the most empirically validated model of human cognition. The framework dissects general intelligence into ten core cognitive domains-including reasoning, memory, and perception-and adapts established human psychometric batteries to evaluate AI systems. Application of this framework reveals a highly "jagged" cognitive profile in contemporary models. While proficient in knowledge-intensive domains, current AI systems have critical deficits in foundational cognitive machinery, particularly long-term memory storage. The resulting AGI scores (e.g., GPT-4 at 27%, GPT-5 at 58%) concretely quantify both rapid progress and the substantial gap remaining before AGI.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:06:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.18212</guid></item><item><title>Sparser Block-Sparse Attention via Token Permutation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21270</link><description>Permuted Block-Sparse Attention improves computational efficiency in large language models by enhancing block-level sparsity in the self-attention mechanism, achieving significant speedups without compromising accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Scaling the context length of large language models (LLMs) offers significant benefits but is computationally expensive. This expense stems primarily from the self-attention mechanism, whose O(N^2) complexity with respect to sequence length presents a major bottleneck for both memory and latency. Fortunately, the attention matrix is often sparse, particularly for long sequences, suggesting an opportunity for optimization. Block-sparse attention has emerged as a promising solution that partitions sequences into blocks and skips computation for a subset of these blocks. However, the effectiveness of this method is highly dependent on the underlying attention patterns, which can lead to sub-optimal block-level sparsity. For instance, important key tokens for queries within a single block may be scattered across numerous other blocks, leading to computational redundancy. In this work, we propose Permuted Block-Sparse Attention (PBS-Attn), a plug-and-play method that leverages the permutation properties of attention to increase block-level sparsity and enhance the computational efficiency of LLM prefilling. We conduct comprehensive experiments on challenging real-world long-context datasets, demonstrating that PBS-Attn consistently outperforms existing block-sparse attention methods in model accuracy and closely matches the full attention baseline. Powered by our custom permuted-FlashAttention kernels, PBS-Attn achieves an end-to-end speedup of up to 2.75times in long-context prefilling, confirming its practical viability. Code available at https://github.com/xinghaow99/pbs-attn</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 03:41:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21270</guid></item><item><title>Reasoning with Sampling: Your Base Model is Smarter Than You Think</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.14901</link><description>An iterative sampling algorithm enhances reasoning capabilities in base models without additional training, matching or outperforming reinforcement learning on single-shot tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Frontier reasoning models have exhibited incredible capabilities across a wide array of disciplines, driven by posttraining large language models (LLMs) with reinforcement learning (RL). However, despite the widespread success of this paradigm, much of the literature has been devoted to disentangling truly novel behaviors that emerge during RL but are not present in the base models. In our work, we approach this question from a different angle, instead asking whether comparable reasoning capabilites can be elicited from base models at inference time by pure sampling, without any additional training. Inspired by Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) techniques for sampling from sharpened distributions, we propose a simple iterative sampling algorithm leveraging the base models' own likelihoods. Over different base models, we show that our algorithm offers substantial boosts in reasoning that nearly match and even outperform those from RL on a wide variety of single-shot tasks, including MATH500, HumanEval, and GPQA. Moreover, our sampler avoids the collapse in diversity over multiple samples that is characteristic of RL-posttraining. Crucially, our method does not require training, curated datasets, or a verifier, suggesting broad applicability beyond easily verifiable domains.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:40:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.14901</guid></item><item><title>RECALL: REpresentation-aligned Catastrophic-forgetting ALLeviation via
  Hierarchical Model Merging</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20479</link><description>RECALL is a representation-aware framework for continual learning in large language models that merges models without historical data, preserving domain-general features and adapting to task-specific knowledge.  					AI-generated summary 				 We unveil that internal representations in large language models (LLMs) serve as reliable proxies of learned knowledge, and propose RECALL, a novel representation-aware model merging framework for continual learning without access to historical data. RECALL computes inter-model similarity from layer-wise hidden representations over clustered typical samples, and performs adaptive, hierarchical parameter fusion to align knowledge across models. This design enables the preservation of domain-general features in shallow layers while allowing task-specific adaptation in deeper layers. Unlike prior methods that require task labels or incur performance trade-offs, RECALL achieves seamless multi-domain integration and strong resistance to catastrophic forgetting. Extensive experiments across five NLP tasks and multiple continual learning scenarios show that RECALL outperforms baselines in both knowledge retention and generalization, providing a scalable and data-free solution for evolving LLMs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 03:03:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20479</guid></item><item><title>WorldGrow: Generating Infinite 3D World</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21682</link><description>WorldGrow, a hierarchical framework, generates large, continuous 3D environments with coherent geometry and realistic appearance using pre-trained 3D models and a coarse-to-fine generation strategy.  					AI-generated summary 				 We tackle the challenge of generating the infinitely extendable 3D world -- large, continuous environments with coherent geometry and realistic appearance. Existing methods face key challenges: 2D-lifting approaches suffer from geometric and appearance inconsistencies across views, 3D implicit representations are hard to scale up, and current 3D foundation models are mostly object-centric, limiting their applicability to scene-level generation. Our key insight is leveraging strong generation priors from pre-trained 3D models for structured scene block generation. To this end, we propose WorldGrow, a hierarchical framework for unbounded 3D scene synthesis. Our method features three core components: (1) a data curation pipeline that extracts high-quality scene blocks for training, making the 3D structured latent representations suitable for scene generation; (2) a 3D block inpainting mechanism that enables context-aware scene extension; and (3) a coarse-to-fine generation strategy that ensures both global layout plausibility and local geometric/textural fidelity. Evaluated on the large-scale 3D-FRONT dataset, WorldGrow achieves SOTA performance in geometry reconstruction, while uniquely supporting infinite scene generation with photorealistic and structurally consistent outputs. These results highlight its capability for constructing large-scale virtual environments and potential for building future world models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:48:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21682</guid></item><item><title>Model Merging with Functional Dual Anchors</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21223</link><description>Functional Dual Anchors (FDAs) enhance model merging by aligning gradients with task vectors in the input-representation space, offering robustness and flexibility compared to parameter-space methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 Model merging is an efficient post-training strategy for integrating knowledge from multiple finetuned checkpoints of a shared foundation model. Existing methods operate in the parameter space, combining task vectors to mitigate conflicts, but remain constrained by parameter inconsistencies. We propose Functional Dual Anchors (FDAs), a framework that instead models the input-representation space. FDAs are synthetic inputs whose induced gradients align with task vectors, capturing task-specific functional shifts relative to the pretrained model. This perspective bridges joint multi-task training and post-hoc merging, offering both robustness and flexibility. We further introduce a principled initialization scheme and show that FDAs are complementary to parameter-space model merging. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of FDAs in model merging.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:24:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21223</guid></item><item><title>RAPO++: Cross-Stage Prompt Optimization for Text-to-Video Generation via
  Data Alignment and Test-Time Scaling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20206</link><description>RAPO++ enhances text-to-video generation by optimizing user prompts through retrieval, iterative refinement, and LLM fine-tuning, improving semantic alignment, compositionality, and temporal coherence.  					AI-generated summary 				 Prompt design plays a crucial role in text-to-video (T2V) generation, yet user-provided prompts are often short, unstructured, and misaligned with training data, limiting the generative potential of diffusion-based T2V models. We present RAPO++, a cross-stage prompt optimization framework that unifies training-data--aligned refinement, test-time iterative scaling, and large language model (LLM) fine-tuning to substantially improve T2V generation without modifying the underlying generative backbone. In Stage 1, Retrieval-Augmented Prompt Optimization (RAPO) enriches user prompts with semantically relevant modifiers retrieved from a relation graph and refactors them to match training distributions, enhancing compositionality and multi-object fidelity. Stage 2 introduces Sample-Specific Prompt Optimization (SSPO), a closed-loop mechanism that iteratively refines prompts using multi-source feedback -- including semantic alignment, spatial fidelity, temporal coherence, and task-specific signals such as optical flow -- yielding progressively improved video generation quality. Stage 3 leverages optimized prompt pairs from SSPO to fine-tune the rewriter LLM, internalizing task-specific optimization patterns and enabling efficient, high-quality prompt generation even before inference. Extensive experiments across five state-of-the-art T2V models and five benchmarks demonstrate that RAPO++ achieves significant gains in semantic alignment, compositional reasoning, temporal stability, and physical plausibility, outperforming existing methods by large margins. Our results highlight RAPO++ as a model-agnostic, cost-efficient, and scalable solution that sets a new standard for prompt optimization in T2V generation. The code is available at https://github.com/Vchitect/RAPO.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 03:16:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20206</guid></item><item><title>Map the Flow: Revealing Hidden Pathways of Information in VideoLLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13251</link><description>Video Large Language Models (VideoLLMs) perform video question answering by initiating temporal reasoning through cross-frame interactions, followed by video-language integration, and generate answers using effective information pathways while suppressing unnecessary attention edges.  					AI-generated summary 				 Video Large Language Models (VideoLLMs) extend the capabilities of vision-language models to spatiotemporal inputs, enabling tasks such as video question answering (VideoQA). Despite recent advances in VideoLLMs, their internal mechanisms on where and how they extract and propagate video and textual information remain less explored. In this study, we investigate the internal information flow of VideoLLMs using mechanistic interpretability techniques. Our analysis reveals consistent patterns across diverse VideoQA tasks: (1) temporal reasoning in VideoLLMs initiates with active cross-frame interactions in early-to-middle layers, (2) followed by progressive video-language integration in middle layers. This is facilitated by alignment between video representations and linguistic embeddings containing temporal concepts. (3) Upon completion of this integration, the model is ready to generate correct answers in middle-to-late layers. (4) Based on our analysis, we show that VideoLLMs can retain their VideoQA performance by selecting these effective information pathways while suppressing a substantial amount of attention edges, e.g., 58% in LLaVA-NeXT-7B-Video-FT. These findings provide a blueprint on how VideoLLMs perform temporal reasoning and offer practical insights for improving model interpretability and downstream generalization. Our project page with the source code is available at https://map-the-flow.github.io</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 03:58:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13251</guid></item><item><title>Visual Diffusion Models are Geometric Solvers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21697</link><description>Visual diffusion models can solve geometric problems by transforming noisy images into valid solutions, demonstrating a novel approach to geometric reasoning through image generation.  					AI-generated summary 				 In this paper we show that visual diffusion models can serve as effective geometric solvers: they can directly reason about geometric problems by working in pixel space. We first demonstrate this on the Inscribed Square Problem, a long-standing problem in geometry that asks whether every Jordan curve contains four points forming a square. We then extend the approach to two other well-known hard geometric problems: the Steiner Tree Problem and the Simple Polygon Problem.   Our method treats each problem instance as an image and trains a standard visual diffusion model that transforms Gaussian noise into an image representing a valid approximate solution that closely matches the exact one. The model learns to transform noisy geometric structures into correct configurations, effectively recasting geometric reasoning as image generation.   Unlike prior work that necessitates specialized architectures and domain-specific adaptations when applying diffusion to parametric geometric representations, we employ a standard visual diffusion model that operates on the visual representation of the problem. This simplicity highlights a surprising bridge between generative modeling and geometric problem solving. Beyond the specific problems studied here, our results point toward a broader paradigm: operating in image space provides a general and practical framework for approximating notoriously hard problems, and opens the door to tackling a far wider class of challenging geometric tasks.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:04:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21697</guid></item><item><title>PhysWorld: From Real Videos to World Models of Deformable Objects via
  Physics-Aware Demonstration Synthesis</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21447</link><description>PhysWorld uses a simulator to generate diverse demonstrations for training a GNN-based world model, enabling accurate and fast predictions for deformable objects with competitive performance and faster inference speeds.  					AI-generated summary 				 Interactive world models that simulate object dynamics are crucial for robotics, VR, and AR. However, it remains a significant challenge to learn physics-consistent dynamics models from limited real-world video data, especially for deformable objects with spatially-varying physical properties. To overcome the challenge of data scarcity, we propose PhysWorld, a novel framework that utilizes a simulator to synthesize physically plausible and diverse demonstrations to learn efficient world models. Specifically, we first construct a physics-consistent digital twin within MPM simulator via constitutive model selection and global-to-local optimization of physical properties. Subsequently, we apply part-aware perturbations to the physical properties and generate various motion patterns for the digital twin, synthesizing extensive and diverse demonstrations. Finally, using these demonstrations, we train a lightweight GNN-based world model that is embedded with physical properties. The real video can be used to further refine the physical properties. PhysWorld achieves accurate and fast future predictions for various deformable objects, and also generalizes well to novel interactions. Experiments show that PhysWorld has competitive performance while enabling inference speeds 47 times faster than the recent state-of-the-art method, i.e., PhysTwin.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:54:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21447</guid></item><item><title>Are Large Reasoning Models Good Translation Evaluators? Analysis and
  Performance Boost</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20780</link><description>Calibrating large reasoning models with synthetic human-like thinking trajectories improves their efficiency and performance in machine translation evaluation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advancements in large reasoning models (LRMs) have introduced an intermediate "thinking" process prior to generating final answers, improving their reasoning capabilities on complex downstream tasks. However, the potential of LRMs as evaluators for machine translation (MT) quality remains underexplored. We provides the first systematic analysis of LRM-as-a-judge in MT evaluation. We identify key challenges, revealing LRMs require tailored evaluation materials, tend to "overthink" simpler instances and have issues with scoring mechanisms leading to overestimation. To address these, we propose to calibrate LRM thinking by training them on synthetic, human-like thinking trajectories. Our experiments on WMT24 Metrics benchmarks demonstrate that this approach largely reduces thinking budgets by ~35x while concurrently improving evaluation performance across different LRM scales from 7B to 32B (e.g., R1-Distill-Qwen-7B achieves a +8.7 correlation point improvement). These findings highlight the potential of efficiently calibrated LRMs to advance fine-grained automatic MT evaluation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:03:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20780</guid></item><item><title>ARC-Encoder: learning compressed text representations for large language
  models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20535</link><description>An ARC-Encoder compresses context into continuous representations for LLMs, improving inference efficiency and performance across various scenarios.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent techniques such as retrieval-augmented generation or chain-of-thought reasoning have led to longer contexts and increased inference costs. Context compression techniques can reduce these costs, but the most effective approaches require fine-tuning the target model or even modifying its architecture. This can degrade its general abilities when not used for this specific purpose. Here we explore an alternative approach: an encoder that compresses the context into continuous representations which replace token embeddings in decoder LLMs. First, we perform a systematic study of training strategies and architecture choices for the encoder. Our findings led to the design of an Adaptable text Representations Compressor, named ARC-Encoder, which outputs x-times fewer continuous representations (typically x!in!{4,8}) than text tokens. We evaluate ARC-Encoder across a variety of LLM usage scenarios, ranging from in-context learning to context window extension, on both instruct and base decoders. Results show that ARC-Encoder achieves state-of-the-art performance on several benchmarks while improving computational efficiency at inference. Finally, we demonstrate that our models can be adapted to multiple decoders simultaneously, allowing a single encoder to generalize across different decoder LLMs. This makes ARC-Encoder a flexible and efficient solution for portable encoders that work seamlessly with multiple LLMs. We release a training code at https://github.com/kyutai-labs/ARC-Encoder , fine-tuning dataset and pretrained models are available at https://huggingface.co/collections/kyutai/arc-encoders-68ee18787301407d60a57047 .</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:55:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.20535</guid></item><item><title>Taming Modality Entanglement in Continual Audio-Visual Segmentation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.17234</link><description>A novel Continual Audio-Visual Segmentation (CAVS) task addresses challenges in multi-modal continual learning through a Collision-based Multi-modal Rehearsal (CMR) framework, improving performance over single-modal methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recently, significant progress has been made in multi-modal continual learning, aiming to learn new tasks sequentially in multi-modal settings while preserving performance on previously learned ones. However, existing methods mainly focus on coarse-grained tasks, with limitations in addressing modality entanglement in fine-grained continual learning settings. To bridge this gap, we introduce a novel Continual Audio-Visual Segmentation (CAVS) task, aiming to continuously segment new classes guided by audio. Through comprehensive analysis, two critical challenges are identified: 1) multi-modal semantic drift, where a sounding objects is labeled as background in sequential tasks; 2) co-occurrence confusion, where frequent co-occurring classes tend to be confused. In this work, a Collision-based Multi-modal Rehearsal (CMR) framework is designed to address these challenges. Specifically, for multi-modal semantic drift, a Multi-modal Sample Selection (MSS) strategy is proposed to select samples with high modal consistency for rehearsal. Meanwhile, for co-occurence confusion, a Collision-based Sample Rehearsal (CSR) mechanism is designed, allowing for the increase of rehearsal sample frequency of those confusable classes during training process. Moreover, we construct three audio-visual incremental scenarios to verify effectiveness of our method. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that our method significantly outperforms single-modal continual learning methods.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 03:07:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.17234</guid></item><item><title>AstaBench: Rigorous Benchmarking of AI Agents with a Scientific Research
  Suite</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21652</link><description>AstaBench provides a comprehensive benchmark suite for evaluating AI agents in scientific research, revealing that while progress has been made, AI still falls short in fully assisting scientific research.  					AI-generated summary 				 AI agents hold the potential to revolutionize scientific productivity by automating literature reviews, replicating experiments, analyzing data, and even proposing new directions of inquiry; indeed, there are now many such agents, ranging from general-purpose "deep research" systems to specialized science-specific agents, such as AI Scientist and AIGS. Rigorous evaluation of these agents is critical for progress. Yet existing benchmarks fall short on several fronts: they (1) fail to provide holistic, product-informed measures of real-world use cases such as science research; (2) lack reproducible agent tools necessary for a controlled comparison of core agentic capabilities; (3) do not account for confounding variables such as model cost and tool access; (4) do not provide standardized interfaces for quick agent prototyping and evaluation; and (5) lack comprehensive baseline agents necessary to identify true advances. In response, we define principles and tooling for more rigorously benchmarking agents. Using these, we present AstaBench, a suite that provides the first holistic measure of agentic ability to perform scientific research, comprising 2400+ problems spanning the entire scientific discovery process and multiple scientific domains, and including many problems inspired by actual user requests to deployed Asta agents. Our suite comes with the first scientific research environment with production-grade search tools that enable controlled, reproducible evaluation, better accounting for confounders. Alongside, we provide a comprehensive suite of nine science-optimized classes of Asta agents and numerous baselines. Our extensive evaluation of 57 agents across 22 agent classes reveals several interesting findings, most importantly that despite meaningful progress on certain individual aspects, AI remains far from solving the challenge of science research assistance.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:07:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21652</guid></item><item><title>Document Understanding, Measurement, and Manipulation Using Category
  Theory</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21553</link><description>Category theory is used to develop information-theoretic measures, summarization, and self-supervised improvement of large pretrained models through a mathematical framework of question-answer pairs and orthogonalization.  					AI-generated summary 				 We apply category theory to extract multimodal document structure which leads us to develop information theoretic measures, content summarization and extension, and self-supervised improvement of large pretrained models. We first develop a mathematical representation of a document as a category of question-answer pairs. Second, we develop an orthogonalization procedure to divide the information contained in one or more documents into non-overlapping pieces. The structures extracted in the first and second steps lead us to develop methods to measure and enumerate the information contained in a document. We also build on those steps to develop new summarization techniques, as well as to develop a solution to a new problem viz. exegesis resulting in an extension of the original document. Our question-answer pair methodology enables a novel rate distortion analysis of summarization techniques. We implement our techniques using large pretrained models, and we propose a multimodal extension of our overall mathematical framework. Finally, we develop a novel self-supervised method using RLVR to improve large pretrained models using consistency constraints such as composability and closure under certain operations that stem naturally from our category theoretic framework.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:30:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21553</guid></item><item><title>PhysVLM-AVR: Active Visual Reasoning for Multimodal Large Language
  Models in Physical Environments</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21111</link><description>Active Visual Reasoning (AVR) extends visual reasoning to interactive, partially observable environments, requiring agents to sequentially gather and integrate information for coherent decision-making, as evaluated by the CLEVR-AVR benchmark.  					AI-generated summary 				 Visual reasoning in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) has primarily been studied in static, fully observable settings, limiting their effectiveness in real-world environments where information is often incomplete due to occlusion or limited field of view. Humans, in contrast, actively explore and interact with their environment-moving, examining, and manipulating objects-to gather information through a closed-loop process integrating perception, reasoning, and action. Inspired by this human capability, we introduce the Active Visual Reasoning (AVR) task, extending visual reasoning to partially observable, interactive environments. AVR necessitates agents to: (1) actively acquire information via sequential physical actions, (2) integrate observations across multiple steps for coherent reasoning, and (3) dynamically adjust decisions based on evolving visual feedback. To rigorously evaluate AVR, we introduce CLEVR-AVR, a simulation benchmark featuring multi-round interactive environments designed to assess both reasoning correctness and information-gathering efficiency. We present AVR-152k, a large-scale dataset that offers rich Chain-of-Thought (CoT) annotations detailing iterative reasoning for uncertainty identification, action-conditioned information gain prediction, and information-maximizing action selection, crucial for training agents in a higher-order Markov Decision Process. Building on this, we develop PhysVLM-AVR, an MLLM achieving state-of-the-art performance on CLEVR-AVR, embodied reasoning (OpenEQA, RoboVQA), and passive visual reasoning (GeoMath, Geometry30K). Our analysis also reveals that current embodied MLLMs, despite detecting information incompleteness, struggle to actively acquire and integrate new information through interaction, highlighting a fundamental gap in active reasoning capabilities.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 07:15:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.21111</guid></item></channel></rss>