<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>A Survey on Latent Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06203</link><description>Latent reasoning enhances large language models by performing multi-step inference in continuous hidden states, improving efficiency and expressiveness beyond token-level supervision.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive reasoning capabilities, especially when guided by explicit chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning that verbalizes intermediate steps. While CoT improves both interpretability and accuracy, its dependence on natural language reasoning limits the model's expressive bandwidth. Latent reasoning tackles this bottleneck by performing multi-step inference entirely in the model's continuous hidden state, eliminating token-level supervision. To advance latent reasoning research, this survey provides a comprehensive overview of the emerging field of latent reasoning. We begin by examining the foundational role of neural network layers as the computational substrate for reasoning, highlighting how hierarchical representations support complex transformations. Next, we explore diverse latent reasoning methodologies, including activation-based recurrence, hidden state propagation, and fine-tuning strategies that compress or internalize explicit reasoning traces. Finally, we discuss advanced paradigms such as infinite-depth latent reasoning via masked diffusion models, which enable globally consistent and reversible reasoning processes. By unifying these perspectives, we aim to clarify the conceptual landscape of latent reasoning and chart future directions for research at the frontier of LLM cognition. An associated GitHub repository collecting the latest papers and repos is available at: https://github.com/multimodal-art-projection/LatentCoT-Horizon/.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 03:15:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06203</guid></item><item><title>SingLoRA: Low Rank Adaptation Using a Single Matrix</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05566</link><description>SingLoRA, a reformulated low-rank adaptation method, enhances parameter-efficient fine-tuning by learning a single low-rank matrix update, ensuring stable optimization and reduced parameter count.  					AI-generated summary 				 Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) has significantly advanced parameter-efficient fine-tuning of large pretrained models. LoRA augments the pre-trained weights of a model by adding the product of two smaller matrices that together form a low-rank matrix update. Recent research has shown that scale disparities between these two matrices often cause unstable training dynamics, leading to suboptimal performance. In this paper, we propose SingLoRA, which reformulates low-rank adaptation by learning the weights update as a decomposition of a single low-rank matrix multiplied by its transpose. This simple design inherently removes inter-matrix scale conflicts, ensuring stable optimization, and roughly halves the parameter count. We analyze SingLoRA within the infinite-width neural network framework, showing that it guarantees stable feature learning by construction. Extensive experiments on multiple tasks validate these benefits. In common sense reasoning, fine-tuning LLama 7B on MNLI with SingLoRA achieves 91.3% accuracy - surpassing LoRA (89.1%) and LoRA+ (90.2%) - while using only 60% of their parameter budget. In image generation, fine-tuning Stable Diffusion with SingLoRA significantly improves image fidelity on DreamBooth, achieving a DINO similarity score of 0.151, compared to scores of 0.148 and 0.143 for DoRA and LoRA, respectively.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 06:25:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05566</guid></item><item><title>OmniPart: Part-Aware 3D Generation with Semantic Decoupling and
  Structural Cohesion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06165</link><description>OmniPart generates part-aware 3D objects with high semantic decoupling and robust structural cohesion using an autoregressive structure planning module and a spatially-conditioned rectified flow model.  					AI-generated summary 				 The creation of 3D assets with explicit, editable part structures is crucial for advancing interactive applications, yet most generative methods produce only monolithic shapes, limiting their utility. We introduce OmniPart, a novel framework for part-aware 3D object generation designed to achieve high semantic decoupling among components while maintaining robust structural cohesion. OmniPart uniquely decouples this complex task into two synergistic stages: (1) an autoregressive structure planning module generates a controllable, variable-length sequence of 3D part bounding boxes, critically guided by flexible 2D part masks that allow for intuitive control over part decomposition without requiring direct correspondences or semantic labels; and (2) a spatially-conditioned rectified flow model, efficiently adapted from a pre-trained holistic 3D generator, synthesizes all 3D parts simultaneously and consistently within the planned layout. Our approach supports user-defined part granularity, precise localization, and enables diverse downstream applications. Extensive experiments demonstrate that OmniPart achieves state-of-the-art performance, paving the way for more interpretable, editable, and versatile 3D content.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 03:35:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06165</guid></item><item><title>CriticLean: Critic-Guided Reinforcement Learning for Mathematical
  Formalization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06181</link><description>CriticLean, a reinforcement learning framework with CriticLeanGPT and CriticLeanBench, enhances semantic evaluation in automated theorem proving by actively learning to distinguish correct from incorrect formalizations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Translating natural language mathematical statements into formal, executable code is a fundamental challenge in automated theorem proving. While prior work has focused on generation and compilation success, little attention has been paid to the critic phase-the evaluation of whether generated formalizations truly capture the semantic intent of the original problem. In this paper, we introduce CriticLean, a novel critic-guided reinforcement learning framework that elevates the role of the critic from a passive validator to an active learning component. Specifically, first, we propose the CriticLeanGPT, trained via supervised fine-tuning and reinforcement learning, to rigorously assess the semantic fidelity of Lean 4 formalizations. Then, we introduce CriticLeanBench, a benchmark designed to measure models' ability to distinguish semantically correct from incorrect formalizations, and demonstrate that our trained CriticLeanGPT models can significantly outperform strong open- and closed-source baselines. Building on the CriticLean framework, we construct FineLeanCorpus, a dataset comprising over 285K problems that exhibits rich domain diversity, broad difficulty coverage, and high correctness based on human evaluation. Overall, our findings highlight that optimizing the critic phase is essential for producing reliable formalizations, and we hope our CriticLean will provide valuable insights for future advances in formal mathematical reasoning.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 02:15:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06181</guid></item><item><title>StreamVLN: Streaming Vision-and-Language Navigation via SlowFast Context
  Modeling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05240</link><description>StreamVLN, a streaming VLN framework, uses a hybrid slow-fast context modeling strategy to balance fine-grained visual understanding, long-term context modeling, and computational efficiency in real-world settings.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-and-Language Navigation (VLN) in real-world settings requires agents to process continuous visual streams and generate actions with low latency grounded in language instructions. While Video-based Large Language Models (Video-LLMs) have driven recent progress, current VLN methods based on Video-LLM often face trade-offs among fine-grained visual understanding, long-term context modeling and computational efficiency. We introduce StreamVLN, a streaming VLN framework that employs a hybrid slow-fast context modeling strategy to support multi-modal reasoning over interleaved vision, language and action inputs. The fast-streaming dialogue context facilitates responsive action generation through a sliding-window of active dialogues, while the slow-updating memory context compresses historical visual states using a 3D-aware token pruning strategy. With this slow-fast design, StreamVLN achieves coherent multi-turn dialogue through efficient KV cache reuse, supporting long video streams with bounded context size and inference cost. Experiments on VLN-CE benchmarks demonstrate state-of-the-art performance with stable low latency, ensuring robustness and efficiency in real-world deployment. The project page is: https://streamvln.github.io/{https://streamvln.github.io/}.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 04:48:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05240</guid></item><item><title>RLVER: Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Emotion Rewards for
  Empathetic Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.03112</link><description>An end-to-end reinforcement learning framework using simulated user emotion rewards enhances emotional intelligence in large language models while maintaining cognitive skills.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) excel at logical and algorithmic reasoning, yet their emotional intelligence (EQ) still lags far behind their cognitive prowess. While reinforcement learning from verifiable rewards (RLVR) has advanced in other domains, its application to dialogue-especially for emotional intelligence-remains underexplored. In this work, we introduce RLVER, the first end-to-end reinforcement learning framework that leverages verifiable emotion rewards from simulated users to cultivate higher-order empathetic abilities in LLMs. Within this framework, self-consistent affective simulated users engage in dialogue rollouts and produce deterministic emotion scores during conversations, serving as reward signals to guide the LLM's learning. Fine-tuning publicly available Qwen2.5-7B-Instruct model with PPO boosts its Sentient-Benchmark score from 13.3 to 79.2 while largely preserving mathematical and coding competence. Extensive experiments reveal that: (i) RLVER consistently improves multiple dialogue capabilities; (ii) Thinking and non-thinking models show distinct trends--thinking models excel in empathy and insight, while non-thinking models favor action; (iii) GRPO often yields stable gains, while PPO can push certain capabilities to a higher ceiling; (iv) More challenging environments are not always better-moderate ones can yield stronger outcomes. Our results show that RLVER is a practical route toward emotionally intelligent and broadly capable language agents.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 02:35:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.03112</guid></item><item><title>MedGen: Unlocking Medical Video Generation by Scaling
  Granularly-annotated Medical Videos</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05675</link><description>MedGen, a model trained on the large-scale MedVideoCap-55K dataset, achieves top performance in medical video generation by balancing visual quality and medical accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in video generation have shown remarkable progress in open-domain settings, yet medical video generation remains largely underexplored. Medical videos are critical for applications such as clinical training, education, and simulation, requiring not only high visual fidelity but also strict medical accuracy. However, current models often produce unrealistic or erroneous content when applied to medical prompts, largely due to the lack of large-scale, high-quality datasets tailored to the medical domain. To address this gap, we introduce MedVideoCap-55K, the first large-scale, diverse, and caption-rich dataset for medical video generation. It comprises over 55,000 curated clips spanning real-world medical scenarios, providing a strong foundation for training generalist medical video generation models. Built upon this dataset, we develop MedGen, which achieves leading performance among open-source models and rivals commercial systems across multiple benchmarks in both visual quality and medical accuracy. We hope our dataset and model can serve as a valuable resource and help catalyze further research in medical video generation. Our code and data is available at https://github.com/FreedomIntelligence/MedGen</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 03:10:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05675</guid></item><item><title>Is Diversity All You Need for Scalable Robotic Manipulation?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06219</link><description>Investigation into data diversity in robotic manipulation reveals that task diversity is crucial, multi-embodiment data is optional, and expert diversity can be confounding, leading to a distribution debiasing method for improved performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Data scaling has driven remarkable success in foundation models for Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Computer Vision (CV), yet the principles of effective data scaling in robotic manipulation remain insufficiently understood. In this work, we investigate the nuanced role of data diversity in robot learning by examining three critical dimensions-task (what to do), embodiment (which robot to use), and expert (who demonstrates)-challenging the conventional intuition of "more diverse is better". Throughout extensive experiments on various robot platforms, we reveal that (1) task diversity proves more critical than per-task demonstration quantity, benefiting transfer from diverse pre-training tasks to novel downstream scenarios; (2) multi-embodiment pre-training data is optional for cross-embodiment transfer-models trained on high-quality single-embodiment data can efficiently transfer to different platforms, showing more desirable scaling property during fine-tuning than multi-embodiment pre-trained models; and (3) expert diversity, arising from individual operational preferences and stochastic variations in human demonstrations, can be confounding to policy learning, with velocity multimodality emerging as a key contributing factor. Based on this insight, we propose a distribution debiasing method to mitigate velocity ambiguity, the yielding GO-1-Pro achieves substantial performance gains of 15%, equivalent to using 2.5 times pre-training data. Collectively, these findings provide new perspectives and offer practical guidance on how to scale robotic manipulation datasets effectively.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:59:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06219</guid></item><item><title>Coding Triangle: How Does Large Language Model Understand Code?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06138</link><description>The Code Triangle framework evaluates large language models across editorial analysis, code implementation, and test case generation, revealing limitations in diversity and robustness compared to human programmers and suggesting enhancements through human-generated content and model mixtures.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) have achieved remarkable progress in code generation, yet their true programming competence remains underexplored. We introduce the Code Triangle framework, which systematically evaluates LLMs across three fundamental dimensions: editorial analysis, code implementation, and test case generation. Through extensive experiments on competitive programming benchmarks, we reveal that while LLMs can form a self-consistent system across these dimensions, their solutions often lack the diversity and robustness of human programmers. We identify a significant distribution shift between model cognition and human expertise, with model errors tending to cluster due to training data biases and limited reasoning transfer. Our study demonstrates that incorporating human-generated editorials, solutions, and diverse test cases, as well as leveraging model mixtures, can substantially enhance both the performance and robustness of LLMs. Furthermore, we reveal both the consistency and inconsistency in the cognition of LLMs that may facilitate self-reflection and self-improvement, providing a potential direction for developing more powerful coding models.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 03:09:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06138</guid></item><item><title>GTA1: GUI Test-time Scaling Agent</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05791</link><description>GTA1 addresses task planning ambiguity and visual grounding in GUI interactions using test-time scaling and reinforcement learning, achieving state-of-the-art performance across benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Graphical user interface (GUI) agents autonomously operate across platforms (e.g., Linux) to complete tasks by interacting with visual elements. Specifically, a user instruction is decomposed into a sequence of action proposals, each corresponding to an interaction with the GUI. After each action, the agent observes the updated GUI environment to plan the next step. However, two main challenges arise: i) resolving ambiguity in task planning (i.e., the action proposal sequence), where selecting an appropriate plan is non-trivial, as many valid ones may exist; ii) accurately grounding actions in complex and high-resolution interfaces, i.e., precisely interacting with visual targets.   This paper investigates the two aforementioned challenges with our GUI Test-time Scaling Agent, namely GTA1. First, to select the most appropriate action proposal, we introduce a test-time scaling method. At each step, we sample multiple candidate action proposals and leverage a judge model to evaluate and select the most suitable one. It trades off computation for better decision quality by concurrent sampling, shortening task execution steps, and improving overall performance. Second, we propose a model that achieves improved accuracy when grounding the selected action proposal to its corresponding visual elements. Our key insight is that reinforcement learning (RL) facilitates visual grounding through inherent objective alignments, rewarding successful clicks on interface elements.   Experimentally, our method establishes state-of-the-art performance across diverse benchmarks. For example, GTA1-7B achieves 50.1%, 92.4%, and 67.7% accuracies on Screenspot-Pro, Screenspot-V2, and OSWorld-G, respectively. When paired with a planner applying our test-time scaling strategy, it exhibits state-of-the-art agentic performance (e.g., 45.2% task success rate on OSWorld). We open-source our code and models here.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:55:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05791</guid></item><item><title>Nile-Chat: Egyptian Language Models for Arabic and Latin Scripts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.04569</link><description>Nile-Chat models, using Branch-Train-MiX strategy, outperform existing multilingual and Arabic LLMs on Egyptian dialect benchmarks in both Arabic and Latin scripts.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Nile-Chat-4B, 3x4B-A6B, and 12B, a collection of LLMs for Egyptian dialect, uniquely designed to understand and generate texts written in both Arabic and Latin scripts. Specifically, with Nile-Chat-3x4B-A6B, we introduce a novel language adaptation approach by leveraging the Branch-Train-MiX strategy to merge script-specialized experts, into a single MoE model. Our Nile-Chat models significantly outperform leading multilingual and Arabic LLMs, such as LLaMa, Jais, and ALLaM, on our newly introduced Egyptian evaluation benchmarks, which span both understanding and generative tasks. Notably, our 12B model yields a 14.4% performance gain over Qwen2.5-14B-Instruct on Latin-script benchmarks. All our resources are publicly available. We believe this work presents a comprehensive methodology for adapting LLMs to dual-script languages, addressing an often overlooked aspect in modern LLM development.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 08:44:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.04569</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency-Effectiveness Reranking FLOPs for LLM-based Rerankers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06223</link><description>E\textsuperscript{2}R-FLOPs evaluates LLM-based rerankers by measuring relevance and throughput per PetaFLOP, providing a hardware-agnostic metric for efficiency and effectiveness.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Models (LLMs) have recently been applied to reranking tasks in information retrieval, achieving strong performance. However, their high computational demands often hinder practical deployment. Existing studies evaluate the efficiency of LLM-based rerankers using proxy metrics such as latency, the number of forward passes, input tokens, and output tokens. However, these metrics depend on hardware and running-time choices (\eg parallel or not, batch size, etc), and often fail to account for model size, making it difficult to interpret and obscuring the evaluation of the efficiency-effectiveness tradeoff. To address this issue, we propose E2R-FLOPs, for LLM-based rerankers: ranking metrics per PetaFLOP (RPP) for relevance per compute and queries per PetaFLOP (QPP) for hardware-agnostic throughput. Companied with the new metrics, an interpretable FLOPs estimator is built to estimate the FLOPs of an LLM-based reranker even without running any experiments. Based on the proposed metrics, we conduct comprehensive experiments to evaluate a wide range of LLM-based rerankers with different architecture, studying the efficiency-effectiveness trade-off and bringing this issue to the attention of the research community.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:50:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06223</guid></item><item><title>PRING: Rethinking Protein-Protein Interaction Prediction from Pairs to
  Graphs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05101</link><description>Deep learning-based computational methods have achieved promising results in predicting protein-protein interactions (PPIs). However, existing benchmarks predominantly focus on isolated pairwise evaluations, overlooking a model's capability to reconstruct biologically meaningful PPI networks, which is crucial for biology research. To address this gap, we introduce PRING, the first comprehensive benchmark that evaluates protein-protein interaction prediction from a graph-level perspective. PRING curates a high-quality, multi-species PPI network dataset comprising 21,484 proteins and 186,818 interactions, with well-designed strategies to address both data redundancy and leakage. Building on this golden-standard dataset, we establish two complementary evaluation paradigms: (1) topology-oriented tasks, which assess intra and cross-species PPI network construction, and (2) function-oriented tasks, including protein complex pathway prediction, GO module analysis, and essential protein justification. These evaluations not only reflect the model's capability to understand the network topology but also facilitate protein function annotation, biological module detection, and even disease mechanism analysis. Extensive experiments on four representative model categories, consisting of sequence similarity-based, naive sequence-based, protein language model-based, and structure-based approaches, demonstrate that current PPI models have potential limitations in recovering both structural and functional properties of PPI networks, highlighting the gap in supporting real-world biological applications. We believe PRING provides a reliable platform to guide the development of more effective PPI prediction models for the community. The dataset and source code of PRING are available at https://github.com/SophieSarceau/PRING.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 02:31:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05101</guid></item><item><title>SAMed-2: Selective Memory Enhanced Medical Segment Anything Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.03698</link><description>SAMed-2, an adaptation of SAM-2 for medical image segmentation, incorporates a temporal adapter and confidence-driven memory to improve performance across diverse medical datasets and tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent "segment anything" efforts show promise by learning from large-scale data, but adapting such models directly to medical images remains challenging due to the complexity of medical data, noisy annotations, and continual learning requirements across diverse modalities and anatomical structures. In this work, we propose SAMed-2, a new foundation model for medical image segmentation built upon the SAM-2 architecture. Specifically, we introduce a temporal adapter into the image encoder to capture image correlations and a confidence-driven memory mechanism to store high-certainty features for later retrieval. This memory-based strategy counters the pervasive noise in large-scale medical datasets and mitigates catastrophic forgetting when encountering new tasks or modalities. To train and evaluate SAMed-2, we curate MedBank-100k, a comprehensive dataset spanning seven imaging modalities and 21 medical segmentation tasks. Our experiments on both internal benchmarks and 10 external datasets demonstrate superior performance over state-of-the-art baselines in multi-task scenarios. The code is available at: https://github.com/ZhilingYan/Medical-SAM-Bench.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:38:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.03698</guid></item><item><title>Tora2: Motion and Appearance Customized Diffusion Transformer for
  Multi-Entity Video Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05963</link><description>Tora2 enhances motion-guided video generation by introducing a decoupled personalization extractor, gated self-attention mechanism, and contrastive loss, enabling simultaneous multi-entity customization and advanced motion control.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in diffusion transformer models for motion-guided video generation, such as Tora, have shown significant progress. In this paper, we present Tora2, an enhanced version of Tora, which introduces several design improvements to expand its capabilities in both appearance and motion customization. Specifically, we introduce a decoupled personalization extractor that generates comprehensive personalization embeddings for multiple open-set entities, better preserving fine-grained visual details compared to previous methods. Building on this, we design a gated self-attention mechanism to integrate trajectory, textual description, and visual information for each entity. This innovation significantly reduces misalignment in multimodal conditioning during training. Moreover, we introduce a contrastive loss that jointly optimizes trajectory dynamics and entity consistency through explicit mapping between motion and personalization embeddings. Tora2 is, to our best knowledge, the first method to achieve simultaneous multi-entity customization of appearance and motion for video generation. Experimental results demonstrate that Tora2 achieves competitive performance with state-of-the-art customization methods while providing advanced motion control capabilities, which marks a critical advancement in multi-condition video generation. Project page: https://github.com/alibaba/Tora .</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 03:13:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05963</guid></item><item><title>LOOM-Scope: a comprehensive and efficient LOng-cOntext Model evaluation
  framework</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.04723</link><description>Long-context processing has become a fundamental capability for large language models~(LLMs). To assess model's long-context performance, numerous long-context evaluation benchmarks have been proposed. However, variations in evaluation settings across these benchmarks lead to inconsistent results, making it difficult to draw reliable comparisons. Besides, the high computational cost of long-context evaluation poses a significant barrier for the community to conduct comprehensive assessments of long-context models. In this paper, we propose LOOM-Scope, a comprehensive and efficient framework for long-context evaluation. LOOM-Scope standardizes evaluation settings across diverse benchmarks, supports deployment of efficient long-context inference acceleration methods, and introduces a holistic yet lightweight benchmark suite to evaluate models comprehensively. Homepage: https://loomscope.github.io</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 04:55:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.04723</guid></item><item><title>Differential Mamba</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06204</link><description>A novel differential mechanism for Mamba, a selective state-space layer architecture, improves retrieval capabilities and performance by addressing overallocation issues.  					AI-generated summary 				 Sequence models like Transformers and RNNs often overallocate attention to irrelevant context, leading to noisy intermediate representations. This degrades LLM capabilities by promoting hallucinations, weakening long-range and retrieval abilities, and reducing robustness. Recent work has shown that differential design can mitigate this issue in Transformers, improving their effectiveness across various applications. In this paper, we explore whether these techniques, originally developed for Transformers, can be applied to Mamba, a recent architecture based on selective state-space layers that achieves Transformer-level performance with greater efficiency. We show that a naive adaptation of differential design to Mamba is insufficient and requires careful architectural modifications. To address this, we introduce a novel differential mechanism for Mamba, empirically validated on language modeling benchmarks, demonstrating improved retrieval capabilities and superior performance over vanilla Mamba. Finally, we conduct extensive ablation studies and empirical analyses to justify our design choices and provide evidence that our approach effectively mitigates the overallocation problem in Mamba-based models. Our code is publicly available.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 06:36:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06204</guid></item><item><title>How to Train Your LLM Web Agent: A Statistical Diagnosis</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.04103</link><description>A study on compute allocation for post-training LLM-based web agents finds that combining supervised fine-tuning with on-policy reinforcement learning improves performance and reduces computational costs compared to either method alone.  					AI-generated summary 				 LLM-based web agents have recently made significant progress, but much of it has occurred in closed-source systems, widening the gap with open-source alternatives. Progress has been held back by two key challenges: first, a narrow focus on single-step tasks that overlooks the complexity of multi-step web interactions; and second, the high compute costs required to post-train LLM-based web agents. To address this, we present the first statistically grounded study on compute allocation for LLM web-agent post-training. Our approach uses a two-stage pipeline, training a Llama 3.1 8B student to imitate a Llama 3.3 70B teacher via supervised fine-tuning (SFT), followed by on-policy reinforcement learning. We find this process highly sensitive to hyperparameter choices, making exhaustive sweeps impractical. To spare others from expensive trial-and-error, we sample 1,370 configurations and use bootstrapping to estimate effective hyperparameters. Our results show that combining SFT with on-policy RL consistently outperforms either approach alone on both WorkArena and MiniWob++. Further, this strategy requires only 55% of the compute to match the peak performance of pure SFT on MiniWob++, effectively pushing the compute-performance Pareto frontier, and is the only strategy that can close the gap with closed-source models.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 03:30:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.04103</guid></item><item><title>any4: Learned 4-bit Numeric Representation for LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.04610</link><description>any4 is a learned 4-bit weight quantization method for LLMs that achieves high accuracy without preprocessing and uses a GPU-efficient lookup table strategy.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present any4, a learned 4-bit weight quantization solution for large language models (LLMs) providing arbitrary numeric representations without requiring pre-processing of weights or activations. any4 yields higher accuracy compared to other related 4-bit numeric representation types: int4, fp4 and nf4, as evaluated on a range of model sizes, generations and families (Llama 2, Llama 3, Mistral and Mixtral). While any4 does not require preprocessing of weights or activations, it is also competitive with orthogonal techniques that require such preprocessing (e.g., AWQ and GPTQ). We also experiment with any3 and any2 and show competitiveness at lower bits. Additionally, we show that we can calibrate using a single curated diverse sample rather than hundreds of samples from a dataset as done in most quantization approaches. We also open source tinygemm, a latency optimized GPU matrix multiplication library for LLMs, that implements any4 using a GPU-efficient lookup table strategy along with other common quantization methods. We open source our code at https://github.com/facebookresearch/any4 .</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 02:02:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.04610</guid></item><item><title>Feed-Forward SceneDINO for Unsupervised Semantic Scene Completion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06230</link><description>SceneDINO achieves state-of-the-art segmentation accuracy in unsupervised semantic scene completion by leveraging self-supervised representation learning and 2D unsupervised scene understanding techniques.  					AI-generated summary 				 Semantic scene completion (SSC) aims to infer both the 3D geometry and semantics of a scene from single images. In contrast to prior work on SSC that heavily relies on expensive ground-truth annotations, we approach SSC in an unsupervised setting. Our novel method, SceneDINO, adapts techniques from self-supervised representation learning and 2D unsupervised scene understanding to SSC. Our training exclusively utilizes multi-view consistency self-supervision without any form of semantic or geometric ground truth. Given a single input image, SceneDINO infers the 3D geometry and expressive 3D DINO features in a feed-forward manner. Through a novel 3D feature distillation approach, we obtain unsupervised 3D semantics. In both 3D and 2D unsupervised scene understanding, SceneDINO reaches state-of-the-art segmentation accuracy. Linear probing our 3D features matches the segmentation accuracy of a current supervised SSC approach. Additionally, we showcase the domain generalization and multi-view consistency of SceneDINO, taking the first steps towards a strong foundation for single image 3D scene understanding.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 12:20:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.06230</guid></item><item><title>High-Resolution Visual Reasoning via Multi-Turn Grounding-Based
  Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05920</link><description>MGPO, an end-to-end reinforcement learning framework, enhances large multi-modal models' ability to focus on key visual regions without requiring additional grounding annotations, improving performance on both in-distribution and out-of-distribution benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 State-of-the-art large multi-modal models (LMMs) face challenges when processing high-resolution images, as these inputs are converted into enormous visual tokens, many of which are irrelevant to the downstream task. In this paper, we propose Multi-turn Grounding-based Policy Optimization (MGPO), an end-to-end reinforcement learning (RL) framework that enables LMMs to iteratively focus on key visual regions by automatically cropping sub-images, based on model-predicted grounding coordinates within a multi-turn conversation framework. Compared to supervised fine-tuning (SFT), which requires costly additional grounding annotations, our approach highlights that LMMs can emerge robust grounding abilities during the RL training process, leveraging only a binary reward function derived from the correctness of the final answer. Additionally, we observe that LMMs struggle to autonomously trigger visual grounding during the rollout process. To address this cold start problem, we design a multi-turn conversational template and restrict policy loss computation to model outputs generated across multiple dialogue rounds, thereby promoting stable optimization. Extensive experiments demonstrate that, when trained on standard visual-question-short answering data without grounding annotations, MGPO effectively elicits stronger grounding capabilities compared to GRPO, leading to 5.4\% improvement on in-distribution MME-Realworld and 5.2\% improvement on the challenging out-of-distribution (OOD) V* Bench. Notably, MGPO post-training on Qwen2.5-VL-7B with 21K samples surpasses OpenAI's o1 and GPT-4o models on the OOD V* Bench. Codes are available at https://github.com/EvolvingLMMs-Lab/MGPO.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 04:12:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05920</guid></item><item><title>The Landscape of Memorization in LLMs: Mechanisms, Measurement, and
  Mitigation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05578</link><description>The paper reviews recent studies on memorization in Large Language Models, exploring factors that influence memorization, detection methodologies, and mitigation strategies, while addressing privacy and ethical implications.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across a wide range of tasks, yet they also exhibit memorization of their training data. This phenomenon raises critical questions about model behavior, privacy risks, and the boundary between learning and memorization. Addressing these concerns, this paper synthesizes recent studies and investigates the landscape of memorization, the factors influencing it, and methods for its detection and mitigation. We explore key drivers, including training data duplication, training dynamics, and fine-tuning procedures that influence data memorization. In addition, we examine methodologies such as prefix-based extraction, membership inference, and adversarial prompting, assessing their effectiveness in detecting and measuring memorized content. Beyond technical analysis, we also explore the broader implications of memorization, including the legal and ethical implications. Finally, we discuss mitigation strategies, including data cleaning, differential privacy, and post-training unlearning, while highlighting open challenges in balancing the minimization of harmful memorization with utility. This paper provides a comprehensive overview of the current state of research on LLM memorization across technical, privacy, and performance dimensions, identifying critical directions for future work.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:47:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05578</guid></item><item><title>FAROS: Fair Graph Generation via Attribute Switching Mechanisms</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.03728</link><description>FAROS is a framework that enhances fairness in graph diffusion models by strategically switching node attributes during generation to balance accuracy and fairness.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advancements in graph diffusion models (GDMs) have enabled the synthesis of realistic network structures, yet ensuring fairness in the generated data remains a critical challenge. Existing solutions attempt to mitigate bias by re-training the GDMs with ad-hoc fairness constraints. Conversely, with this work, we propose FAROS, a novel FAir graph geneRatiOn framework leveraging attribute Switching mechanisms and directly running in the generation process of the pre-trained GDM. Technically, our approach works by altering nodes' sensitive attributes during the generation. To this end, FAROS calculates the optimal fraction of switching nodes, and selects the diffusion step to perform the switch by setting tailored multi-criteria constraints to preserve the node-topology profile from the original distribution (a proxy for accuracy) while ensuring the edge independence on the sensitive attributes for the generated graph (a proxy for fairness). Our experiments on benchmark datasets for link prediction demonstrate that the proposed approach effectively reduces fairness discrepancies while maintaining comparable (or even higher) accuracy performance to other similar baselines. Noteworthy, FAROS is also able to strike a better accuracy-fairness trade-off than other competitors in some of the tested settings under the Pareto optimality concept, demonstrating the effectiveness of the imposed multi-criteria constraints.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 09:34:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.03728</guid></item><item><title>AXLearn: Modular Large Model Training on Heterogeneous Infrastructure</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05411</link><description>AXLearn is a modular deep learning system designed for scalable training on heterogeneous hardware, maintaining performance and modularity through efficient code integration methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 We design and implement AXLearn, a production deep learning system that facilitates scalable and high-performance training of large deep learning models. Compared to other state-of-the-art deep learning systems, AXLearn has a unique focus on modularity and support for heterogeneous hardware infrastructure. AXLearn's internal interfaces between software components follow strict encapsulation, allowing different components to be assembled to facilitate rapid model development and experimentation on heterogeneous compute infrastructure. We introduce a novel method of quantifying modularity via Lines-of-Code (LoC)-complexity, which demonstrates how our system maintains constant complexity as we scale the components in the system, compared to linear or quadratic complexity in other systems. This allows integrating features such as Rotary Position Embeddings (RoPE) into AXLearn across hundred of modules with just 10 lines of code, compared to hundreds as required in other systems. At the same time, AXLearn maintains equivalent performance compared to state-of-the-art training systems. Finally, we share our experience in the development and operation of AXLearn.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 08:39:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.05411</guid></item></channel></rss>