<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>you gotta go fast and go read the latest blog by</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/463161503197574</link><description>you gotta go fast and go read the latest blog by @ ror et al. explaining Continuous Batching in depth https://huggingface.co/blog/continuous_batching See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/463161503197574</guid></item><item><title>🚀 I've just shipped a major update to the</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Nymbo/982136402285178</link><description>🚀 I've just shipped a major update to the Nymbo/Tools MCP server: the Agent_Terminal , a single "master tool" that cuts token usage by over 90%! Anthropic found 98.7% context savings using code execution with MCP, Cloudflare published similar findings. This is my open-source implementation of the same idea. # The Problem Traditional MCP exposes every tool definition directly to the model. With 12 tools, that's thousands of tokens consumed *before the conversation even starts*. Each tool call also passes intermediate results through the context window — a 10,000-row spreadsheet? That's all going into context just to sum a column. # The Solution: One Tool to Rule Them All Agent_Terminal wraps all 12 tools ( Web_Search , Web_Fetch , File_System , Generate_Image , Generate_Speech , Generate_Video , Deep_Research , Memory_Manager , Obsidian_Vault , Shell_Command , Code_Interpreter ) into a single Python code execution gateway. Instead of the model making individual tool calls, it writes...</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Nymbo/982136402285178</guid></item><item><title>🔥🎵 ➕ 🖹 🔥Check out my new large-scale MIDI + Lyrics dataset!!!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/asigalov61/839437202675249</link><description>🔥🎵 ➕ 🖹 🔥Check out my new large-scale MIDI + Lyrics dataset!!! asigalov61/Lyrics-MIDI-Dataset ~179k MIDIs with corresponding Lyrics to play with!!! 🤗 If you liked the dataset, please ❤️ Any feedback and/or suggestions are also appreciated 🤗 See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/asigalov61/839437202675249</guid></item><item><title>Two weeks ago I had an engaging discussion with locals in Cockermouth about AI and the broader industry, a reminder that hearing candid perspectives beyond our professional circles is invaluable and something anyone working full-time in this field should make time for.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/takarajordan/457583486458611</link><description>Two weeks ago I had an engaging discussion with locals in Cockermouth about AI and the broader industry, a reminder that hearing candid perspectives beyond our professional circles is invaluable and something anyone working full-time in this field should make time for. Thank you! See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/takarajordan/457583486458611</guid></item><item><title>Interested in RL training environments?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/841067327080467</link><description>Interested in RL training environments? We just released a beginner-friendly walkthrough notebook! Train a model to play Wordle using TRL + OpenEnv (TextArena) + GRPO + vLLM. happy learning! 🌱 Notebook: https://github.com/huggingface/trl/blob/main/examples/notebooks/openenv_wordle_grpo.ipynb OpenEnv guide in TRL: https://huggingface.co/docs/trl/main/en/openenv See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/sergiopaniego/841067327080467</guid></item><item><title>FLUX 2 vs FLUX SRPO, New FLUX Training Kohya SS GUI Premium App With Presets &amp; Features :</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/938257136422472</link><description>FLUX 2 vs FLUX SRPO, New FLUX Training Kohya SS GUI Premium App With Presets &amp; Features : https://youtu.be/RQHmyJVOHXo FLUX 2 has been published and I have compared it to the very best FLUX base model known as FLUX SRPO. Moreover, we have updated our FLUX Training APP and presets to the next level. Massive speed up gaings with 0 quality loss and lots of new features. I will show all of the new features we have with new SECourses Kohya SS GUI Premium app and compare FLUX SRPO trained model results with FLUX 2. https://youtu.be/RQHmyJVOHXo Get the SECourses Premium Kohya Trainer DreamBooth / Fine Tuning : [ https://www.patreon.com/posts/Kohya-FLUX-DreamBooth-Trainer-App-112099700 ] Get the SECourses Premium Kohya Trainer LoRA : [ https://www.patreon.com/posts/Kohya-FLUX-LoRA-Trainer-App-110879657 ] DreamBooth Training Tutorial: [ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FvpWy1x5etM ] LoRA Training Tutorial: [ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nySGu12Y05k ] Qwen Image Realism Tutorial: [...</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/938257136422472</guid></item><item><title>When models get too large for a single GPU, simply stacking layers vertically (Pipeline Parallelism) isn't always the answer. Sometimes, you need to slice the matrices themselves.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/flozi00/715911271022864</link><description>When models get too large for a single GPU, simply stacking layers vertically (Pipeline Parallelism) isn't always the answer. Sometimes, you need to slice the matrices themselves. My latest guide breaks down the hardware mechanics of Tensor Parallelism (TP). We look at how to shard individual operations across devices to make a cluster function as one massive accelerator. This isn't high-level theory—it is a look at the bare metal implementation. Here is what is covered in the deep dive: The Strategies: Column vs. Row Parallelism We analyze how to split weight matrices (W) and inputs (X). Column-Linear: Splits weights by columns. Requires an All-Gather to reconstruct the output. Row-Linear: Splits weights by rows. Requires an All-Reduce to sum partial results. The "Megatron-LM" Optimization Efficiency comes from minimizing communication. By sandwiching the non-linearity (GeLU) between a Column-Parallel layer and a Row-Parallel layer, we can skip synchronization entirely during the...</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/flozi00/715911271022864</guid></item><item><title>Introducing the japanese-trending-words dataset: a dataset consisting 593 words from Japan’s annual trending word rankings (流行語大賞) from 2006-2025. This dataset provides the top 30 words from each year and its meaning in Japanese and english. This resource is awesome for NLP tasks understanding recent Japanese culture and history.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ronantakizawa/796142001232258</link><description>Introducing the japanese-trending-words dataset: a dataset consisting 593 words from Japan’s annual trending word rankings (流行語大賞) from 2006-2025. This dataset provides the top 30 words from each year and its meaning in Japanese and english. This resource is awesome for NLP tasks understanding recent Japanese culture and history. ronantakizawa/japanese-trending-words #japanese #japanesedataset #trending See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ronantakizawa/796142001232258</guid></item><item><title>I wanted to call attention to Arli Ai's success in applying my recent modifications to refusal ablation to a MoE model successfully. Nice work,</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/grimjim/634931502597925</link><description>I wanted to call attention to Arli Ai's success in applying my recent modifications to refusal ablation to a MoE model successfully. Nice work, @ OwenArli ! ArliAI/GLM-4.5-Air-Derestricted Ablation on a MoE model is no small thing; I expect preserving norms/magnitudes during intervention better respects routing compared to naive refusal ablation. (I would have tagged their org earlier, but that feature seemed to be broken via "@") ArliAI See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/grimjim/634931502597925</guid></item><item><title>SceneWeaver — AI-Powered Background Generation &amp; Image Composition 🎨✨</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DawnC/810522223628641</link><description>SceneWeaver — AI-Powered Background Generation &amp; Image Composition 🎨✨ Transform ordinary portraits into professional studio shots with just one click! What can SceneWeaver do? - 📸 Upload any portrait photo and instantly generate stunning, professional-quality backgrounds - 🎭 Smart Subject Detection — Automatically identifies and extracts people, pets, or objects from your photos, even handling tricky cases like dark clothing and cartoon characters. - 🌄 Creative Scene Library — Choose from 24 professionally curated backgrounds spanning offices, nature landscapes, urban settings, artistic styles, and seasonal themes, or describe your own custom vision. - ⚙️ Professional Results — Delivers studio-quality compositions in seconds, saving hours of manual editing work while maintaining natural lighting and color harmony. What's next? 🎬 Enhanced context-aware generation 🎨 Batch processing for multiple style variations 🔧 Higher resolution output support 🌐 Accessible cloud deployment Current...</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DawnC/810522223628641</guid></item></channel></rss>