<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>PhysX: Physical-Grounded 3D Asset Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.12465</link><description>PhysX addresses the lack of physical properties in 3D generative models by introducing PhysXNet, a physics-annotated dataset, and PhysXGen, a framework that integrates physical knowledge into 3D asset generation.  					AI-generated summary 				 3D modeling is moving from virtual to physical. Existing 3D generation primarily emphasizes geometries and textures while neglecting physical-grounded modeling. Consequently, despite the rapid development of 3D generative models, the synthesized 3D assets often overlook rich and important physical properties, hampering their real-world application in physical domains like simulation and embodied AI. As an initial attempt to address this challenge, we propose PhysX, an end-to-end paradigm for physical-grounded 3D asset generation. 1) To bridge the critical gap in physics-annotated 3D datasets, we present PhysXNet - the first physics-grounded 3D dataset systematically annotated across five foundational dimensions: absolute scale, material, affordance, kinematics, and function description. In particular, we devise a scalable human-in-the-loop annotation pipeline based on vision-language models, which enables efficient creation of physics-first assets from raw 3D assets.2) Furthermore, we propose PhysXGen, a feed-forward framework for physics-grounded image-to-3D asset generation, injecting physical knowledge into the pre-trained 3D structural space. Specifically, PhysXGen employs a dual-branch architecture to explicitly model the latent correlations between 3D structures and physical properties, thereby producing 3D assets with plausible physical predictions while preserving the native geometry quality. Extensive experiments validate the superior performance and promising generalization capability of our framework. All the code, data, and models will be released to facilitate future research in generative physical AI.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 02:56:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.12465</guid></item><item><title>Towards Agentic RAG with Deep Reasoning: A Survey of RAG-Reasoning
  Systems in LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.09477</link><description>This survey integrates reasoning and retrieval in Large Language Models to improve factuality and multi-step inference, highlighting Synergized RAG-Reasoning frameworks and outlining future research directions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) lifts the factuality of Large Language Models (LLMs) by injecting external knowledge, yet it falls short on problems that demand multi-step inference; conversely, purely reasoning-oriented approaches often hallucinate or mis-ground facts. This survey synthesizes both strands under a unified reasoning-retrieval perspective. We first map how advanced reasoning optimizes each stage of RAG (Reasoning-Enhanced RAG). Then, we show how retrieved knowledge of different type supply missing premises and expand context for complex inference (RAG-Enhanced Reasoning). Finally, we spotlight emerging Synergized RAG-Reasoning frameworks, where (agentic) LLMs iteratively interleave search and reasoning to achieve state-of-the-art performance across knowledge-intensive benchmarks. We categorize methods, datasets, and open challenges, and outline research avenues toward deeper RAG-Reasoning systems that are more effective, multimodally-adaptive, trustworthy, and human-centric. The collection is available at https://github.com/DavidZWZ/Awesome-RAG-Reasoning.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 03:57:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.09477</guid></item><item><title>DrafterBench: Benchmarking Large Language Models for Tasks Automation in
  Civil Engineering</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.11527</link><description>DrafterBench is an open-source benchmark for evaluating LLM agents in technical drawing revision, assessing their capabilities in structured data comprehension, function execution, instruction following, and critical reasoning.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Model (LLM) agents have shown great potential for solving real-world problems and promise to be a solution for tasks automation in industry. However, more benchmarks are needed to systematically evaluate automation agents from an industrial perspective, for example, in Civil Engineering. Therefore, we propose DrafterBench for the comprehensive evaluation of LLM agents in the context of technical drawing revision, a representation task in civil engineering. DrafterBench contains twelve types of tasks summarized from real-world drawing files, with 46 customized functions/tools and 1920 tasks in total. DrafterBench is an open-source benchmark to rigorously test AI agents' proficiency in interpreting intricate and long-context instructions, leveraging prior knowledge, and adapting to dynamic instruction quality via implicit policy awareness. The toolkit comprehensively assesses distinct capabilities in structured data comprehension, function execution, instruction following, and critical reasoning. DrafterBench offers detailed analysis of task accuracy and error statistics, aiming to provide deeper insight into agent capabilities and identify improvement targets for integrating LLMs in engineering applications. Our benchmark is available at https://github.com/Eason-Li-AIS/DrafterBench, with the test set hosted at https://huggingface.co/datasets/Eason666/DrafterBench.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 03:00:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.11527</guid></item><item><title>MOSPA: Human Motion Generation Driven by Spatial Audio</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.11949</link><description>A diffusion-based generative framework, MOSPA, is introduced to model human motion in response to spatial audio, achieving state-of-the-art performance using the newly created SAM dataset.  					AI-generated summary 				 Enabling virtual humans to dynamically and realistically respond to diverse auditory stimuli remains a key challenge in character animation, demanding the integration of perceptual modeling and motion synthesis. Despite its significance, this task remains largely unexplored. Most previous works have primarily focused on mapping modalities like speech, audio, and music to generate human motion. As of yet, these models typically overlook the impact of spatial features encoded in spatial audio signals on human motion. To bridge this gap and enable high-quality modeling of human movements in response to spatial audio, we introduce the first comprehensive Spatial Audio-Driven Human Motion (SAM) dataset, which contains diverse and high-quality spatial audio and motion data. For benchmarking, we develop a simple yet effective diffusion-based generative framework for human MOtion generation driven by SPatial Audio, termed MOSPA, which faithfully captures the relationship between body motion and spatial audio through an effective fusion mechanism. Once trained, MOSPA could generate diverse realistic human motions conditioned on varying spatial audio inputs. We perform a thorough investigation of the proposed dataset and conduct extensive experiments for benchmarking, where our method achieves state-of-the-art performance on this task. Our model and dataset will be open-sourced upon acceptance. Please refer to our supplementary video for more details.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 04:18:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.11949</guid></item><item><title>MMHU: A Massive-Scale Multimodal Benchmark for Human Behavior
  Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.12463</link><description>A large-scale benchmark, MMHU, is proposed for human behavior analysis in autonomous driving, featuring rich annotations and diverse data sources, and benchmarking multiple tasks including motion prediction and behavior question answering.  					AI-generated summary 				 Humans are integral components of the transportation ecosystem, and understanding their behaviors is crucial to facilitating the development of safe driving systems. Although recent progress has explored various aspects of human behaviorx2014such as motion, trajectories, and intentionx2014a comprehensive benchmark for evaluating human behavior understanding in autonomous driving remains unavailable. In this work, we propose MMHU, a large-scale benchmark for human behavior analysis featuring rich annotations, such as human motion and trajectories, text description for human motions, human intention, and critical behavior labels relevant to driving safety. Our dataset encompasses 57k human motion clips and 1.73M frames gathered from diverse sources, including established driving datasets such as Waymo, in-the-wild videos from YouTube, and self-collected data. A human-in-the-loop annotation pipeline is developed to generate rich behavior captions. We provide a thorough dataset analysis and benchmark multiple tasksx2014ranging from motion prediction to motion generation and human behavior question answeringx2014thereby offering a broad evaluation suite. Project page : https://MMHU-Benchmark.github.io.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 05:18:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.12463</guid></item><item><title>Lizard: An Efficient Linearization Framework for Large Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.09025</link><description>Lizard is a linearization framework that transforms Transformer-based LLMs into subquadratic architectures for efficient infinite-context generation, using a hybrid attention mechanism and hardware-aware training.  					AI-generated summary 				 We propose Lizard, a linearization framework that transforms pretrained Transformer-based Large Language Models (LLMs) into flexible, subquadratic architectures for infinite-context generation. Transformer-based LLMs face significant memory and computational bottlenecks as context lengths increase, due to the quadratic complexity of softmax attention and the growing key-value (KV) cache. Lizard addresses these limitations by introducing a subquadratic attention mechanism that closely approximates softmax attention while preserving the output quality. Unlike previous linearization methods, which are often limited by fixed model structures and therefore exclude gating mechanisms, Lizard incorporates a gating module inspired by recent state-of-the-art linear models. This enables adaptive memory control, supports constant-memory inference, offers strong length generalization, and allows more flexible model design. Lizard combines gated linear attention for global context compression with sliding window attention enhanced by meta memory, forming a hybrid mechanism that captures both long-range dependencies and fine-grained local interactions. Moreover, we introduce a hardware-aware algorithm that accelerates the training speed of our models. Extensive experiments show that Lizard achieves near-lossless recovery of the teacher model's performance across standard language modeling tasks, while significantly outperforming previous linearization methods. On the 5-shot MMLU benchmark, Lizard improves over prior models by 18 points and shows significant improvements on associative recall tasks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 03:30:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2507.09025</guid></item></channel></rss>