<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>12 Foundational AI Model Types</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/795992300839975</link><description>12 Foundational AI Model Types Let’s refresh some fundamentals today to stay fluent in the what we all work with. Here are some of the most popular model types that shape the vast world of AI (with examples in the brackets): 1. LLM - Large Language Model (GPT, LLaMA) -&gt; Large Language Models: A Survey (2402.06196) + history of LLMs: https://www.turingpost.com/t/The%20History%20of%20LLMs It's trained on massive text datasets to understand and generate human language. They are mostly build on Transformer architecture, predicting the next token. LLMs scale by increasing overall parameter count across all components (layers, attention heads, MLPs, etc.) 2. SLM - Small Language Model (TinyLLaMA, Phi models, SmolLM) A Survey of Small Language Models (2410.20011) Lightweight LM optimized for efficiency, low memory use, fast inference, and edge use. SLMs work using the same principles as LLMs 3. VLM - Vision-Language Model (CLIP, Flamingo) -&gt; An Introduction to Vision-Language Modeling...</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/795992300839975</guid></item><item><title>The past year I have been trying to get diffusion models to work for language generation, without having to retrain a LLM from scratch. And recently, we finally succeeded:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Ruurd/491522052497480</link><description>The past year I have been trying to get diffusion models to work for language generation, without having to retrain a LLM from scratch. And recently, we finally succeeded: We introduce "LAD: LoRA-Adapted Denoiser", a method to convert a LLaMA model into a text diffusion model using LoRA finetuning and structured input corruption. 🎯 Try the demo and read the write-up here! https://ruurdkuiper.github.io/tini-lad/ Unlike autoregressive (word-for-word) models like ChatGPT, diffusion models iteratively refine a noised sequence. However, most current diffusion approaches rely on all-parameter retraining and repeatedly remasking tokens, which is costly and slow during both training and inference! 🧠 With LAD: - We can finetune an autoregressive model for diffusive generation in just 10 hours on a single GPU. - Test-time compute is fully adjustable: fewer steps means faster outputs while more steps improve output quality. - Due to our unique noising schedule, remasking is not always needed...</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Ruurd/491522052497480</guid></item><item><title>Having an insanely good medical LLM is pointless if it won’t answer your questions!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/drwlf/878228510592624</link><description>Having an insanely good medical LLM is pointless if it won’t answer your questions! So we’ve made 2 notebook for abliterating any model in order to achieve a good model that will actually help you! The notebooks are made using @ mlabonne ‘s abliteration logic and datasets! Feel free to use them and happy training 😊 https://github.com/dralexlup/LLM-Abliteration See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/drwlf/878228510592624</guid></item><item><title>C/ua Cloud Containers  - Docker for Computer-Use Agents. Zero local setup. Same Computer and Agent interfaces. Scale 1-100 agents instantly.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/dhruv3006/635329388692480</link><description>C/ua Cloud Containers - Docker for Computer-Use Agents. Zero local setup. Same Computer and Agent interfaces. Scale 1-100 agents instantly. Github : https://github.com/trycua/cua Website : https://www.trycua.com See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/dhruv3006/635329388692480</guid></item><item><title>🚀 I'm excited to share a recent update to VisionScout, a system built to help machines do more than just detect — but actually understand what’s happening in a scene.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DawnC/336678978162593</link><description>🚀 I'm excited to share a recent update to VisionScout, a system built to help machines do more than just detect — but actually understand what’s happening in a scene. 🎯 At its core, VisionScout is about deep scene interpretation. It combines the sharp detection of YOLOv8, the semantic awareness of CLIP, the environmental grounding of Places365, and the expressive fluency of Llama 3.2. Together, they deliver more than bounding boxes, they produce rich narratives about layout, lighting, activities, and contextual cues. 🏞️ For example: - CLIP’s zero-shot capability recognizes cultural landmarks without any task-specific training - Places365 helps anchor the scene into one of 365 categories, refining lighting interpretation and spatial understanding. It also assists in distinguishing indoor vs. outdoor scenes and enables lighting condition classification such as “sunset”, “sunrise”, or “indoor commercial” - Llama 3.2 turns structured analysis into human-readable, context-rich...</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DawnC/336678978162593</guid></item><item><title>Hi everyone,</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/jbilcke-hf/300373913700278</link><description>Hi everyone, I've seen some unsuccessful attempts at running Wan2GP inside a Hugging Face Space, which is a shame as it is a great Gradio app! So here is a fork that you can use, with some instructions on how to do this: jbilcke-hf/Wan2GP_you_must_clone_this_space_to_use_it#1 Note : some things like persistent models/storage/custom LoRAs might not be fully working out of the box. If you need those, you might have to dig into the Wan2GP codebase, see how to tweak the storage folder. Happy hacking! See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/jbilcke-hf/300373913700278</guid></item><item><title>RedNote 小红书  just released their first LLM 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/611247032364638</link><description>RedNote 小红书 just released their first LLM 🔥 dots.llm1.base 🪐 a 142B MoE model with only 14B active params. rednote-hilab/dotsllm1-68246aaaaba3363374a8aa7c ✨ Base &amp; Instruct - MIT license ✨ Trained on 11.2T non-synthetic high-quality data ✨ Competitive with Qwen2.5/3 on reasoning, code, alignment See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/611247032364638</guid></item><item><title>I just finished AI Engineering by Chip Huyen. Probably the best resource I’ve seen that covers the full AI stack. People wondering how to shift their careers toward AI might find this very useful.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ArturoNereu/637456411770549</link><description>I just finished AI Engineering by Chip Huyen. Probably the best resource I’ve seen that covers the full AI stack. People wondering how to shift their careers toward AI might find this very useful. I recently shared this list of resources I’ve been using to learn AI: 🔗 https://github.com/ArturoNereu/AI-Study-Group See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ArturoNereu/637456411770549</guid></item><item><title>New models from Qwen 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/473255162200609</link><description>New models from Qwen 🔥 Qwen3-Embedding and Qwen3-Reranker Series just released on the hub by Alibaba Qwen team. ✨ 0.6B/ 4B/ 8B with Apache2.0 ✨ Supports 119 languages 🤯 ✨ Top-tier performance: Leading the MTEB multilingual leaderboard！ Reranker: Qwen/qwen3-reranker-6841b22d0192d7ade9cdefea Embedding: Qwen/qwen3-embedding-6841b2055b99c44d9a4c371f See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/473255162200609</guid></item><item><title>Qwen2.5-Omni is soooo good that people build multimodal reasoning models off of it 🥹</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/361903268457703</link><description>Qwen2.5-Omni is soooo good that people build multimodal reasoning models off of it 🥹 &gt; KE-Team/Ke-Omni-R-3B is open-source audio reasoning model sota on average of benchmarks, based on Qwen/Qwen2.5-Omni-3B 🗣️ &gt; Haoz0206/Omni-R1 is a video reasoning model with pixel level grounding (see below) and it's super competitive ⏯️ based on Qwen/Qwen2.5-Omni-7B See translation</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/361903268457703</guid></item></channel></rss>