<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>One of the hardest challenges in AI safety is finding the right balance: how do we protect people from harm without undermining their agency? This tension is especially visible in conversational systems, where safeguards can sometimes feel more paternalistic than supportive.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/giadap/999915316832908</link><description>One of the hardest challenges in AI safety is finding the right balance: how do we protect people from harm without undermining their agency? This tension is especially visible in conversational systems, where safeguards can sometimes feel more paternalistic than supportive. In my latest piece for Hugging Face, I argue that open source and community-driven approaches offer a promising (though not exclusive) way forward. ✨ Transparency can make safety mechanisms into learning opportunities. ✨ Collaboration with diverse communities makes safeguards more relevant across contexts. ✨ Iteration in the open lets protections evolve rather than freeze into rigid, one-size-fits-all rules. Of course, this isn’t a silver bullet. Top-down safety measures will still be necessary in some cases. But if we only rely on corporate control, we risk building systems that are safe at the expense of trust and autonomy. Read the blog post here: https://huggingface.co/blog/giadap/preserving-agency See...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/giadap/999915316832908</guid></item><item><title>🖤  Probably one of my favorite projects that I've worked on so far, introducing Новояз (Novoyaz).</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ZennyKenny/720018379255407</link><description>🖤 Probably one of my favorite projects that I've worked on so far, introducing Новояз (Novoyaz). 🛠 One of the first acts of the Bolshevik government after the Russian Revolution was the reform and standardization of the Russian language, which at the time had a non-standard and challenging orthography. 📚 Upon its reform the government launched a nationwide campaign called Ликбез (Likbez), which sought to improve literacy in the country (by the way, it worked, bringing the national literacy rate from &lt;20% in the 1920s to &gt;80% by the 1930s). ‼ While this is a remarkable result that should absolutely be celebrated, it's one that has left behind literally hundreds of thousands if not millions of artifacts using pre-reform Russian orthography. 😓 Researchers and historians are working tirelessly to translate these artifacts to modern Russian so that they may be archived and studied but many have told me that. they are doing this BY HAND (!). 💡 I thought, well this is a perfect use case...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ZennyKenny/720018379255407</guid></item><item><title>12 Excellent MCP Servers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/566496725881885</link><description>12 Excellent MCP Servers The family of MCP (Model Context Protocol) servers keeps expanding to bridge agents, models, tools, web, data and apps. Here are 12 useful MCP servers that will help you create convenient agentic ecosystems: 1. Chrome DevTools MCP → https://github.com/ChromeDevTools/chrome-devtools-mcp Lets your coding agent (Gemini, Claude, Cursor, Copilot) control a live Chrome browser with full DevTools access for automation, debugging, and performance analysis 2. Windows-MCP → https://github.com/CursorTouch/Windows-MCP Provides interaction between agents and Windows, handling file navigation, app control, UI actions, QA testing 3. MCPControl → https://github.com/claude-did-this/MCPControl Windows control server for programmatic control of mouse, keyboard, window management, and screen capture 4. MetaMCP → https://github.com/metatool-ai/metamcp A proxy that aggregates multiple MCP servers into one, with middleware support. Works as a standard MCP server for any client 5....</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/566496725881885</guid></item><item><title>Now You Can Edit Word Documents and Excel Spreadsheets With Claude AI and Wan Training Has Arrived. Also tell me what you think about voice quality.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/580682771947064</link><description>Now You Can Edit Word Documents and Excel Spreadsheets With Claude AI and Wan Training Has Arrived. Also tell me what you think about voice quality. https://youtu.be/6cH-6JaBMnM See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/580682771947064</guid></item><item><title>Ring-1T-preview 🔥 1T thinking model released by Ant Group.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/592151236664481</link><description>Ring-1T-preview 🔥 1T thinking model released by Ant Group. inclusionAI/Ring-1T-preview ✨ MoE architecture + 20T tokens + RLVR via ASystem ✨ Strong natural language reasoning (AIME’25: 92.6, close to GPT-5) ✨IMO tests: advanced problem-solving &amp; reasoning See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/AdinaY/592151236664481</guid></item><item><title>Duality AI's latest Kaggle competition was our most difficult one yet! Contestants had to train for Multiclass object detection using data from FalconCloud (you can still use the scenarios  for free here -</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/825230107127104</link><description>Duality AI's latest Kaggle competition was our most difficult one yet! Contestants had to train for Multiclass object detection using data from FalconCloud (you can still use the scenarios for free here - https://tinyurl.com/5n7yhvha , https://tinyurl.com/38ktjfkn ) Duality partnered with @ 3LC and their software for creating better, smaller, faster AI models! The following winners showed skill and perseverance, analyzing and generating targeted data that trains a model to works on real-world data 👏 👏 👏 🥇 1st place: A team consisting of: @ Leo5566 and kaggle user "Ariel__" https://www.kaggle.com/gogoka 🥈 2nd place: @ Moe153 🥉 3rd place: A team consisting of Kaggle users "Kostiantyn Kazanin" ( https://www.kaggle.com/kostya876 ), "Yuriy Greben" ( https://www.kaggle.com/yuriygreben ), "Illya Movchan"( https://www.kaggle.com/illyamovchan ), and "Maryna Borovska"( https://www.kaggle.com/marynaborovska ) Top 10 Honorable mentions include: 🏅@younesbenalia (top 10 2x in a row!)...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/825230107127104</guid></item><item><title>🚀 Big news from XenArcAI!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Parveshiiii/228189451590505</link><description>🚀 Big news from XenArcAI! We’ve just released our new dataset: **Bhagwat‑Gita‑Infinity** 🌸📖 ✨ What’s inside: - Verse‑aligned Sanskrit, Hindi, and English - Clean, structured, and ready for ML/AI projects - Perfect for research, education, and open‑source exploration 🔗 Hugging Face: XenArcAI/Bhagwat-Gita-Infinity Let’s bring timeless wisdom into modern AI together 🙌 See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Parveshiiii/228189451590505</guid></item><item><title>Hey, amazing, awesome people of the beautiful internet 😍🥰</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/hba123/508032894003486</link><description>Hey, amazing, awesome people of the beautiful internet 😍🥰 Distillation has been (from my point of view) a main driving factor for the success of hashtag#LLMs - like distilling the knowledge of an amazing big model (say hashtag#DeepSeekv3, or hashtag#GeminiAI) into yours. Probably, you have done it with minimising a KL divergence, and it somehow worked. Well, not that well, right? 1️⃣ Your model tends to memorise! 2️⃣ Your model might get the right answer, but its reasoning might be flawed. To fix those problems, we rethink distillation and process a new approach! A method that is based on constrained RL that comes with nice theoretical guarantees and excellent performance! Check it out: Rethinking Large Language Model Distillation: A Constrained Markov Decision Process Perspective (2509.22921) Let us do distillation right! Please upvote if you find it useful! See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/hba123/508032894003486</guid></item><item><title>⚡ ColBERT-ko-v1.0 Complete On-device Study: SOTA Korean Retrieval on Mobile</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/yeonseok-zeticai/773315710052361</link><description>⚡ ColBERT-ko-v1.0 Complete On-device Study: SOTA Korean Retrieval on Mobile Major Release: Comprehensive mobile deployment study of yoonjong's ColBERT-ko-v1.0 with detailed performance benchmarks across 50+ mobile devices! 🎯 Model Overview: Architecture: Korean-optimized ColBERT (late interaction) Parameters: 0.1B (compact and efficient) Specialty: Korean document retrieval and semantic search Performance: 1.0 recall@10, 0.966 nDCG@10 on AutoRAGRetrieval Benchmark: Outperforms Jina-ColBERT-v2 on Korean MTEB tasks 📊 Mobile Performance Results: Latency Metrics: NPU (Best): 3.17ms average inference GPU: 11.67ms average CPU: 21.36ms average NPU Advantage: 18.46x speedup over CPU Memory Efficiency: Model Size: 567.89 MB (production optimized) Runtime Memory: 170.87 MB peak consumption Load Range: 4-614 MB across device categories FP32 Memory: 642.65 MB (optional high precision) Accuracy Preservation: - FP16 Precision: 53.51 dB maintained - Quantized Mode: 32.77 dB (available for memory...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/yeonseok-zeticai/773315710052361</guid></item><item><title>Try Banana Zoom an advanced image enhancement web app that lets users select regions of an image for AI-powered upscaling and detail refinement. Using Google’s (nano banana), it analyzes selections, generates context-aware enhancements, and produces high-resolution outputs. Simply drag-and-drop or upload images, make precise or fixed-size selections, and watch improvements in real-time with smooth zoom and pixel-dissolve effects.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/278211210315293</link><description>Try Banana Zoom an advanced image enhancement web app that lets users select regions of an image for AI-powered upscaling and detail refinement. Using Google’s (nano banana), it analyzes selections, generates context-aware enhancements, and produces high-resolution outputs. Simply drag-and-drop or upload images, make precise or fixed-size selections, and watch improvements in real-time with smooth zoom and pixel-dissolve effects. Space / App: prithivMLmods/Banana-Zoom Collection: prithivMLmods/image-gen-apps-diffusion-lastupdated-09-23-68a2f4c5ef3e5e394eacc20a GitHub: https://github.com/prithivsakthiur/banana-zoom Your API will be automatically destroyed once you refresh the app or exit it, so each user's API will be cycled in this way. See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:22:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/prithivMLmods/278211210315293</guid></item></channel></rss>