<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>New DeepSeek-R1-0528 1.65-bit Dynamic GGUF!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/109493636647945</link><description>New DeepSeek-R1-0528 1.65-bit Dynamic GGUF! Run the model locally even easier! Will fit on a 192GB Macbook and run at 7 tokens/s. DeepSeek-R1-0528 GGUFs: unsloth/DeepSeek-R1-0528-GGUF Qwen3-8B DeepSeek-R1-0528 GGUFs: unsloth/DeepSeek-R1-0528-Qwen3-8B-GGUF And read our Guide: https://docs.unsloth.ai/basics/deepseek-r1-0528 See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/109493636647945</guid></item><item><title>🚀 NEW DROP: run your own on-device LLM—in minutes, on any phone</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/yeonseok-zeticai/994151475169260</link><description>🚀 NEW DROP: run your own on-device LLM—in minutes, on any phone Today we’re open-sourcing everything you need to put Qwen3-0.6B straight into a production-ready mobile app: 🎥 Watch Qwen3-0.6B chat in real time on any smartphones! 📊 TPS benchmarks – slides comparing token-per-second across heterogeneous mobile devices 💻 Plug-and-play source – Just Copy &amp; Run the source to your project for Android (Kotlin &amp; Java) and iOS (Swift). 🤞 Cross-platform, one pipeline – ZETIC.MLange auto-tunes kernels for every different devices, we’ve tested. 👨‍💻 Ready for production – swap in your own model, re-benchmark with one command, publish. Get started Just Sign-up and check the playground project, QWEN-0.6B - https://mlange.zetic.ai/p/zetic-example/Qwen3-0.6B We built this to show that cloud-free LLMs are ready today. Dive in, fork it, and tag ZETIC.ai when you launch your own on-device assistant, game NPC, or offline content generator—we’ll spotlight the best projects. See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/yeonseok-zeticai/994151475169260</guid></item><item><title>We just dropped SmolVLA: A Vision-Language-Action Model for Affordable and Efficient Robotics!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danaaubakirova/558502564618988</link><description>We just dropped SmolVLA: A Vision-Language-Action Model for Affordable and Efficient Robotics! check out the blog: https://huggingface.co/blog/smolvla read the technical report: SmolVLA: A Vision-Language-Action Model for Affordable and Efficient Robotics (2506.01844) access the model weights: lerobot/smolvla_base See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danaaubakirova/558502564618988</guid></item><item><title>I built an AI Website: ai-garden.netlify.app</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/VirtualOasis/960727410952690</link><description>I built an AI Website: ai-garden.netlify.app It is a curated garden of AI resources. It's my database for writing and research, organized by category and designed for quick access. Whether you're looking for learning materials, development tools, research papers, or industry news, everything's laid out in a clean, searchable format. Feel free to suggest new resources or improvements - this garden grows better with community input. 🍻 See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/VirtualOasis/960727410952690</guid></item><item><title>Today, we're unveiling two new open-source AI robots! HopeJR for $3,000 &amp; Reachy Mini for $300 🤖🤖🤖</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/clem/522668354429256</link><description>Today, we're unveiling two new open-source AI robots! HopeJR for $3,000 &amp; Reachy Mini for $300 🤖🤖🤖 Let's go open-source AI robotics! See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/clem/522668354429256</guid></item><item><title>Agents &amp; MCP Hackathon Day 1</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/azettl/397733899741459</link><description>Agents &amp; MCP Hackathon Day 1 Before starting with the second night of the Agents &amp; MCP Hackathon, I briefly wanted to share my progress from last night. Not much sleep, but lots of progress! So I managed to build the first MVP version of my custom Gradio component, azettl/gradio_consilium_roundtable ( https://pypi.org/project/gradio-consilium-roundtable/ ). This creates a visual roundtable component for AI consensus discussions. Displays AI participants as avatars positioned around an oval table (poker style!) with animated speech bubbles, thinking states, and real-time discussion updates. Also, I managed to get a rough draft of the Gradio app + MCP server done, but not so much yet that I can share the space with you. You will be able to define your question the AI participants should discuss, decide on the protocol, do role assignments like having a devil's advocate on the table, and define the communication pattern. Lastly, you can decide which AI should be the moderator and how...</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/azettl/397733899741459</guid></item><item><title>🧠 We just implemented Andrej Karpathy's "third paradigm" for LLM learning!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/495839598023200</link><description>🧠 We just implemented Andrej Karpathy's "third paradigm" for LLM learning! System Prompt Learning (SPL) enables LLMs to automatically learn problem-solving strategies from experience, rather than relying on static prompts. 🚀 How it works: Your LLM builds a database of effective strategies, selects the best ones for each problem, and refines them over time based on success rates. 📊 Results across math benchmarks: Arena Hard: 29% → 37.6% (+8.6%) AIME24: 23.33% → 30% (+6.67%) OptILLMBench: 61% → 65% (+4%) The best part? All strategies are human-readable and the system gets progressively better at problem types you use frequently. ✨ Key benefits: 🔄 Cumulative learning over time 📖 Transparent, inspectable strategies 🔌 Works with any OpenAI-compatible API ⚡ Simple integration: just add "spl-" prefix to your model Built as an open-source plugin in optillm. After 500 queries, our system developed 129 strategies and refined 97 of them! This feels like a genuine step toward AI that learns...</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/codelion/495839598023200</guid></item><item><title>HALOOO MY COMMUNITY</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/attackerElvies/415846064784363</link><description>HALOOO MY COMMUNITY</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/attackerElvies/415846064784363</guid></item><item><title>The AI Memory Layer Will Change Everything ‼️</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/shivance/186510046131128</link><description>The AI Memory Layer Will Change Everything ‼️ Why do even the smartest AIs like OpenAI's o3 and GPT-4o, Google's Gemini and Anthropic's Claude forget? In this blog we unpack this challenge and explore how building a real memory into AI will redefine personalization and agent capabilities! https://fullstackagents.substack.com/p/forget-me-not-the-ai-memory-layer See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/shivance/186510046131128</guid></item><item><title>60 followers,</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/ProCreations/446640923874701</link><description>60 followers, yay</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:21:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/ProCreations/446640923874701</guid></item></channel></rss>