<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Learning to Reason under Off-Policy Guidance</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14945</link><description>Recent advances in large reasoning models (LRMs) demonstrate that sophisticated behaviors such as multi-step reasoning and self-reflection can emerge via reinforcement learning (RL) with simple rule-based rewards. However, existing zero-RL approaches are inherently ``on-policy'', limiting learning to a model's own outputs and failing to acquire reasoning abilities beyond its initial capabilities. We introduce LUFFY (Learning to reason Under oFF-policY guidance), a framework that augments zero-RL with off-policy reasoning traces. LUFFY dynamically balances imitation and exploration by combining off-policy demonstrations with on-policy rollouts during training. Notably, we propose policy shaping via regularized importance sampling to avoid superficial and rigid imitation during mixed-policy training. Remarkably, LUFFY achieves an over +7.0 average gain across six math benchmarks and an advantage of over +6.2 points in out-of-distribution tasks. It also substantially surpasses imitation-based supervised fine-tuning (SFT), particularly in generalization. Analysis shows LUFFY not only imitates effectively but also explores beyond demonstrations, offering a scalable path to train generalizable reasoning models with off-policy guidance.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 02:27:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14945</guid></item><item><title>FlowReasoner: Reinforcing Query-Level Meta-Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15257</link><description>This paper proposes a query-level meta-agent named FlowReasoner to automate the design of query-level multi-agent systems, i.e., one system per user query. Our core idea is to incentivize a reasoning-based meta-agent via external execution feedback. Concretely, by distilling DeepSeek R1, we first endow the basic reasoning ability regarding the generation of multi-agent systems to FlowReasoner. Then, we further enhance it via reinforcement learning (RL) with external execution feedback. A multi-purpose reward is designed to guide the RL training from aspects of performance, complexity, and efficiency. In this manner, FlowReasoner is enabled to generate a personalized multi-agent system for each user query via deliberative reasoning. Experiments on both engineering and competition code benchmarks demonstrate the superiority of FlowReasoner. Remarkably, it surpasses o1-mini by 10.52% accuracy across three benchmarks. The code is available at https://github.com/sail-sg/FlowReasoner.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 03:42:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15257</guid></item><item><title>Eagle 2.5: Boosting Long-Context Post-Training for Frontier
  Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15271</link><description>We introduce Eagle 2.5, a family of frontier vision-language models (VLMs) for long-context multimodal learning. Our work addresses the challenges in long video comprehension and high-resolution image understanding, introducing a generalist framework for both tasks. The proposed training framework incorporates Automatic Degrade Sampling and Image Area Preservation, two techniques that preserve contextual integrity and visual details. The framework also includes numerous efficiency optimizations in the pipeline for long-context data training. Finally, we propose Eagle-Video-110K, a novel dataset that integrates both story-level and clip-level annotations, facilitating long-video understanding. Eagle 2.5 demonstrates substantial improvements on long-context multimodal benchmarks, providing a robust solution to the limitations of existing VLMs. Notably, our best model Eagle 2.5-8B achieves 72.4% on Video-MME with 512 input frames, matching the results of top-tier commercial model such as GPT-4o and large-scale open-source models like Qwen2.5-VL-72B and InternVL2.5-78B.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 07:44:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15271</guid></item><item><title>ToolRL: Reward is All Tool Learning Needs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13958</link><description>Current Large Language Models (LLMs) often undergo supervised fine-tuning (SFT) to acquire tool use capabilities. However, SFT struggles to generalize to unfamiliar or complex tool use scenarios. Recent advancements in reinforcement learning (RL), particularly with R1-like models, have demonstrated promising reasoning and generalization abilities. Yet, reward design for tool use presents unique challenges: multiple tools may be invoked with diverse parameters, and coarse-grained reward signals, such as answer matching, fail to offer the finegrained feedback required for effective learning. In this work, we present the first comprehensive study on reward design for tool selection and application tasks within the RL paradigm. We systematically explore a wide range of reward strategies, analyzing their types, scales, granularity, and temporal dynamics. Building on these insights, we propose a principled reward design tailored for tool use tasks and apply it to train LLMs using Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO). Empirical evaluations across diverse benchmarks demonstrate that our approach yields robust, scalable, and stable training, achieving a 17% improvement over base models and a 15% gain over SFT models. These results highlight the critical role of thoughtful reward design in enhancing the tool use capabilities and generalization performance of LLMs. All the codes are released to facilitate future research.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 03:07:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13958</guid></item><item><title>SphereDiff: Tuning-free Omnidirectional Panoramic Image and Video
  Generation via Spherical Latent Representation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14396</link><description>The increasing demand for AR/VR applications has highlighted the need for high-quality 360-degree panoramic content. However, generating high-quality 360-degree panoramic images and videos remains a challenging task due to the severe distortions introduced by equirectangular projection (ERP). Existing approaches either fine-tune pretrained diffusion models on limited ERP datasets or attempt tuning-free methods that still rely on ERP latent representations, leading to discontinuities near the poles. In this paper, we introduce SphereDiff, a novel approach for seamless 360-degree panoramic image and video generation using state-of-the-art diffusion models without additional tuning. We define a spherical latent representation that ensures uniform distribution across all perspectives, mitigating the distortions inherent in ERP. We extend MultiDiffusion to spherical latent space and propose a spherical latent sampling method to enable direct use of pretrained diffusion models. Moreover, we introduce distortion-aware weighted averaging to further improve the generation quality in the projection process. Our method outperforms existing approaches in generating 360-degree panoramic content while maintaining high fidelity, making it a robust solution for immersive AR/VR applications. The code is available here. https://github.com/pmh9960/SphereDiff</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 02:20:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14396</guid></item><item><title>StyleMe3D: Stylization with Disentangled Priors by Multiple Encoders on
  3D Gaussians</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15281</link><description>3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) excels in photorealistic scene reconstruction but struggles with stylized scenarios (e.g., cartoons, games) due to fragmented textures, semantic misalignment, and limited adaptability to abstract aesthetics. We propose StyleMe3D, a holistic framework for 3D GS style transfer that integrates multi-modal style conditioning, multi-level semantic alignment, and perceptual quality enhancement. Our key insights include: (1) optimizing only RGB attributes preserves geometric integrity during stylization; (2) disentangling low-, medium-, and high-level semantics is critical for coherent style transfer; (3) scalability across isolated objects and complex scenes is essential for practical deployment. StyleMe3D introduces four novel components: Dynamic Style Score Distillation (DSSD), leveraging Stable Diffusion's latent space for semantic alignment; Contrastive Style Descriptor (CSD) for localized, content-aware texture transfer; Simultaneously Optimized Scale (SOS) to decouple style details and structural coherence; and 3D Gaussian Quality Assessment (3DG-QA), a differentiable aesthetic prior trained on human-rated data to suppress artifacts and enhance visual harmony. Evaluated on NeRF synthetic dataset (objects) and tandt db (scenes) datasets, StyleMe3D outperforms state-of-the-art methods in preserving geometric details (e.g., carvings on sculptures) and ensuring stylistic consistency across scenes (e.g., coherent lighting in landscapes), while maintaining real-time rendering. This work bridges photorealistic 3D GS and artistic stylization, unlocking applications in gaming, virtual worlds, and digital art.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 05:48:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15281</guid></item><item><title>X-Teaming: Multi-Turn Jailbreaks and Defenses with Adaptive Multi-Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13203</link><description>Multi-turn interactions with language models (LMs) pose critical safety risks, as harmful intent can be strategically spread across exchanges. Yet, the vast majority of prior work has focused on single-turn safety, while adaptability and diversity remain among the key challenges of multi-turn red-teaming. To address these challenges, we present X-Teaming, a scalable framework that systematically explores how seemingly harmless interactions escalate into harmful outcomes and generates corresponding attack scenarios. X-Teaming employs collaborative agents for planning, attack optimization, and verification, achieving state-of-the-art multi-turn jailbreak effectiveness and diversity with success rates up to 98.1% across representative leading open-weight and closed-source models. In particular, X-Teaming achieves a 96.2% attack success rate against the latest Claude 3.7 Sonnet model, which has been considered nearly immune to single-turn attacks. Building on X-Teaming, we introduce XGuard-Train, an open-source multi-turn safety training dataset that is 20x larger than the previous best resource, comprising 30K interactive jailbreaks, designed to enable robust multi-turn safety alignment for LMs. Our work offers essential tools and insights for mitigating sophisticated conversational attacks, advancing the multi-turn safety of LMs.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 02:43:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13203</guid></item><item><title>UFO2: The Desktop AgentOS</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14603</link><description>Recent Computer-Using Agents (CUAs), powered by multimodal large language models (LLMs), offer a promising direction for automating complex desktop workflows through natural language. However, most existing CUAs remain conceptual prototypes, hindered by shallow OS integration, fragile screenshot-based interaction, and disruptive execution.   We present UFO2, a multiagent AgentOS for Windows desktops that elevates CUAs into practical, system-level automation. UFO2 features a centralized HostAgent for task decomposition and coordination, alongside a collection of application-specialized AppAgent equipped with native APIs, domain-specific knowledge, and a unified GUI--API action layer. This architecture enables robust task execution while preserving modularity and extensibility. A hybrid control detection pipeline fuses Windows UI Automation (UIA) with vision-based parsing to support diverse interface styles. Runtime efficiency is further enhanced through speculative multi-action planning, reducing per-step LLM overhead. Finally, a Picture-in-Picture (PiP) interface enables automation within an isolated virtual desktop, allowing agents and users to operate concurrently without interference.   We evaluate UFO2 across over 20 real-world Windows applications, demonstrating substantial improvements in robustness and execution accuracy over prior CUAs. Our results show that deep OS integration unlocks a scalable path toward reliable, user-aligned desktop automation.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 02:11:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14603</guid></item><item><title>Seeing from Another Perspective: Evaluating Multi-View Understanding in
  MLLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15280</link><description>Multi-view understanding, the ability to reconcile visual information across diverse viewpoints for effective navigation, manipulation, and 3D scene comprehension, is a fundamental challenge in Multi-Modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) to be used as embodied agents. While recent MLLMs have shown impressive advances in high-level reasoning and planning, they frequently fall short when confronted with multi-view geometric consistency and cross-view correspondence. To comprehensively evaluate the challenges of MLLMs in multi-view scene reasoning, we propose All-Angles Bench, a benchmark of over 2,100 human carefully annotated multi-view question-answer pairs across 90 diverse real-world scenes. Our six tasks (counting, attribute identification, relative distance, relative direction, object manipulation, and camera pose estimation) specifically test model's geometric correspondence and the capacity to align information consistently across views. Our extensive experiments, benchmark on 27 representative MLLMs including Gemini-2.0-Flash, Claude-3.7-Sonnet, and GPT-4o against human evaluators reveals a substantial performance gap, indicating that current MLLMs remain far from human-level proficiency. Through in-depth analysis, we show that MLLMs are particularly underperforming under two aspects: (1) cross-view correspondence for partially occluded views and (2) establishing the coarse camera poses. These findings highlight the necessity of domain-specific refinements or modules that embed stronger multi-view awareness. We believe that our All-Angles Bench offers valuable insights and contribute to bridging the gap between MLLMs and human-level multi-view understanding. The project and benchmark are publicly available at https://danielchyeh.github.io/All-Angles-Bench/.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 03:19:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15280</guid></item><item><title>InfiGUI-R1: Advancing Multimodal GUI Agents from Reactive Actors to
  Deliberative Reasoners</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14239</link><description>Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have powered Graphical User Interface (GUI) Agents, showing promise in automating tasks on computing devices. Recent works have begun exploring reasoning in GUI tasks with encouraging results. However, many current approaches rely on manually designed reasoning templates, which may result in reasoning that is not sufficiently robust and adaptive for complex GUI environments. Meanwhile, some existing agents continue to operate as Reactive Actors, relying primarily on implicit reasoning that may lack sufficient depth for GUI tasks demanding planning and error recovery. We argue that advancing these agents requires a shift from reactive acting towards acting based on deliberate reasoning. To facilitate this transformation, we introduce InfiGUI-R1, an MLLM-based GUI agent developed through our Actor2Reasoner framework, a reasoning-centric, two-stage training approach designed to progressively evolve agents from Reactive Actors to Deliberative Reasoners. The first stage, Reasoning Injection, focuses on establishing a basic reasoner. We employ Spatial Reasoning Distillation to transfer cross-modal spatial reasoning capabilities from teacher models to MLLMs through trajectories with explicit reasoning steps, enabling models to integrate GUI visual-spatial information with logical reasoning before action generation. The second stage, Deliberation Enhancement, refines the basic reasoner into a deliberative one using Reinforcement Learning. This stage introduces two approaches: Sub-goal Guidance, which rewards models for generating accurate intermediate sub-goals, and Error Recovery Scenario Construction, which creates failure-and-recovery training scenarios from identified prone-to-error steps. Experimental results show InfiGUI-R1 achieves strong performance in GUI grounding and trajectory tasks. Resources at https://github.com/Reallm-Labs/InfiGUI-R1.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 03:56:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14239</guid></item><item><title>LeetCodeDataset: A Temporal Dataset for Robust Evaluation and Efficient
  Training of Code LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14655</link><description>We introduce LeetCodeDataset, a high-quality benchmark for evaluating and training code-generation models, addressing two key challenges in LLM research: the lack of reasoning-focused coding benchmarks and self-contained training testbeds. By curating LeetCode Python problems with rich metadata, broad coverage, 100+ test cases per problem, and temporal splits (pre/post July 2024), our dataset enables contamination-free evaluation and efficient supervised fine-tuning (SFT). Experiments show reasoning models significantly outperform non-reasoning counterparts, while SFT with only 2.6K model-generated solutions achieves performance comparable to 110K-sample counterparts. The dataset and evaluation framework are available on Hugging Face and Github.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 03:16:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14655</guid></item><item><title>LearnAct: Few-Shot Mobile GUI Agent with a Unified Demonstration
  Benchmark</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13805</link><description>Mobile GUI agents show promise in automating tasks but face generalization challenges in diverse real-world scenarios. Traditional approaches using pre-training or fine-tuning with massive datasets struggle with the diversity of mobile applications and user-specific tasks. We propose enhancing mobile GUI agent capabilities through human demonstrations, focusing on improving performance in unseen scenarios rather than pursuing universal generalization through larger datasets. To realize this paradigm, we introduce LearnGUI, the first comprehensive dataset specifically designed for studying demonstration-based learning in mobile GUI agents, comprising 2,252 offline tasks and 101 online tasks with high-quality human demonstrations. We further develop LearnAct, a sophisticated multi-agent framework that automatically extracts knowledge from demonstrations to enhance task completion. This framework integrates three specialized agents: DemoParser for knowledge extraction, KnowSeeker for relevant knowledge retrieval, and ActExecutor for demonstration-enhanced task execution. Our experimental results show significant performance gains in both offline and online evaluations. In offline assessments, a single demonstration improves model performance, increasing Gemini-1.5-Pro's accuracy from 19.3% to 51.7%. In online evaluations, our framework enhances UI-TARS-7B-SFT's task success rate from 18.1% to 32.8%. LearnAct framework and LearnGUI benchmark establish demonstration-based learning as a promising direction for more adaptable, personalized, and deployable mobile GUI agents.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 02:44:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13805</guid></item><item><title>LookingGlass: Generative Anamorphoses via Laplacian Pyramid Warping</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.08902</link><description>Anamorphosis refers to a category of images that are intentionally distorted, making them unrecognizable when viewed directly. Their true form only reveals itself when seen from a specific viewpoint, which can be through some catadioptric device like a mirror or a lens. While the construction of these mathematical devices can be traced back to as early as the 17th century, they are only interpretable when viewed from a specific vantage point and tend to lose meaning when seen normally. In this paper, we revisit these famous optical illusions with a generative twist. With the help of latent rectified flow models, we propose a method to create anamorphic images that still retain a valid interpretation when viewed directly. To this end, we introduce Laplacian Pyramid Warping, a frequency-aware image warping technique key to generating high-quality visuals. Our work extends Visual Anagrams (arXiv:2311.17919) to latent space models and to a wider range of spatial transforms, enabling the creation of novel generative perceptual illusions.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 06:29:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.08902</guid></item><item><title>DRAGON: Distributional Rewards Optimize Diffusion Generative Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15217</link><description>We present Distributional RewArds for Generative OptimizatioN (DRAGON), a versatile framework for fine-tuning media generation models towards a desired outcome. Compared with traditional reinforcement learning with human feedback (RLHF) or pairwise preference approaches such as direct preference optimization (DPO), DRAGON is more flexible. It can optimize reward functions that evaluate either individual examples or distributions of them, making it compatible with a broad spectrum of instance-wise, instance-to-distribution, and distribution-to-distribution rewards. Leveraging this versatility, we construct novel reward functions by selecting an encoder and a set of reference examples to create an exemplar distribution. When cross-modality encoders such as CLAP are used, the reference examples may be of a different modality (e.g., text versus audio). Then, DRAGON gathers online and on-policy generations, scores them to construct a positive demonstration set and a negative set, and leverages the contrast between the two sets to maximize the reward. For evaluation, we fine-tune an audio-domain text-to-music diffusion model with 20 different reward functions, including a custom music aesthetics model, CLAP score, Vendi diversity, and Frechet audio distance (FAD). We further compare instance-wise (per-song) and full-dataset FAD settings while ablating multiple FAD encoders and reference sets. Over all 20 target rewards, DRAGON achieves an 81.45% average win rate. Moreover, reward functions based on exemplar sets indeed enhance generations and are comparable to model-based rewards. With an appropriate exemplar set, DRAGON achieves a 60.95% human-voted music quality win rate without training on human preference annotations. As such, DRAGON exhibits a new approach to designing and optimizing reward functions for improving human-perceived quality. Sound examples at https://ml-dragon.github.io/web.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 03:37:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15217</guid></item><item><title>EasyEdit2: An Easy-to-use Steering Framework for Editing Large Language
  Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15133</link><description>In this paper, we introduce EasyEdit2, a framework designed to enable plug-and-play adjustability for controlling Large Language Model (LLM) behaviors. EasyEdit2 supports a wide range of test-time interventions, including safety, sentiment, personality, reasoning patterns, factuality, and language features. Unlike its predecessor, EasyEdit2 features a new architecture specifically designed for seamless model steering. It comprises key modules such as the steering vector generator and the steering vector applier, which enable automatic generation and application of steering vectors to influence the model's behavior without modifying its parameters. One of the main advantages of EasyEdit2 is its ease of use-users do not need extensive technical knowledge. With just a single example, they can effectively guide and adjust the model's responses, making precise control both accessible and efficient. Empirically, we report model steering performance across different LLMs, demonstrating the effectiveness of these techniques. We have released the source code on GitHub at https://github.com/zjunlp/EasyEdit along with a demonstration notebook. In addition, we provide a demo video at https://zjunlp.github.io/project/EasyEdit2/video for a quick introduction.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 06:42:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15133</guid></item><item><title>RainbowPlus: Enhancing Adversarial Prompt Generation via Evolutionary
  Quality-Diversity Search</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15047</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) exhibit remarkable capabilities but are susceptible to adversarial prompts that exploit vulnerabilities to produce unsafe or biased outputs. Existing red-teaming methods often face scalability challenges, resource-intensive requirements, or limited diversity in attack strategies. We propose RainbowPlus, a novel red-teaming framework rooted in evolutionary computation, enhancing adversarial prompt generation through an adaptive quality-diversity (QD) search that extends classical evolutionary algorithms like MAP-Elites with innovations tailored for language models. By employing a multi-element archive to store diverse high-quality prompts and a comprehensive fitness function to evaluate multiple prompts concurrently, RainbowPlus overcomes the constraints of single-prompt archives and pairwise comparisons in prior QD methods like Rainbow Teaming. Experiments comparing RainbowPlus to QD methods across six benchmark datasets and four open-source LLMs demonstrate superior attack success rate (ASR) and diversity (Diverse-Score approx 0.84), generating up to 100 times more unique prompts (e.g., 10,418 vs. 100 for Ministral-8B-Instruct-2410). Against nine state-of-the-art methods on the HarmBench dataset with twelve LLMs (ten open-source, two closed-source), RainbowPlus achieves an average ASR of 81.1%, surpassing AutoDAN-Turbo by 3.9%, and is 9 times faster (1.45 vs. 13.50 hours). Our open-source implementation fosters further advancements in LLM safety, offering a scalable tool for vulnerability assessment. Code and resources are publicly available at https://github.com/knoveleng/rainbowplus, supporting reproducibility and future research in LLM red-teaming.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 02:17:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15047</guid></item><item><title>TAPIP3D: Tracking Any Point in Persistent 3D Geometry</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14717</link><description>We introduce TAPIP3D, a novel approach for long-term 3D point tracking in monocular RGB and RGB-D videos. TAPIP3D represents videos as camera-stabilized spatio-temporal feature clouds, leveraging depth and camera motion information to lift 2D video features into a 3D world space where camera motion is effectively canceled. TAPIP3D iteratively refines multi-frame 3D motion estimates within this stabilized representation, enabling robust tracking over extended periods. To manage the inherent irregularities of 3D point distributions, we propose a Local Pair Attention mechanism. This 3D contextualization strategy effectively exploits spatial relationships in 3D, forming informative feature neighborhoods for precise 3D trajectory estimation. Our 3D-centric approach significantly outperforms existing 3D point tracking methods and even enhances 2D tracking accuracy compared to conventional 2D pixel trackers when accurate depth is available. It supports inference in both camera coordinates (i.e., unstabilized) and world coordinates, and our results demonstrate that compensating for camera motion improves tracking performance. Our approach replaces the conventional 2D square correlation neighborhoods used in prior 2D and 3D trackers, leading to more robust and accurate results across various 3D point tracking benchmarks. Project Page: https://tapip3d.github.io</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 04:55:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14717</guid></item><item><title>An LMM for Efficient Video Understanding via Reinforced Compression of
  Video Cubes</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15270</link><description>Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) uniformly perceive video frames, creating computational inefficiency for videos with inherently varying temporal information density. This paper present Quicksviewer, an LMM with new perceiving paradigm that partitions a video of nonuniform density into varying cubes using Gumbel Softmax, followed by a unified resampling for each cube to achieve efficient video understanding. This simple and intuitive approach dynamically compress video online based on its temporal density, significantly reducing spatiotemporal redundancy (overall 45times compression rate), while enabling efficient training with large receptive field. We train the model from a language backbone through three progressive stages, each incorporating lengthy videos on average of 420s/1fps thanks to the perceiving efficiency. With only 0.8M total video-text samples for training, our model outperforms the direct baseline employing a fixed partitioning strategy by a maximum of 8.72 in accuracy, demonstrating the effectiveness in performance. On Video-MME, Quicksviewer achieves SOTA under modest sequence lengths using just up to 5\% of tokens per frame required by baselines. With this paradigm, scaling up the number of input frames reveals a clear power law of the model capabilities. It is also empirically verified that the segments generated by the cubing network can help for analyzing continuous events in videos.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 08:09:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.15270</guid></item><item><title>NEMOTRON-CROSSTHINK: Scaling Self-Learning beyond Math Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13941</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown strong reasoning capabilities, particularly when enhanced through Reinforcement Learning (RL). While prior work has successfully applied RL to mathematical reasoning -- where rules and correctness are well-defined -- generalizing these methods to broader reasoning domains remains challenging due to limited data, the lack of verifiable reward structures, and diverse task requirements. In this work, we propose NEMOTRON-CROSSTHINK, a framework that systematically incorporates multi-domain corpora, including both synthetic and real-world question-answer pairs, into RL training to improve generalization across diverse reasoning tasks. NEMOTRON-CROSSTHINK addresses key challenges by (1) incorporating data from varied sources spanning STEM, humanities, social sciences, etc.; (2) applying structured templates (e.g., multiple-choice and open-ended) to control answer-space complexity; (3) filtering for verifiable answers; and (4) optimizing data blending strategies that utilizes data from multiple sources effectively. Our approach enables scalable and verifiable reward modeling beyond mathematics and demonstrates improved accuracies on both math (MATH-500: +30.1%, AMC23:+27.5%) and non-math reasoning benchmarks (MMLU-PRO: +12.8%, GPQA-DIAMOND: +11.3%, AGIEVAL: +15.1%, SUPERGPQA: +3.8%). Moreover, NEMOTRON-CROSSTHINK exhibits significantly improved response efficiency -- using 28% fewer tokens for correct answers -- highlighting more focused and effective reasoning. Through NEMOTRON-CROSSTHINK, we demonstrate that integrating multi-domain, multi-format data in RL leads to more accurate, efficient, and generalizable LLMs.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 01:58:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13941</guid></item><item><title>Uni3C: Unifying Precisely 3D-Enhanced Camera and Human Motion Controls
  for Video Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14899</link><description>Camera and human motion controls have been extensively studied for video generation, but existing approaches typically address them separately, suffering from limited data with high-quality annotations for both aspects. To overcome this, we present Uni3C, a unified 3D-enhanced framework for precise control of both camera and human motion in video generation. Uni3C includes two key contributions. First, we propose a plug-and-play control module trained with a frozen video generative backbone, PCDController, which utilizes unprojected point clouds from monocular depth to achieve accurate camera control. By leveraging the strong 3D priors of point clouds and the powerful capacities of video foundational models, PCDController shows impressive generalization, performing well regardless of whether the inference backbone is frozen or fine-tuned. This flexibility enables different modules of Uni3C to be trained in specific domains, i.e., either camera control or human motion control, reducing the dependency on jointly annotated data. Second, we propose a jointly aligned 3D world guidance for the inference phase that seamlessly integrates both scenic point clouds and SMPL-X characters to unify the control signals for camera and human motion, respectively. Extensive experiments confirm that PCDController enjoys strong robustness in driving camera motion for fine-tuned backbones of video generation. Uni3C substantially outperforms competitors in both camera controllability and human motion quality. Additionally, we collect tailored validation sets featuring challenging camera movements and human actions to validate the effectiveness of our method.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 09:00:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.14899</guid></item></channel></rss>