<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Cube: A Roblox View of 3D Intelligence</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15475</link><description>Foundation models trained on vast amounts of data have demonstrated remarkable reasoning and generation capabilities in the domains of text, images, audio and video. Our goal at Roblox is to build such a foundation model for 3D intelligence, a model that can support developers in producing all aspects of a Roblox experience, from generating 3D objects and scenes to rigging characters for animation to producing programmatic scripts describing object behaviors. We discuss three key design requirements for such a 3D foundation model and then present our first step towards building such a model. We expect that 3D geometric shapes will be a core data type and describe our solution for 3D shape tokenizer. We show how our tokenization scheme can be used in applications for text-to-shape generation, shape-to-text generation and text-to-scene generation. We demonstrate how these applications can collaborate with existing large language models (LLMs) to perform scene analysis and reasoning. We conclude with a discussion outlining our path to building a fully unified foundation model for 3D intelligence.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 02:27:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15475</guid></item><item><title>TULIP: Towards Unified Language-Image Pretraining</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15485</link><description>Despite the recent success of image-text contrastive models like CLIP and SigLIP, these models often struggle with vision-centric tasks that demand high-fidelity image understanding, such as counting, depth estimation, and fine-grained object recognition. These models, by performing language alignment, tend to prioritize high-level semantics over visual understanding, weakening their image understanding. On the other hand, vision-focused models are great at processing visual information but struggle to understand language, limiting their flexibility for language-driven tasks. In this work, we introduce TULIP, an open-source, drop-in replacement for existing CLIP-like models. Our method leverages generative data augmentation, enhanced image-image and text-text contrastive learning, and image/text reconstruction regularization to learn fine-grained visual features while preserving global semantic alignment. Our approach, scaling to over 1B parameters, outperforms existing state-of-the-art (SOTA) models across multiple benchmarks, establishing a new SOTA zero-shot performance on ImageNet-1K, delivering up to a 2times enhancement over SigLIP on RxRx1 in linear probing for few-shot classification, and improving vision-language models, achieving over 3times higher scores than SigLIP on MMVP. Our code/checkpoints are available at https://tulip-berkeley.github.io</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 02:31:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15485</guid></item><item><title>Temporal Regularization Makes Your Video Generator Stronger</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15417</link><description>Temporal quality is a critical aspect of video generation, as it ensures consistent motion and realistic dynamics across frames. However, achieving high temporal coherence and diversity remains challenging. In this work, we explore temporal augmentation in video generation for the first time, and introduce FluxFlow for initial investigation, a strategy designed to enhance temporal quality. Operating at the data level, FluxFlow applies controlled temporal perturbations without requiring architectural modifications. Extensive experiments on UCF-101 and VBench benchmarks demonstrate that FluxFlow significantly improves temporal coherence and diversity across various video generation models, including U-Net, DiT, and AR-based architectures, while preserving spatial fidelity. These findings highlight the potential of temporal augmentation as a simple yet effective approach to advancing video generation quality.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 03:40:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15417</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Personalization of Quantized Diffusion Model without
  Backpropagation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.14868</link><description>Diffusion models have shown remarkable performance in image synthesis, but they demand extensive computational and memory resources for training, fine-tuning and inference. Although advanced quantization techniques have successfully minimized memory usage for inference, training and fine-tuning these quantized models still require large memory possibly due to dequantization for accurate computation of gradients and/or backpropagation for gradient-based algorithms. However, memory-efficient fine-tuning is particularly desirable for applications such as personalization that often must be run on edge devices like mobile phones with private data. In this work, we address this challenge by quantizing a diffusion model with personalization via Textual Inversion and by leveraging a zeroth-order optimization on personalization tokens without dequantization so that it does not require gradient and activation storage for backpropagation that consumes considerable memory. Since a gradient estimation using zeroth-order optimization is quite noisy for a single or a few images in personalization, we propose to denoise the estimated gradient by projecting it onto a subspace that is constructed with the past history of the tokens, dubbed Subspace Gradient. In addition, we investigated the influence of text embedding in image generation, leading to our proposed time steps sampling, dubbed Partial Uniform Timestep Sampling for sampling with effective diffusion timesteps. Our method achieves comparable performance to prior methods in image and text alignment scores for personalizing Stable Diffusion with only forward passes while reducing training memory demand up to 8.2times.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 04:55:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.14868</guid></item><item><title>DeepMesh: Auto-Regressive Artist-mesh Creation with Reinforcement
  Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15265</link><description>Triangle meshes play a crucial role in 3D applications for efficient manipulation and rendering. While auto-regressive methods generate structured meshes by predicting discrete vertex tokens, they are often constrained by limited face counts and mesh incompleteness. To address these challenges, we propose DeepMesh, a framework that optimizes mesh generation through two key innovations: (1) an efficient pre-training strategy incorporating a novel tokenization algorithm, along with improvements in data curation and processing, and (2) the introduction of Reinforcement Learning (RL) into 3D mesh generation to achieve human preference alignment via Direct Preference Optimization (DPO). We design a scoring standard that combines human evaluation with 3D metrics to collect preference pairs for DPO, ensuring both visual appeal and geometric accuracy. Conditioned on point clouds and images, DeepMesh generates meshes with intricate details and precise topology, outperforming state-of-the-art methods in both precision and quality. Project page: https://zhaorw02.github.io/DeepMesh/</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 04:52:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15265</guid></item><item><title>ViSpeak: Visual Instruction Feedback in Streaming Videos</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.12769</link><description>Recent advances in Large Multi-modal Models (LMMs) are primarily focused on offline video understanding. Instead, streaming video understanding poses great challenges to recent models due to its time-sensitive, omni-modal and interactive characteristics. In this work, we aim to extend the streaming video understanding from a new perspective and propose a novel task named Visual Instruction Feedback in which models should be aware of visual contents and learn to extract instructions from them. For example, when users wave their hands to agents, agents should recognize the gesture and start conversations with welcome information. Thus, following instructions in visual modality greatly enhances user-agent interactions. To facilitate research, we define seven key subtasks highly relevant to visual modality and collect the ViSpeak-Instruct dataset for training and the ViSpeak-Bench for evaluation. Further, we propose the ViSpeak model, which is a SOTA streaming video understanding LMM with GPT-4o-level performance on various streaming video understanding benchmarks. After finetuning on our ViSpeak-Instruct dataset, ViSpeak is equipped with basic visual instruction feedback ability, serving as a solid baseline for future research.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 02:18:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.12769</guid></item><item><title>STEVE: AStep Verification Pipeline for Computer-use Agent Training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.12532</link><description>Developing AI agents to autonomously manipulate graphical user interfaces is a long challenging task. Recent advances in data scaling law inspire us to train computer-use agents with a scaled instruction set, yet using behavior cloning to train agents still requires immense high-quality trajectories. To meet the scalability need, we designed STEVE, a step verification pipeline for computer-use agent training. First, we establish a large instruction set for computer-use agents and collect trajectory data with some suboptimal agents. GPT-4o is used to verify the correctness of each step in the trajectories based on the screens before and after the action execution, assigning each step with a binary label. Last, we adopt the Kahneman and Tversky Optimization to optimize the agent from the binary stepwise labels. Extensive experiments manifest that our agent outperforms supervised finetuning by leveraging both positive and negative actions within a trajectory. Also, STEVE enables us to train a 7B vision-language model as a computer-use agent, achieving leading performance in the challenging live desktop environment WinAgentArena with great efficiency at a reduced cost. Code and data: https://github.com/FanbinLu/STEVE.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 03:08:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.12532</guid></item><item><title>MusicInfuser: Making Video Diffusion Listen and Dance</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.14505</link><description>We introduce MusicInfuser, an approach for generating high-quality dance videos that are synchronized to a specified music track. Rather than attempting to design and train a new multimodal audio-video model, we show how existing video diffusion models can be adapted to align with musical inputs by introducing lightweight music-video cross-attention and a low-rank adapter. Unlike prior work requiring motion capture data, our approach fine-tunes only on dance videos. MusicInfuser achieves high-quality music-driven video generation while preserving the flexibility and generative capabilities of the underlying models. We introduce an evaluation framework using Video-LLMs to assess multiple dimensions of dance generation quality. The project page and code are available at https://susunghong.github.io/MusicInfuser.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 04:09:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.14505</guid></item><item><title>ELTEX: A Framework for Domain-Driven Synthetic Data Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15055</link><description>We present ELTEX (Efficient LLM Token Extraction), a domain-driven framework for generating high-quality synthetic training data in specialized domains. While Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown impressive general capabilities, their performance in specialized domains like cybersecurity remains limited by the scarcity of domain-specific training data. ELTEX addresses this challenge by systematically integrating explicit domain indicator extraction with dynamic prompting to preserve critical domain knowledge throughout the generation process. We demonstrate ELTEX's effectiveness in the context of blockchain-related cyberattack detection, where we fine-tune Gemma-2B using various combinations of real and ELTEX-generated data. Our results show that the ELTEX-enhanced model achieves performance competitive with GPT-4 across both standard classification metrics and uncertainty calibration, while requiring significantly fewer computational resources. We release a curated synthetic dataset of social media texts for cyberattack detection in blockchain. Our work demonstrates that domain-driven synthetic data generation can effectively bridge the performance gap between resource-efficient models and larger architectures in specialized domains.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 04:16:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15055</guid></item></channel></rss>