<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Hala Technical Report: Building Arabic-Centric Instruction &amp; Translation
  Models at Scale</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14008</link><description>Hala, a family of Arabic-centric instruction and translation models, achieves state-of-the-art results using a translate-and-tune pipeline, slerp merging, and fine-tuning on high-quality bilingual supervision.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present Hala, a family of Arabic-centric instruction and translation models built with our translate-and-tune pipeline. We first compress a strong ARleftrightarrowEN teacher to FP8 (yielding sim2times higher throughput with no quality loss) and use it to create high-fidelity bilingual supervision. A lightweight language model LFM2-1.2B is then fine-tuned on this data and used to translate high-quality English instruction sets into Arabic, producing a million-scale corpus tailored to instruction following. We train Hala models at 350M, 700M, 1.2B, and 9B parameters, and apply slerp merging to balance Arabic specialization with base-model strengths. On Arabic-centric benchmarks, Hala achieves state-of-the-art results within both the "nano" (leq2B) and "small" (7-9B) categories, outperforming their bases. We release models, data, evaluation, and recipes to accelerate research in Arabic NLP.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 07:37:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14008</guid></item><item><title>SAIL-VL2 Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14033</link><description>SAIL-VL2, a vision-language foundation model, achieves state-of-the-art performance across diverse benchmarks through data curation, progressive training, and sparse MoE architecture.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce SAIL-VL2, an open-suite vision-language foundation model (LVM) for comprehensive multimodal understanding and reasoning. As the successor to SAIL-VL, SAIL-VL2 achieves state-of-the-art performance at the 2B and 8B parameter scales across diverse image and video benchmarks, demonstrating strong capabilities from fine-grained perception to complex reasoning. Three core innovations drive its effectiveness. First, a large-scale data curation pipeline with scoring and filtering strategies enhances both quality and distribution across captioning, OCR, QA, and video data, improving training efficiency. Second, a progressive training framework begins with a powerful pre-trained vision encoder (SAIL-ViT), advances through multimodal pre-training, and culminates in a thinking-fusion SFT-RL hybrid paradigm that systematically strengthens model capabilities. Third, architectural advances extend beyond dense LLMs to efficient sparse Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) designs. With these contributions, SAIL-VL2 demonstrates competitive performance across 106 datasets and achieves state-of-the-art results on challenging reasoning benchmarks such as MMMU and MathVista. Furthermore, on the OpenCompass leaderboard, SAIL-VL2-2B ranks first among officially released open-source models under the 4B parameter scale, while serving as an efficient and extensible foundation for the open-source multimodal community.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:09:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14033</guid></item><item><title>PANORAMA: The Rise of Omnidirectional Vision in the Embodied AI Era</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.12989</link><description>Recent advancements in omnidirectional vision, driven by industrial and academic interest, have led to breakthroughs in generation, perception, and understanding, with the proposal of a new system architecture called PANORAMA.  					AI-generated summary 				 Omnidirectional vision, using 360-degree vision to understand the environment, has become increasingly critical across domains like robotics, industrial inspection, and environmental monitoring. Compared to traditional pinhole vision, omnidirectional vision provides holistic environmental awareness, significantly enhancing the completeness of scene perception and the reliability of decision-making. However, foundational research in this area has historically lagged behind traditional pinhole vision. This talk presents an emerging trend in the embodied AI era: the rapid development of omnidirectional vision, driven by growing industrial demand and academic interest. We highlight recent breakthroughs in omnidirectional generation, omnidirectional perception, omnidirectional understanding, and related datasets. Drawing on insights from both academia and industry, we propose an ideal panoramic system architecture in the embodied AI era, PANORAMA, which consists of four key subsystems. Moreover, we offer in-depth opinions related to emerging trends and cross-community impacts at the intersection of panoramic vision and embodied AI, along with the future roadmap and open challenges. This overview synthesizes state-of-the-art advancements and outlines challenges and opportunities for future research in building robust, general-purpose omnidirectional AI systems in the embodied AI era.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:58:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.12989</guid></item><item><title>GenExam: A Multidisciplinary Text-to-Image Exam</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14232</link><description>GenExam is a benchmark for evaluating text-to-image generation in exam-style settings across multiple disciplines, highlighting the challenges in integrating knowledge, reasoning, and generation.  					AI-generated summary 				 Exams are a fundamental test of expert-level intelligence and require integrated understanding, reasoning, and generation. Existing exam-style benchmarks mainly focus on understanding and reasoning tasks, and current generation benchmarks emphasize the illustration of world knowledge and visual concepts, neglecting the evaluation of rigorous drawing exams. We introduce GenExam, the first benchmark for multidisciplinary text-to-image exams, featuring 1,000 samples across 10 subjects with exam-style prompts organized under a four-level taxonomy. Each problem is equipped with ground-truth images and fine-grained scoring points to enable a precise evaluation of semantic correctness and visual plausibility. Experiments show that even state-of-the-art models such as GPT-Image-1 and Gemini-2.5-Flash-Image achieve less than 15% strict scores, and most models yield almost 0%, suggesting the great challenge of our benchmark. By framing image generation as an exam, GenExam offers a rigorous assessment of models' ability to integrate knowledge, reasoning, and generation, providing insights on the path to general AGI.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:00:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14232</guid></item><item><title>Scrub It Out! Erasing Sensitive Memorization in Code Language Models via
  Machine Unlearning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13755</link><description>CodeEraser effectively and efficiently removes sensitive memorized information from Code Language Models using machine unlearning techniques without full retraining.  					AI-generated summary 				 While Code Language Models (CLMs) have demonstrated superior performance in software engineering tasks such as code generation and summarization, recent empirical studies reveal a critical privacy vulnerability: these models exhibit unintended memorization of sensitive training data, enabling verbatim reproduction of confidential information when specifically prompted. To address this issue, several approaches, including training data de-duplication and differential privacy augmentation, have been proposed. However, these methods require full-model retraining for deployed CLMs, which incurs substantial computational costs. In this paper, we aim to answer the following research question: Can sensitive information memorized by CLMs be erased effectively and efficiently?   We conduct a pioneering investigation into erasing sensitive memorization in CLMs through machine unlearning - a post-hoc modification method that removes specific information from trained models without requiring full retraining. Specifically, we first quantify the memorization risks of sensitive data within CLM training datasets and curate a high-risk dataset of 50,000 sensitive memorized samples as unlearning targets. We study two widely used gradient ascent-based unlearning approaches: the vanilla and constraint-based methods, and introduce CodeEraser, an advanced variant that selectively unlearns sensitive memorized segments in code while preserving the structural integrity and functional correctness of the surrounding code. Extensive experiments on three families of CLMs, i.e., CodeParrot, CodeGen-Mono, and Qwen2.5-Coder, validate the effectiveness and efficiency of CodeEraser in erasing targeted sensitive memorization while maintaining model utility.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 07:40:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13755</guid></item><item><title>Wan-Animate: Unified Character Animation and Replacement with Holistic
  Replication</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14055</link><description>Wan-Animate is a unified framework for character animation and replacement, using spatially-aligned skeleton signals and implicit facial features to generate high-fidelity character videos with seamless environmental integration.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Wan-Animate, a unified framework for character animation and replacement. Given a character image and a reference video, Wan-Animate can animate the character by precisely replicating the expressions and movements of the character in the video to generate high-fidelity character videos. Alternatively, it can integrate the animated character into the reference video to replace the original character, replicating the scene's lighting and color tone to achieve seamless environmental integration. Wan-Animate is built upon the Wan model. To adapt it for character animation tasks, we employ a modified input paradigm to differentiate between reference conditions and regions for generation. This design unifies multiple tasks into a common symbolic representation. We use spatially-aligned skeleton signals to replicate body motion and implicit facial features extracted from source images to reenact expressions, enabling the generation of character videos with high controllability and expressiveness. Furthermore, to enhance environmental integration during character replacement, we develop an auxiliary Relighting LoRA. This module preserves the character's appearance consistency while applying the appropriate environmental lighting and color tone. Experimental results demonstrate that Wan-Animate achieves state-of-the-art performance. We are committed to open-sourcing the model weights and its source code.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:03:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14055</guid></item><item><title>THOR: Tool-Integrated Hierarchical Optimization via RL for Mathematical
  Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13761</link><description>THOR, a tool-integrated hierarchical optimization framework using RL, enhances mathematical reasoning and code generation by constructing high-quality datasets, optimizing reasoning paths, and correcting errors during inference.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Models (LLMs) have made remarkable progress in mathematical reasoning, but still continue to struggle with high-precision tasks like numerical computation and formal symbolic manipulation. Integrating external tools has emerged as a promising approach to bridge this gap. Despite recent advances, existing methods struggle with three key challenges: constructing tool-integrated reasoning data, performing fine-grained optimization, and enhancing inference. To overcome these limitations, we propose THOR (Tool-Integrated Hierarchical Optimization via RL). First, we introduce TIRGen, a multi-agent actor-critic-based pipeline for constructing high-quality datasets of tool-integrated reasoning paths, aligning with the policy and generalizing well across diverse models. Second, to perform fine-grained hierarchical optimization, we introduce an RL strategy that jointly optimizes for both trajectory-level problem solving and step-level code generation. This is motivated by our key insight that the success of an intermediate tool call is a strong predictor of the final answer's correctness. Finally, THOR incorporates a self-correction mechanism that leverages immediate tool feedback to dynamically revise erroneous reasoning paths during inference. Our approach demonstrates strong generalization across diverse models, performing effectively in both reasoning and non-reasoning models. It further achieves state-of-the-art performance for models of a similar scale on multiple mathematical benchmarks, while also delivering consistent improvements on code benchmarks. Our code will be publicly available at https://github.com/JingMog/THOR.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 01:58:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13761</guid></item><item><title>MARS2 2025 Challenge on Multimodal Reasoning: Datasets, Methods,
  Results, Discussion, and Outlook</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14142</link><description>The MARS2 2025 Challenge focuses on multimodal reasoning with large language models through real-world and specialized scenarios, evaluating 40+ models across three competition tracks using tailored datasets.  					AI-generated summary 				 This paper reviews the MARS2 2025 Challenge on Multimodal Reasoning. We aim to bring together different approaches in multimodal machine learning and LLMs via a large benchmark. We hope it better allows researchers to follow the state-of-the-art in this very dynamic area. Meanwhile, a growing number of testbeds have boosted the evolution of general-purpose large language models. Thus, this year's MARS2 focuses on real-world and specialized scenarios to broaden the multimodal reasoning applications of MLLMs. Our organizing team released two tailored datasets Lens and AdsQA as test sets, which support general reasoning in 12 daily scenarios and domain-specific reasoning in advertisement videos, respectively. We evaluated 40+ baselines that include both generalist MLLMs and task-specific models, and opened up three competition tracks, i.e., Visual Grounding in Real-world Scenarios (VG-RS), Visual Question Answering with Spatial Awareness (VQA-SA), and Visual Reasoning in Creative Advertisement Videos (VR-Ads). Finally, 76 teams from the renowned academic and industrial institutions have registered and 40+ valid submissions (out of 1200+) have been included in our ranking lists. Our datasets, code sets (40+ baselines and 15+ participants' methods), and rankings are publicly available on the MARS2 workshop website and our GitHub organization page https://github.com/mars2workshop/, where our updates and announcements of upcoming events will be continuously provided.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:01:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.14142</guid></item><item><title>Improving Context Fidelity via Native Retrieval-Augmented Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13683</link><description>CARE, a retrieval-augmented reasoning framework, enhances LLMs by integrating in-context evidence, improving retrieval accuracy and answer generation performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language models (LLMs) often struggle with context fidelity, producing inconsistent answers when responding to questions based on provided information. Existing approaches either rely on expensive supervised fine-tuning to generate evidence post-answer or train models to perform web searches without necessarily improving utilization of the given context. We propose CARE, a novel native retrieval-augmented reasoning framework that teaches LLMs to explicitly integrate in-context evidence within their reasoning process with the model's own retrieval capabilities. Our method requires limited labeled evidence data while significantly enhancing both retrieval accuracy and answer generation performance through strategically retrieved in-context tokens in the reasoning chain. Extensive experiments on multiple real-world and counterfactual QA benchmarks demonstrate that our approach substantially outperforms supervised fine-tuning, traditional retrieval-augmented generation methods, and external retrieval solutions. This work represents a fundamental advancement in making LLMs more accurate, reliable, and efficient for knowledge-intensive tasks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:37:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13683</guid></item><item><title>AERIS: Argonne Earth Systems Model for Reliable and Skillful Predictions</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13523</link><description>AERIS, a large-scale pixel-level Swin diffusion transformer, addresses scaling issues in high-resolution weather forecasting using SWiPe parallelism, achieving high performance and stability.  					AI-generated summary 				 Generative machine learning offers new opportunities to better understand complex Earth system dynamics. Recent diffusion-based methods address spectral biases and improve ensemble calibration in weather forecasting compared to deterministic methods, yet have so far proven difficult to scale stably at high resolutions. We introduce AERIS, a 1.3 to 80B parameter pixel-level Swin diffusion transformer to address this gap, and SWiPe, a generalizable technique that composes window parallelism with sequence and pipeline parallelism to shard window-based transformers without added communication cost or increased global batch size. On Aurora (10,080 nodes), AERIS sustains 10.21 ExaFLOPS (mixed precision) and a peak performance of 11.21 ExaFLOPS with 1 times 1 patch size on the 0.25{\deg} ERA5 dataset, achieving 95.5% weak scaling efficiency, and 81.6% strong scaling efficiency. AERIS outperforms the IFS ENS and remains stable on seasonal scales to 90 days, highlighting the potential of billion-parameter diffusion models for weather and climate prediction.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:07:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13523</guid></item><item><title>SteeringControl: Holistic Evaluation of Alignment Steering in LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13450</link><description>SteeringControl evaluates representation steering methods across bias, harmful generation, and hallucination, revealing tradeoffs and entanglement effects on secondary behaviors like sycophancy and commonsense morality.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce SteeringControl, a benchmark for evaluating representation steering methods across core alignment objectives--bias, harmful generation, and hallucination--and their effects on secondary behaviors such as sycophancy and commonsense morality. While prior alignment work often highlights truthfulness or reasoning ability to demonstrate the side effects of representation steering, we find there are many unexplored tradeoffs not yet understood in a systematic way. We collect a dataset of safety-relevant primary and secondary behaviors to evaluate steering effectiveness and behavioral entanglement centered around five popular steering methods. To enable this, we craft a modular steering framework based on unique components that serve as the building blocks of many existing methods. Our results on Qwen-2.5-7B and Llama-3.1-8B find that strong steering performance is dependent on the specific combination of steering method, model, and targeted behavior, and that severe concept entanglement can result from poor combinations of these three as well. We release our code here: https://github.com/wang-research-lab/SteeringControl.git.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 05:33:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2509.13450</guid></item></channel></rss>