<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Attention Illuminates LLM Reasoning: The Preplan-and-Anchor Rhythm
  Enables Fine-Grained Policy Optimization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13554</link><description>Attention mechanisms in LLMs are analyzed to reveal reasoning patterns, leading to novel RL strategies that improve performance by focusing on critical tokens.  					AI-generated summary 				 The reasoning pattern of Large language models (LLMs) remains opaque, and Reinforcement learning (RL) typically applies uniform credit across an entire generation, blurring the distinction between pivotal and routine steps. This work positions attention as a privileged substrate that renders the internal logic of LLMs legible, not merely as a byproduct of computation, but as a mechanistic blueprint of reasoning itself. We first distinguish attention heads between locally and globally focused information processing and reveal that locally focused heads produce a sawtooth pattern near the diagonal indicating phrasal chunks, while globally focused heads expose tokens that exert broad downstream influence over future tokens. We formalize these with two metrics: 1) Windowed Average Attention Distance, which measures the extent of backward attention within a clipped window; 2) Future Attention Influence, which quantifies a token's global importance as the average attention it receives from subsequent tokens. Taken together, these signals reveal a recurring preplan-and-anchor mechanism, where the model first performs a long-range contextual reference to generate an introductory token, which is immediately followed by or coincides with a semantic anchor token that organizes subsequent reasoning. Leveraging these insights, we introduce three novel RL strategies that dynamically perform targeted credit assignment to critical nodes (preplan tokens, anchor tokens, and their temporal coupling) and show consistent performance gains across various reasoning tasks. By aligning optimization with the model's intrinsic reasoning rhythm, we aim to transform opaque optimization into an actionable structure-aware process, hoping to offer a potential step toward more transparent and effective optimization of LLM reasoning.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 03:20:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13554</guid></item><item><title>FlashWorld: High-quality 3D Scene Generation within Seconds</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13678</link><description>FlashWorld generates 3D scenes from single images or text prompts quickly and with high quality by combining MV-oriented and 3D-oriented generation methods.  					AI-generated summary 				 We propose FlashWorld, a generative model that produces 3D scenes from a single image or text prompt in seconds, 10~100times faster than previous works while possessing superior rendering quality. Our approach shifts from the conventional multi-view-oriented (MV-oriented) paradigm, which generates multi-view images for subsequent 3D reconstruction, to a 3D-oriented approach where the model directly produces 3D Gaussian representations during multi-view generation. While ensuring 3D consistency, 3D-oriented method typically suffers poor visual quality. FlashWorld includes a dual-mode pre-training phase followed by a cross-mode post-training phase, effectively integrating the strengths of both paradigms. Specifically, leveraging the prior from a video diffusion model, we first pre-train a dual-mode multi-view diffusion model, which jointly supports MV-oriented and 3D-oriented generation modes. To bridge the quality gap in 3D-oriented generation, we further propose a cross-mode post-training distillation by matching distribution from consistent 3D-oriented mode to high-quality MV-oriented mode. This not only enhances visual quality while maintaining 3D consistency, but also reduces the required denoising steps for inference. Also, we propose a strategy to leverage massive single-view images and text prompts during this process to enhance the model's generalization to out-of-distribution inputs. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superiority and efficiency of our method.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:06:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13678</guid></item><item><title>UniMoE-Audio: Unified Speech and Music Generation with Dynamic-Capacity
  MoE</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13344</link><description>UniMoE-Audio, a unified speech and music generation model using a Dynamic-Capacity Mixture-of-Experts framework, addresses data imbalance and task conflicts, achieving state-of-the-art performance and enhanced cross-domain synergy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in unified multimodal models indicate a clear trend towards comprehensive content generation. However, the auditory domain remains a significant challenge, with music and speech often developed in isolation, hindering progress towards universal audio synthesis. This separation stems from inherent task conflicts and severe data imbalances, which impede the development of a truly unified audio generation model. To address this challenge, we propose UniMoE-Audio, a unified speech and music generation model within a novel Dynamic-Capacity Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) framework. Architecturally, UniMoE-Audio introduces a Top-P routing strategy for dynamic expert number allocation, and a hybrid expert design comprising routed experts for domain-specific knowledge, shared experts for domain-agnostic features, and null experts for adaptive computation skipping. To tackle data imbalance, we introduce a three-stage training curriculum: 1) Independent Specialist Training leverages original datasets to instill domain-specific knowledge into each "proto-expert" without interference; 2) MoE Integration and Warmup incorporates these specialists into the UniMoE-Audio architecture, warming up the gate module and shared expert using a subset of balanced dataset; and 3) Synergistic Joint Training trains the entire model end-to-end on the fully balanced dataset, fostering enhanced cross-domain synergy. Extensive experiments show that UniMoE-Audio not only achieves state-of-the-art performance on major speech and music generation benchmarks, but also demonstrates superior synergistic learning, mitigating the performance degradation typically seen in naive joint training. Our findings highlight the substantial potential of specialized MoE architecture and curated training strategies in advancing the field of universal audio generation. Homepage: https://mukioxun.github.io/Uni-MoE-site/home.html</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:33:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13344</guid></item><item><title>Bee: A High-Quality Corpus and Full-Stack Suite to Unlock Advanced Fully
  Open MLLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13795</link><description>A new dataset and pipeline for data curation improve the performance of fully open multimodal large language models, achieving state-of-the-art results competitive with semi-open models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Fully open multimodal large language models (MLLMs) currently lag behind proprietary counterparts, primarily due to a significant gap in data quality for supervised fine-tuning (SFT). Existing open-source datasets are often plagued by widespread noise and a critical deficit in complex reasoning data, such as Chain-of-Thought (CoT), which hinders the development of advanced model capabilities. Addressing these challenges, our work makes three primary contributions. First, we introduce Honey-Data-15M, a new SFT dataset comprising approximately 15 million QA pairs, processed through multiple cleaning techniques and enhanced with a novel dual-level (short and long) CoT enrichment strategy. Second, we introduce HoneyPipe, the data curation pipeline, and its underlying framework DataStudio, providing the community with a transparent and adaptable methodology for data curation that moves beyond static dataset releases. Finally, to validate our dataset and pipeline, we train Bee-8B, an 8B model on Honey-Data-15M. Experiments show that Bee-8B establishes a new state-of-the-art (SOTA) for fully open MLLMs, achieving performance that is competitive with, and in some cases surpasses, recent semi-open models such as InternVL3.5-8B. Our work delivers to the community a suite of foundational resources, including: the Honey-Data-15M corpus; the full-stack suite comprising HoneyPipe and DataStudio; training recipes; an evaluation harness; and the model weights. This effort demonstrates that a principled focus on data quality is a key pathway to developing fully open MLLMs that are highly competitive with their semi-open counterparts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:56:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13795</guid></item><item><title>InteractiveOmni: A Unified Omni-modal Model for Audio-Visual Multi-turn
  Dialogue</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13747</link><description>InteractiveOmni is a unified omni-modal large language model for audio-visual multi-turn interactions, offering comprehensive understanding and speech generation capabilities with efficient parameter usage.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce InteractiveOmni, a unified and open-source omni-modal large language model for audio-visual multi-turn interaction, ranging from 4B to 8B parameters, designed to lead the field of lightweight models by offering comprehensive omni-modal understanding and speech generation capabilities. To achieve this, we integrate the vision encoder, audio encoder, large language model, and speech decoder into a unified model for understanding and generation tasks. We design a multi-stage training strategy to ensure robust cross-modal capabilities, including pre-training for omni-modal understanding, followed by post-training with speech conversation and audio-visual interaction. To enable human-like long-term conversational ability, we meticulously curate a multi-turn training dataset that enhances the model's ability to handle complex and multi-turn interactions. To effectively evaluate the multi-turn memory and speech interaction capabilities, we construct the multi-modal multi-turn memory benchmark and the multi-turn speech interaction benchmark. Experiments demonstrate that InteractiveOmni significantly outperforms leading open-source models and provides a more intelligent multi-turn audio-visual experience, particularly in its long-term memory capabilities. Notably, InteractiveOmni-4B is comparable to the much larger model like Qwen2.5-Omni-7B on general benchmarks, and it can retain 97% of the performance of the InteractiveOmni-8B while utilizing only 50% of the model size. Achieving state-of-the-art results against similarly sized models across image, audio, video understanding, and speech generation tasks, InteractiveOmni is an accessible, open-source foundation for next-generation intelligent interactive systems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:36:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13747</guid></item><item><title>PhysMaster: Mastering Physical Representation for Video Generation via
  Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13809</link><description>PhysMaster enhances video generation by integrating physical knowledge through PhysEncoder, using reinforcement learning and Direct Preference Optimization to improve physics-awareness.  					AI-generated summary 				 Video generation models nowadays are capable of generating visually realistic videos, but often fail to adhere to physical laws, limiting their ability to generate physically plausible videos and serve as ''world models''. To address this issue, we propose PhysMaster, which captures physical knowledge as a representation for guiding video generation models to enhance their physics-awareness. Specifically, PhysMaster is based on the image-to-video task where the model is expected to predict physically plausible dynamics from the input image. Since the input image provides physical priors like relative positions and potential interactions of objects in the scenario, we devise PhysEncoder to encode physical information from it as an extra condition to inject physical knowledge into the video generation process. The lack of proper supervision on the model's physical performance beyond mere appearance motivates PhysEncoder to apply reinforcement learning with human feedback to physical representation learning, which leverages feedback from generation models to optimize physical representations with Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) in an end-to-end manner. PhysMaster provides a feasible solution for improving physics-awareness of PhysEncoder and thus of video generation, proving its ability on a simple proxy task and generalizability to wide-ranging physical scenarios. This implies that our PhysMaster, which unifies solutions for various physical processes via representation learning in the reinforcement learning paradigm, can act as a generic and plug-in solution for physics-aware video generation and broader applications.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:47:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13809</guid></item><item><title>LIBERO-Plus: In-depth Robustness Analysis of Vision-Language-Action
  Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13626</link><description>State-of-the-art Visual-Language-Action models show high benchmark scores but are brittle to various perturbations, particularly in camera viewpoints and robot initial states, and often ignore language instructions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Visual-Language-Action (VLA) models report impressive success rates on robotic manipulation benchmarks, yet these results may mask fundamental weaknesses in robustness. We perform a systematic vulnerability analysis by introducing controlled perturbations across seven dimensions: objects layout, camera viewpoints, robot initial states, language instructions, light conditions, background textures and sensor noise. We comprehensively analyzed multiple state-of-the-art models and revealed consistent brittleness beneath apparent competence. Our analysis exposes critical weaknesses: models exhibit extreme sensitivity to perturbation factors, including camera viewpoints and robot initial states, with performance dropping from 95% to below 30% under modest perturbations. Surprisingly, models are largely insensitive to language variations, with further experiments revealing that models tend to ignore language instructions completely. Our findings challenge the assumption that high benchmark scores equate to true competency and highlight the need for evaluation practices that assess reliability under realistic variation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:50:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13626</guid></item><item><title>CVD-STORM: Cross-View Video Diffusion with Spatial-Temporal
  Reconstruction Model for Autonomous Driving</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.07944</link><description>CVD-STORM, a cross-view video diffusion model with a spatial-temporal reconstruction VAE, enhances video generation quality and provides depth estimation for dynamic scenes.  					AI-generated summary 				 Generative models have been widely applied to world modeling for environment simulation and future state prediction. With advancements in autonomous driving, there is a growing demand not only for high-fidelity video generation under various controls, but also for producing diverse and meaningful information such as depth estimation. To address this, we propose CVD-STORM, a cross-view video diffusion model utilizing a spatial-temporal reconstruction Variational Autoencoder (VAE) that generates long-term, multi-view videos with 4D reconstruction capabilities under various control inputs. Our approach first fine-tunes the VAE with an auxiliary 4D reconstruction task, enhancing its ability to encode 3D structures and temporal dynamics. Subsequently, we integrate this VAE into the video diffusion process to significantly improve generation quality. Experimental results demonstrate that our model achieves substantial improvements in both FID and FVD metrics. Additionally, the jointly-trained Gaussian Splatting Decoder effectively reconstructs dynamic scenes, providing valuable geometric information for comprehensive scene understanding.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:46:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.07944</guid></item><item><title>Generative Universal Verifier as Multimodal Meta-Reasoner</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13804</link><description>Generative Universal Verifier enhances multimodal reasoning by providing reliable visual verification through ViVerBench, OmniVerifier-7B, and OmniVerifier-TTS, improving generation and refinement capabilities.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce Generative Universal Verifier, a novel concept and plugin designed for next-generation multimodal reasoning in vision-language models and unified multimodal models, providing the fundamental capability of reflection and refinement on visual outcomes during the reasoning and generation process. This work makes three main contributions: (1) We build ViVerBench, a comprehensive benchmark spanning 16 categories of critical tasks for evaluating visual outcomes in multimodal reasoning. Results show that existing VLMs consistently underperform across these tasks, underscoring a substantial gap from human-level capability in reliable visual verification. (2) We design two automated pipelines to construct large-scale visual verification data and train OmniVerifier-7B, the first omni-capable generative verifier trained for universal visual verification and achieves notable gains on ViVerBench(+8.3). Through training, we identify three atomic capabilities in visual verification and demonstrate how they generalize and interact synergistically. (3) We propose OmniVerifier-TTS, a sequential test-time scaling paradigm that leverages the universal verifier to bridge image generation and editing within unified models, enhancing the upper bound of generative ability through iterative fine-grained optimization. Beyond generation, we extend universal verifier to broader world-modeling interleaved reasoning scenarios. Empirically, OmniVerifier-TTS achieves improvements on T2I-ReasonBench(+3.7), and GenEval++(+4.3), outperforming existing parallel test-time scaling methods, such as Best-of-N. By endowing multimodal reasoning with reliable visual verification, OmniVerifier advances both reliable reflection during generation and scalable test-time refinement, marking a step toward more trustworthy and controllable next-generation reasoning systems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:48:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13804</guid></item><item><title>ParallelBench: Understanding the Trade-offs of Parallel Decoding in
  Diffusion LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.04767</link><description>Parallel decoding in diffusion LLMs degrades generation quality due to ignored token dependencies, highlighting the need for new decoding methods and benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 While most autoregressive LLMs are constrained to one-by-one decoding, diffusion LLMs (dLLMs) have attracted growing interest for their potential to dramatically accelerate inference through parallel decoding. Despite this promise, the conditional independence assumption in dLLMs causes parallel decoding to ignore token dependencies, inevitably degrading generation quality when these dependencies are strong. However, existing works largely overlook these inherent challenges, and evaluations on standard benchmarks (e.g., math and coding) are not sufficient to capture the quality degradation caused by parallel decoding. To address this gap, we first provide an information-theoretic analysis of parallel decoding. We then conduct case studies on analytically tractable synthetic list operations from both data distribution and decoding strategy perspectives, offering quantitative insights that highlight the fundamental limitations of parallel decoding. Building on these insights, we propose ParallelBench, the first benchmark specifically designed for dLLMs, featuring realistic tasks that are trivial for humans and autoregressive LLMs yet exceptionally challenging for dLLMs under parallel decoding. Using ParallelBench, we systematically analyze both dLLMs and autoregressive LLMs, revealing that: (i) dLLMs under parallel decoding can suffer dramatic quality degradation in real-world scenarios, and (ii) current parallel decoding strategies struggle to adapt their degree of parallelism based on task difficulty, thus failing to achieve meaningful speedup without compromising quality. Our findings underscore the pressing need for innovative decoding methods that can overcome the current speed-quality trade-off. We release our benchmark to help accelerate the development of truly efficient dLLMs.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:30:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.04767</guid></item><item><title>Trace Anything: Representing Any Video in 4D via Trajectory Fields</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13802</link><description>Trace Anything, a neural network, predicts video trajectories in a single pass, achieving state-of-the-art performance and demonstrating efficiency and emergent abilities like motion forecasting.  					AI-generated summary 				 Effective spatio-temporal representation is fundamental to modeling, understanding, and predicting dynamics in videos. The atomic unit of a video, the pixel, traces a continuous 3D trajectory over time, serving as the primitive element of dynamics. Based on this principle, we propose representing any video as a Trajectory Field: a dense mapping that assigns a continuous 3D trajectory function of time to each pixel in every frame. With this representation, we introduce Trace Anything, a neural network that predicts the entire trajectory field in a single feed-forward pass. Specifically, for each pixel in each frame, our model predicts a set of control points that parameterizes a trajectory (i.e., a B-spline), yielding its 3D position at arbitrary query time instants. We trained the Trace Anything model on large-scale 4D data, including data from our new platform, and our experiments demonstrate that: (i) Trace Anything achieves state-of-the-art performance on our new benchmark for trajectory field estimation and performs competitively on established point-tracking benchmarks; (ii) it offers significant efficiency gains thanks to its one-pass paradigm, without requiring iterative optimization or auxiliary estimators; and (iii) it exhibits emergent abilities, including goal-conditioned manipulation, motion forecasting, and spatio-temporal fusion. Project page: https://trace-anything.github.io/.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:49:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13802</guid></item><item><title>Reasoning in Space via Grounding in the World</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13800</link><description>GS-Reasoner, a 3D LLM with a dual-path pooling mechanism, achieves autoregressive grounding and state-of-the-art spatial reasoning without external modules.  					AI-generated summary 				 In this paper, we claim that 3D visual grounding is the cornerstone of spatial reasoning and introduce the Grounded-Spatial Reasoner (GS-Reasoner) to explore the effective spatial representations that bridge the gap between them. Existing 3D LLMs suffer from the absence of a unified 3D representation capable of jointly capturing semantic and geometric information. This deficiency is manifested either in poor performance on grounding or in an excessive reliance on external modules, ultimately hindering the seamless integration of grounding and spatial reasoning. To address this, we propose a simple yet effective dual-path pooling mechanism that tightly aligns geometric features with both semantic and positional cues, constructing a unified image patch-based 3D representation that encapsulates all essential information without increasing the number of input tokens. Leveraging this holistic representation, GS-Reasoner is the first 3D LLM that achieves autoregressive grounding entirely without external modules while delivering performance comparable to state-of-the-art models, establishing a unified and self-contained framework for 3D spatial reasoning. To further bridge grounding and spatial reasoning, we introduce the Grounded Chain-of-Thought (GCoT) dataset. This dataset is meticulously curated to include both 3D bounding box annotations for objects referenced in reasoning questions and step-by-step reasoning paths that integrate grounding as a core component of the problem-solving process. Extensive experiments demonstrate that GS-Reasoner achieves impressive results on 3D visual grounding, which in turn significantly enhances its spatial reasoning capabilities, leading to state-of-the-art performance.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:18:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13800</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Computing Resources in Publishing Foundation Model Research</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13621</link><description>Increased computing resources are correlated with national funding and citations in foundation model research, but not with research environment, domain, or methodology.  					AI-generated summary 				 Cutting-edge research in Artificial Intelligence (AI) requires considerable resources, including Graphics Processing Units (GPUs), data, and human resources. In this paper, we evaluate of the relationship between these resources and the scientific advancement of foundation models (FM). We reviewed 6517 FM papers published between 2022 to 2024, and surveyed 229 first-authors to the impact of computing resources on scientific output. We find that increased computing is correlated with national funding allocations and citations, but our findings don't observe the strong correlations with research environment (academic or industrial), domain, or study methodology. We advise that individuals and institutions focus on creating shared and affordable computing opportunities to lower the entry barrier for under-resourced researchers. These steps can help expand participation in FM research, foster diversity of ideas and contributors, and sustain innovation and progress in AI. The data will be available at: https://mit-calc.csail.mit.edu/</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:59:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13621</guid></item><item><title>UniME-V2: MLLM-as-a-Judge for Universal Multimodal Embedding Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13515</link><description>A novel Universal Multimodal Embedding (UniME-V2) model uses MLLMs to enhance representation learning by identifying diverse, high-quality hard negatives and improving discriminative capacity through soft semantic matching scores.  					AI-generated summary 				 Universal multimodal embedding models are foundational to various tasks. Existing approaches typically employ in-batch negative mining by measuring the similarity of query-candidate pairs. However, these methods often struggle to capture subtle semantic differences among candidates and lack diversity in negative samples. Moreover, the embeddings exhibit limited discriminative ability in distinguishing false and hard negatives. In this paper, we leverage the advanced understanding capabilities of MLLMs to enhance representation learning and present a novel Universal Multimodal Embedding (UniME-V2) model. Our approach first constructs a potential hard negative set through global retrieval. We then introduce the MLLM-as-a-Judge mechanism, which utilizes MLLMs to assess the semantic alignment of query-candidate pairs and generate soft semantic matching scores. These scores serve as a foundation for hard negative mining, mitigating the impact of false negatives and enabling the identification of diverse, high-quality hard negatives. Furthermore, the semantic matching scores are used as soft labels to mitigate the rigid one-to-one mapping constraint. By aligning the similarity matrix with the soft semantic matching score matrix, the model learns semantic distinctions among candidates, significantly enhancing its discriminative capacity. To further improve performance, we propose UniME-V2-Reranker, a reranking model trained on our mined hard negatives through a joint pairwise and listwise optimization approach. We conduct comprehensive experiments on the MMEB benchmark and multiple retrieval tasks, demonstrating that our method achieves state-of-the-art performance on average across all tasks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:06:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13515</guid></item><item><title>InternVLA-M1: A Spatially Guided Vision-Language-Action Framework for
  Generalist Robot Policy</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13778</link><description>A unified framework for spatial grounding and robot control, InternVLA-M1, enhances instruction-following robots through spatially guided vision-language-action training, achieving significant improvements across various tasks and simulations.  					AI-generated summary 				 We introduce InternVLA-M1, a unified framework for spatial grounding and robot control that advances instruction-following robots toward scalable, general-purpose intelligence. Its core idea is spatially guided vision-language-action training, where spatial grounding serves as the critical link between instructions and robot actions. InternVLA-M1 employs a two-stage pipeline: (i) spatial grounding pre-training on over 2.3M spatial reasoning data to determine ``where to act'' by aligning instructions with visual, embodiment-agnostic positions, and (ii) spatially guided action post-training to decide ``how to act'' by generating embodiment-aware actions through plug-and-play spatial prompting. This spatially guided training recipe yields consistent gains: InternVLA-M1 outperforms its variant without spatial guidance by +14.6% on SimplerEnv Google Robot, +17% on WidowX, and +4.3% on LIBERO Franka, while demonstrating stronger spatial reasoning capability in box, point, and trace prediction. To further scale instruction following, we built a simulation engine to collect 244K generalizable pick-and-place episodes, enabling a 6.2% average improvement across 200 tasks and 3K+ objects. In real-world clustered pick-and-place, InternVLA-M1 improved by 7.3%, and with synthetic co-training, achieved +20.6% on unseen objects and novel configurations. Moreover, in long-horizon reasoning-intensive scenarios, it surpassed existing works by over 10%. These results highlight spatially guided training as a unifying principle for scalable and resilient generalist robots. Code and models are available at https://github.com/InternRobotics/InternVLA-M1.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:12:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13778</guid></item><item><title>Uni-MMMU: A Massive Multi-discipline Multimodal Unified Benchmark</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13759</link><description>Uni-MMMU is a benchmark that evaluates the bidirectional synergy between visual understanding and generation across multiple domains, providing insights into their integration and performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Unified multimodal models aim to jointly enable visual understanding and generation, yet current benchmarks rarely examine their true integration. Existing evaluations either treat the two abilities in isolation or overlook tasks that inherently couple them. To address this gap, we present Uni-MMMU, a comprehensive and discipline-aware benchmark that systematically unfolds the bidirectional synergy between generation and understanding across eight reasoning-centric domains, including science, coding, mathematics, and puzzles. Each task is bidirectionally coupled, demanding models to (i) leverage conceptual understanding to guide precise visual synthesis, or (ii) utilize generation as a cognitive scaffold for analytical reasoning. Uni-MMMU incorporates verifiable intermediate reasoning steps, unique ground truths, and a reproducible scoring protocol for both textual and visual outputs. Through extensive evaluation of state-of-the-art unified, generation-only, and understanding-only models, we reveal substantial performance disparities and cross-modal dependencies, offering new insights into when and how these abilities reinforce one another, and establishing a reliable foundation for advancing unified models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 03:01:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13759</guid></item><item><title>Universal Image Restoration Pre-training via Masked Degradation
  Classification</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13282</link><description>A Masked Degradation Classification Pre-Training method enhances image restoration by using degradation type classification and image reconstruction, improving performance across CNNs and Transformers.  					AI-generated summary 				 This study introduces a Masked Degradation Classification Pre-Training method (MaskDCPT), designed to facilitate the classification of degradation types in input images, leading to comprehensive image restoration pre-training. Unlike conventional pre-training methods, MaskDCPT uses the degradation type of the image as an extremely weak supervision, while simultaneously leveraging the image reconstruction to enhance performance and robustness. MaskDCPT includes an encoder and two decoders: the encoder extracts features from the masked low-quality input image. The classification decoder uses these features to identify the degradation type, whereas the reconstruction decoder aims to reconstruct a corresponding high-quality image. This design allows the pre-training to benefit from both masked image modeling and contrastive learning, resulting in a generalized representation suited for restoration tasks. Benefit from the straightforward yet potent MaskDCPT, the pre-trained encoder can be used to address universal image restoration and achieve outstanding performance. Implementing MaskDCPT significantly improves performance for both convolution neural networks (CNNs) and Transformers, with a minimum increase in PSNR of 3.77 dB in the 5D all-in-one restoration task and a 34.8% reduction in PIQE compared to baseline in real-world degradation scenarios. It also emergences strong generalization to previously unseen degradation types and levels. In addition, we curate and release the UIR-2.5M dataset, which includes 2.5 million paired restoration samples across 19 degradation types and over 200 degradation levels, incorporating both synthetic and real-world data. The dataset, source code, and models are available at https://github.com/MILab-PKU/MaskDCPT.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 04:38:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13282</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting Model Interpolation for Efficient Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10977</link><description>Model merging, typically on Instruct and Thinking models, has shown remarkable performance for efficient reasoning. In this paper, we systematically revisit the simplest merging method that interpolates two weights directly. Particularly, we observe that model interpolation follows a three-stage evolutionary paradigm with distinct behaviors on the reasoning trajectory. These dynamics provide a principled guide for navigating the performance-cost trade-off. Empirical results demonstrate that a strategically interpolated model surprisingly surpasses sophisticated model merging baselines on both efficiency and effectiveness. We further validate our findings with extensive ablation studies on model layers, modules, and decoding strategies. Ultimately, this work demystifies model interpolation and offers a practical framework for crafting models with precisely targeted reasoning capabilities. Code is available at https://github.com/wutaiqiang/MI{Github}.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:16:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10977</guid></item><item><title>FG-CLIP 2: A Bilingual Fine-grained Vision-Language Alignment Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10921</link><description>FG-CLIP 2, a bilingual vision-language model, enhances fine-grained alignment for English and Chinese through rich supervision and a new TIC loss, achieving state-of-the-art performance across multiple datasets and tasks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Fine-grained vision-language understanding requires precise alignment between visual content and linguistic descriptions, a capability that remains limited in current models, particularly in non-English settings. While models like CLIP perform well on global alignment, they often struggle to capture fine-grained details in object attributes, spatial relations, and linguistic expressions, with limited support for bilingual comprehension. To address these challenges, we introduce FG-CLIP 2, a bilingual vision-language model designed to advance fine-grained alignment for both English and Chinese. Our approach leverages rich fine-grained supervision, including region-text matching and long-caption modeling, alongside multiple discriminative objectives. We further introduce the Textual Intra-modal Contrastive (TIC) loss to better distinguish semantically similar captions. Trained on a carefully curated mixture of large-scale English and Chinese data, FG-CLIP 2 achieves powerful bilingual performance. To enable rigorous evaluation, we present a new benchmark for Chinese multimodal understanding, featuring long-caption retrieval and bounding box classification. Extensive experiments on 29 datasets across 8 tasks show that FG-CLIP 2 outperforms existing methods, achieving state-of-the-art results in both languages. We release the model, code, and benchmark to facilitate future research on bilingual fine-grained alignment.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 03:27:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10921</guid></item><item><title>X-VLA: Soft-Prompted Transformer as Scalable Cross-Embodiment
  Vision-Language-Action Model</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10274</link><description>A novel Soft Prompt approach enhances Vision-Language-Action models by using learnable embeddings for diverse robotic data, enabling superior performance across simulations and real-world robots.  					AI-generated summary 				 Successful generalist Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models rely on effective training across diverse robotic platforms with large-scale, cross-embodiment, heterogeneous datasets. To facilitate and leverage the heterogeneity in rich, diverse robotic data sources, we propose a novel Soft Prompt approach with minimally added parameters, by infusing prompt learning concepts into cross-embodiment robot learning and introducing separate sets of learnable embeddings for each distinct data source. These embeddings serve as embodiment-specific prompts, which in unity empower VLA models with effective exploitation of varying cross-embodiment features. Our new X-VLA, a neat flow-matching-based VLA architecture, relies exclusively on soft-prompted standard Transformer encoders, enjoying both scalability and simplicity. Evaluated across 6 simulations as well as 3 real-world robots, our 0.9B instantiation-X-VLA-0.9B simultaneously achieves SOTA performance over a sweep of benchmarks, demonstrating superior results on a wide axes of capabilities, from flexible dexterity to quick adaptation across embodiments, environments, and tasks. Website: https://thu-air-dream.github.io/X-VLA/</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 03:38:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10274</guid></item><item><title>CoIRL-AD: Collaborative-Competitive Imitation-Reinforcement Learning in
  Latent World Models for Autonomous Driving</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.12560</link><description>End-to-end autonomous driving models trained solely with imitation learning (IL) often suffer from poor generalization. In contrast, reinforcement learning (RL) promotes exploration through reward maximization but faces challenges such as sample inefficiency and unstable convergence. A natural solution is to combine IL and RL. Moving beyond the conventional two-stage paradigm (IL pretraining followed by RL fine-tuning), we propose CoIRL-AD, a competitive dual-policy framework that enables IL and RL agents to interact during training. CoIRL-AD introduces a competition-based mechanism that facilitates knowledge exchange while preventing gradient conflicts. Experiments on the nuScenes dataset show an 18% reduction in collision rate compared to baselines, along with stronger generalization and improved performance on long-tail scenarios. Code is available at: https://github.com/SEU-zxj/CoIRL-AD.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:23:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.12560</guid></item><item><title>Direct Multi-Token Decoding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11958</link><description>Direct Multi-Token Decoding (DMTD) accelerates large language model inference by using only late layers for token generation, achieving significant speedup with minimal performance loss.  					AI-generated summary 				 Decoder-only transformers have become the standard architecture for large language models (LLMs) due to their strong performance. Recent studies suggest that, in pre-trained LLMs, early, middle, and late layers may serve distinct roles: Early layers focus on understanding the input context, middle layers handle task-specific processing, and late layers convert abstract representations into output tokens. We hypothesize that once representations have been processed by the early and middle layers, the resulting hidden states may encapsulate sufficient information to support the generation of multiple tokens using only the late layers, eliminating the need to repeatedly traverse the early and middle layers. We refer to this inference paradigm as Direct Multi-Token Decoding (DMTD). Unlike speculative decoding, our method introduces no additional parameters, auxiliary routines, or post-generation verification. Despite being trained on a limited dataset, a fine-tuned DMTD Qwen3-4B model has already demonstrated promising results, achieving up to a 2x speedup with only minor performance loss. Moreover, as shown in our scaling analysis, its performance is expected to further improve with larger training datasets.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:09:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11958</guid></item><item><title>NOSA: Native and Offloadable Sparse Attention</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13602</link><description>NOSA, a trainable sparse attention framework, enhances decoding throughput by enabling efficient KV cache offloading without compromising performance.  					AI-generated summary 				 Trainable sparse attention has emerged as a promising solution to address the decoding efficiency bottleneck of LLMs in long-context processing, significantly saving memory accesses while minimally impacting task performance. However, existing sparse attention methods leave a crucial limitation unresolved: the size of the key-value (KV) cache remains unreduced, which constrains on-GPU batch sizes and throttles decoding throughput, especially in large-scale batched inference. In this paper, we show that trainable sparse attention naturally exhibits strong locality in token selection across adjacent decoding steps, thereby enabling KV cache offloading without altering the underlying attention computation. However, the inherent locality remains insufficient to achieve efficient offloading, as the transfer of selected KV pairs between the CPU and GPU continues to dominate the overall decoding cost. Building on this insight, we present NOSA, a trainable sparse attention framework designed to natively support KV cache offloading. NOSA introduces explicit locality constraints by decomposing token selection into query-aware and query-agnostic components, thereby reducing KV transfers while preserving the same attention computation as used during training. We pretrain a 1B-parameter model with NOSA and conduct extensive benchmarks, showing that it preserves near-lossless performance while achieving up to a 2.3x improvement in decoding throughput compared with the vanilla trainable sparse attention baseline (InfLLM-V2).</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:41:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13602</guid></item><item><title>HyperAgent: Leveraging Hypergraphs for Topology Optimization in
  Multi-Agent Communication</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10611</link><description>HyperAgent, a hypergraph-based framework, optimizes communication topologies and captures group collaboration patterns, improving performance and efficiency in multi-agent systems.  					AI-generated summary 				 Recent advances in large language model-powered multi-agent systems have demonstrated remarkable collective intelligence through effective communication. However, existing approaches face two primary challenges: (i) Ineffective group collaboration modeling, as they rely on pairwise edge representations in graph structures, limiting their ability to capture relationships among multiple agents; and (ii) Limited task-adaptiveness in communication topology design, leading to excessive communication cost for simple tasks and insufficient coordination for complex scenarios. These issues restrict the scalability and practical deployment of adaptive collaboration frameworks. To address these challenges, we propose HyperAgent, a hypergraph-based framework that optimizes communication topologies and effectively captures group collaboration patterns using direct hyperedge representations. Unlike edge-based approaches, HyperAgent uses hyperedges to link multiple agents within the same subtask and employs hypergraph convolutional layers to achieve one-step information aggregation in collaboration groups. Additionally, it incorporates a variational autoencoder framework with sparsity regularization to dynamically adjust hypergraph topologies based on task complexity. Experiments highlight the superiority of HyperAgent in both performance and efficiency. For instance, on GSM8K, HyperAgent achieves 95.07\% accuracy while reducing token consumption by 25.33\%, demonstrating the potential of hypergraph-based optimization for multi-agent communication.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:16:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10611</guid></item><item><title>Hard2Verify: A Step-Level Verification Benchmark for Open-Ended Frontier
  Math</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13744</link><description>Hard2Verify, a human-annotated benchmark, evaluates step-level verifiers for LLM-based mathematical reasoning systems, highlighting the challenges and performance gaps between open-source and closed-source models.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large language model (LLM)-based reasoning systems have recently achieved gold medal-level performance in the IMO 2025 competition, writing mathematical proofs where, to receive full credit, each step must be not only correct but also sufficiently supported. To train LLM-based reasoners in such challenging, open-ended settings, strong verifiers capable of catching step-level mistakes are necessary prerequisites. We introduce Hard2Verify, a human-annotated, step-level verification benchmark produced with over 500 hours of human labor. Hard2Verify is designed to rigorously assess step-level verifiers at the frontier: Verifiers must provide step-level annotations or identify the first error in responses generated by frontier LLMs for very recent, challenging, and open-ended math questions. We evaluate 29 generative critics and process reward models, demonstrating that, beyond a few standouts, open-source verifiers lag closed source models. We subsequently analyze what drives poor performance in step-level verification, the impacts of scaling verifier compute, as well as fundamental questions such as self-verification and verification-generation dynamics.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:50:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13744</guid></item><item><title>Stronger Together: On-Policy Reinforcement Learning for Collaborative
  LLMs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11062</link><description>AT-GRPO, a tailored RL algorithm for multi-agent systems, significantly enhances performance across various tasks by addressing unique challenges in on-policy RL.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multi-agent systems (MAS) and reinforcement learning (RL) are widely used to enhance the agentic capabilities of large language models (LLMs). MAS improves task performance through role-based orchestration, while RL uses environmental rewards to learn stronger policies, such as GRPO-style optimization. However, applying on-policy RL to MAS remains underexplored and presents unique challenges. Algorithmically, standard GRPO grouping assumptions break down because prompts vary by role and by turn. System-wise, the training stack must support MAS-workflow rollouts and on-policy updates for both single-policy and multi-policy models.   We propose AT-GRPO, which includes (i) an agent- and turn-wise grouped RL algorithm tailored to MAS and (ii) a training system that supports both single- and multi-policy regimes. Across game, planning, coding, and math tasks, AT-GRPO delivers substantial gains. On long-horizon planning, it increases accuracy from a 14.0 to 47.0 percent single-agent RL baseline to 96.0 to 99.5 percent. It also improves reasoning performance, with average gains of 3.87 to 7.62 percent on coding tasks and 9.0 to 17.93 percent on math. Code and environments are available at: https://github.com/pettingllms-ai/PettingLLMs.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 06:01:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11062</guid></item><item><title>MTSQL-R1: Towards Long-Horizon Multi-Turn Text-to-SQL via Agentic
  Training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.12831</link><description>MTSQL-R1, an agentic training framework, improves multi-turn Text-to-SQL by treating it as an MDP with iterative propose-execute-verify-refine cycles, enhancing coherence and execution.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multi-turn Text-to-SQL aims to translate a user's conversational utterances into executable SQL while preserving dialogue coherence and grounding to the target schema. However, most existing systems only regard this task as a simple text translation task and follow a short-horizon paradigm, generating a query per turn without execution, explicit verification, and refinement, which leads to non-executable or incoherent outputs. We present MTSQL-R1, an agentic training framework for long-horizon multi-turn Text-to-SQL. We cast the task as a Markov Decision Process (MDP) in which an agent interacts with (i) a database for execution feedback and (ii) a persistent dialogue memory for coherence verification, performing an iterative propose to execute -&gt; verify -&gt; refine cycle until all checks pass. Experiments on COSQL and SPARC demonstrate that MTSQL-R1 consistently outperforms strong baselines, highlighting the importance of environment-driven verification and memory-guided refinement for conversational semantic parsing. Full recipes (including code, trained models, logs, reasoning trajectories, etc.) will be released after the internal review to contribute to community research.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:23:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.12831</guid></item><item><title>GraphTracer: Graph-Guided Failure Tracing in LLM Agents for Robust
  Multi-Turn Deep Search</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10581</link><description>GraphTracer addresses multi-agent system failure attribution by constructing Information Dependency Graphs to trace information flow and improve debugging accuracy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Multi-agent systems powered by Large Language Models excel at complex tasks through coordinated collaboration, yet they face high failure rates in multi-turn deep search scenarios. Existing temporal attribution methods struggle to accurately diagnose root causes, particularly when errors propagate across multiple agents. Attempts to automate failure attribution by analyzing action sequences remain ineffective due to their inability to account for information dependencies that span agents. This paper identifies two core challenges: (i) distinguishing symptoms from root causes in multi-agent error propagation, and (ii) tracing information dependencies beyond temporal order. To address these issues, we introduce GraphTracer, a framework that redefines failure attribution through information flow analysis. GraphTracer constructs Information Dependency Graphs (IDGs) to explicitly capture how agents reference and build on prior outputs. It localizes root causes by tracing through these dependency structures instead of relying on temporal sequences. GraphTracer also uses graph-aware synthetic data generation to target critical nodes, creating realistic failure scenarios. Evaluations on the Who\&amp;When benchmark and integration into production systems demonstrate that GraphTracer-8B achieves up to 18.18\% higher attribution accuracy compared to state-of-the-art models and enables 4.8\% to 14.2\% performance improvements in deployed multi-agent frameworks, establishing a robust solution for multi-agent system debugging.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:17:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.10581</guid></item><item><title>Deflanderization for Game Dialogue: Balancing Character Authenticity
  with Task Execution in LLM-based NPCs</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13586</link><description>Participants in the CPDC 2025 used lightweight prompting and fine-tuned large models to achieve high rankings in task-oriented and context-aware dialogue challenges.  					AI-generated summary 				 The emergence of large language models (LLMs) has opened new opportunities for cre- ating dynamic non-player characters (NPCs) in gaming environments, enabling both func- tional task execution and persona-consistent dialogue generation. In this paper, we (Tu_Character_lab) report our participation in the Commonsense Persona-Grounded Dialogue Challenge (CPDC) 2025 Round 2, which eval- uates agents across three tracks: task-oriented dialogue, context-aware dialogue, and their integration. Our approach combines two complementary strategies: (i) lightweight prompting techniques in the API track, including a Deflanderization prompting method to suppress excessive role-play and improve task fidelity, and (ii) fine-tuned large models in the GPU track, leveraging Qwen3-14B with supervisedfinetuning (SFT) and Low-Rank Adaptation(LoRA). Our best submissions ranked 2nd on Task 1, 2nd on Task 3 (API track), and 4th on Task 3 (GPU track).</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:51:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.13586</guid></item><item><title>Point Prompting: Counterfactual Tracking with Video Diffusion Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11715</link><description>Pretrained video diffusion models can perform zero-shot point tracking by visually marking points and regenerating video frames, outperforming prior methods and handling occlusions.  					AI-generated summary 				 Trackers and video generators solve closely related problems: the former analyze motion, while the latter synthesize it. We show that this connection enables pretrained video diffusion models to perform zero-shot point tracking by simply prompting them to visually mark points as they move over time. We place a distinctively colored marker at the query point, then regenerate the rest of the video from an intermediate noise level. This propagates the marker across frames, tracing the point's trajectory. To ensure that the marker remains visible in this counterfactual generation, despite such markers being unlikely in natural videos, we use the unedited initial frame as a negative prompt. Through experiments with multiple image-conditioned video diffusion models, we find that these "emergent" tracks outperform those of prior zero-shot methods and persist through occlusions, often obtaining performance that is competitive with specialized self-supervised models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:04:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2510.11715</guid></item></channel></rss>