<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>DeepResearchEval: An Automated Framework for Deep Research Task Construction and Agentic Evaluation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09688</link><description>DeepResearchEval presents an automated framework for creating complex research tasks and evaluating them through agent-based methods that adapt to task specifics and verify facts without relying on citations.  					AI-generated summary 				 Deep research systems are widely used for multi-step web research, analysis, and cross-source synthesis, yet their evaluation remains challenging. Existing benchmarks often require annotation-intensive task construction, rely on static evaluation dimensions, or fail to reliably verify facts when citations are missing. To bridge these gaps, we introduce DeepResearchEval, an automated framework for deep research task construction and agentic evaluation. For task construction, we propose a persona-driven pipeline generating realistic, complex research tasks anchored in diverse user profiles, applying a two-stage filter Task Qualification and Search Necessity to retain only tasks requiring multi-source evidence integration and external retrieval. For evaluation, we propose an agentic pipeline with two components: an Adaptive Point-wise Quality Evaluation that dynamically derives task-specific evaluation dimensions, criteria, and weights conditioned on each generated task, and an Active Fact-Checking that autonomously extracts and verifies report statements via web search, even when citations are missing.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:03:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09688</guid></item><item><title>Controlled Self-Evolution for Algorithmic Code Optimization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.07348</link><description>Controlled Self-Evolution method improves code generation through diversified initialization, feedback-guided genetic evolution, and hierarchical memory to enhance exploration efficiency and solution quality.  					AI-generated summary 				 Self-evolution methods enhance code generation through iterative "generate-verify-refine" cycles, yet existing approaches suffer from low exploration efficiency, failing to discover solutions with superior complexity within limited budgets. This inefficiency stems from initialization bias trapping evolution in poor solution regions, uncontrolled stochastic operations lacking feedback guidance, and insufficient experience utilization across tasks. To address these bottlenecks, we propose Controlled Self-Evolution (CSE), which consists of three key components. Diversified Planning Initialization generates structurally distinct algorithmic strategies for broad solution space coverage. Genetic Evolution replaces stochastic operations with feedback-guided mechanisms, enabling targeted mutation and compositional crossover. Hierarchical Evolution Memory captures both successful and failed experiences at inter-task and intra-task levels. Experiments on EffiBench-X demonstrate that CSE consistently outperforms all baselines across various LLM backbones. Furthermore, CSE achieves higher efficiency from early generations and maintains continuous improvement throughout evolution. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/QuantaAlpha/EvoControl.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:53:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.07348</guid></item><item><title>SkinFlow: Efficient Information Transmission for Open Dermatological Diagnosis via Dynamic Visual Encoding and Staged RL</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09136</link><description>SkinFlow introduces a novel framework for dermatological vision-language modeling that improves diagnostic accuracy through optimized visual information transmission efficiency rather than parameter scaling alone.  					AI-generated summary 				 General-purpose Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs), despite their massive scale, often falter in dermatology due to "diffuse attention" - the inability to disentangle subtle pathological lesions from background noise. In this paper, we challenge the assumption that parameter scaling is the only path to medical precision. We introduce SkinFlow, a framework that treats diagnosis as an optimization of visual information transmission efficiency. Our approach utilizes a Virtual-Width Dynamic Vision Encoder (DVE) to "unfold" complex pathological manifolds without physical parameter expansion, coupled with a two-stage Reinforcement Learning strategy. This strategy sequentially aligns explicit medical descriptions (Stage I) and reconstructs implicit diagnostic textures (Stage II) within a constrained semantic space. Furthermore, we propose a clinically grounded evaluation protocol that prioritizes diagnostic safety and hierarchical relevance over rigid label matching. Empirical results are compelling: our 7B model establishes a new state-of-the-art on the Fitzpatrick17k benchmark, achieving a +12.06% gain in Top-1 accuracy and a +28.57% boost in Top-6 accuracy over the massive general-purpose models (e.g., Qwen3VL-235B and GPT-5.2). These findings demonstrate that optimizing geometric capacity and information flow yields superior diagnostic reasoning compared to raw parameter scaling.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:29:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09136</guid></item><item><title>Fast-ThinkAct: Efficient Vision-Language-Action Reasoning via Verbalizable Latent Planning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09708</link><description>Fast-ThinkAct is an efficient vision-language-action framework that reduces inference latency by 89.3% through compact latent reasoning while maintaining long-horizon planning and few-shot adaptation capabilities.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-Language-Action (VLA) tasks require reasoning over complex visual scenes and executing adaptive actions in dynamic environments. While recent studies on reasoning VLAs show that explicit chain-of-thought (CoT) can improve generalization, they suffer from high inference latency due to lengthy reasoning traces. We propose Fast-ThinkAct, an efficient reasoning framework that achieves compact yet performant planning through verbalizable latent reasoning. Fast-ThinkAct learns to reason efficiently with latent CoTs by distilling from a teacher, driven by a preference-guided objective to align manipulation trajectories that transfers both linguistic and visual planning capabilities for embodied control. This enables reasoning-enhanced policy learning that effectively connects compact reasoning to action execution. Extensive experiments across diverse embodied manipulation and reasoning benchmarks demonstrate that Fast-ThinkAct achieves strong performance with up to 89.3\% reduced inference latency over state-of-the-art reasoning VLAs, while maintaining effective long-horizon planning, few-shot adaptation, and failure recovery.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:40:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09708</guid></item><item><title>MAXS: Meta-Adaptive Exploration with LLM Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09259</link><description>MAXS is a meta-adaptive reasoning framework for LLM agents that improves multi-tool reasoning through lookahead strategies and trajectory convergence mechanisms, balancing global effectiveness and computational efficiency.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Model (LLM) Agents exhibit inherent reasoning abilities through the collaboration of multiple tools. However, during agent inference, existing methods often suffer from (i) locally myopic generation, due to the absence of lookahead, and (ii) trajectory instability, where minor early errors can escalate into divergent reasoning paths. These issues make it difficult to balance global effectiveness and computational efficiency. To address these two issues, we propose meta-adaptive exploration with LLM agents https://github.com/exoskeletonzj/MAXS, a meta-adaptive reasoning framework based on LLM Agents that flexibly integrates tool execution and reasoning planning. MAXS employs a lookahead strategy to extend reasoning paths a few steps ahead, estimating the advantage value of tool usage, and combines step consistency variance and inter-step trend slopes to jointly select stable, consistent, and high-value reasoning steps. Additionally, we introduce a trajectory convergence mechanism that controls computational cost by halting further rollouts once path consistency is achieved, enabling a balance between resource efficiency and global effectiveness in multi-tool reasoning. We conduct extensive empirical studies across three base models (MiMo-VL-7B, Qwen2.5-VL-7B, Qwen2.5-VL-32B) and five datasets, demonstrating that MAXS consistently outperforms existing methods in both performance and inference efficiency. Further analysis confirms the effectiveness of our lookahead strategy and tool usage.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:52:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09259</guid></item><item><title>A^3-Bench: Benchmarking Memory-Driven Scientific Reasoning via Anchor and Attractor Activation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09274</link><description>Scientific reasoning relies not only on logical inference but also on activating prior knowledge and experiential structures. Memory can efficiently reuse knowledge and enhance reasoning consistency and stability. However, existing benchmarks mainly evaluate final answers or step-by-step coherence, overlooking the memory-driven mechanisms that underlie human reasoning, which involves activating anchors and attractors, then integrating them into multi-step inference. To address this gap, we propose A^3-Bench~ https://a3-bench.github.io, a benchmark designed to evaluate scientific reasoning through dual-scale memory-driven activation, grounded in Anchor and Attractor Activation. First, we annotate 2,198 science reasoning problems across domains using the SAPM process(subject, anchor &amp; attractor, problem, and memory developing). Second, we introduce a dual-scale memory evaluation framework utilizing anchors and attractors, along with the AAUI(Anchor--Attractor Utilization Index) metric to measure memory activation rates. Finally, through experiments with various base models and paradigms, we validate A^3-Bench and analyze how memory activation impacts reasoning performance, providing insights into memory-driven scientific reasoning.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:53:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09274</guid></item><item><title>Are LLMs Vulnerable to Preference-Undermining Attacks (PUA)? A Factorial Analysis Methodology for Diagnosing the Trade-off between Preference Alignment and Real-World Validity</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.06596</link><description>Research examines how large language models can be manipulated through preference-undermining attacks that exploit alignment objectives, revealing model vulnerabilities and proposing a factorial evaluation method for diagnosing alignment risks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Large Language Model (LLM) training often optimizes for preference alignment, rewarding outputs that are perceived as helpful and interaction-friendly. However, this preference-oriented objective can be exploited: manipulative prompts can steer responses toward user-appeasing agreement and away from truth-oriented correction. In this work, we investigate whether aligned models are vulnerable to Preference-Undermining Attacks (PUA), a class of manipulative prompting strategies designed to exploit the model's desire to please user preferences at the expense of truthfulness. We propose a diagnostic methodology that provides a finer-grained and more directive analysis than aggregate benchmark scores, using a factorial evaluation framework to decompose prompt-induced shifts into interpretable effects of system objectives (truth- vs. preference-oriented) and PUA-style dialogue factors (directive control, personal derogation, conditional approval, reality denial) within a controlled 2 times 2^4 design. Surprisingly, more advanced models are sometimes more susceptible to manipulative prompts. Beyond the dominant reality-denial factor, we observe model-specific sign reversals and interactions with PUA-style factors, suggesting tailored defenses rather than uniform robustness. These findings offer a novel, reproducible factorial evaluation methodology that provides finer-grained diagnostics for post-training processes like RLHF, enabling better trade-offs in the product iteration of LLMs by offering a more nuanced understanding of preference alignment risks and the impact of manipulative prompts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:28:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.06596</guid></item><item><title>ExpSeek: Self-Triggered Experience Seeking for Web Agents</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.08605</link><description>ExpSeek enables web agents to proactively seek experience during interaction by using entropy-based timing and tailored content, achieving significant performance improvements across multiple benchmarks.  					AI-generated summary 				 Experience intervention in web agents emerges as a promising technical paradigm, enhancing agent interaction capabilities by providing valuable insights from accumulated experiences. However, existing methods predominantly inject experience passively as global context before task execution, struggling to adapt to dynamically changing contextual observations during agent-environment interaction. We propose ExpSeek, which shifts experience toward step-level proactive seeking: (1) estimating step-level entropy thresholds to determine intervention timing using the model's intrinsic signals; (2) designing step-level tailor-designed experience content. Experiments on Qwen3-8B and 32B models across four challenging web agent benchmarks demonstrate that ExpSeek achieves absolute improvements of 9.3% and 7.5%, respectively. Our experiments validate the feasibility and advantages of entropy as a self-triggering signal, reveal that even a 4B small-scale experience model can significantly boost the performance of larger agent models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:02:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.08605</guid></item><item><title>FocusUI: Efficient UI Grounding via Position-Preserving Visual Token Selection</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03928</link><description>FocusUI is an efficient UI grounding framework that reduces computational overhead by selecting relevant visual tokens while preserving positional continuity through a novel PosPad strategy.  					AI-generated summary 				 Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have shown remarkable performance in User Interface (UI) grounding tasks, driven by their ability to process increasingly high-resolution screenshots. However, screenshots are tokenized into thousands of visual tokens (e.g., about 4700 for 2K resolution), incurring significant computational overhead and diluting attention. In contrast, humans typically focus on regions of interest when interacting with UI. In this work, we pioneer the task of efficient UI grounding. Guided by practical analysis of the task's characteristics and challenges, we propose FocusUI, an efficient UI grounding framework that selects patches most relevant to the instruction while preserving positional continuity for precise grounding. FocusUI addresses two key challenges: (1) Eliminating redundant tokens in visual encoding. We construct patch-level supervision by fusing an instruction-conditioned score with a rule-based UI-graph score that down-weights large homogeneous regions to select distinct and instruction-relevant visual tokens. (2) Preserving positional continuity during visual token selection. We find that general visual token pruning methods suffer from severe accuracy degradation on UI grounding tasks due to broken positional information. We introduce a novel PosPad strategy, which compresses each contiguous sequence of dropped visual tokens into a single special marker placed at the sequence's last index to preserve positional continuity. Comprehensive experiments on four grounding benchmarks demonstrate that FocusUI surpasses GUI-specific baselines. On the ScreenSpot-Pro benchmark, FocusUI-7B achieves a performance improvement of 3.7% over GUI-Actor-7B. Even with only 30% visual token retention, FocusUI-7B drops by only 3.2% while achieving up to 1.44x faster inference and 17% lower peak GPU memory.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:44:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.03928</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Camera-Controlled Video Generation of Static Scenes via Sparse Diffusion and 3D Rendering</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09697</link><description>Diffusion-based video generation is made more efficient through keyframe-based 3D reconstruction and rendering, enabling faster synthesis with maintained visual quality.  					AI-generated summary 				 Modern video generative models based on diffusion models can produce very realistic clips, but they are computationally inefficient, often requiring minutes of GPU time for just a few seconds of video. This inefficiency poses a critical barrier to deploying generative video in applications that require real-time interactions, such as embodied AI and VR/AR. This paper explores a new strategy for camera-conditioned video generation of static scenes: using diffusion-based generative models to generate a sparse set of keyframes, and then synthesizing the full video through 3D reconstruction and rendering. By lifting keyframes into a 3D representation and rendering intermediate views, our approach amortizes the generation cost across hundreds of frames while enforcing geometric consistency. We further introduce a model that predicts the optimal number of keyframes for a given camera trajectory, allowing the system to adaptively allocate computation. Our final method, SRENDER, uses very sparse keyframes for simple trajectories and denser ones for complex camera motion. This results in video generation that is more than 40 times faster than the diffusion-based baseline in generating 20 seconds of video, while maintaining high visual fidelity and temporal stability, offering a practical path toward efficient and controllable video synthesis.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:56:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09697</guid></item><item><title>OpenVoxel: Training-Free Grouping and Captioning Voxels for Open-Vocabulary 3D Scene Understanding</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09575</link><description>OpenVoxel enables open-vocabulary 3D scene understanding through training-free grouping and captioning of sparse voxels using Vision Language Models and Multi-modal Large Language Models.  					AI-generated summary 				 We propose OpenVoxel, a training-free algorithm for grouping and captioning sparse voxels for the open-vocabulary 3D scene understanding tasks. Given the sparse voxel rasterization (SVR) model obtained from multi-view images of a 3D scene, our OpenVoxel is able to produce meaningful groups that describe different objects in the scene. Also, by leveraging powerful Vision Language Models (VLMs) and Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs), our OpenVoxel successfully build an informative scene map by captioning each group, enabling further 3D scene understanding tasks such as open-vocabulary segmentation (OVS) or referring expression segmentation (RES). Unlike previous methods, our method is training-free and does not introduce embeddings from a CLIP/BERT text encoder. Instead, we directly proceed with text-to-text search using MLLMs. Through extensive experiments, our method demonstrates superior performance compared to recent studies, particularly in complex referring expression segmentation (RES) tasks. The code will be open.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:14:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09575</guid></item><item><title>EvoFSM: Controllable Self-Evolution for Deep Research with Finite State Machines</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09465</link><description>EvoFSM is a structured self-evolving framework for LLM agents that uses finite state machines to improve adaptability while maintaining control through constrained optimization and memory mechanisms.  					AI-generated summary 				 While LLM-based agents have shown promise for deep research, most existing approaches rely on fixed workflows that struggle to adapt to real-world, open-ended queries. Recent work therefore explores self-evolution by allowing agents to rewrite their own code or prompts to improve problem-solving ability, but unconstrained optimization often triggers instability, hallucinations, and instruction drift. We propose EvoFSM, a structured self-evolving framework that achieves both adaptability and control by evolving an explicit Finite State Machine (FSM) instead of relying on free-form rewriting. EvoFSM decouples the optimization space into macroscopic Flow (state-transition logic) and microscopic Skill (state-specific behaviors), enabling targeted improvements under clear behavioral boundaries. Guided by a critic mechanism, EvoFSM refines the FSM through a small set of constrained operations, and further incorporates a self-evolving memory that distills successful trajectories as reusable priors and failure patterns as constraints for future queries. Extensive evaluations on five multi-hop QA benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of EvoFSM. In particular, EvoFSM reaches 58.0% accuracy on the DeepSearch benchmark. Additional results on interactive decision-making tasks further validate its generalization.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:06:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09465</guid></item><item><title>The AI Hippocampus: How Far are We From Human Memory?</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09113</link><description>Memory mechanisms in large language models and multi-modal language models are categorized into implicit, explicit, and agentic paradigms, supporting enhanced reasoning, adaptability, and contextual fidelity through internal parameters, external knowledge storage, and persistent agent memory structures.  					AI-generated summary 				 Memory plays a foundational role in augmenting the reasoning, adaptability, and contextual fidelity of modern Large Language Models and Multi-Modal LLMs. As these models transition from static predictors to interactive systems capable of continual learning and personalized inference, the incorporation of memory mechanisms has emerged as a central theme in their architectural and functional evolution. This survey presents a comprehensive and structured synthesis of memory in LLMs and MLLMs, organizing the literature into a cohesive taxonomy comprising implicit, explicit, and agentic memory paradigms. Specifically, the survey delineates three primary memory frameworks. Implicit memory refers to the knowledge embedded within the internal parameters of pre-trained transformers, encompassing their capacity for memorization, associative retrieval, and contextual reasoning. Recent work has explored methods to interpret, manipulate, and reconfigure this latent memory. Explicit memory involves external storage and retrieval components designed to augment model outputs with dynamic, queryable knowledge representations, such as textual corpora, dense vectors, and graph-based structures, thereby enabling scalable and updatable interaction with information sources. Agentic memory introduces persistent, temporally extended memory structures within autonomous agents, facilitating long-term planning, self-consistency, and collaborative behavior in multi-agent systems, with relevance to embodied and interactive AI. Extending beyond text, the survey examines the integration of memory within multi-modal settings, where coherence across vision, language, audio, and action modalities is essential. Key architectural advances, benchmark tasks, and open challenges are discussed, including issues related to memory capacity, alignment, factual consistency, and cross-system interoperability.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:04:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09113</guid></item><item><title>TranslateGemma Technical Report</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09012</link><description>TranslateGemma enhances Gemma 3's multilingual capabilities through two-stage fine-tuning with synthetic and human-translated data, achieving superior translation quality with improved efficiency.  					AI-generated summary 				 We present TranslateGemma, a suite of open machine translation models based on the Gemma 3 foundation models. To enhance the inherent multilingual capabilities of Gemma 3 for the translation task, we employ a two-stage fine-tuning process. First, supervised fine-tuning is performed using a rich mixture of high-quality large-scale synthetic parallel data generated via state-of-the-art models and human-translated parallel data. This is followed by a reinforcement learning phase, where we optimize translation quality using an ensemble of reward models, including MetricX-QE and AutoMQM, targeting translation quality. We demonstrate the effectiveness of TranslateGemma with human evaluation on the WMT25 test set across 10 language pairs and with automatic evaluation on the WMT24++ benchmark across 55 language pairs. Automatic metrics show consistent and substantial gains over the baseline Gemma 3 models across all sizes. Notably, smaller TranslateGemma models often achieve performance comparable to larger baseline models, offering improved efficiency. We also show that TranslateGemma models retain strong multimodal capabilities, with enhanced performance on the Vistra image translation benchmark. The release of the open TranslateGemma models aims to provide the research community with powerful and adaptable tools for machine translation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:15:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2601.09012</guid></item></channel></rss>