<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>🚀 ZeroGPU now supports PyTorch native quantization via</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/cbensimon/565026286160860</link><description>🚀 ZeroGPU now supports PyTorch native quantization via torchao While it hasn’t been battle-tested yet, Int8WeightOnlyConfig is already working flawlessly in our tests. Let us know if you run into any issues — and we’re excited to see what the community will build! import spaces from diffusers import FluxPipeline from torchao.quantization.quant_api import Int8WeightOnlyConfig, quantize_ pipeline = FluxPipeline.from_pretrained(...).to( 'cuda' ) quantize_(pipeline.transformer, Int8WeightOnlyConfig()) # Or any other component(s) @spaces.GPU def generate ( prompt: str ): return pipeline(prompt).images[ 0 ] See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/cbensimon/565026286160860</guid></item><item><title>Has anyone ever backed up a model to a sequential tape drive, or I'm the world first? :D</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/csabakecskemeti/762115035937109</link><description>Has anyone ever backed up a model to a sequential tape drive, or I'm the world first? :D Just played around with my retro PC that has got a tape drive—did it just because I can. See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/csabakecskemeti/762115035937109</guid></item><item><title>🚀 Videoxity is live on Hugging Face! 🎞️</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/zamal/148346638153657</link><description>🚀 Videoxity is live on Hugging Face! 🎞️ A powerful, modular toolkit for intelligent video manipulation and scene editing. With Videoxity, you can: 🖼️ Auto-caption keyframes with BLIP 🧠 Filter scenes using natural language (e.g. “remove dog scenes”) ✂️ Seamlessly trim videos with FFmpeg 📊 Generate frame-based summaries Powered by Groq LLM + LangChain, OpenCV, BLIP, and SentenceTransformers, Videoxity bridges vision and language to give developers full control over video content. 🔧 Built for developers. Feedback welcome! 👉 Try it out here fau/videoxity See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/zamal/148346638153657</guid></item><item><title>Imagine you could have an Image Arena score equivalent at each checkpoint during training. We released the first version of just that:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/871941197791232</link><description>Imagine you could have an Image Arena score equivalent at each checkpoint during training. We released the first version of just that: Crowd-Eval Add one line of code to your training loop and you will have a new real human loss curve in your W&amp;B dashboard. Thousands of real humans from around the world rating your model in real time at the cost of a few dollars per checkpoint is a game changer. Check it out here: https://github.com/RapidataAI/crowd-eval First 5 people to put it in their loop get 100'000 human responses for free! (ping me) See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/871941197791232</guid></item><item><title>Super excited to launch Hugging Face Sheets: Spreadsheets meet AI and unstructured data.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/dvilasuero/324662497616161</link><description>Super excited to launch Hugging Face Sheets: Spreadsheets meet AI and unstructured data. A few months ago, we started imagining new ways to build and transform datasets with the latest open-source models. Today, I'm thrilled to introduce our first step in this direction. In a nutshell: 📁 Effortlessly run prompts and models over your data. 🌐 Agentic search for accuracy and real-time information. 🖼️ Familiar, minimalistic interface for interacting with data. 🎯 Human feedback 2.0: Your input directly improves generated data. 💯 Access hundreds of open models and leading inference providers. Go to this space to try it out! aisheets/sheets Leave your questions below, we're just getting started! See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/dvilasuero/324662497616161</guid></item><item><title>Mistral releases Magistral, their new reasoning models! 🔥</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/426556210957370</link><description>Mistral releases Magistral, their new reasoning models! 🔥 GGUFs to run: unsloth/Magistral-Small-2506-GGUF Magistral-Small-2506 excels at mathematics and coding. You can run the 24B model locally with just 32GB RAM by using our Dynamic GGUFs. See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/426556210957370</guid></item><item><title>12 Foundational AI Model Types</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/795992300839975</link><description>12 Foundational AI Model Types Let’s refresh some fundamentals today to stay fluent in the what we all work with. Here are some of the most popular model types that shape the vast world of AI (with examples in the brackets): 1. LLM - Large Language Model (GPT, LLaMA) -&gt; Large Language Models: A Survey (2402.06196) + history of LLMs: https://www.turingpost.com/t/The%20History%20of%20LLMs It's trained on massive text datasets to understand and generate human language. They are mostly build on Transformer architecture, predicting the next token. LLMs scale by increasing overall parameter count across all components (layers, attention heads, MLPs, etc.) 2. SLM - Small Language Model (TinyLLaMA, Phi models, SmolLM) A Survey of Small Language Models (2410.20011) Lightweight LM optimized for efficiency, low memory use, fast inference, and edge use. SLMs work using the same principles as LLMs 3. VLM - Vision-Language Model (CLIP, Flamingo) -&gt; An Introduction to Vision-Language Modeling...</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Kseniase/795992300839975</guid></item><item><title>🗣️ 📢  New article alert!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/462704497331407</link><description>🗣️ 📢 New article alert! "Integrity Threats in AI: When Data Poisoning Undermines Model Effectiveness" from Duality AI is now on HuggingFace here: https://huggingface.co/blog/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/integrity-threats-in-ai Significant threats to AI model performance aren’t always loud or obvious. Integrity violations—like subtle data poisoning attacks—can quietly erode your model’s reliability, long before anyone notices. These attacks can be surprisingly effective with minimal changes to the dataset. At Duality, our work in high-stakes sectors like defense has driven us to tackle this threat head-on. In our latest blog from Duality's Director of Infrastructure and Security at Duality, David Strout, we unpack how data poisoning works, why it’s so dangerous, and how organizations can secure their AI pipelines with clear provenance, regular performance auditing, and a trusted synthetic data supply chain. Whether you're building AI models for finance, healthcare, manufacturing, or...</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/462704497331407</guid></item><item><title>Ultimate ComfyUI &amp; SwarmUI on RunPod Tutorial with Addition RTX 5000 Series GPUs &amp; 1-Click to Setup :</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/478306591921253</link><description>Ultimate ComfyUI &amp; SwarmUI on RunPod Tutorial with Addition RTX 5000 Series GPUs &amp; 1-Click to Setup : https://youtu.be/R02kPf9Y3_w Tutorial Video : https://youtu.be/R02kPf9Y3_w If you want to use ComfyUI or SwarmUI with ComfyUI backend on RunPod cloud platform, this is the ultimate tutorial that you will find to step by step install ComfyUI and SwarmUI on RunPod and use each one of them. RunPod is a great platform to scale your AI generation or if you are a GPU poor, rent the very best GPUs and leverage the AI in your profession. ComfyUI is the ultimate ecosystem right now for Image and Video generation models and with SwarmUI interface leveraging ComfyUI, you can become master for gen AI. So learn how to install ComfyUI on RunPod step by step and run it. Then learn how to install SwarmUI on RunPod step by step and learn how to use it. Then learn how to give installed ComfyUI backend to SwarmUI and leverage its features and ultimate performance and optimizations. Moreover, the...</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/478306591921253</guid></item><item><title>Snooping on HF is the best because sometimes you just discover that someone (in this case, Earth Species Project) is about to drop terabytes of sick (high quality animal sounds) data...</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/cgeorgiaw/953713233096323</link><description>Snooping on HF is the best because sometimes you just discover that someone (in this case, Earth Species Project) is about to drop terabytes of sick (high quality animal sounds) data... EarthSpeciesProject/NatureLM-audio-training See translation</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 05:23:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/cgeorgiaw/953713233096323</guid></item></channel></rss>