<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>CLIMB: CLustering-based Iterative Data Mixture Bootstrapping for
  Language Model Pre-training</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13161</link><description>Pre-training datasets are typically collected from web content and lack inherent domain divisions. For instance, widely used datasets like Common Crawl do not include explicit domain labels, while manually curating labeled datasets such as The Pile is labor-intensive. Consequently, identifying an optimal pre-training data mixture remains a challenging problem, despite its significant benefits for pre-training performance. To address these challenges, we propose CLustering-based Iterative Data Mixture Bootstrapping (CLIMB), an automated framework that discovers, evaluates, and refines data mixtures in a pre-training setting. Specifically, CLIMB embeds and clusters large-scale datasets in a semantic space and then iteratively searches for optimal mixtures using a smaller proxy model and a predictor. When continuously trained on 400B tokens with this mixture, our 1B model exceeds the state-of-the-art Llama-3.2-1B by 2.0%. Moreover, we observe that optimizing for a specific domain (e.g., Social Sciences) yields a 5% improvement over random sampling. Finally, we introduce ClimbLab, a filtered 1.2-trillion-token corpus with 20 clusters as a research playground, and ClimbMix, a compact yet powerful 400-billion-token dataset designed for efficient pre-training that delivers superior performance under an equal token budget. We analyze the final data mixture, elucidating the characteristics of an optimal data mixture. Our data is available at: https://research.nvidia.com/labs/lpr/climb/</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 04:35:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13161</guid></item><item><title>Antidistillation Sampling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13146</link><description>Frontier models that generate extended reasoning traces inadvertently produce rich token sequences that can facilitate model distillation. Recognizing this vulnerability, model owners may seek sampling strategies that limit the effectiveness of distillation without compromising model performance. Antidistillation sampling provides exactly this capability. By strategically modifying a model's next-token probability distribution, antidistillation sampling poisons reasoning traces, rendering them significantly less effective for distillation while preserving the model's practical utility. For further details, see https://antidistillation.com.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 02:29:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13146</guid></item><item><title>A Strategic Coordination Framework of Small LLMs Matches Large LLMs in
  Data Synthesis</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12322</link><description>While data synthesis and distillation are promising strategies to enhance small language models, current approaches heavily rely on Large Language Models (LLMs), which suffer from high computational costs, environmental inefficiency, and potential biases inherited from monolithic architectures. In contrast, smaller LLMs are more accessible and sustainable, but their individual capabilities often fall short in generating high-quality, diverse, and reliable data. Inspired by collaborative human processes (e.g., peer review), we propose a multiple small LLMs involved framework, GRA, that aggregates specialized roles across small LLMs to iterative refinement and quality control typically achieved by a single large LLM. In this collaborative framework, multiple small LLMs assume distinct roles-Generator, Reviewer, and Adjudicator-to simulate a peer-review-inspired data synthesis pipeline. The Generator proposes initial data samples, the Reviewer critiques their quality and diversity, and the Adjudicator resolves conflicts to finalize the output. By decomposing the synthesis process into specialized sub-tasks, collaborative small LLMs can achieve data-level parity with large LLM-based distillation. Through experiments across multiple benchmarks, we demonstrate that GRA-produced data matches or exceeds the quality of single large LLM outputs, e.g., Qwen-2.5-72B-Instruct. Our results challenge the necessity of monolithic large models for high-quality data synthesis, advocating instead for strategic coordination of smaller agents. Our datasets, models, and code are publicly available at https://github.com/GX-XinGao/GRA.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 05:28:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12322</guid></item><item><title>Generate, but Verify: Reducing Hallucination in Vision-Language Models
  with Retrospective Resampling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13169</link><description>Vision-Language Models (VLMs) excel at visual understanding but often suffer from visual hallucinations, where they generate descriptions of nonexistent objects, actions, or concepts, posing significant risks in safety-critical applications. Existing hallucination mitigation methods typically follow one of two paradigms: generation adjustment, which modifies decoding behavior to align text with visual inputs, and post-hoc verification, where external models assess and correct outputs. While effective, generation adjustment methods often rely on heuristics and lack correction mechanisms, while post-hoc verification is complicated, typically requiring multiple models and tending to reject outputs rather than refine them. In this work, we introduce REVERSE, a unified framework that integrates hallucination-aware training with on-the-fly self-verification. By leveraging a new hallucination-verification dataset containing over 1.3M semi-synthetic samples, along with a novel inference-time retrospective resampling technique, our approach enables VLMs to both detect hallucinations during generation and dynamically revise those hallucinations. Our evaluations show that REVERSE achieves state-of-the-art hallucination reduction, outperforming the best existing methods by up to 12% on CHAIR-MSCOCO and 28% on HaloQuest. Our dataset, model, and code are available at: https://reverse-vlm.github.io.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 02:46:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13169</guid></item><item><title>Packing Input Frame Context in Next-Frame Prediction Models for Video
  Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12626</link><description>We present a neural network structure, FramePack, to train next-frame (or next-frame-section) prediction models for video generation. The FramePack compresses input frames to make the transformer context length a fixed number regardless of the video length. As a result, we are able to process a large number of frames using video diffusion with computation bottleneck similar to image diffusion. This also makes the training video batch sizes significantly higher (batch sizes become comparable to image diffusion training). We also propose an anti-drifting sampling method that generates frames in inverted temporal order with early-established endpoints to avoid exposure bias (error accumulation over iterations). Finally, we show that existing video diffusion models can be finetuned with FramePack, and their visual quality may be improved because the next-frame prediction supports more balanced diffusion schedulers with less extreme flow shift timesteps.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 02:17:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12626</guid></item><item><title>VistaDPO: Video Hierarchical Spatial-Temporal Direct Preference
  Optimization for Large Video Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13122</link><description>Large Video Models (LVMs) built upon Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown promise in video understanding but often suffer from misalignment with human intuition and video hallucination issues. To address these challenges, we introduce VistaDPO, a novel framework for Video Hierarchical Spatial-Temporal Direct Preference Optimization. VistaDPO enhances text-video preference alignment across three hierarchical levels: i) Instance Level, aligning overall video content with responses; ii) Temporal Level, aligning video temporal semantics with event descriptions; and iii) Perceptive Level, aligning spatial objects with language tokens. Given the lack of datasets for fine-grained video-language preference alignment, we construct VistaDPO-7k, a dataset of 7.2K QA pairs annotated with chosen and rejected responses, along with spatial-temporal grounding information such as timestamps, keyframes, and bounding boxes. Extensive experiments on benchmarks such as Video Hallucination, Video QA, and Captioning performance tasks demonstrate that VistaDPO significantly improves the performance of existing LVMs, effectively mitigating video-language misalignment and hallucination. The code and data are available at https://github.com/HaroldChen19/VistaDPO.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 02:17:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13122</guid></item><item><title>WORLDMEM: Long-term Consistent World Simulation with Memory</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12369</link><description>World simulation has gained increasing popularity due to its ability to model virtual environments and predict the consequences of actions. However, the limited temporal context window often leads to failures in maintaining long-term consistency, particularly in preserving 3D spatial consistency. In this work, we present WorldMem, a framework that enhances scene generation with a memory bank consisting of memory units that store memory frames and states (e.g., poses and timestamps). By employing a memory attention mechanism that effectively extracts relevant information from these memory frames based on their states, our method is capable of accurately reconstructing previously observed scenes, even under significant viewpoint or temporal gaps. Furthermore, by incorporating timestamps into the states, our framework not only models a static world but also captures its dynamic evolution over time, enabling both perception and interaction within the simulated world. Extensive experiments in both virtual and real scenarios validate the effectiveness of our approach.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 01:54:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12369</guid></item><item><title>DMM: Building a Versatile Image Generation Model via Distillation-Based
  Model Merging</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12364</link><description>The success of text-to-image (T2I) generation models has spurred a proliferation of numerous model checkpoints fine-tuned from the same base model on various specialized datasets. This overwhelming specialized model production introduces new challenges for high parameter redundancy and huge storage cost, thereby necessitating the development of effective methods to consolidate and unify the capabilities of diverse powerful models into a single one. A common practice in model merging adopts static linear interpolation in the parameter space to achieve the goal of style mixing. However, it neglects the features of T2I generation task that numerous distinct models cover sundry styles which may lead to incompatibility and confusion in the merged model. To address this issue, we introduce a style-promptable image generation pipeline which can accurately generate arbitrary-style images under the control of style vectors. Based on this design, we propose the score distillation based model merging paradigm (DMM), compressing multiple models into a single versatile T2I model. Moreover, we rethink and reformulate the model merging task in the context of T2I generation, by presenting new merging goals and evaluation protocols. Our experiments demonstrate that DMM can compactly reorganize the knowledge from multiple teacher models and achieve controllable arbitrary-style generation.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 04:49:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12364</guid></item><item><title>ChartQAPro: A More Diverse and Challenging Benchmark for Chart Question
  Answering</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.05506</link><description>Charts are ubiquitous, as people often use them to analyze data, answer questions, and discover critical insights. However, performing complex analytical tasks with charts requires significant perceptual and cognitive effort. Chart Question Answering (CQA) systems automate this process by enabling models to interpret and reason with visual representations of data. However, existing benchmarks like ChartQA lack real-world diversity and have recently shown performance saturation with modern large vision-language models (LVLMs). To address these limitations, we introduce ChartQAPro, a new benchmark that includes 1,341 charts from 157 diverse sources, spanning various chart types, including infographics and dashboards, and featuring 1,948 questions in various types, such as multiple-choice, conversational, hypothetical, and unanswerable questions, to better reflect real-world challenges. Our evaluations with 21 models show a substantial performance drop for LVLMs on ChartQAPro; e.g., Claude Sonnet 3.5 scores 90.5% on ChartQA but only 55.81% on ChartQAPro, underscoring the complexity of chart reasoning. We complement our findings with detailed error analyses and ablation studies, identifying key challenges and opportunities for advancing LVLMs in chart understanding and reasoning. We release ChartQAPro at https://github.com/vis-nlp/ChartQAPro.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 01:51:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.05506</guid></item><item><title>Exploring Expert Failures Improves LLM Agent Tuning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13145</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown tremendous potential as agents, excelling at tasks that require multiple rounds of reasoning and interactions. Rejection Sampling Fine-Tuning (RFT) has emerged as an effective method for finetuning LLMs as agents: it first imitates expert-generated successful trajectories and further improves agentic skills through iterative fine-tuning on successful, self-generated trajectories. However, since the expert (e.g., GPT-4) succeeds primarily on simpler subtasks and RFT inherently favors simpler scenarios, many complex subtasks remain unsolved and persistently out-of-distribution (OOD). Upon investigating these challenging subtasks, we discovered that previously failed expert trajectories can often provide valuable guidance, e.g., plans and key actions, that can significantly improve agent exploration efficiency and acquisition of critical skills. Motivated by these observations, we propose Exploring Expert Failures (EEF), which identifies beneficial actions from failed expert trajectories and integrates them into the training dataset. Potentially harmful actions are meticulously excluded to prevent contamination of the model learning process. By leveraging the beneficial actions in expert failures, EEF successfully solves some previously unsolvable subtasks and improves agent tuning performance. Remarkably, our approach achieved a 62\% win rate in WebShop, outperforming RFT (53. 6\%) and GPT-4 (35. 6\%), and to the best of our knowledge, setting a new state-of-the-art as the first method to surpass a score of 0.81 in WebShop and exceed 81 in SciWorld.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 03:56:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13145</guid></item><item><title>NoisyRollout: Reinforcing Visual Reasoning with Data Augmentation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13055</link><description>Recent advances in reinforcement learning (RL) have strengthened the reasoning capabilities of vision-language models (VLMs). However, enhancing policy exploration to more effectively scale test-time compute remains underexplored in VLMs. In addition, VLMs continue to struggle with imperfect visual perception, which in turn affects the subsequent reasoning process. To this end, we propose NoisyRollout, a simple yet effective RL approach that mixes trajectories from both clean and moderately distorted images to introduce targeted diversity in visual perception and the resulting reasoning patterns. Without additional training cost, NoisyRollout enhances the exploration capabilities of VLMs by incorporating a vision-oriented inductive bias. Furthermore, NoisyRollout employs a noise annealing schedule that gradually reduces distortion strength over training, ensuring benefit from noisy signals early while maintaining training stability and scalability in later stages. With just 2.1K training samples, NoisyRollout achieves state-of-the-art performance among open-source RL-tuned models on 5 out-of-domain benchmarks spanning both reasoning and perception tasks, while preserving comparable or even better in-domain performance.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:05:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13055</guid></item><item><title>InstantCharacter: Personalize Any Characters with a Scalable Diffusion
  Transformer Framework</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12395</link><description>Current learning-based subject customization approaches, predominantly relying on U-Net architectures, suffer from limited generalization ability and compromised image quality. Meanwhile, optimization-based methods require subject-specific fine-tuning, which inevitably degrades textual controllability. To address these challenges, we propose InstantCharacter, a scalable framework for character customization built upon a foundation diffusion transformer. InstantCharacter demonstrates three fundamental advantages: first, it achieves open-domain personalization across diverse character appearances, poses, and styles while maintaining high-fidelity results. Second, the framework introduces a scalable adapter with stacked transformer encoders, which effectively processes open-domain character features and seamlessly interacts with the latent space of modern diffusion transformers. Third, to effectively train the framework, we construct a large-scale character dataset containing 10-million-level samples. The dataset is systematically organized into paired (multi-view character) and unpaired (text-image combinations) subsets. This dual-data structure enables simultaneous optimization of identity consistency and textual editability through distinct learning pathways. Qualitative experiments demonstrate the advanced capabilities of InstantCharacter in generating high-fidelity, text-controllable, and character-consistent images, setting a new benchmark for character-driven image generation. Our source code is available at https://github.com/Tencent/InstantCharacter.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 07:04:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12395</guid></item><item><title>FocusedAD: Character-centric Movie Audio Description</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12157</link><description>Movie Audio Description (AD) aims to narrate visual content during dialogue-free segments, particularly benefiting blind and visually impaired (BVI) audiences. Compared with general video captioning, AD demands plot-relevant narration with explicit character name references, posing unique challenges in movie understanding.To identify active main characters and focus on storyline-relevant regions, we propose FocusedAD, a novel framework that delivers character-centric movie audio descriptions. It includes: (i) a Character Perception Module(CPM) for tracking character regions and linking them to names; (ii) a Dynamic Prior Module(DPM) that injects contextual cues from prior ADs and subtitles via learnable soft prompts; and (iii) a Focused Caption Module(FCM) that generates narrations enriched with plot-relevant details and named characters. To overcome limitations in character identification, we also introduce an automated pipeline for building character query banks. FocusedAD achieves state-of-the-art performance on multiple benchmarks, including strong zero-shot results on MAD-eval-Named and our newly proposed Cinepile-AD dataset. Code and data will be released at https://github.com/Thorin215/FocusedAD .</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 04:26:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12157</guid></item><item><title>Retrieval-Augmented Generation with Conflicting Evidence</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13079</link><description>Large language model (LLM) agents are increasingly employing retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) to improve the factuality of their responses. However, in practice, these systems often need to handle ambiguous user queries and potentially conflicting information from multiple sources while also suppressing inaccurate information from noisy or irrelevant documents. Prior work has generally studied and addressed these challenges in isolation, considering only one aspect at a time, such as handling ambiguity or robustness to noise and misinformation. We instead consider multiple factors simultaneously, proposing (i) RAMDocs (Retrieval with Ambiguity and Misinformation in Documents), a new dataset that simulates complex and realistic scenarios for conflicting evidence for a user query, including ambiguity, misinformation, and noise; and (ii) MADAM-RAG, a multi-agent approach in which LLM agents debate over the merits of an answer over multiple rounds, allowing an aggregator to collate responses corresponding to disambiguated entities while discarding misinformation and noise, thereby handling diverse sources of conflict jointly. We demonstrate the effectiveness of MADAM-RAG using both closed and open-source models on AmbigDocs -- which requires presenting all valid answers for ambiguous queries -- improving over strong RAG baselines by up to 11.40% and on FaithEval -- which requires suppressing misinformation -- where we improve by up to 15.80% (absolute) with Llama3.3-70B-Instruct. Furthermore, we find that RAMDocs poses a challenge for existing RAG baselines (Llama3.3-70B-Instruct only obtains 32.60 exact match score). While MADAM-RAG begins to address these conflicting factors, our analysis indicates that a substantial gap remains especially when increasing the level of imbalance in supporting evidence and misinformation.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 03:21:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13079</guid></item><item><title>Set You Straight: Auto-Steering Denoising Trajectories to Sidestep
  Unwanted Concepts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12782</link><description>Ensuring the ethical deployment of text-to-image models requires effective techniques to prevent the generation of harmful or inappropriate content. While concept erasure methods offer a promising solution, existing finetuning-based approaches suffer from notable limitations. Anchor-free methods risk disrupting sampling trajectories, leading to visual artifacts, while anchor-based methods rely on the heuristic selection of anchor concepts. To overcome these shortcomings, we introduce a finetuning framework, dubbed ANT, which Automatically guides deNoising Trajectories to avoid unwanted concepts. ANT is built on a key insight: reversing the condition direction of classifier-free guidance during mid-to-late denoising stages enables precise content modification without sacrificing early-stage structural integrity. This inspires a trajectory-aware objective that preserves the integrity of the early-stage score function field, which steers samples toward the natural image manifold, without relying on heuristic anchor concept selection. For single-concept erasure, we propose an augmentation-enhanced weight saliency map to precisely identify the critical parameters that most significantly contribute to the unwanted concept, enabling more thorough and efficient erasure. For multi-concept erasure, our objective function offers a versatile plug-and-play solution that significantly boosts performance. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ANT achieves state-of-the-art results in both single and multi-concept erasure, delivering high-quality, safe outputs without compromising the generative fidelity. Code is available at https://github.com/lileyang1210/ANT</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 03:55:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.12782</guid></item><item><title>Sleep-time Compute: Beyond Inference Scaling at Test-time</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13171</link><description>Scaling test-time compute has emerged as a key ingredient for enabling large language models (LLMs) to solve difficult problems, but comes with high latency and inference cost. We introduce sleep-time compute, which allows models to "think" offline about contexts before queries are presented: by anticipating what queries users might ask and pre-computing useful quantities, we can significantly reduce the compute requirements at test-time. To demonstrate the efficacy of our method, we create modified versions of two reasoning tasks - Stateful GSM-Symbolic and Stateful AIME. We find that sleep-time compute can reduce the amount of test-time compute needed to achieve the same accuracy by ~ 5x on Stateful GSM-Symbolic and Stateful AIME and that by scaling sleep-time compute we can further increase accuracy by up to 13% on Stateful GSM-Symbolic and 18% on Stateful AIME. Furthermore, we introduce Multi-Query GSM-Symbolic, which extends GSM-Symbolic by including multiple related queries per context. By amortizing sleep-time compute across related queries about the same context using Multi-Query GSM-Symbolic, we can decrease the average cost per query by 2.5x. We then conduct additional analysis to understand when sleep-time compute is most effective, finding the predictability of the user query to be well correlated with the efficacy of sleep-time compute. Finally, we conduct a case-study of applying sleep-time compute to a realistic agentic SWE task.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:44:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2504.13171</guid></item></channel></rss>