<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Posts</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the Hugginface trending posts.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>I couldn't watch innocent people get their rights trampled anymore. So I built something to help.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/Severian/232302079144255</link><description>I couldn't watch innocent people get their rights trampled anymore. So I built something to help. Stories of families torn apart, U.S. citizens detained for hours, people arrested just for speaking Spanish. This isn't the America I believe in. Instead of doom-scrolling, I spent a few days building FIREWATCH - a free civil rights protection app. What it does: • Real-time ICE raid alerts • Know Your Rights education in 10+ languages • Secure evidence recording • Emergency panic button • Legal hotlines and resources • 100% private, no tracking The catch? There isn't one. You just need a free Google API key that stays on your device. Works completely offline. https://firewatch-ice.vercel.app/ I built this because everyone deserves constitutional protection. The 4th Amendment doesn't have an asterisk. If this helps one family stay safe, every sleepless night was worth it. Please share with anyone who needs it. Stay safe. See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/Severian/232302079144255</guid></item><item><title>"Why did the bee get married?"</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/847126227827487</link><description>"Why did the bee get married?" "Because he found his honey!" This was the "funniest" joke out of 10'000 jokes we generated with LLMs. With 68% of respondents rating it as "funny". Original jokes are particularly hard for LLMs, as jokes are very nuanced and a lot of context is needed to understand if something is "funny". Something that can only reliably be measured using humans. LLMs are not equally good at generating jokes in every language. Generated English jokes turned out to be way funnier than the Japanese ones. 46% of English-speaking voters on average found the generated joke funny. The same statistic for other languages: Vietnamese: 44% Portuguese: 40% Arabic: 37% Japanese: 28% There is not much variance in generation quality among models for any fixed language. But still Claude Sonnet 4 slightly outperforms others in Vietnamese, Arabic and Japanese and Gemini 2.5 Flash in Portuguese and English We have release the 1 Million (!) native speaker ratings and the 10'000 jokes...</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/jasoncorkill/847126227827487</guid></item><item><title>📢 Generate your own data in simulation using two new free and customizable data-generating Scenarios on Duality's FalconCloud service.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/377698831818015</link><description>📢 Generate your own data in simulation using two new free and customizable data-generating Scenarios on Duality's FalconCloud service. 🙌 These multi-class Scenarios are designed to target model weaknesses for our recent Kaggle competition, but they are free to anyone for non-commercial use! Just create a free account. 📸 Control object and camera posing 👉 Select random variable ranges 🖼️ Set post-processing effects ➕ and more to create a robust dataset for strong model training. Access the 2 Scenarios here: 💠 https://falcon.duality.ai/secure/scenarios/edit/9e90e036-8af9-41e4-8af0-1343b8e8f467?utm_source=Kaggle&amp;utm_medium=post&amp;utm_campaign=competition_4 💠 https://falcon.duality.ai/secure/scenarios/edit/e3294c19-49d4-4f64-9ca8-8373876c2c94?utm_source=Kaggle&amp;utm_medium=post&amp;utm_campaign=competition_4 See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/DualityAI-RebekahBogdanoff/377698831818015</guid></item><item><title>Made some 245GB (80% size reduction) 1.8bit quants for Kimi K2!</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/383539577783045</link><description>Made some 245GB (80% size reduction) 1.8bit quants for Kimi K2! unsloth/Kimi-K2-Instruct-GGUF See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/danielhanchen/383539577783045</guid></item><item><title>past week had huuuge releases 💗</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/294233425076045</link><description>past week had huuuge releases 💗 here's our picks 🔥 find more models, datasets, demos here merve/releases-july-11-68750452c358c98b0fa663f7 &gt; moonshotai/Kimi-K2-Instruct is the new sota LLM with 1T total 32B active parameters 🤯 &gt; HuggingFaceTB/SmolLM3-3B is the new best LM for it's size, offers thinking mode 💭 as well as the dataset HuggingFaceTB/smoltalk2 &gt; Alibaba-NLP/WebSailor-3B is the new agentic LLM for complex browsing &gt; Google DeepMind released medical vision LMs with an agentic doctor-patient app google/medgemma-release-680aade845f90bec6a3f60c4 &gt; fal released a LoRA to improve details on face images fal/Realism-Detailer-Kontext-Dev-LoRA See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/merve/294233425076045</guid></item><item><title>Hey fellow developers and AI enthusiasts,</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/SohanVichat/728099751320142</link><description>Hey fellow developers and AI enthusiasts, I am with the team at TeraVera, and we have just launched something we are really excited about — the TeraVera Secure API for AI solutions. TeraVera API helps protect your data, prevents AI hallucinations, and ensures the integrity of your AI responses. It’s designed to work seamlessly across major platforms like OpenAI/Azure, Google/Gemini, and AWS/Anthropic. Don’t hesitate to request access to the TeraVera Secure API and ensure your data is never leaked into the AI model. Grab your API key here: 🔗 https://www.teravera.com/api-access-form/ You can also check out more about what we do on our site: 🌐 teravera.com Read: https://huggingface.co/blog/TeraVera/teravera We would love to hear your thoughts — feedback, suggestions, or any questions are more than welcome! Cheers, Sohan See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/SohanVichat/728099751320142</guid></item><item><title>Join us in Austin tomorrow for AI Camp’s monthly meetup.</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/GeorgiaArm/326406743119964</link><description>Join us in Austin tomorrow for AI Camp’s monthly meetup. Arm’s Zach Lasiuk and Geremy Cohen will dive into “From Model to Product: Right-Sizing Infrastructure for Real-World Use Cases.” RSVP here 👉 https://www.aicamp.ai/event/eventdetails/W2025071616 See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/GeorgiaArm/326406743119964</guid></item><item><title>Is your code written by a human or an AI? 🤖</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/YerbaPage/335085486816500</link><description>Is your code written by a human or an AI? 🤖 With the rise of AI coding assistants, this question is more critical than ever. Our new tool, DetectCodeGPT, effectively identifies AI-generated code, outperforming SOTA methods with a 7.6% increase in AUC! How? By analyzing unique stylistic and syntactic patterns in code, not just the text. 👇 Explore more: Paper (ICSE 2025): https://arxiv.org/html/2401.06461v2 Code: https://github.com/YerbaPage/DetectCodeGPT #AI #Programming #DeveloperTools #LLM #GenAI See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/YerbaPage/335085486816500</guid></item><item><title>MultiTalk Levelled Up - Way Better Animation Compared to Before with New Workflows - Image to Video &gt;</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/139363304280237</link><description>MultiTalk Levelled Up - Way Better Animation Compared to Before with New Workflows - Image to Video &gt; https://youtu.be/wgCtUeog41g MultiTalk is greatly upgraded. After doing more than 1 day more research with MultiTalk by using 8x A6000 48 GB GPUs, I have significantly improved the MultiTalk workflows and now I am sharing 4 different category workflows with you. VRAM usages and speeds are same but just better quality and animation. Moreover I am introducing a new app which is image and video comparison sliders. Ultra fast and lightweight. Runs as a html app and no GPU is required. https://youtu.be/wgCtUeog41g MultiTalk Full Tutorial With 1-Click Installer - Make Talking and Singing Videos From Static Images &gt; https://youtu.be/8cMIwS9qo4M By using MeiGen MultiTalk you can generate amazing fully animated real-like videos from given audio input. Not only talking but also animating the body movements is possible. In this video I will show you how to install ComfyUI on Windows and...</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/MonsterMMORPG/139363304280237</guid></item><item><title>Ark is now pip-installable and supports the following robots!! If you want to do robotics in python, check it out here:</title><link>https://huggingface.co/posts/hba123/135659637334846</link><description>Ark is now pip-installable and supports the following robots!! If you want to do robotics in python, check it out here: https://robotics-ark.github.io/ark_robotics.github.io/ Now, you can pip-install robotics and work completely in Python. Why Ark you ask, well we love Python :D See translation</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/posts/hba123/135659637334846</guid></item></channel></rss>