<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Hugging Face Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/</link><description>This is a website scraping RSS feed for the HuggingFace Papers.</description><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Stop Overthinking: A Survey on Efficient Reasoning for Large Language
  Models</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16419</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in complex tasks. Recent advancements in Large Reasoning Models (LRMs), such as OpenAI o1 and DeepSeek-R1, have further improved performance in System-2 reasoning domains like mathematics and programming by harnessing supervised fine-tuning (SFT) and reinforcement learning (RL) techniques to enhance the Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning. However, while longer CoT reasoning sequences improve performance, they also introduce significant computational overhead due to verbose and redundant outputs, known as the "overthinking phenomenon". In this paper, we provide the first structured survey to systematically investigate and explore the current progress toward achieving efficient reasoning in LLMs. Overall, relying on the inherent mechanism of LLMs, we categorize existing works into several key directions: (1) model-based efficient reasoning, which considers optimizing full-length reasoning models into more concise reasoning models or directly training efficient reasoning models; (2) reasoning output-based efficient reasoning, which aims to dynamically reduce reasoning steps and length during inference; (3) input prompts-based efficient reasoning, which seeks to enhance reasoning efficiency based on input prompt properties such as difficulty or length control. Additionally, we introduce the use of efficient data for training reasoning models, explore the reasoning capabilities of small language models, and discuss evaluation methods and benchmarking.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 03:26:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16419</guid></item><item><title>Unleashing Vecset Diffusion Model for Fast Shape Generation</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16302</link><description>3D shape generation has greatly flourished through the development of so-called "native" 3D diffusion, particularly through the Vecset Diffusion Model (VDM). While recent advancements have shown promising results in generating high-resolution 3D shapes, VDM still struggles with high-speed generation. Challenges exist because of difficulties not only in accelerating diffusion sampling but also VAE decoding in VDM, areas under-explored in previous works. To address these challenges, we present FlashVDM, a systematic framework for accelerating both VAE and DiT in VDM. For DiT, FlashVDM enables flexible diffusion sampling with as few as 5 inference steps and comparable quality, which is made possible by stabilizing consistency distillation with our newly introduced Progressive Flow Distillation. For VAE, we introduce a lightning vecset decoder equipped with Adaptive KV Selection, Hierarchical Volume Decoding, and Efficient Network Design. By exploiting the locality of the vecset and the sparsity of shape surface in the volume, our decoder drastically lowers FLOPs, minimizing the overall decoding overhead. We apply FlashVDM to Hunyuan3D-2 to obtain Hunyuan3D-2 Turbo. Through systematic evaluation, we show that our model significantly outperforms existing fast 3D generation methods, achieving comparable performance to the state-of-the-art while reducing inference time by over 45x for reconstruction and 32x for generation. Code and models are available at https://github.com/Tencent/FlashVDM.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 03:55:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16302</guid></item><item><title>MathFusion: Enhancing Mathematic Problem-solving of LLM through
  Instruction Fusion</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16212</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown impressive progress in mathematical reasoning. While data augmentation is promising to enhance mathematical problem-solving ability, current approaches are predominantly limited to instance-level modifications-such as rephrasing or generating syntactic variations-which fail to capture and leverage the intrinsic relational structures inherent in mathematical knowledge. Inspired by human learning processes, where mathematical proficiency develops through systematic exposure to interconnected concepts, we introduce MathFusion, a novel framework that enhances mathematical reasoning through cross-problem instruction synthesis. MathFusion implements this through three fusion strategies: (1) sequential fusion, which chains related problems to model solution dependencies; (2) parallel fusion, which combines analogous problems to reinforce conceptual understanding; and (3) conditional fusion, which creates context-aware selective problems to enhance reasoning flexibility. By applying these strategies, we generate a new dataset, MathFusionQA, followed by fine-tuning models (DeepSeekMath-7B, Mistral-7B, Llama3-8B) on it. Experimental results demonstrate that MathFusion achieves substantial improvements in mathematical reasoning while maintaining high data efficiency, boosting performance by 18.0 points in accuracy across diverse benchmarks while requiring only 45K additional synthetic instructions, representing a substantial improvement over traditional single-instruction approaches. Our datasets, models, and code are publicly available at https://github.com/QizhiPei/mathfusion.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:48:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16212</guid></item><item><title>CaKE: Circuit-aware Editing Enables Generalizable Knowledge Learners</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16356</link><description>Knowledge Editing (KE) enables the modification of outdated or incorrect information in large language models (LLMs). While existing KE methods can update isolated facts, they struggle to generalize these updates to multi-hop reasoning tasks that depend on the modified knowledge. Through an analysis of reasoning circuits -- the neural pathways LLMs use for knowledge-based inference, we observe that current layer-localized KE approaches, such as MEMIT and WISE, which edit only single or a few model layers, struggle to effectively incorporate updated information into these reasoning pathways. To address this limitation, we propose CaKE (Circuit-aware Knowledge Editing), a novel method that enables more effective integration of updated knowledge in LLMs. CaKE leverages strategically curated data, guided by our circuits-based analysis, that enforces the model to utilize the modified knowledge, stimulating the model to develop appropriate reasoning circuits for newly integrated knowledge. Experimental results show that CaKE enables more accurate and consistent use of updated knowledge across related reasoning tasks, leading to an average of 20% improvement in multi-hop reasoning accuracy on MQuAKE dataset compared to existing KE methods. We release the code and data in https://github.com/zjunlp/CaKE.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:42:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16356</guid></item><item><title>Cosmos-Reason1: From Physical Common Sense To Embodied Reasoning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15558</link><description>Physical AI systems need to perceive, understand, and perform complex actions in the physical world. In this paper, we present the Cosmos-Reason1 models that can understand the physical world and generate appropriate embodied decisions (e.g., next step action) in natural language through long chain-of-thought reasoning processes. We begin by defining key capabilities for Physical AI reasoning, with a focus on physical common sense and embodied reasoning. To represent physical common sense, we use a hierarchical ontology that captures fundamental knowledge about space, time, and physics. For embodied reasoning, we rely on a two-dimensional ontology that generalizes across different physical embodiments. Building on these capabilities, we develop two multimodal large language models, Cosmos-Reason1-8B and Cosmos-Reason1-56B. We curate data and train our models in four stages: vision pre-training, general supervised fine-tuning (SFT), Physical AI SFT, and Physical AI reinforcement learning (RL) as the post-training. To evaluate our models, we build comprehensive benchmarks for physical common sense and embodied reasoning according to our ontologies. Evaluation results show that Physical AI SFT and reinforcement learning bring significant improvements. To facilitate the development of Physical AI, we will make our code and pre-trained models available under the NVIDIA Open Model License at https://github.com/nvidia-cosmos/cosmos-reason1.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:39:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15558</guid></item><item><title>1000+ FPS 4D Gaussian Splatting for Dynamic Scene Rendering</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16422</link><description>4D Gaussian Splatting (4DGS) has recently gained considerable attention as a method for reconstructing dynamic scenes. Despite achieving superior quality, 4DGS typically requires substantial storage and suffers from slow rendering speed. In this work, we delve into these issues and identify two key sources of temporal redundancy. (Q1) Short-Lifespan Gaussians: 4DGS uses a large portion of Gaussians with short temporal span to represent scene dynamics, leading to an excessive number of Gaussians. (Q2) Inactive Gaussians: When rendering, only a small subset of Gaussians contributes to each frame. Despite this, all Gaussians are processed during rasterization, resulting in redundant computation overhead. To address these redundancies, we present 4DGS-1K, which runs at over 1000 FPS on modern GPUs. For Q1, we introduce the Spatial-Temporal Variation Score, a new pruning criterion that effectively removes short-lifespan Gaussians while encouraging 4DGS to capture scene dynamics using Gaussians with longer temporal spans. For Q2, we store a mask for active Gaussians across consecutive frames, significantly reducing redundant computations in rendering. Compared to vanilla 4DGS, our method achieves a 41times reduction in storage and 9times faster rasterization speed on complex dynamic scenes, while maintaining comparable visual quality. Please see our project page at https://4DGS-1K.github.io.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:59:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16422</guid></item><item><title>JARVIS-VLA: Post-Training Large-Scale Vision Language Models to Play
  Visual Games with Keyboards and Mouse</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16365</link><description>Recently, action-based decision-making in open-world environments has gained significant attention. Visual Language Action (VLA) models, pretrained on large-scale web datasets, have shown promise in decision-making tasks. However, previous work has primarily focused on action post-training, often neglecting enhancements to the foundational model itself. In response, we introduce a novel approach, Act from Visual Language Post-Training, which refines Visual Language Models (VLMs) through visual and linguistic guidance in a self-supervised manner. This enhancement improves the models' capabilities in world knowledge, visual recognition, and spatial grounding in open-world environments. Following the above post-training paradigms, we obtain the first VLA models in Minecraft that can follow human instructions on over 1k different atomic tasks, including crafting, smelting, cooking, mining, and killing. Our experiments demonstrate that post-training on non-trajectory tasks leads to a significant 40% improvement over the best agent baseline on a diverse set of atomic tasks. Furthermore, we demonstrate that our approach surpasses traditional imitation learning-based policies in Minecraft, achieving state-of-the-art performance. We have open-sourced the code, models, and datasets to foster further research. The project page can be found in https://craftjarvis.github.io/JarvisVLA.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 03:29:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16365</guid></item><item><title>Uni-3DAR: Unified 3D Generation and Understanding via Autoregression on
  Compressed Spatial Tokens</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16278</link><description>Recent advancements in large language models and their multi-modal extensions have demonstrated the effectiveness of unifying generation and understanding through autoregressive next-token prediction. However, despite the critical role of 3D structural generation and understanding ({3D GU}) in AI for science, these tasks have largely evolved independently, with autoregressive methods remaining underexplored. To bridge this gap, we introduce Uni-3DAR, a unified framework that seamlessly integrates {3D GU} tasks via autoregressive prediction. At its core, Uni-3DAR employs a novel hierarchical tokenization that compresses 3D space using an octree, leveraging the inherent sparsity of 3D structures. It then applies an additional tokenization for fine-grained structural details, capturing key attributes such as atom types and precise spatial coordinates in microscopic 3D structures. We further propose two optimizations to enhance efficiency and effectiveness. The first is a two-level subtree compression strategy, which reduces the octree token sequence by up to 8x. The second is a masked next-token prediction mechanism tailored for dynamically varying token positions, significantly boosting model performance. By combining these strategies, Uni-3DAR successfully unifies diverse {3D GU} tasks within a single autoregressive framework. Extensive experiments across multiple microscopic {3D GU} tasks, including molecules, proteins, polymers, and crystals, validate its effectiveness and versatility. Notably, Uni-3DAR surpasses previous state-of-the-art diffusion models by a substantial margin, achieving up to 256\% relative improvement while delivering inference speeds up to 21.8x faster. The code is publicly available at https://github.com/dptech-corp/Uni-3DAR.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:06:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16278</guid></item><item><title>CLS-RL: Image Classification with Rule-Based Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16188</link><description>Classification is a core task in machine learning. Recent research has shown that although Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) are initially poor at image classification, fine-tuning them with an adequate amount of data can significantly enhance their performance, making them comparable to SOTA classification models. However, acquiring large-scale labeled data is expensive. In this paper, we explore few-shot MLLM classification fine-tuning. We found that SFT can cause severe overfitting issues and may even degrade performance over the zero-shot approach. To address this challenge, inspired by the recent successes in rule-based reinforcement learning, we propose CLS-RL, which uses verifiable signals as reward to fine-tune MLLMs. We discovered that CLS-RL outperforms SFT in most datasets and has a much higher average accuracy on both base-to-new and few-shot learning setting. Moreover, we observed a free-lunch phenomenon for CLS-RL; when models are fine-tuned on a particular dataset, their performance on other distinct datasets may also improve over zero-shot models, even if those datasets differ in distribution and class names. This suggests that RL-based methods effectively teach models the fundamentals of classification. Lastly, inspired by recent works in inference time thinking, we re-examine the `thinking process' during fine-tuning, a critical aspect of RL-based methods, in the context of visual classification. We question whether such tasks require extensive thinking process during fine-tuning, proposing that this may actually detract from performance. Based on this premise, we introduce the No-Thinking-CLS-RL method, which minimizes thinking processes during training by setting an equality accuracy reward. Our findings indicate that, with much less fine-tuning time, No-Thinking-CLS-RL method achieves superior in-domain performance and generalization capabilities than CLS-RL.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 05:17:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16188</guid></item><item><title>Towards Unified Latent Space for 3D Molecular Latent Diffusion Modeling</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15567</link><description>3D molecule generation is crucial for drug discovery and material science, requiring models to process complex multi-modalities, including atom types, chemical bonds, and 3D coordinates. A key challenge is integrating these modalities of different shapes while maintaining SE(3) equivariance for 3D coordinates. To achieve this, existing approaches typically maintain separate latent spaces for invariant and equivariant modalities, reducing efficiency in both training and sampling. In this work, we propose Unified Variational Auto-Encoder for 3D Molecular Latent Diffusion Modeling (UAE-3D), a multi-modal VAE that compresses 3D molecules into latent sequences from a unified latent space, while maintaining near-zero reconstruction error. This unified latent space eliminates the complexities of handling multi-modality and equivariance when performing latent diffusion modeling. We demonstrate this by employing the Diffusion Transformer--a general-purpose diffusion model without any molecular inductive bias--for latent generation. Extensive experiments on GEOM-Drugs and QM9 datasets demonstrate that our method significantly establishes new benchmarks in both de novo and conditional 3D molecule generation, achieving leading efficiency and quality.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:03:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.15567</guid></item><item><title>XAttention: Block Sparse Attention with Antidiagonal Scoring</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16428</link><description>Long-Context Transformer Models (LCTMs) are vital for real-world applications but suffer high computational costs due to attention's quadratic complexity. Block-sparse attention mitigates this by focusing computation on critical regions, yet existing methods struggle with balancing accuracy and efficiency due to costly block importance measurements. In this paper, we introduce XAttention, a plug-and-play framework that dramatically accelerates long-context inference in Transformers models using sparse attention. XAttention's key innovation is the insight that the sum of antidiagonal values (i.e., from the lower-left to upper-right) in the attention matrix provides a powerful proxy for block importance. This allows for precise identification and pruning of non-essential blocks, resulting in high sparsity and dramatically accelerated inference. Across comprehensive evaluations on demanding long-context benchmarks-including RULER and LongBench for language, VideoMME for video understanding, and VBench for video generation. XAttention achieves accuracy comparable to full attention while delivering substantial computational gains. We demonstrate up to 13.5x acceleration in attention computation. These results underscore XAttention's ability to unlock the practical potential of block sparse attention, paving the way for scalable and efficient deployment of LCTMs in real-world applications. Code is available at https://github.com/mit-han-lab/x-attention.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 03:06:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16428</guid></item><item><title>MagicMotion: Controllable Video Generation with Dense-to-Sparse
  Trajectory Guidance</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16421</link><description>Recent advances in video generation have led to remarkable improvements in visual quality and temporal coherence. Upon this, trajectory-controllable video generation has emerged to enable precise object motion control through explicitly defined spatial paths. However, existing methods struggle with complex object movements and multi-object motion control, resulting in imprecise trajectory adherence, poor object consistency, and compromised visual quality. Furthermore, these methods only support trajectory control in a single format, limiting their applicability in diverse scenarios. Additionally, there is no publicly available dataset or benchmark specifically tailored for trajectory-controllable video generation, hindering robust training and systematic evaluation. To address these challenges, we introduce MagicMotion, a novel image-to-video generation framework that enables trajectory control through three levels of conditions from dense to sparse: masks, bounding boxes, and sparse boxes. Given an input image and trajectories, MagicMotion seamlessly animates objects along defined trajectories while maintaining object consistency and visual quality. Furthermore, we present MagicData, a large-scale trajectory-controlled video dataset, along with an automated pipeline for annotation and filtering. We also introduce MagicBench, a comprehensive benchmark that assesses both video quality and trajectory control accuracy across different numbers of objects. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MagicMotion outperforms previous methods across various metrics. Our project page are publicly available at https://quanhaol.github.io/magicmotion-site.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:58:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16421</guid></item><item><title>InfiniteYou: Flexible Photo Recrafting While Preserving Your Identity</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16418</link><description>Achieving flexible and high-fidelity identity-preserved image generation remains formidable, particularly with advanced Diffusion Transformers (DiTs) like FLUX. We introduce InfiniteYou (InfU), one of the earliest robust frameworks leveraging DiTs for this task. InfU addresses significant issues of existing methods, such as insufficient identity similarity, poor text-image alignment, and low generation quality and aesthetics. Central to InfU is InfuseNet, a component that injects identity features into the DiT base model via residual connections, enhancing identity similarity while maintaining generation capabilities. A multi-stage training strategy, including pretraining and supervised fine-tuning (SFT) with synthetic single-person-multiple-sample (SPMS) data, further improves text-image alignment, ameliorates image quality, and alleviates face copy-pasting. Extensive experiments demonstrate that InfU achieves state-of-the-art performance, surpassing existing baselines. In addition, the plug-and-play design of InfU ensures compatibility with various existing methods, offering a valuable contribution to the broader community.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 04:11:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16418</guid></item><item><title>M3: 3D-Spatial MultiModal Memory</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16413</link><description>We present 3D Spatial MultiModal Memory (M3), a multimodal memory system designed to retain information about medium-sized static scenes through video sources for visual perception. By integrating 3D Gaussian Splatting techniques with foundation models, M3 builds a multimodal memory capable of rendering feature representations across granularities, encompassing a wide range of knowledge. In our exploration, we identify two key challenges in previous works on feature splatting: (1) computational constraints in storing high-dimensional features for each Gaussian primitive, and (2) misalignment or information loss between distilled features and foundation model features. To address these challenges, we propose M3 with key components of principal scene components and Gaussian memory attention, enabling efficient training and inference. To validate M3, we conduct comprehensive quantitative evaluations of feature similarity and downstream tasks, as well as qualitative visualizations to highlight the pixel trace of Gaussian memory attention. Our approach encompasses a diverse range of foundation models, including vision-language models (VLMs), perception models, and large multimodal and language models (LMMs/LLMs). Furthermore, to demonstrate real-world applicability, we deploy M3's feature field in indoor scenes on a quadruped robot. Notably, we claim that M3 is the first work to address the core compression challenges in 3D feature distillation.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:22:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16413</guid></item><item><title>Ultra-Resolution Adaptation with Ease</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16322</link><description>Text-to-image diffusion models have achieved remarkable progress in recent years. However, training models for high-resolution image generation remains challenging, particularly when training data and computational resources are limited. In this paper, we explore this practical problem from two key perspectives: data and parameter efficiency, and propose a set of key guidelines for ultra-resolution adaptation termed URAE. For data efficiency, we theoretically and empirically demonstrate that synthetic data generated by some teacher models can significantly promote training convergence. For parameter efficiency, we find that tuning minor components of the weight matrices outperforms widely-used low-rank adapters when synthetic data are unavailable, offering substantial performance gains while maintaining efficiency. Additionally, for models leveraging guidance distillation, such as FLUX, we show that disabling classifier-free guidance, i.e., setting the guidance scale to 1 during adaptation, is crucial for satisfactory performance. Extensive experiments validate that URAE achieves comparable 2K-generation performance to state-of-the-art closed-source models like FLUX1.1 [Pro] Ultra with only 3K samples and 2K iterations, while setting new benchmarks for 4K-resolution generation. Codes are available https://github.com/Huage001/URAE{here}.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 04:06:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16322</guid></item><item><title>Fin-R1: A Large Language Model for Financial Reasoning through
  Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16252</link><description>Reasoning large language models are rapidly evolving across various domains. However, their capabilities in handling complex financial tasks still require in-depth exploration. In this paper, we introduce Fin-R1, a reasoning large language model specifically designed for the financial sector. Fin-R1 is built using a two-stage architecture, leveraging a financial reasoning dataset distilled and processed based on DeepSeek-R1. Through supervised fine-tuning (SFT) and reinforcement learning (RL) training, it demonstrates performance close to DeepSeek-R1 with a parameter size of 7 billion across a range of financial reasoning tasks. It achieves the state-of-the-art (SOTA) in the FinQA and ConvFinQA tasks between those LLMs in our evaluation, surpassing larger models in other tasks as well. Fin-R1 showcases strong reasoning and decision-making capabilities, providing solutions to various problems encountered in the financial domain. Our code is available at https://github.com/SUFE-AIFLM-Lab/Fin-R1.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:24:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16252</guid></item><item><title>Improving Autoregressive Image Generation through Coarse-to-Fine Token
  Prediction</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16194</link><description>Autoregressive models have shown remarkable success in image generation by adapting sequential prediction techniques from language modeling. However, applying these approaches to images requires discretizing continuous pixel data through vector quantization methods like VQ-VAE. To alleviate the quantization errors that existed in VQ-VAE, recent works tend to use larger codebooks. However, this will accordingly expand vocabulary size, complicating the autoregressive modeling task. This paper aims to find a way to enjoy the benefits of large codebooks without making autoregressive modeling more difficult. Through empirical investigation, we discover that tokens with similar codeword representations produce similar effects on the final generated image, revealing significant redundancy in large codebooks. Based on this insight, we propose to predict tokens from coarse to fine (CTF), realized by assigning the same coarse label for similar tokens. Our framework consists of two stages: (1) an autoregressive model that sequentially predicts coarse labels for each token in the sequence, and (2) an auxiliary model that simultaneously predicts fine-grained labels for all tokens conditioned on their coarse labels. Experiments on ImageNet demonstrate our method's superior performance, achieving an average improvement of 59 points in Inception Score compared to baselines. Notably, despite adding an inference step, our approach achieves faster sampling speeds.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 05:16:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16194</guid></item><item><title>Deceptive Humor: A Synthetic Multilingual Benchmark Dataset for Bridging
  Fabricated Claims with Humorous Content</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16031</link><description>This paper presents the Deceptive Humor Dataset (DHD), a novel resource for studying humor derived from fabricated claims and misinformation. In an era of rampant misinformation, understanding how humor intertwines with deception is essential. DHD consists of humor-infused comments generated from false narratives, incorporating fabricated claims and manipulated information using the ChatGPT-4o model. Each instance is labeled with a Satire Level, ranging from 1 for subtle satire to 3 for high-level satire and classified into five distinct Humor Categories: Dark Humor, Irony, Social Commentary, Wordplay, and Absurdity. The dataset spans multiple languages including English, Telugu, Hindi, Kannada, Tamil, and their code-mixed variants (Te-En, Hi-En, Ka-En, Ta-En), making it a valuable multilingual benchmark. By introducing DHD, we establish a structured foundation for analyzing humor in deceptive contexts, paving the way for a new research direction that explores how humor not only interacts with misinformation but also influences its perception and spread. We establish strong baselines for the proposed dataset, providing a foundation for future research to benchmark and advance deceptive humor detection models.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:58:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.16031</guid></item><item><title>MagicID: Hybrid Preference Optimization for ID-Consistent and
  Dynamic-Preserved Video Customization</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.12689</link><description>Video identity customization seeks to produce high-fidelity videos that maintain consistent identity and exhibit significant dynamics based on users' reference images. However, existing approaches face two key challenges: identity degradation over extended video length and reduced dynamics during training, primarily due to their reliance on traditional self-reconstruction training with static images. To address these issues, we introduce MagicID, a novel framework designed to directly promote the generation of identity-consistent and dynamically rich videos tailored to user preferences. Specifically, we propose constructing pairwise preference video data with explicit identity and dynamic rewards for preference learning, instead of sticking to the traditional self-reconstruction. To address the constraints of customized preference data, we introduce a hybrid sampling strategy. This approach first prioritizes identity preservation by leveraging static videos derived from reference images, then enhances dynamic motion quality in the generated videos using a Frontier-based sampling method. By utilizing these hybrid preference pairs, we optimize the model to align with the reward differences between pairs of customized preferences. Extensive experiments show that MagicID successfully achieves consistent identity and natural dynamics, surpassing existing methods across various metrics.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 03:55:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.12689</guid></item><item><title>See-Saw Modality Balance: See Gradient, and Sew Impaired Vision-Language
  Balance to Mitigate Dominant Modality Bias</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.13834</link><description>Vision-language (VL) models have demonstrated strong performance across various tasks. However, these models often rely on a specific modality for predictions, leading to "dominant modality bias.'' This bias significantly hurts performance, especially when one modality is impaired. In this study, we analyze model behavior under dominant modality bias and theoretically show that unaligned gradients or differences in gradient magnitudes prevent balanced convergence of the loss. Based on these findings, we propose a novel framework, BalGrad to mitigate dominant modality bias. Our approach includes inter-modality gradient reweighting, adjusting the gradient of KL divergence based on each modality's contribution, and inter-task gradient projection to align task directions in a non-conflicting manner. Experiments on UPMC Food-101, Hateful Memes, and MM-IMDb datasets confirm that BalGrad effectively alleviates over-reliance on specific modalities when making predictions.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 05:18:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://huggingface.co/papers/2503.13834</guid></item></channel></rss>